<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idee6f7061-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301"><num value="1301">§ 1301.</num><heading> Definitions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee6f7062-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> General definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this subchapter and the declaration of policy—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f7063-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f7064-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The “parity price” for any agricultural commodity, as of any date, shall be determined by multiplying the adjusted base price of such commodity as of such date by the parity index as of such date.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f7065-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The “adjusted base price” of any agricultural commodity, as of any date, shall be (i) the average of the prices received by farmers for such commodity, at such times as the Secretary may select during each year of the ten-year period ending on the 31st of December last before such date, or during each marketing season beginning in such period if the Secretary determines use of a calendar year basis to be impracticable, divided by (ii) the ratio of the general level of prices received by farmers for agricultural commodities during such period to the general level of prices received by farmers for agricultural commodities during the period January 1910 to December 1914, inclusive. As used in this subparagraph, the term “prices” shall include wartime subsidy payments made to producers under programs designed to maintain maximum prices established under the Emergency Price Control Act of 1942.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f7066-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The “parity index”, as of any date, shall be the ratio of (i) the general level of prices for articles and services that farmers buy, wages paid hired farm labor, interest on farm indebtedness secured by farm real estate, and taxes on farm real estate, for the calendar month ending last before such date to (ii) the general level of such prices, wages, rates, and taxes during the period January 1910 to December 1914, inclusive.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f7067-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The prices and indices provided for herein, and the data used in computing them, shall be determined by the Secretary, whose determination shall be final.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f7068-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/a/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding the provisions of subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, the transitional parity price for any agricultural commodity, computed as provided in this subparagraph, shall be used as the parity price for such commodity until such date after <date date="1950-01-01">January 1, 1950</date>, as such transitional parity price may be lower than the parity price, computed as provided in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, for such commodity. The transitional parity price for any agricultural commodity as of any date shall be—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idee6f7069-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/a/1/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> its parity price determined in the manner used prior to the effective date of the Agricultural Act of 1948, less</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idee6f706a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/a/1/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> 5 per centum of the parity price so determined multiplied by the number of full calendar years (not counting 1956 in the case of basic agricultural commodities) which, as of such date, have elapsed after <date date="1949-01-01">January 1, 1949</date>, in the case of non-basic agricultural commodities, and after <date date="1955-01-01">January 1, 1955</date>, in the case of the basic agricultural commodities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f706b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/a/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> Notwithstanding the provisions of subparagraphs (A) and (E) of this paragraph, if the parity price for any agricultural commodity, computed as provided in subparagraphs (A) and (E) of this paragraph, appears to be seriously out of line with the parity prices of other agricultural commodities, the Secretary may, and upon the request of a substantial number of interested producers shall, hold public hearings to determine the proper relationship between the parity price of such commodity and the parity prices of other agricultural commodities. Within sixty days after commencing such hearing the Secretary shall complete such hearing, proclaim his findings as to whether the facts require a revision of the method of computing the parity price of such commodity, and put into effect any revision so found to be required.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f706c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/a/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this section, the parity price for any basic agricultural commodity, as of any date during the six-year period beginning <date date="1950-01-01">January 1, 1950</date>, shall not be less than its parity price computed in the manner used prior to <date date="1949-10-31">October 31, 1949</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f706d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> “Parity”, as applied to income, shall be that gross income from agriculture which will provide the farm operator and his family with a standard of living equivalent to those afforded persons dependent upon other gainful occupation. “Parity” as applied to income from any agricultural commodity for any year, shall be that gross income which bears the same relationship to parity income from agriculture for such year as the average gross income from such commodity for the preceding ten calendar years bears to the average gross income from agriculture for such ten calendar years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f706e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “interstate and foreign commerce” means sale, marketing, trade, and traffic between any State or Territory or the District of Columbia or Puerto Rico, and any place outside thereof; or between points within the same State or Territory or within the District of Columbia or Puerto Rico, through any place outside thereof; or within any Territory or within the District of Columbia or Puerto Rico.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f706f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The term “affect interstate and foreign commerce” means, among other things, in such commerce, or to burden or obstruct such commerce or the free and orderly flow thereof; or to create or tend to create a surplus of any agricultural commodity which burdens or obstructs such commerce or the free and orderly flow thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f7070-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The term “United States” means the several States and Territories and the District of Columbia and Puerto Rico.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f7071-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The term “State” includes a Territory and the District of Columbia and Puerto Rico.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f7072-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture, and the term “Department” means the Department of Agriculture.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f7073-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> The term “person” means an individual, partnership, firm, joint-stock company, corporation, association, trust, estate, or any agency of a State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f7074-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> The term “corn” means field corn.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee6f7075-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions applicable to one or more commodities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this subchapter—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f7076-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f7077-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> “Actual production” as applied to any acreage of corn means the number of bushels of corn which the local committee determines would be harvested as grain from such acreage if all the corn on such acreage were so harvested. In case of a disagreement between the farmer and the local committee as to the actual production of the acreage of corn on the farm, or in case the local committee determines that such actual production is substantially below normal, the local committee, in accordance with regulations of the Secretary, shall weigh representative samples of ear corn taken from the acreage involved, make proper deductions for moisture content, and determine the actual production of such acreage on the basis of such samples.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f7078-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> “Actual production” of any number of acres of cotton, rice or peanuts on a farm means the actual average yield for the farm times such number of acres.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f7079-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> “Bushel” means in the case of ear corn that amount of ear corn, including not to exceed 15½ per centum of moisture content, which weighs seventy pounds, and in the case of shelled corn, means that amount of shelled corn including not to exceed 15½ per centum of moisture content, which weighs fifty-six pounds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f707a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f707b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> “Carry-over”, in the case of corn, rice, and peanuts for any marketing year shall be the quantity of the commodity on hand in the United States at the beginning of such marketing year, not including any quantity which was produced in the United States during the calendar year then current.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f707c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> “Carry-over” of cotton for any marketing year shall be the quantity of cotton on hand in the United States at the beginning of such marketing year, not including any part of the crop which was produced in the United States during the calendar year then current.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f707d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> “Carry-over” of wheat, for any marketing year shall be the quantity of wheat on hand in the United States at the beginning of such marketing year, not including any wheat which was produced in the United States during the calendar year then current, and not including any wheat held by the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation under the Federal Crop Insurance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1501">7 U.S.C. 1501</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f707e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f707f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> “Commercial corn-producing area” shall include all counties in which the average production of corn (excluding corn used as silage) during the ten calendar years immediately preceding the calendar year for which such area is determined, after adjustment for abnormal weather conditions, is four hundred and fifty bushels or more per farm and four bushels or more for each acre of farm land in the county.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f7080-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Whenever prior to February 1 of any calendar year the Secretary has reason to believe that any county which is not included in the commercial corn-producing area determined pursuant to the provisions of subparagraph (A) of this subsection, but which borders upon one of the counties in such area, or that any minor civil division in a county bordering on such area, is producing (excluding corn used for silage) an average of at least four hundred and fifty bushels of corn per farm and an average of at least four bushels for each acre of farm land in the county or in the minor civil division, as the case may be, he shall cause immediate investigation to be made to determine such fact. If, upon the basis of such investigation, the Secretary finds that such county or minor civil division is likely to produce corn in such average amounts during such calendar year, he shall proclaim such determination and, commencing with such calendar year, such county shall be included in the commercial corn-producing area. In the case of a county included in the commercial corn-producing area pursuant to this subparagraph, whenever prior to February 1 of any calendar year the Secretary has reason to believe that facts justifying the inclusion of such county are not likely to exist in such calendar year, he shall cause an immediate investigation to be made with respect thereto. If, upon the basis of such investigation, the Secretary finds that such facts are not likely to exist in such calendar year, he shall proclaim such determination, and commencing with such calendar year, such county shall be excluded from the commercial corn-producing area.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f7081-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> “Farm consumption” of corn means consumption by the farmer’s family, employees, or household, or by his work stock; or consumption by poultry or livestock on his farm if such poultry or livestock, or the products thereof, are consumed or to be consumed by the farmer’s family, employees, or household.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f7082-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee6f7083-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> “Market”, in the case of corn, cotton, rice, and wheat, means to dispose of, in raw or processed form, by voluntary or involuntary sale, barter, or exchange, or by gift inter vivos, and, in the case of corn and wheat, by feeding (in any form) to poultry or livestock which, or the products of which, are sold, bartered, or exchanged, or to be so disposed of, but does not include disposing of any such commodities as premium to the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation under the Federal Crop Insurance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1501">7 U.S.C. 1501</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b974-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> “Marketed”, “marketing”, and “for market” shall have corresponding meanings to the term “market” in the connection in which they are used.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b975-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> “Market”, in the case of peanuts, means to dispose of peanuts, including farmers’ stock peanuts, shelled peanuts, cleaned peanuts, or peanuts in processed form, by voluntary or involuntary sale, barter, or exchange, or by gift inter vivos.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b976-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> “Marketing year” means, in the case of the following commodities, the period beginning on the first and ending with the second date specified below:<p style="-uslm-lc:I13" role="listItem" class="indent2">Corn, September 1–August 31;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I13" role="listItem" class="indent2">Cotton, August 1–July 31;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Rice, August 1–July 31;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Tobacco (flue-cured), July 1–June 30;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Tobacco (other than flue-cured), October 1–September 30;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Wheat, June 1–May 31.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b977-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b978-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> “National average yield” as applied to cotton or wheat shall be the national average yield per acre of the commodity during the ten calendar years in the case of wheat, and during the five calendar years in the case of cotton, preceding the year in which such national average yield is used in any computation authorized in this subchapter, adjusted for abnormal weather conditions and, in the case of wheat, but not in the case of cotton, for trends in yields.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b979-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> “Projected national yield” as applied to any crop of wheat shall be determined on the basis of the national yield per harvested acre of the commodity during each of the five calendar years immediately preceding the year in which such projected national yield is determined, adjusted for abnormal weather conditions affecting such yield, for trends in yields and for any significant changes in production practices.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b97a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> “Normal production” as applied to any number of acres of corn or rice means the normal yield for the farm times such number of acres. “Normal production” as applied to any number of acres of cotton or wheat means the projected farm yield times such number of acres.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b97b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b97c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/10/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> “Normal supply” in the case of corn, rice, wheat, and peanuts for any marketing year shall be (i) the estimated domestic consumption of the commodity for the marketing year ending immediately prior to the marketing year for which normal supply is being determined, plus (ii) the estimated exports of the commodity for the marketing year for which normal supply is being determined, plus (iii) an allowance for carry-over. The allowance for carry-over shall be the following percentage of the sum of the consumption and exports used in computing normal supply: 15 per centum in the case of corn; 10 per centum in the case of rice; 20 per centum in the case of wheat; and 15 per centum in the case of peanuts. In determining normal supply the Secretary shall make such adjustments for current trends in consumption and for unusual conditions as he may deem necessary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b97d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/10/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The “normal supply” of cotton for any marketing year shall be the estimated domestic consumption of cotton for the marketing year for which such normal supply is being determined, plus the estimated exports of cotton for such marketing year, plus, 30 per centum of the sum of such consumption and exports as an allowance for carry-over.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b97e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b97f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/11/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> “Normal year’s domestic consumption”, in the case of corn and wheat, shall be the yearly average quantity of the commodity, wherever produced, that was cosumed <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002132">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002132"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “consumed”.</note> in the United States during the ten marketing years immediately preceding the marketing year in which such consumption is determined, adjusted for current trends in such consumption.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b980-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/11/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> “Normal year’s domestic consumption”, in the case of cotton, shall be the yearly average quantity of the commodity produced in the United States that was consumed in the United States during the ten marketing years immediately preceding the marketing year in which such consumption is determined, adjusted for current trends in such consumption.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b981-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/11/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> “Normal year’s domestic consumption”, in the case of rice, shall be the yearly average quantity of rice produced in the United States that was consumed in the United States during the five marketing years immediately preceding the marketing year in which such consumption is determined, adjusted for current trends in such consumption.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b982-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> “Normal year’s exports” in the case of corn, cotton, rice, and wheat shall be the yearly average quantity of the commodity produced in the United States that was exported from the United States during the ten marketing years (or, in the case of rice, the five marketing years) immediately preceding the marketing year in which such exports are determined, adjusted for current trends in such exports.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b983-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b984-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/13/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/87/703/tIII/s320/1">Pub. L. 87–703, title III, § 320(1)</ref>, <date date="1962-09-27">Sept. 27, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/625">76 Stat. 625</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b985-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/13/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> “Normal yield” for any county, in the case of peanuts, shall be the average yield per acre of peanuts for the county, adjusted for abnormal weather conditions, during the five calendar years immediately preceding the year in which such normal yield is determined. For 1942, the normal yield for any county, in the case of peanuts, shall be the average yield per acre for peanuts for the county, adjusted for abnormal conditions, during the years 1936–1940, inclusive, except that for any county in which the years 1935–1939, inclusive, are equally as representative, such period may be used in determining the normal yields for counties in the State.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b986-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/13/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> In applying subparagraph (A) or (B) of this paragraph, if for any such year the data are not available, or there is no actual yield, an appraised yield for such year, determined in accordance with regulations issued by the Secretary, shall be used as the actual yield for such year. In applying such subparagraphs, if, on account of drought, flood, insect pests, plant disease, or other uncontrollable natural cause, the yield in any year of such ten-year period or five-year period, as the case may be, is less than 75 per centum of the average (computed without regard to such year) such year shall be eliminated in calculating the normal yield per acre.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b987-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/13/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> “Normal yield” for any county, in the case of rice and wheat, shall be the average yield per acre of rice or wheat, as the case may be, for the county during the five calendar years immediately preceding the year for which such normal yield is determined in the case of rice, or during the five years immediately preceding the year in which such normal yield is determined in the case of wheat, adjusted for abnormal weather conditions and for trends in yields. If for any such year data are not available, or there is no actual yield, an appraised yield for such year, determined in accordance with regulations issued by the Secretary, taking into consideration the yields obtained in surrounding counties during such year and the yield in years for which data are available, shall be used as the actual yield for such year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b988-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/13/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> “Normal yield” for any farm, in the case of rice and wheat, shall be the average yield per acre of rice or wheat, as the case may be, for the farm during the five calendar years immediately preceding the year for which such normal yield is determined in the case of rice, or during the five years immediately preceding the year in which such normal yield is determined in the case of wheat, adjusted for abnormal weather conditions and for trends in yields. If for any such year the data are not available or there is no actual yield, then the normal yield for the farm shall be appraised in accordance with regulations issued by the Secretary, taking into consideration abnormal weather conditions, trends in yields, the normal yield for the county, the yields obtained on adjacent farms during such year and the yield in years for which data are available.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b989-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/13/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> In applying subparagraphs (D) and (E) of this paragraph, if on account of drought, flood, insect pests, plant disease, or other uncontrollable natural cause, the yield for any year of such five-year period is less than 75 per centum of the average, 75 per centum of such average shall be substituted therefor in calculating the normal yield per acre. If, on account of abnormally favorable weather conditions, the yield for any year of such five-year period is in excess of 125 per centum of the average, 125 per centum of such average shall be substituted therefor in calculating the normal yield per acre.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b98a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/13/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> “Normal yield” for any farm, in the case of corn or peanuts, shall be the average yield per acre of corn or peanuts, as the case may be, for the farm, adjusted for abnormal weather conditions, during the five calendar years immediately preceding the year in which such normal yield is determined. For 1942, the normal yield for any farm, in the case of peanuts, shall be the average yield per acre of peanuts for the farm, adjusted for abnormal conditions, during the years 1936–1940, inclusive, except that for any county in which the years 1935–1939, inclusive, are equally as representative, such period may be used in determining normal yields for farms in the county. If for any such year the data are not available or there is no actual yield, then the normal yield for the farm shall be appraised in accordance with regulations of the Secretary, taking into consideration abnormal weather conditions, the normal yield for the county, and the yield in years for which data are available.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b98b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/13/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> “Normal yield” for any county, for any crop of cotton, shall be the average yield per acre of cotton for the county, adjusted for abnormal weather conditions and any significant changes in production practices during the five calendar years immediately preceding the year in which the national marketing quota for such crop is proclaimed. If for any such year the data are not available, or there is no actual yield, an appraised yield for such year, determined in accordance with regulations issued by the Secretary, shall be used as the actual yield for such year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b98c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/13/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> “Normal yield” for any farm, for any crop of cotton, shall be the average yield per acre of cotton for the farm, adjusted for abnormal weather conditions and any significant changes in production practices during the three calendar years immediately preceding the year in which such normal yield is determined. If for any such year the data are not available, or there is no actual yield, then the normal yield for the farm shall be appraised in accordance with regulations of the Secretary, taking into consideration abnormal weather conditions, the normal yield for the county, changes in production practices, and the yield in years for which data are available.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b98d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/13/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><content> “Projected county yield” for any crop of wheat shall be determined on the basis of the yield per harvested acre of such commodity in the county during each of the five calendar years immediately preceding the year in which such projected county yield is determined, adjusted for abnormal weather conditions affecting such yield, for trends in yields and for any significant changes in production practices.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b98e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/13/K"><num value="K">(K)</num><content> “Projected farm yield” for any crop of wheat shall be determined on the basis of the yield per harvested acre of such commodity on the farm during each of the three calendar years immediately preceding the year in which such projected farm yield is determined, adjusted for abnormal weather conditions affecting such yield, for trends in yields and for any significant changes in production practices, but in no event shall such projected farm yield be less than the normal yield for such farm as provided in subparagraph (E) of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b98f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/13/L"><num value="L">(L)</num><content> “Projected national, State, and county yields” for any crop of cotton shall be determined on the basis of the yield per harvested acre of such crop in the United States, the State and the county, respectively, during each of the five calendar years immediately preceding the year in which such projected yield for the United States, the State, and the county, respectively, is determined, adjusted for abnormal weather conditions affecting such yield, for trends in yields, and for any significant changes in production practices.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b990-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/13/M"><num value="M">(M)</num><content> “Projected farm yield” for any crop of cotton shall be determined on the basis of the yield per harvested acre of such crop on the farm during each of the three calendar years immediately preceding the year in which such projected farm yield is determined, adjusted for abnormal weather conditions affecting such yield, for trends in yields, and for any significant changes in production practices, but in no event shall such projected farm yield be less than the normal yield for such farm as provided in subparagraph (I) of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b991-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> “Reserve supply level”, in the case of corn, shall be a normal year’s domestic consumption and exports of corn plus 10 per centum of a normal year’s domestic consumption and exports, to insure a supply adequate to meet domestic consumption and export needs in years of drought, flood, or other adverse conditions, as well as in years of plenty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b992-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b993-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/15/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> “Total supply” of wheat, corn, rice, and peanuts for any marketing year shall be the carry-over of the commodity for such marketing year, plus the estimated production of the commodity in the United States during the calendar year in which such marketing year begins and the estimated imports of the commodity into the United States during such marketing year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee71b994-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/b/15/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> “Total supply” of cotton for any marketing year shall be the carry-over at the beginning of such marketing year, plus the estimated production of cotton in the United States during the calendar year in which such marketing year begins and the estimated imports of cotton into the United States during such marketing year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee71b995-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of Federal statistics</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The latest available statistics of the Federal Government shall be used by the Secretary in making the determinations required to be made by the Secretary under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee71b996-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1301/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Exclusion of stocks of certain commodities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In making any determination under this chapter or under the Agricultural Act of 1949 [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1421">7 U.S.C. 1421</ref> et seq.] with respect to the carryover of any agricultural commodity, the Secretary shall exclude from such determination the stocks of any commodity acquired pursuant to, or under the authority of, the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act (<ref href="/us/stat/60/596">60 Stat. 596</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s98">50 U.S.C. 98</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idee71b997-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-02-16/ch30">Feb. 16, 1938, ch. 30</ref>, title III, § 301, <ref href="/us/stat/52/38">52 Stat. 38</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1938-04-07/ch107">Apr. 7, 1938, ch. 107</ref>, §§ 2–4, <ref href="/us/stat/52/202">52 Stat. 202</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1940-06-13/ch360/s1">June 13, 1940, ch. 360, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/54/392">54 Stat. 392</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1940-07-02/ch521">July 2, 1940, ch. 521</ref>, §§ 3–5, <ref href="/us/stat/54/727">54 Stat. 727</ref>, 728; <ref href="/us/act/1940-11-22/ch914">Nov. 22, 1940, ch. 914</ref>, §§ 1, 3, 4, <ref href="/us/stat/54/1209">54 Stat. 1209</ref>, 1210; <ref href="/us/act/1940-11-25/ch917">Nov. 25, 1940, ch. 917</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/54/1211">54 Stat. 1211</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1941-04-03/ch39">Apr. 3, 1941, ch. 39</ref>, §§ 2, 3, <ref href="/us/stat/55/91">55 Stat. 91</ref>, 92; <ref href="/us/act/1942-07-09/ch497/s1/4">July 9, 1942, ch. 497, § 1(4)</ref>, (5), <ref href="/us/stat/56/654">56 Stat. 654</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1948-07-03/ch827">July 3, 1948, ch. 827</ref>, title II, § 201(a), (b), (d), (e), <ref href="/us/stat/62/1250">62 Stat. 1250</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-08-29/ch518/s2/a">Aug. 29, 1949, ch. 518, § 2(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/675">63 Stat. 675</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-10-31/ch792">Oct. 31, 1949, ch. 792</ref>, title IV, §§ 409(a)–(d), 415(c)–(e), 418(b), (c), <ref href="/us/stat/63/1056-1058">63 Stat. 1056–1058</ref>, 1062; <ref href="/us/act/1952-07-08/ch587">July 8, 1952, ch. 587</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/442">66 Stat. 442</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1952-07-17/ch933/s1">July 17, 1952, ch. 933, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/758">66 Stat. 758</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1953-07-14/ch194/s6">July 14, 1953, ch. 194, § 6</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/152">67 Stat. 152</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-28/ch1041">Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title III, §§ 301, 302, <ref href="/us/stat/68/902">68 Stat. 902</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1956-05-28/ch327">May 28, 1956, ch. 327</ref>, title V, § 502, title VI, § 602, <ref href="/us/stat/70/212">70 Stat. 212</ref>, 213; <ref href="/us/pl/85/92/s1">Pub. L. 85–92, § 1</ref>, <date date="1957-07-10">July 10, 1957</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/71/284">71 Stat. 284</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/703/tIII/s320">Pub. L. 87–703, title III, § 320</ref>, <date date="1962-09-27">Sept. 27, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/625">76 Stat. 625</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/297/tI/s106/5">Pub. L. 88–297, title I, § 106(5)</ref>–(7), <date date="1964-04-11">Apr. 11, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/177">78 Stat. 177</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/321/tIV/s403">Pub. L. 89–321, title IV, § 403</ref>, title V, §§ 509, 511(a), <date date="1965-11-03">Nov. 3, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1197">79 Stat. 1197</ref>, 1204, 1205; <ref href="/us/pl/91/524/tIV/s405/b">Pub. L. 91–524, title IV, § 405(b)</ref>, <date date="1970-11-30">Nov. 30, 1970</date>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/93/86/s1/12/a">Pub. L. 93–86, § 1(12)(a)</ref>, <date date="1973-08-10">Aug. 10, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/229">87 Stat. 229</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/61/s1">Pub. L. 94–61, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-07-25">July 25, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/302">89 Stat. 302</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/218/tIII/s303/a">Pub. L. 97–218, title III, § 303(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-07-20">July 20, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/211">96 Stat. 211</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/198/tX/s1020">Pub. L. 99–198, title X, § 1020</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1459">99 Stat. 1459</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/tI/s1103/a">Pub. L. 99–272, title I, § 1103(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/85">100 Stat. 85</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/171/tI/s1610">Pub. L. 107–171, title I, § 1610</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/218">116 Stat. 218</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/tVI/s611/f">Pub. L. 108–357, title VI, § 611(f)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-22">Oct. 22, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1522">118 Stat. 1522</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idee71b998-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idee71b999-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idee71b99a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Emergency Price Control Act of 1942, referred to in subsec. (a)(1)(B), was <ref href="/us/act/1942-01-30/ch26">act Jan. 30, 1942, ch. 26</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/56/23">56 Stat. 23</ref>, which was classified to section 901 et seq. of the former Appendix to Title 50, War and National Defense, and which terminated <date date="1947-06-30">June 30, 1947</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of the Agricultural Act of 1948, referred to in subsec. (a)(1)(E)(i), see Effective Date of 1948 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s624">section 624 of this title</ref> with reference to title I of said act, and Effective Date of 1948 Amendment note set out below with reference to titles II and III of said Act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Crop Insurance Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(3)(C), (6)(A), is subtitle A of title V of <ref href="/us/act/1938-02-16/ch30">act Feb. 16, 1938, ch. 30</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/72">52 Stat. 72</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 1501 et seq.) of chapter 36 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1501">section 1501 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Agricultural Act of 1949, referred to in subsec. (d), is <ref href="/us/act/1949-10-31/ch792">act Oct. 31, 1949, ch. 792</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/1051">63 Stat. 1051</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 35A (§ 1421 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1421">section 1421 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act, referred to in subsec. (d), is <ref href="/us/act/1939-06-07/ch190">act June 7, 1939, ch. 190</ref>, as revised generally by <ref href="/us/pl/96/41/s2">Pub. L. 96–41, § 2</ref>, <date date="1979-07-30">July 30, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/319">93 Stat. 319</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter III (§ 98 et seq.) of chapter 5 of Title 50, War and National Defense. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s98">section 98 of Title 50</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idee71b99b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (b)(3)(C), (D). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s611/f/1">Pub. L. 108–357, § 611(f)(1)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (D) as (C) and struck out former subpar. (C) which defined “carry-over” of tobacco for any marketing year.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s611/f/2">Pub. L. 108–357, § 611(f)(2)</ref>, struck out “tobacco,” after “rice,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(10)(B), (C). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s611/f/3">Pub. L. 108–357, § 611(f)(3)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (C) as (B) and struck out former subpar. (B) which defined “normal supply” in the case of tobacco.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(11)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s611/f/4">Pub. L. 108–357, § 611(f)(4)</ref>, struck out “and tobacco” after “cotton”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(12). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s611/f/5">Pub. L. 108–357, § 611(f)(5)</ref>, struck out “tobacco,” after “rice,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(14). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s611/f/6">Pub. L. 108–357, § 611(f)(6)</ref>, struck out “(A)” after “(14)” and subpars. (B) to (D) which defined “reserve supply level” of tobacco, “reserve stock level” in the case of Flue-cured tobacco, and “reserve stock level” in the case of Burley tobacco.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(15). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s611/f/7">Pub. L. 108–357, § 611(f)(7)</ref>, (10), redesignated par. (16) as (15) and struck out former par. (15) which defined “tobacco” and “kind of tobacco”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(16). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s611/f/10">Pub. L. 108–357, § 611(f)(10)</ref>, redesignated par. (16) as (15).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(16)(B), (C). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s611/f/8">Pub. L. 108–357, § 611(f)(8)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (C) as (B) and struck out former subpar. (B) which defined “total supply” of tobacco for any marketing year.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(17). <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s611/f/9">Pub. L. 108–357, § 611(f)(9)</ref>, struck out par. (17) which defined “domestic manufacturer of cigarettes”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (b)(14)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/107/171">Pub. L. 107–171</ref> substituted “60,000,000” for “100,000,000” in cl. (i) and “10 percent” for “15 percent” in cl. (ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (b)(14)(C), (D). <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/s1103/a/1">Pub. L. 99–272, § 1103(a)(1)</ref>, added subpars. (C) and (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(17). <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/s1103/a/2">Pub. L. 99–272, § 1103(a)(2)</ref>, added par. (17).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (b)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/99/198">Pub. L. 99–198</ref> substituted “Corn, September 1–August 31” for “Corn, October 1–September 30”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (b)(15). <ref href="/us/pl/97/218">Pub. L. 97–218</ref> inserted proviso that for purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1314e">section 1314e of this title</ref>, types 22 and 23, fire-cured tobacco shall be treated as one “kind of tobacco”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (b)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/94/61">Pub. L. 94–61</ref> substituted “Wheat, June 1–May 31” for “Wheat, July 1–June 30”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—Subsec. (b)(13)(K). Pub. L, 91–524, § 405(b), as added by <ref href="/us/pl/93/86">Pub. L. 93–86</ref>, temporarily inserted “(five calendar years in the case of wheat)” after “three calendar years”. See Effective and Termination Dates of 1973 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/89/321/s509/1">Pub. L. 89–321, § 509(1)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A) and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/89/321/s511/a">Pub. L. 89–321, § 511(a)</ref>, struck out “cotton” and “wheat” in first sentence, and inserted definition of normal production when applied to any number of acres of cotton or wheat.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(13). <ref href="/us/pl/89/321">Pub. L. 89–321</ref>, §§ 403, 509(2), added subpars. (J), (K), (L), and (M).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1964—Subsec. (b)(13). <ref href="/us/pl/88/297/s106/5">Pub. L. 88–297, § 106(5)</ref>–(7), struck out “cotton or” before “peanuts” in subpar. (B) in two places, struck out “, cotton,” after “corn” in subpar. (G) in two places, and added subpars. (H) and (I), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Subsec. (b)(13). <ref href="/us/pl/87/703">Pub. L. 87–703</ref> struck out par. (A) which defined “normal yield” for any county in the case of corn or wheat; inserted in pars. (D) and (E) “and wheat” after “in the case of rice”, “or wheat, as the case may be,” after “per acre of rice”, and “in the case of rice, or during the five years immediately preceding the year in which such normal yield is determined in the case of wheat” after “determined”; and struck out from par. (G) “wheat,” after “corn,” in two places, “and, in the case of wheat, but not in the case of corn, cotton, or peanuts, for trends in yields” after “abnormal weather conditions”, “ten calendar years in the case of wheat, and” before “five calendar years” and “in the case of corn, cotton, or peanuts” after “five calendar years”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1957—Subsec. (b)(15). <ref href="/us/pl/85/92">Pub. L. 85–92</ref> inserted proviso relating to treatment of type 21 fire-cured tobacco as a “kind of tobacco”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1956—Subsec. (a)(1)(E). Act <date date="1956-05-28">May 28, 1956</date>, § 602, inserted “(not counting 1956 in the case of basic agricultural commodities)” after “full calendar years”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(13). Act <date date="1956-05-28">May 28, 1956</date>, § 502, limited determination of normal yield provided for in subpar. (D) only to counties and authorized adjustments for abnormal weather conditions and for trends in yields, added subpars. (E) and (F), and redesignated subpar. (E) as (G).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1954—Subsec. (a)(1)(E). Act <date date="1954-08-28">Aug. 28, 1954</date>, § 301, changed definition of “transitional parity price” as applied to basic agricultural commodities so as to make it “old parity” less 5 per centum for each full year elapsed since <date date="1955-01-01">Jan. 1, 1955</date>, instead of <date date="1949-01-01">Jan. 1, 1949</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). Act <date date="1954-08-28">Aug. 28, 1954</date>, § 302, increased carryover allowance from 10 per centum to 15 per centum in case of corn and from 15 per centum to 20 per centum in case of wheat in subpar. (10)(A), and provided for computing county and farm “normal yields” on the basis of 5-year yields instead of 10-year yields in case of corn in subpars. (13)(A) and (13)(E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1953—Subsec. (d). Act <date date="1953-07-14">July 14, 1953</date>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1952—Subsec. (a)(1)(G). Act <date date="1952-07-17">July 17, 1952</date>, extended dual parity provisions for two years.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(C), (16)(B). Act <date date="1952-07-08">July 8, 1952</date>, provided for computation of carry-over as of Jan. 1st, following the beginning of the marketing year instead of Oct. 1st the beginning of the marketing year.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1949—Subsec. (a)(1)(B). Act <date date="1949-10-31">Oct. 31, 1949</date>, § 409(a), inserted last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(C). Act <date date="1949-10-31">Oct. 31, 1949</date>, § 409(b), inserted “, wages paid hired farm labor” after “buy” and “, wages” after “such prices”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(G). Act <date date="1949-10-31">Oct. 31, 1949</date>, § 409(c), added subpar. (G).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B). Act <date date="1949-10-31">Oct. 31, 1949</date>, § 418(b), included the actual production of rice.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B). Act <date date="1949-10-31">Oct. 31, 1949</date>, § 415(e), repealed amendatory provisions of <ref href="/us/act/1948-07-03/ch827/tII/s201/c">act July 3, 1948, ch. 827, title II, § 201(c)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/1250">62 Stat. 1250</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act <date date="1949-08-29">Aug. 29, 1949</date>, § 2(a)(1), changed definition of “carry-over” of cotton by excluding United States cotton on hand outside the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9). Act <date date="1949-10-31">Oct. 31, 1949</date>, § 418(c), included normal production of rice.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(10(A). Act <date date="1949-10-31">Oct. 31, 1949</date>, § 409(d), increased from 7 per centum to 10 per centum the carryover allowance for corn.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act <date date="1949-08-29">Aug. 29, 1949</date>, § 2(a)(2), made provision inapplicable to cotton.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(10)(C). Act <date date="1949-08-29">Aug. 29, 1949</date>, § 2(a)(2), added subpar. (C) which was also reenacted by act <date date="1949-10-31">Oct. 31, 1949</date>, § 415(c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(16)(A). Act <date date="1949-10-31">Oct. 31, 1949</date>, § 415(d), struck out “cotton,” after “corn,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act <date date="1949-08-29">Aug. 29, 1949</date>, § 2(a)(3), made provision inapplicable to cotton.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(16)(C). Act <date date="1949-08-29">Aug. 29, 1949</date>, § 2(a)(3), added subpar. (C) which was also reenacted by act <date date="1949-10-31">Oct. 31, 1949</date>, § 415(d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1948—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1948-07-03">July 3, 1948</date>, § 201(a), struck out paragraphs (1) and (2) and inserted new paragraphs (1) and (2) to change the method of computing parity prices to give recognition to changes in relationships among the prices of agricultural commodities themselves which have occurred since the base period 1910 to 1914, and redefined “parity”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(A). Act <date date="1948-07-03">July 3, 1948</date>, § 201(b), redefined “carry-over” in the case of corn, rice, and peanuts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B). Act <date date="1948-07-03">July 3, 1948</date>, § 201(c), redefined “carry-over” in the case of cotton.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(10). Act <date date="1948-07-03">July 3, 1948</date>, § 201(d), redefined “normal supply”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(16). Act <date date="1948-07-03">July 3, 1948</date>, § 201(e), redefined “total supply”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1942—Subsec. (b)(13)(B). Act <date date="1942-07-09">July 9, 1942</date>, § 1(4), inserted “or peanuts” after “cotton” wherever appearing, and added a new sentence reading “For 1942, the normal yield for any county, in the case of peanuts, shall be the average yield per acre for peanuts for the county, adjusted for abnormal conditions, during the years 1936–1940, inclusive, except that for any county in which the years 1935–1939, inclusive, are equally as representative, such period may be used in determining the normal yields for counties in the State”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(13)(E). Act <date date="1942-07-09">July 9, 1942</date>, § 1(5), struck out “or” after “wheat” and before “cotton” wherever appearing, inserted “or peanuts” after “cotton” wherever appearing, and inserted after first sentence “For 1942, the normal yield for any farm, in the case of peanuts, shall be the average yield per acre of peanuts for the farm, adjusted for abnormal conditions, during the years 1936–1940, inclusive, except that for any county in which the years 1935–1939, inclusive, are equally as representative, such period may be used in determining normal yields for farms in the county”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1941—Subsec. (b)(1)(B). Act <date date="1941-04-03">April 3, 1941</date>, § 2, inserted “or peanuts” after “cotton”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6)(C). Act <date date="1941-04-03">Apr. 3, 1941</date>, § 3, added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1940—Subsec. (a)(1). Act <date date="1940-11-22">Nov. 22, 1940</date>, § 3, inserted “and, in the case of Burley and flue-cured tobacco, shall be the period August 1934 to July 1939; except that the August 1919–July 1929 base period shall be used in allocating any funds appropriated prior to <date date="1940-09-01">September 1, 1940</date>” after “July, 1929” in last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(C). Act <date date="1940-06-13">June 13, 1940</date>, inserted exception.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Former subsec. (b)(6)(C), (D) were omitted in amendment to subsec. (b)(6) by act <date date="1940-07-02">July 2, 1940</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(13)(A). Act <date date="1940-07-02">July 2, 1940</date>, § 4, among other changes inserted “or wheat” after “corn” wherever appearing and substituted “county” for “farm” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(13)(B). Act <date date="1940-07-02">July 2, 1940</date>, § 5, among other changes, struck out “wheat or” before “cotton” and “and, in the case of wheat but not in the case of cotton, for trends in yields, during the ten calendar years in the case of wheat, and” after “weather conditions”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(13)(E). Act <date date="1940-11-25">Nov. 25, 1940</date>, in first sentence substituted “in which such normal yield is determined” for “with respect to such normal yield is used in any computation authorized under this title”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(15). Act <date date="1940-11-22">Nov. 22, 1940</date>, §§ 1, 4, among other changes substituted “Fire-cured tobacco comprising types 21, 22, 23, and 24; Dark air-cured tobacco comprising types 35 and 36” for “Fire-cured and dark air cured tobacco comprising types 21, 22, 23, 24, 35, 36, and 37” and inserted proviso at end of last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1938—Subsec. (b)(13). Act <date date="1938-04-07">Apr. 7, 1938</date>, substituted “county” for “farm” in subpars. (A) and (B) and added subpar. (E).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idee71b99c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idee71b99d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2004 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/357">Pub. L. 108–357</ref> applicable to the 2005 and subsequent crops of tobacco, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s643">section 643 of Pub. L. 108–357</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s518">section 518 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idee71b99e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1975 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/94/61/s2">Pub. L. 94–61, § 2</ref>, <date date="1975-07-25">July 25, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/302">89 Stat. 302</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/94/61/s2">“The amendment made by the first section of this Act [amending this section] shall become effective <date date="1975-06-01">June 1, 1975</date>”.</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idee71b99f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective and Termination Dates of 1973 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/91/524/tIV/s405/b">Pub. L. 91–524, title IV, § 405(b)</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/93/86/s1/12/a">Pub. L. 93–86, § 1(12)(a)</ref>, <date date="1973-08-10">Aug. 10, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/229">87 Stat. 229</ref>, provided that the amendment made by <ref href="/us/pl/91/524">Pub. L. 91–524</ref> is effective with respect to the 1974 through 1977 crops.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idee71b9a0-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1965 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/89/321/tV/s511/a">Pub. L. 89–321, title V, § 511(a)</ref>, <date date="1965-11-03">Nov. 3, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1205">79 Stat. 1205</ref>, provided that the amendment made by that section is effective beginning with the crop planted for harvest in 1966.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idee71b9a1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1962 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/87/703/tIII/s323">Pub. L. 87–703, title III, § 323</ref>, <date date="1962-09-27">Sept. 27, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/626">76 Stat. 626</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/87/703/tIII/s323">“The amendments to the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938, as amended, and to Public Law 74, Seventy-seventh Congress, as amended, made by sections 310 through 322 of this Act [enacting sections 1334b and 1339 of this title, amending this section and sections 1331 to 1336, 1340, 1371 and 1385 of this title, and repealing <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1337">section 1337 of this title</ref>] shall be in effect only with respect to programs applicable to the crops planted for harvest in the calendar year 1964 or any subsequent year and the marketing years beginning in the calendar year 1964, or any subsequent year”.</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idee71b9a2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1949 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1949-10-31/ch792/tIV/s415/a">Act Oct. 31, 1949, ch. 792, title IV, § 415(a)</ref>, (b), <ref href="/us/stat/63/1057">63 Stat. 1057</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/act/1949-10-31/ch792/tIV/s415/a">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> Except as modified by this Act or by Public Law 272 [see Tables for classification], Eighty-first Congress, sections 201(b), 201(d), 201(e), 203, 207(a), and 208 of the Agricultural Act of 1948 [amending this section and sections 1312, 1322, and 1328 of this title] shall be effective for the purpose of taking any action with respect to the 1950 and subsequent crops upon the enactment of this Act [<date date="1949-10-31">Oct. 31, 1949</date>]. If the time within which any such action is required to be taken shall have elapsed prior to the enactment of this Act, such action shall be taken within thirty days after the enactment of the Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> No provision of the Agricultural Act of 1948 shall be deemed to supersede any provision of Public Law 272, Eighty-first Congress.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idee71b9a3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1948 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1948-07-03/ch827/tIII/s303">Act July 3, 1948, ch. 827, title III, § 303</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/1259">62 Stat. 1259</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1948-07-03/ch827/tIII/s303">“Titles II and III of this Act [amending this section and sections 602, 608c, 612c, 672, 1301a, 1302, 1312, 1322, 1328, 1333, 1335, 1336, 1343, 1345, 1355, and 1385 of this title and repealing sections 608e and 1322a of this title] shall take effect on <date date="1950-01-01">January 1, 1950</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="savings" id="idee71b9a4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Savings Provision</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by sections 611 to 614 of <ref href="/us/pl/108/357">Pub. L. 108–357</ref> not to affect the liability of any person under any provision of law so amended with respect to the 2004 or an earlier crop of tobacco, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/357/s614">section 614 of Pub. L. 108–357</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s515">section 515 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idee71b9a5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Rulemaking Procedures</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/272/tI/s1108/c">Pub. L. 99–272, title I, § 1108(c)</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/95">100 Stat. 95</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/272/tI/s1108/c">“The Secretary of Agriculture shall implement sections 1102 through 1109, and the amendments made by such sections [enacting sections 1314g, 1314h, and 1445–3 of this title, amending this section and sections 1312, 1314c, 1314e, 1372, 1445, 1445–1, and 1445–2 of this title, and enacting provisions set out as notes under sections 1314c, 1314e, 1314g, 1314h, 1372, 1445, 1445–1, and 1445–2 of this title], without regard to the provisions requiring notice and other procedures for public participation in rulemaking contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, or in any directive of the Secretary.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idee71b9a6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study of Methods of Improving Parity Formula</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1956-05-28/ch327/tVI/s602">Act May 28, 1956, ch. 327, title VI, § 602</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/213">70 Stat. 213</ref>, required the Secretary to make a thorough study of the possible methods of improving the parity formula and report thereon, with specific recommendations, including drafts of necessary legislation to carry out such recommendations, to Congress not later than <date date="1957-01-31">Jan. 31, 1957</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idee71b9a7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idee71b9a8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of all officers, agencies, and employees of Department of Agriculture transferred, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of Agriculture by 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 1, eff. <date date="1953-06-04">June 4, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 3219, <ref href="/us/stat/67/633">67 Stat. 633</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2201">section 2201 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Administration of program of Federal Crop Insurance Corporation transferred to Secretary of Agriculture by 1946 Reorg. Plan No. 3, § 501, eff. <date date="1946-07-16">July 16, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 7877, <ref href="/us/stat/60/1100">60 Stat. 1100</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of Bureau of Agricultural Economics transferred to other units of Department of Agriculture under Secretary’s memorandum 1320, supp. 4, of <date date="1953-11-02">Nov. 2, 1953</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
