<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idee82832f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1342a"><num value="1342a">§ 1342a.</num><heading> National cotton production goal</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall, not later than November 15, of the calendar years 1970 through 1976 proclaim a national cotton production goal for the 1971 and subsequent crops of upland cotton. The national cotton production goal for any year shall be the number of bales of upland cotton (standard bales of four hundred and eighty pounds net weight) equal to the estimated domestic consumption and estimated exports for the marketing year beginning in the calendar year for which such national cotton production goal is proclaimed, plus an allowance of not less than 5 per centum of such estimated consumption and estimated exports for market expansion except that the Secretary shall make such adjustments in the amount of such production goal as he determines necessary after taking into consideration the estimated stocks of upland cotton in the United States (including the qualities of such stocks) and stocks in foreign countries, which would be available for the marketing year, to assure the maintenance of adequate but not excessive carryover stocks in the United States (not less than 50 per centum of the average offtake for the three preceding marketing years) to provide a continuous and stable supply of the different qualities of upland cotton needed in the United States and in foreign cotton consuming countries and, in addition, to provide an adequate reserve for purposes of national security.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idee828330-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-02-16/ch30">Feb. 16, 1938, ch. 30</ref>, title III, § 342a, as added <ref href="/us/pl/91/524/tVI/s601/2">Pub. L. 91–524, title VI, § 601(2)</ref>, <date date="1970-11-30">Nov. 30, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1371">84 Stat. 1371</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/93/86/s1/19/B">Pub. L. 93–86, § 1(19)(B)</ref>, <date date="1973-08-10">Aug. 10, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/233">87 Stat. 233</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idee828331-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idee828332-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idee828333-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—<ref href="/us/pl/93/86">Pub. L. 93–86</ref> substituted “1970 through 1976” for “1970, 1971, and 1972”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idee828334-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idee828335-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/91/524/tVI/s601">Pub. L. 91–524, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="1970-11-30">Nov. 30, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1371">84 Stat. 1371</ref>, provided that this section is effective beginning with the 1971 crop of upland cotton.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idee828336-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Inapplicability of Section</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section inapplicable to 2014 through 2018 crops of covered commodities, cotton, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, through <date date="2018-12-31">Dec. 31, 2018</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s9092/a/1">section 9092(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section inapplicable to 2008 through 2012 crops of covered commodities, peanuts, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, through <date date="2012-12-31">Dec. 31, 2012</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8782/a/1">section 8782(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section inapplicable to 2002 through 2007 crops of covered commodities, peanuts, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, through <date date="2007-12-31">Dec. 31, 2007</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7992/a/1">section 7992(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section inapplicable to 1996 through 2001 crops of loan commodities, peanuts, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, and ending <date date="2002-12-31">Dec. 31, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7301/a/1/A">section 7301(a)(1)(A) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
