<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idee873da2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1349"><num value="1349">§ 1349.</num><heading> Export market acreage</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee873da3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1349/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Supplementary allotments for 1964 and 1965; acreage limitation; apportionment among States and farms; “export market acreage” on any farm; farm acreage allotment for farms with export acreage; additional allotment; establishment of future allotments without regard to export acreage; exclusion of extra-long-staple cotton and farms receiving additional price support for 1964 and 1965</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The acreage allotment established under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1344">section 1344 of this title</ref> for each farm for the 1964 crop may be supplemented by the Secretary by an acreage equal to such percentage, but not more than 10 per centum, of such acreage allotment as he determines will not increase the carryover of upland cotton at the beginning of the marketing year for the next succeeding crop above one million bales less than the carryover on the same date one year earlier, if the carryover on such earlier date exceeds eight million bales. For the 1965 crop, the Secretary may, after such hearing and investigation as he finds necessary, announce an export market acreage which he finds will not increase the carryover of upland cotton at the beginning of the marketing year for the next succeeding crop above one million bales less than the carryover on the same date one year earlier, if the carryover on such earlier date exceeds eight million bales. Such export market acreage shall be apportioned to the States on the basis of the State acreage allotments established under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1344">section 1344 of this title</ref> and apportioned by the States to farms receiving allotments under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1344">section 1344 of this title</ref>, pursuant to regulations issued by the Secretary, after considering applications for such acreage filed with the county committee of the county in which the farm is located. The “export market acreage” on any farm shall be the number of acres, not exceeding the maximum export market acreage for the farm established pursuant to this subsection, by which the acreage planted to cotton on the farm exceeds the farm acreage allotment. For purposes of sections 1345 and 1374 of this title and the provisions of any law requiring compliance with a farm acreage allotment as a condition of eligibility for price support or payments under any farm program, the farm acreage allotment for farms with export market acreage shall be the sum of the farm acreage allotment established under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1344">section 1344 of this title</ref> and the maximum export market acreage. Export market acreage shall be in addition to the county, State, and National acreage allotments and shall not be taken into account in establishing future State, county, and farm acreage allotments. The provisions of this section shall not apply to extra-long-staple cotton or to any farm which receives price support under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1444/b">section 1444(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee873da4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1349/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Bond, other undertaking, and lieu payments for exportation without subsidy and within specified period; terms and conditions; liquidated damages; farm acreage allotment upon noncompliance with conditions; remissions to CCC for defraying costs of encouraging export sales of cotton</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The producers on any farm on which there is export market acreage or the purchasers of cotton produced thereon shall, under regulations issued by the Secretary, furnish a bond or other undertaking prescribed by the Secretary providing for the exportation, without benefit of any Government cotton export subsidy and within such period of time as the Secretary may specify, of a quantity of cotton produced on the farm equal to the average yield for the farm multiplied by the export market acreage as determined pursuant to regulations issued by the Secretary. The bond or other undertaking given pursuant to this section shall provide that, upon failure to comply with the terms and conditions thereof, the person furnishing such bond or other undertaking shall be liable for liquidated damages in an amount which the Secretary determines and specifies in such undertaking will approximate the amount payable on excess cotton under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1346/a">section 1346(a) of this title</ref>. The Secretary may, in lieu of the furnishing of a bond or other undertaking, provide for the payment of an amount equal to that which would be payable as liquidated damages under such bond or other undertaking. If such bond or other undertaking is not furnished, or if payment in lieu thereof is not made as provided herein, at such time and in the manner required by regulations of the Secretary, or if the acreage planted to cotton on the farm exceeds the farm acreage allotment established under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1344">section 1344 of this title</ref> by more than the maximum export market acreage, the farm acreage allotment shall be the acreage so established under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1344">section 1344 of this title</ref>. Amounts collected by the Secretary under this section shall be remitted to the Commodity Credit Corporation and used by the Corporation to defray costs of encouraging export sales of cotton under section 1853 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002138">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002138"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idee873da5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-02-16/ch30">Feb. 16, 1938, ch. 30</ref>, title III, § 349, as added <ref href="/us/pl/88/297/tI/s106/1">Pub. L. 88–297, title I, § 106(1)</ref>, <date date="1964-04-11">Apr. 11, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/175">78 Stat. 175</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idee873da6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idee873da7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idee873da8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1853">Section 1853 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (b), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/103/465/tIV/s412/c">Pub. L. 103–465, title IV, § 412(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-12-08">Dec. 8, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4964">108 Stat. 4964</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idee873da9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 1349, <ref href="/us/act/1938-02-16/ch30/tIII/s349">act Feb. 16, 1938, ch. 30, title III, § 349</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/59">52 Stat. 59</ref>, was omitted by <ref href="/us/act/1949-08-29/ch518/s1">act Aug. 29, 1949, ch. 518, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/670">63 Stat. 670</ref> which amended sections 342 to 350 of <ref href="/us/act/1938-02-16/ch30/tIII">act Feb. 16, 1938, ch. 30, title III</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/56">52 Stat. 56</ref> to 60 (sections 1342 to 1344, 1345 to 1347, and prior sections 1348 to 1350 of this title) to be sections 342 to 348 of act <date date="1938-02-16">Feb. 16, 1938</date> (sections 1342 to 1344, 1345 to 1347, and a prior <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1348">section 1348 of this title</ref>).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idee873daa-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idee873dab-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Inapplicability of Section</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section inapplicable to 2014 through 2018 crops of covered commodities, cotton, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, through <date date="2018-12-31">Dec. 31, 2018</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s9092/a/1">section 9092(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section inapplicable to 2008 through 2012 crops of covered commodities, peanuts, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, through <date date="2012-12-31">Dec. 31, 2012</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8782/a/1">section 8782(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section inapplicable to 2002 through 2007 crops of covered commodities, peanuts, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, through <date date="2007-12-31">Dec. 31, 2007</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7992/a/1">section 7992(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section inapplicable to 1996 through 2001 crops of loan commodities, peanuts, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, and ending <date date="2002-12-31">Dec. 31, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7301/a/1/A">section 7301(a)(1)(A) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
