<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idee8e697b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1366"><num value="1366">§ 1366.</num><heading> Court review</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The review by the court shall be limited to questions of law, and the findings of fact by the review committee, if supported by evidence shall be conclusive. If application is made to the court for leave to adduce additional evidence, and it is shown to the satisfaction of the court that such additional evidence is material and that there were reasonable grounds for failure to adduce such evidence in the hearing before the review committee, the court may direct such additional evidence to be taken before the review committee in such manner and upon such terms and conditions as to the court may seem proper. The review committee may modify its findings of fact or its determination by reason of the additional evidence so taken, and it shall file with the court such modified findings or determination, which findings of fact shall be conclusive. The court shall hear and determine the case upon the original record of the hearing before the review committee, and upon such record as supplemented if supplemented, by further hearing before the review committee pursuant to direction of the court. The court shall affirm the review committee’s determination, or modified determination, if the court determines that the same is in accordance with law. If the court determines that such determination or modified determination is not in accordance with law, the court shall remand the proceeding to the review committee with direction either to make such determination as the court shall determine to be in accordance with law or to take such further proceedings as, in the court’s opinion, the law requires.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idee8e697c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-02-16/ch30">Feb. 16, 1938, ch. 30</ref>, title III, § 366, <ref href="/us/stat/52/63">52 Stat. 63</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/620/tIV/s402/6">Pub. L. 98–620, title IV, § 402(6)</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3357">98 Stat. 3357</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idee8e697d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idee8e697e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idee8e697f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—<ref href="/us/pl/98/620">Pub. L. 98–620</ref> substituted “The court” for “At the earliest convenient time, the court, in term time or vacation,”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idee8e6980-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idee8e6981-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/620">Pub. L. 98–620</ref> not applicable to cases pending on <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/620/s403">section 403 of Pub. L. 98–620</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1657">section 1657 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
