<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idee95959c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1389"><num value="1389">§ 1389.</num><heading> Personnel</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized and directed to provide for the execution by the Agricultural Adjustment Administration of such of the powers conferred upon him by this chapter as he deems may be appropriately exercised by such Administration; and for such purposes the provisions of law applicable to appointment and compensation of persons employed by the Agricultural Adjustment Administration shall apply.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idee95959d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-02-16/ch30">Feb. 16, 1938, ch. 30</ref>, title III, § 389, <ref href="/us/stat/52/69">52 Stat. 69</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idee95959e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idee95959f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idee9595a0-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of all officers, agencies, and employees of Department of Agriculture transferred, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of Agriculture by 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 1, eff. <date date="1953-06-04">June 4, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 3219, <ref href="/us/stat/67/633">67 Stat. 633</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2201">section 2201 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of Agricultural Adjustment Administration transferred to Secretary of Agriculture by 1946 Reorg. Plan No. 3, § 501, eff. <date date="1946-07-16">July 16, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 7877, <ref href="/us/stat/60/1100">60 Stat. 1100</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees. See note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s610">section 610 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Agricultural Adjustment Administration consolidated with other agencies into Agricultural Conservation and Adjustment Administration for duration of war, see Ex. Ord. No. 9069.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
