<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idee14ccde-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s138f"><num value="138f">§ 138f.</num><heading> Fees</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee14ccdf-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s138f/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">At the time that an application for accreditation is received by the Secretary and annually thereafter, a laboratory seeking accreditation by the Secretary under the authority of this chapter, the Federal Meat Inspection Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s601">21 U.S.C. 601</ref> et seq.), or the Poultry Products Inspection Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s451">21 U.S.C. 451</ref> et seq.) shall pay to the Secretary a nonrefundable accreditation fee. All fees collected by the Secretary shall be credited to the account from which the expenses of the laboratory accreditation program are paid and, subject to subsection (e), shall be available immediately and remain available until expended to pay the expenses of the laboratory accreditation program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee14cce0-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s138f/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount of fee</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The fee required under this section shall be established by the Secretary in an amount that will offset the cost of the laboratory accreditation programs administered by the Secretary under the statutory authorities set forth in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee14cce1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s138f/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Reimbursement of expenses</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each laboratory that is accredited under a statutory authority set forth in subsection (a) or that has applied for accreditation under such authority shall reimburse the Secretary for reasonable travel and other expenses necessary to perform onsite inspections of the laboratory.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee14cce2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s138f/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustment of fees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may, on an annual basis, adjust the fees imposed under this section as necessary to support the full costs of the laboratory accreditation programs carried out under the statutory authorities set forth in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee14cce3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s138f/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Appropriations prerequisite</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No fees collected under this section may be used to offset the cost of laboratory accreditation without appropriations made under subsection (f).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee14cce4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s138f/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated each fiscal year such sums as may be necessary for laboratory accreditation services under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idee14cce5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/624/tXIII/s1327">Pub. L. 101–624, title XIII, § 1327</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3565">104 Stat. 3565</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/237/tX/s1017">Pub. L. 102–237, title X, § 1017</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1904">105 Stat. 1904</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idee14cce6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idee14cce7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idee14cce8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Meat Inspection Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is titles I to V of <ref href="/us/act/1907-03-04/ch2907">act Mar. 4, 1907, ch. 2907</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/90/201">Pub. L. 90–201</ref>, <date date="1967-12-15">Dec. 15, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/584">81 Stat. 584</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/tXI/s11015/a">Pub. L. 110–246, title XI, § 11015(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/2124">122 Stat. 2124</ref>, which are classified generally to subchapters I to IV–A (§ 601 et seq.) of chapter 12 of Title 21, Food and Drugs. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s601">section 601 of Title 21</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Poultry Products Inspection Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/85/172">Pub. L. 85–172</ref>, <date date="1957-08-28">Aug. 28, 1957</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/71/441">71 Stat. 441</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 10 (§ 451 et seq.) of Title 21. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s451">section 451 of Title 21</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idee14cce9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—<ref href="/us/pl/102/237">Pub. L. 102–237</ref> amended section generally, in subsec. (a), inserting provisions relating to Federal Meat Inspection Act and Poultry Products Inspection Act and provisions relating to crediting and availability of fees, in subsec. (b), substituting provisions relating to fee under this section for provisions relating to fee under subsec. (a) of this section, and provisions relating to laboratory accreditation programs administered by Secretary under statutory authorities set forth in subsec. (a) of this section for provisions relating to program established under this chapter, in subsec. (c), substituting provisions relating to statutory authority set forth in subsec. (a) of this section for provisions relating to this chapter, in subsec. (d), substituting provisions relating to laboratory accreditation programs under statutory authority set forth in subsec. (a) of this section for provisions relating to program established under this chapter, and adding subsecs. (e) and (f).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
