<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idedd6d901-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s13a"><num value="13a">§ 13a.</num><heading> Nonenforcement of rules of government or other violations; cease and desist orders; fines and penalties; imprisonment; misdemeanor; separate offenses</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If any registered entity is not enforcing or has not enforced its rules of government made a condition of its designation or registration as set forth in sections 7 through 7a–2 of this title, or if any registered entity, or any director, officer, agent, or employee of any registered entity otherwise is violating or has violated any of the provisions of this chapter or any of the rules, regulations, or orders of the Commission thereunder, the Commission may, upon notice and hearing on the record and subject to appeal as in other cases provided for in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8/b">section 8(b) of this title</ref>, make and enter an order directing that such registered entity, director, officer, agent, or employee shall cease and desist from such violation, and assess a civil penalty of not more than $500,000 for each such violation, or, in any case of manipulation or attempted manipulation in violation of section 9, 15, 13b, or 13(a)(2) of this title, a civil penalty of not more than $1,000,000 for each such violation. If such registered entity, director, officer, agent, or employee, after the entry of such a cease and desist order and the lapse of the period allowed for appeal of such order or after the affirmance of such order, shall fail or refuse to obey or comply with such order, such registered entity, director, officer, agent, or employee shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction thereof, shall be fined not more than $500,000 or imprisoned for not less than six months nor more than one year, or both, except that if the failure or refusal to obey or comply with the order involved any offense under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s13/a/2">section 13(a)(2) of this title</ref>, the registered entity, director, officer, agent, or employee shall be guilty of a felony and, on conviction, shall be subject to penalties under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s13/a/2">section 13(a)(2) of this title</ref>. Each day during which such failure or refusal to obey such cease and desist order continues shall be deemed a separate offense. If the offending registered entity or other person upon whom such penalty is imposed, after the lapse of the period allowed for appeal or after the affirmance of such penalty, shall fail to pay such penalty, the Commission shall refer the matter to the Attorney General who shall recover such penalty by action in the appropriate United States district court. In determining the amount of the money penalty assessed under this section, the Commission shall consider the gravity of the offense, and in the case of a registered entity shall further consider whether the amount of the penalty will materially impair the ability of the registered entity to carry on its operations and duties.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idedd6d902-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1922-09-21/ch369/s6b">Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 369, § 6b</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/act/1936-06-15/ch545/s9">June 15, 1936, ch. 545, § 9</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1500">49 Stat. 1500</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/90/258/s18">Pub. L. 90–258, § 18</ref>, <date date="1968-02-19">Feb. 19, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/31">82 Stat. 31</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/463/tII/s212/b">Pub. L. 93–463, title II, § 212(b)</ref>, <date date="1974-10-23">Oct. 23, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1403">88 Stat. 1403</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/405/s14">Pub. L. 95–405, § 14</ref>, <date date="1978-09-30">Sept. 30, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/872">92 Stat. 872</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/546/tII">Pub. L. 102–546, title II</ref>, §§ 209(b)(5), 212(c), <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3607">106 Stat. 3607</ref>, 3609; <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tI/s123/a/14">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title I, § 123(a)(14)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2763">114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–409; <ref href="/us/pl/110/234/tXIII/s13103/b">Pub. L. 110–234, title XIII, § 13103(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1433">122 Stat. 1433</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XIII, § 13103(b), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1664">122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2195.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idedd6d903-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idedd6d904-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idedd6d905-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> made identical amendments to this section. The amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> were repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idedd6d906-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—<ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s13103/b">Pub. L. 110–246, § 13103(b)</ref>, in first sentence, inserted before period at end “, or, in any case of manipulation or attempted manipulation in violation of section 9, 15, 13b, or 13(a)(2) of this title, a civil penalty of not more than $1,000,000 for each such violation” and, in second sentence, inserted before period at end “, except that if the failure or refusal to obey or comply with the order involved any offense under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s13/a/2">section 13(a)(2) of this title</ref>, the registered entity, director, officer, agent, or employee shall be guilty of a felony and, on conviction, shall be subject to penalties under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s13/a/2">section 13(a)(2) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—<ref href="/us/pl/106/554">Pub. L. 106–554</ref> substituted “registered entity” for “contract market” wherever appearing, “designation or registration as set forth in sections 7 through 7a–2 of this title” for “designation as set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7">section 7 of this title</ref>” in first sentence, and “the ability of the registered entity” for “the contract market’s ability” in last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—<ref href="/us/pl/102/546">Pub. L. 102–546</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8/b">section 8(b) of this title</ref>” for “paragraph (a) of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8">section 8 of this title</ref>”, substituted “$500,000” for “$100,000” in two places, and in last sentence struck out “the appropriateness of such penalty to the net worth of the offending person and” after “Commission shall consider”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—<ref href="/us/pl/95/405">Pub. L. 95–405</ref> inserted “on the record” after “notice and hearing”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—<ref href="/us/pl/93/463">Pub. L. 93–463</ref> inserted provision for assessment of a civil penalty of not more than $100,000 for each violation, substituted “not more than $100,000” for “not less than $500 nor more than $10,000” as permissible range of fines imposed, inserted provisions for enforcement of a penalty, and substituted “orders of the Commission” for “orders of the Secretary of Agriculture or the commission”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—<ref href="/us/pl/90/258">Pub. L. 90–258</ref> amended section to clarify application only to boards of trade designated as contract markets, to include as grounds for cease and desist orders failure to enforce the market’s rules of government made a condition of its designation and violation of rules or regulations of the commission or orders of the Secretary, and to authorize such orders in conjunction with a suspension or revocation of designation as a contract market rather than in lieu of suspension or revocation.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idedd6d907-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedd6d908-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment of this section and repeal of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> effective <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8701">section 8701 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedd6d909-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/405">Pub. L. 95–405</ref> effective <date date="1978-10-01">Oct. 1, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/405/s28">section 28 of Pub. L. 95–405</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedd6d90a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1974 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/93/463">Pub. L. 93–463</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/463/s418">section 418 of Pub. L. 93–463</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedd6d90b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1968 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/90/258">Pub. L. 90–258</ref> effective 120 days after <date date="1968-02-19">Feb. 19, 1968</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/258/s28">section 28 of Pub. L. 90–258</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idedd6d90c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of section, see section 13 of act <date date="1936-06-15">June 15, 1936</date>, set out as an Effective Date of 1936 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
