<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idee97df02-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1421b"><num value="1421b">§ 1421b.</num><heading> Costs of production</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Congress finds that, to improve the accuracy of commodity program benefit forecasts, the Secretary of Agriculture should designate a single organization to manage its commodity program forecasting and establish a quality control program to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee97df03-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1421b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> systematically identify the source of forecasting errors;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee97df04-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1421b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> maintain records of data used for supply and demand forecasts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee97df05-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1421b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> document its forecasting methods; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee97df06-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1421b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> correct weaknesses in its various forecasting components.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idee97df07-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/624/tXXV/s2512">Pub. L. 101–624, title XXV, § 2512</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4073">104 Stat. 4073</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/tI/s1011/b">Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1011(b)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/709">109 Stat. 709</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idee97df08-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idee97df09-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idee97df0a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990, and not as part of the Agricultural Act of 1949 which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of the 1949 Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1421">section 1421 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idee97df0b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—<ref href="/us/pl/104/66">Pub. L. 104–66</ref> struck out subsec. (a) designation and heading “Improving accuracy of commodity program budget forecasts” before “Congress finds that”, and struck out subsec. (b) “Return on assets” which read as follows: “The Secretary of Agriculture shall annually publish a report analyzing the return on assets resulting from the production of upland cotton, rice, wheat, corn, oats, barley, grain sorghum, soybeans, peanuts, sugar from sugar beets, and raw sugar from sugar cane. In conducting this analysis, the Secretary shall consider returns from agricultural price support programs, the effects of agricultural price support programs on cost of production, the factors currently used in Department of Agriculture cost of production data, current value of land, and any other information that he considers necessary to reflect accurately return on the production of such crops.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
