<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idee97df2e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1423"><num value="1423">§ 1423.</num><heading> Adjustments of support prices</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee97df2f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1423/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may make appropriate adjustments in the support price for any commodity (excluding cotton) for differences in grade, type, quality, location and other factors. The adjustments shall, so far as practicable, be made in such manner that the average support price for the commodity will, on the basis of the anticipated incidence of such factors be equal to the level of support determined as provided in this Act. Beginning with the 1991 crops of wheat, feed grains, and soybeans for which price support is provided under this Act, the Secretary shall establish premiums and discounts related to cleanliness factors in addition to any other premiums or discounts related to quality.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee97df30-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1423/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustment in support prices for cotton</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may make appropriate adjustments in the support price for cotton for differences in quality factors and location. Beginning with the 1991 crop, the quality differences (premiums and discounts for quality factors) for the upland cotton loan program shall be established by the Secretary by giving equal weight to (1) loan differences for the preceding crop, and (2) market differences for such crop in the designated United States spot markets.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee97df31-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1423/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on adjustments for wheat and feed grains</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, for each of the 1990 through 1995 crops of wheat and feed grains, no adjustment in the loan rate applicable to a particular region, State, or county for the purpose of reflecting transportation differentials may increase or decrease the regional, State, or county loan rate from the level established for the previous year by more than the percentage change in the national average loan rate plus or minus 3 percent.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idee97df32-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1949-10-31/ch792">Oct. 31, 1949, ch. 792</ref>, title IV, § 403, <ref href="/us/stat/63/1054">63 Stat. 1054</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/835/tI">Pub. L. 85–835, title I</ref>, §§ 108, 111, <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/993">72 Stat. 993</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/321/tVIII/s802">Pub. L. 89–321, title VIII, § 802</ref>, <date date="1965-11-03">Nov. 3, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1213">79 Stat. 1213</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/tV/s507">Pub. L. 97–98, title V, § 507</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1241">95 Stat. 1241</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tI/s1105">Pub. L. 100–203, title I, § 1105</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-5">101 Stat. 1330–5</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/tXI/s1128">Pub. L. 101–624, title XI, § 1128</ref>, title XX, § 2011, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3508">104 Stat. 3508</ref>, 3932.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idee97df33-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idee97df34-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idee97df35-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1949-10-31/ch792">act Oct. 31, 1949, ch. 792</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/1051">63 Stat. 1051</ref>, known as the Agricultural Act of 1949, which is classified principally to this chapter (§ 1421 et seq.). For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1421">section 1421 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idee97df36-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—<ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s2011">Pub. L. 101–624, § 2011</ref>, inserted at end of subsec. (a) “Beginning with the 1991 crops of wheat, feed grains, and soybeans for which price support is provided under this Act, the Secretary shall establish premiums and discounts related to cleanliness factors in addition to any other premiums or discounts related to quality.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s1128">Pub. L. 101–624, § 1128</ref>, in amending section generally, designated part of existing text as subsecs. (a), (b), and (c), and in subsec. (a) inserted provisions excluding cotton, in subsec. (b) substituted reference to 1991 crop for reference to 1982 crop, and substituted reference to quality factors for reference to grade, staple and micronaire, and in subsec. (c) substituted reference to 1990 through 1995 crops for reference to 1988 through 1990 crops, substituted reference to 3 percent for reference to 2 percent, and struck out provisions relating to establishment and duties of a study committee and authority of Secretary to review and revise procedures and criteria for establishing values of premiums and discounts for grade, staple and micronaire for upland cotton program.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—<ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref> inserted at end “Notwithstanding the preceding provisions of this section, for each of the 1988 through 1990 crops of wheat and feed grains, no adjustment in the loan rate applicable to a particular region, State, or county for the purpose of reflecting transportation differentials may increase or decrease such regional, State, or county loan rate from the level established for the previous year by more than the percentage change in the national average loan rate plus or minus 2 percent.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—<ref href="/us/pl/97/98">Pub. L. 97–98</ref> inserted provision directing that beginning with 1982 crop of upland cotton, the quality differences for the loan program be established by giving equal weight to the loan differences for the preceding crop and to the market differences for the crop in the nine designated United States spot markets and authorizing the Secretary to establish a study committee to study and report on alternative methods of establishing values of premiums and discounts for grade, staple, and micronaire for the upland cotton loan program that accurately represent true relative market values and reflect actual market demand for upland cotton produced in the United States and to review procedures and criteria for determining quality differences, prior to the announcement of the loan rate differences for the 1982 crop of upland cotton, and based on such review, revise such procedures and criteria to actually reflect the actual market value of upland cotton produced in the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—<ref href="/us/pl/89/321">Pub. L. 89–321</ref> provided that, in determining support prices for 1966 and 1967 rice crops, the Secretary shall use head and broken rice value factors for the various varieties which are not lower than those with respect to the 1965 crop and which do not differ as between any two varieties by a greater amount than the value factors used with respect to the 1965 crop for such two varieties differed.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—<ref href="/us/pl/85/835">Pub. L. 85–835</ref> provided for support of split grades and struck out, effective with the 1961 crop, sentence prescribing standard cotton grade for parity and price support purposes.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idee97df37-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idee97df38-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s1128">section 1128 of Pub. L. 101–624</ref> effective beginning with 1991 crop of an agricultural commodity, with provision for prior crops, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s1171">section 1171 of Pub. L. 101–624</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1421">section 1421 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idee97df39-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/98">Pub. L. 97–98</ref> effective <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/s1801">section 1801 of Pub. L. 97–98</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s4301">section 4301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idee97df3a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Inapplicability of Section</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section inapplicable to 2014 through 2018 crops of covered commodities, cotton, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, through <date date="2018-12-31">Dec. 31, 2018</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s9092/b/10">section 9092(b)(10) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section inapplicable to 2008 through 2012 crops of covered commodities, peanuts, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, through <date date="2012-12-31">Dec. 31, 2012</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8782/b/10">section 8782(b)(10) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section inapplicable to 2002 through 2007 crops of covered commodities, peanuts, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, through <date date="2007-12-31">Dec. 31, 2007</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7992/b/10">section 7992(b)(10) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section inapplicable to 1996 through 2002 crops of loan commodities, peanuts, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, and ending <date date="2002-12-31">Dec. 31, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7301/b/1/J">section 7301(b)(1)(J) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idee97df3b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="idee97df3c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Exceptions From Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of Corporations of Department of Agriculture, boards of directors and officers of such corporations; Advisory Board of Commodity Credit Corporation; and Farm Credit Administration or any agency, officer, or entity of, under, or subject to supervision of said Administration excepted from functions of officers, agencies, and employees transferred to Secretary of Agriculture by 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 1, effective <date date="1953-06-04">June 4, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 3219, <ref href="/us/stat/67/633">67 Stat. 633</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2201">section 2201 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
