<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idee9f0b48-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1431d"><num value="1431d">§ 1431d.</num><heading> Donations for school feeding programs abroad; student financing; priorities</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In any school feeding programs undertaken on and after <date date="1962-09-27">September 27, 1962</date> outside the United States pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1431">section 1431 of this title</ref>, section 308 of Public Law 480 (83d Congress), as amended, and <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1431b">section 1431b of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall receive assurances satisfactory to him that, insofar as practicable, there will be student participation in the financing of such programs on the basis of ability to pay, and such programs shall be undertaken with the understanding that commodities will be available for those programs only in accordance with the provisions of such statutes and that commodities made available under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1431">section 1431 of this title</ref> will be available only in accordance with the priorities established in such section.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idee9f0b49-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/703/tII/s205">Pub. L. 87–703, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1962-09-27">Sept. 27, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/611">76 Stat. 611</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idee9f0b4a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idee9f0b4b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idee9f0b4c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 308 of Public Law 480 (83d Congress), referred to in text, which was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1697">section 1697 of this title</ref>, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/89/808/s2/D">Pub. L. 89–808, § 2(D)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-11">Nov. 11, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1535">80 Stat. 1535</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idee9f0b4d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Food and Agriculture Act of 1962, and not as part of the Agricultural Act of 1949 which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of the 1949 Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1421">section 1421 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
