<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idee9f0b77-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1433a"><num value="1433a">§ 1433a.</num><heading> Forgiveness of violations; determinations</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, whenever a producer samples, turns, moves, or replaces grain or any other commodity which is security for a Commodity Credit Corporation producer loan or is held under a producer reserve program, and does so in violation of law or regulation, the appropriate county committee established under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s590h/b">section 590h(b) of title 16</ref> may forgive some or all of the penalties and requirements that would normally be imposed on the producer by reason of the violation, if such committee determines that (1) the violation occurred inadvertently or accidentally, because of lack of knowledge or understanding of the law or regulation, or because the producer or the producer’s agent acted to prevent spoilage of the commodity, and (2) the violation did not result in harm or damage to the rights or interests of any person. The county committee shall furnish a copy of its determination to the Administrator of the Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Service and the appropriate State committee established under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s590h/b">section 590h(b) of title 16</ref>. The determination may be disapproved by either the Administrator or the State committee within sixty days after receipt of a copy of the determination. Any determination not disapproved by the Administrator or such State committee within such sixty-day period shall be considered approved.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idee9f0b78-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1949-10-31/ch792">Oct. 31, 1949, ch. 792</ref>, title IV, § 422, as added <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/tX/s1002">Pub. L. 97–98, title X, § 1002</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1260">95 Stat. 1260</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idee9f0b79-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idee9f0b7a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idee9f0b7b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/s1801">section 1801 of Pub. L. 97–98</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s4301">section 4301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idee9f0b7c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Inapplicability of Section</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section inapplicable to 2014 through 2018 crops of covered commodities, cotton, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, through <date date="2018-12-31">Dec. 31, 2018</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s9092/b/10">section 9092(b)(10) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section inapplicable to 2008 through 2012 crops of covered commodities, peanuts, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, through <date date="2012-12-31">Dec. 31, 2012</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8782/b/10">section 8782(b)(10) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section inapplicable to 2002 through 2007 crops of covered commodities, peanuts, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, through <date date="2007-12-31">Dec. 31, 2007</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7992/b/10">section 7992(b)(10) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section inapplicable to 1996 through 2002 crops of loan commodities, peanuts, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, and ending <date date="2002-12-31">Dec. 31, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7301/b/1/J">section 7301(b)(1)(J) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
