<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idee9f0b7d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1433b"><num value="1433b">§ 1433b.</num><heading> Processing of surplus agricultural commodities into liquid fuels and agricultural commodity byproducts</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee9f0b7e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1433b/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of Commodity Credit Corporation; terms and conditions established by Secretary; fuel prices</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in order to prevent the accumulation of excessive stocks of agricultural commodities through the price support and stabilization operations of the Commodity Credit Corporation <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002152">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002152"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma.</note> the Corporation may, under terms and conditions established by the Secretary, make its accumulated stocks of agricultural commodities available, at no cost or reduced cost, to encourage the purchase of such commodities for the production of liquid fuels and agricultural commodity byproducts. In carrying out the program established by this section, the Secretary shall ensure, insofar as possible, that any use of agricultural commodities made available be made in such manner as to encourage increased use and avoid displacing usual marketings of agricultural commodities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee9f0b7f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1433b/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Feasibility of processing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In determining the feasibility of providing for the processing of Commodity Credit Corporation stocks of commodities under subsection (a), the Secretary shall consider the nature of the commodities, and the acquisition, transportation, handling, storage, interest, and other costs associated with acquiring and maintaining such stocks, including the effect of such stocks in depressing commodity prices, as well as the value and utility of such stocks when processed into liquid fuels and agricultural commodity byproducts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idee9f0b80-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1949-10-31/ch792">Oct. 31, 1949, ch. 792</ref>, title IV, § 423, as added <ref href="/us/pl/97/358/s2">Pub. L. 97–358, § 2</ref>, <date date="1982-10-21">Oct. 21, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1714">96 Stat. 1714</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/99/198/tX/s1024">Pub. L. 99–198, title X, § 1024</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1460">99 Stat. 1460</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idee9f0b81-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idee9f0b82-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idee9f0b83-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (c), which required the Secretary to report annually to Congress on the operation of this section, terminated, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance. See, also, page 46 of House Document No. 103–7.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idee9f0b84-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/198">Pub. L. 99–198</ref> substituted provision authorizing the Corporation to make its accumulated agricultural commodities stocks available at no cost or reduced cost to encourage the purchase thereof for the production of liquid fuels and commodity byproducts, with any use of such commodities to be made in such a manner as to encourage increased use and avoid displacing usual marketings of such commodities for provision authorizing the Corporation to provide for processing of its accumulated stock into liquid fuels and commodity byproducts to be either made available to Federal agencies to meet their regular or emergency needs or to be sold commercially by the Corporation, at a price determined by the Secretary notwithstanding any other provisions of law and in a manner so as not to disrupt the prices in commercial markets of agriculturally-derived liquid fuel.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idee9f0b85-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idee9f0b86-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Inapplicability of Section</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section inapplicable to 2014 through 2018 crops of covered commodities, cotton, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, through <date date="2018-12-31">Dec. 31, 2018</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s9092/b/10">section 9092(b)(10) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section inapplicable to 2008 through 2012 crops of covered commodities, peanuts, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, through <date date="2012-12-31">Dec. 31, 2012</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8782/b/10">section 8782(b)(10) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section inapplicable to 2002 through 2007 crops of covered commodities, peanuts, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, through <date date="2007-12-31">Dec. 31, 2007</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7992/b/10">section 7992(b)(10) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section inapplicable to 1996 through 2002 crops of loan commodities, peanuts, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, and ending <date date="2002-12-31">Dec. 31, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7301/b/1/J">section 7301(b)(1)(J) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
