<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ideeb21e51-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1446b"><num value="1446b">§ 1446b.</num><heading> Policy with regard to dairy products</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The production and use of abundant supplies of high quality milk and dairy products are essential to the health and general welfare of the Nation: a dependable domestic source of supply of these foods in the form of high grade dairy herds and modern, sanitary dairy equipment is important to the national defense; and an economically sound dairy industry affects beneficially the economy of the country as a whole. It is the policy of Congress to assure a stabilized annual production of adequate supplies of milk and dairy products; to promote the increased use of these essential foods; to improve the domestic source of supply of milk and butterfat by encouraging dairy farmers to develop efficient production units consisting of high-grade, disease-free cattle and modern sanitary equipment; and to stabilize the economy of dairy farmers at a level which will provide a fair return for their labor and investment when compared with the cost of things that farmers buy.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="ideeb21e52-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-28/ch1041">Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title II, § 204(a), <ref href="/us/stat/68/899">68 Stat. 899</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ideeb21e53-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ideeb21e54-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="ideeb21e55-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Agricultural Act of 1954, and not as part of the Agricultural Act of 1949 which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of the 1949 Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1421">section 1421 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
