<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ideed5f9a7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1627"><num value="1627">§ 1627.</num><heading> Appointment of personnel; compensation; employment of specialists</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall have the power to appoint, remove, and fix, in accordance with existing law, the compensation of such officers and employees, and to make such expenditures as he deems necessary, including expenditures for rent outside the District of Columbia, travel, supplies, books, equipment, and such other expenditures as may be necessary to the administration of this chapter: <i>Provided</i>, That the Secretary of Agriculture may appoint any technically qualified person, firm, or organization by contract or otherwise on a temporary basis and for a term not to exceed six months in any fiscal year to perform research, inspection, classification, technical, or other special services, without regard to the civil-service laws.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="ideed5f9a8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-08-14/ch966">Aug. 14, 1946, ch. 966</ref>, title II, § 208, <ref href="/us/stat/60/1091">60 Stat. 1091</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ideed5f9a9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ideed5f9aa-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="ideed5f9ab-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions that authorized the Secretary of Agriculture to “fix the compensation” of any technically qualified person, firm, or organization by contract or otherwise on a temporary basis and for a term not to exceed six months in any fiscal year to perform research, inspection, classification, technical or other special services, without regard to the “Classification Act of 1923, as amended” were omitted as obsolete. Sections 1202 and 1204 of the Classification Act of 1949, <ref href="/us/stat/63/972">63 Stat. 972</ref>, 973 repealed the 1923 Act and all laws or parts of laws inconsistent with the 1949 Act. While section 1106(a) of the 1949 Act provided that references in other laws to the 1923 Act should be held and considered to mean the 1949 Act, it did not have the effect of continuing the exceptions contained in this subsection because of section 1106(b) which provided that the application of the 1949 Act to any position, officer, or employee shall not be affected by section 1106(a). The Classification Act of 1949 was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s8/a">Pub. L. 89–554, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/632">80 Stat. 632</ref> (of which section 1 revised and enacted Title 5, U.S.C., into law). <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5102">Section 5102 of Title 5</ref>, now contains the applicability provisions of the 1949 Act, and <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5103">section 5103 of Title 5</ref> authorizes the Office of Personnel Management to determine the applicability to specific positions and employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
