<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ideddb94af-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s16a"><num value="16a">§ 16a.</num><heading> Service fees and National Futures Association study</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="ideddb94b0-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s16a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Development and implementation of plan for user fees; report to and approval by Congressional committees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission may develop and implement a plan to charge and collect reasonable fees to cover the estimated cost of regulating transactions under the jurisdiction of the Commission. However, prior to implementing such a plan, the Commission shall report its intention to do so to the House Committee on Agriculture and the Senate Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry. The Commission shall include in its report the feasibility and desirability of collecting such fees. Any plan developed under this section shall not be implemented until approved by the House Committee on Agriculture and the Senate Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry. Fees collected under any plan approved under this section shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="ideddb94b1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s16a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> National Futures Association regulatory experience; report; contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commodity Futures Trading Commission shall submit to Congress a report containing the results of a study of the regulatory experience of the National Futures Association for the period beginning <date date="1983-01-01">January 1, 1983</date> and ending <date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>. The report shall be submitted not later than <date date="1986-01-01">January 1, 1986</date>. The report shall include (but not to be limited to) the following—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ideddb94b2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s16a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the extent to which the National Futures Association has fully implemented the program provided in the rules approved by the Commission under section 17(p) and (q) of the Commodity Exchange Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s21/p">7 U.S.C. 21(p)</ref>, (q)] and the effectiveness of the operation of such program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ideddb94b3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s16a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the actual and projected cost savings to the Federal Government, if any, resulting from operations of the National Futures Association;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ideddb94b4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s16a/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the actual and projected costs which the Commission and the public would have incurred if the Association had not undertaken self-regulatory responsibility for certain areas under the Commission’s jurisdiction;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ideddb94b5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s16a/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> problem areas, if any, encountered by the Association;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ideddb94b6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s16a/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the nature of the working relationship between the Association and the Commission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ideddb94b7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s16a/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> an assessment of the actual and projected efficiencies the Commission has achieved or expects to be achieved as a result of the continuing regulatory activities of the Association; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ideddb94b8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s16a/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> the immediate and projected capabilities of the Commission at the time of submission of the study to turn its attention to more immediate problems of regulation, as a result of the activities of the Association.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="ideddb94b9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s16a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Schedule of fees for services, activities and functions; notice and hearing; actual cost standard</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall limit the authority of the Commission to promulgate, after notice and opportunity for hearing, a schedule of appropriate fees to be charged for services rendered and activities and functions performed by the Commission in conjunction with its administration and enforcement of the Commodity Exchange Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1">7 U.S.C. 1</ref> et seq.]: <i>Provided</i>, That the fees for any specified service or activity or function shall not exceed the actual cost thereof to the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ideddb94ba-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/405/s26">Pub. L. 95–405, § 26</ref>, <date date="1978-09-30">Sept. 30, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/877">92 Stat. 877</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/444/tII/s237">Pub. L. 97–444, title II, § 237</ref>, <date date="1983-01-11">Jan. 11, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2325">96 Stat. 2325</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ideddb94bb-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ideddb94bc-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="ideddb94bd-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Commodity Exchange Act, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/act/1922-09-21/ch369">act Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 369</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/998">42 Stat. 998</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 1 (§ 1 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1">section 1 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="ideddb94be-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Futures Trading Act of 1978, and not as part of the Commodity Exchange Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ideddb94bf-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—<ref href="/us/pl/97/444">Pub. L. 97–444</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsecs. (b) and (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ideddb94c0-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ideddb94c1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1983 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/444">Pub. L. 97–444</ref> effective <date date="1983-01-11">Jan. 11, 1983</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/444/s239">section 239 of Pub. L. 97–444</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="ideddb94c2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1978-10-01">Oct. 1, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/405/s28">section 28 of Pub. L. 95–405</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1978 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ideddb94c3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study of Assessments on Transactions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/546/tII/s218">Pub. L. 102–546, title II, § 218</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3612">106 Stat. 3612</ref>, required the Comptroller General to conduct a study to determine whether it was feasible to fund some or all of the enforcement and market surveillance activities of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission through the imposition of an assessment on commodity futures and options transactions executed pursuant to the Commodity Exchange Act, and report, by one year after <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, to Congress the Commission determinations together with any appropriate recommendations for the implementation of such a program of assessment-based funding.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
