<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ideefc1f3a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1761"><num value="1761">§ 1761.</num><heading> Foreign markets; collection of information</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of encouraging and promoting the marketing of agricultural commodities of the United States and assisting American farmers, processors, distributors, and exporters to adjust their operations and practices to meet world conditions, the Secretary of Agriculture shall acquire information regarding the competition and demand for United States agricultural commodities, the marketing and distribution of such commodities in foreign countries and shall be responsible for the interpretation and dissemination of such information in the United States and shall make investigations abroad regarding the factors affecting and influencing the export of United States agricultural commodities, and shall conduct abroad any other activities including the demonstration of standards of quality for American agricultural commodities for which the Department of Agriculture now has or in the future may have such standards, as he deems necessary. Nothing contained herein shall be construed as prohibiting the Department of Agriculture from conducting abroad any activity for which authority now exists.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="ideefc1f3b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-28/ch1041">Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title VI, § 601, <ref href="/us/stat/68/908">68 Stat. 908</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/501/tIII/s301/3">Pub. L. 95–501, title III, § 301(3)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1688">92 Stat. 1688</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ideefc1f3c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ideefc1f3d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ideefc1f3e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—<ref href="/us/pl/95/501">Pub. L. 95–501</ref> substituted “agricultural commodities” for “agricultural products” in four places and substituted “such commodities” for “said products”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ideefc1f3f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ideefc1f40-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">World Livestock Market Price Information</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/624/tXV/s1545">Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1545</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3695">104 Stat. 3695</ref>, directed Secretary of Agriculture to develop appropriate methodology for determining world price of livestock and livestock products, to gather and analyze appropriate price and cost of production information concerning such products in foreign countries for purpose of price discovery and to aid in sale of livestock and livestock products in foreign export markets, and to periodically publish such information, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/tII/s273">Pub. L. 104–127, title II, § 273</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/976">110 Stat. 976</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ideefc1f41-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Implementation of 1978 Amendment; Regulations</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/501/tVI/s601">Pub. L. 95–501, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1691">92 Stat. 1691</ref>, which required Secretary of Agriculture to implement provisions of <ref href="/us/pl/95/501">Pub. L. 95–501</ref> as expeditiously as possible, was omitted and a new <ref href="/us/pl/95/501/s601">section 601 of Pub. L. 95–501</ref> added as part of the complete revision of <ref href="/us/pl/95/501">Pub. L. 95–501</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/tXV/s1531">Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3668">104 Stat. 3668</ref>. See chapter 87 (§ 5601 et seq.) of this title.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
