<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ideefc1f42-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1762"><num value="1762">§ 1762.</num><heading> Personnel</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="ideefc1f43-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1762/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To effectuate the carrying out of the purposes of this subchapter, the Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to appoint such personnel as he determines to be necessary and, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, to assign such personnel to service abroad.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="ideefc1f44-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1762/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Titles; rank and privileges; appointments of Agricultural Counselors</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Officers or employees assigned or appointed to posts abroad under this subchapter shall have the designation of Agricultural Counselor, Agricultural Attaché, or such other titles or designations that shall be agreed to by the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Agriculture, and shall be accorded the same rank and privileges as those of other counselors or attachés in United States embassies. An Agricultural Counselor shall be appointed in any nation—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ideefc1f45-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1762/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to which a substantial number of governments with which the United States competes directly for agricultural markets in such nation assign agricultural representatives with the diplomatic status of counselor or its equivalent; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ideefc1f46-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1762/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> in which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ideefc1f47-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1762/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the potential is great for long-term expansion of a market for United States agricultural commodities, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ideefc1f48-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1762/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> competition with other nations for existing and potential agricultural markets is extremely intense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Not less than ten Agricultural Counselors shall be appointed within three years after <date date="1978-10-21">October 21, 1978</date>.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="ideefc1f49-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1762/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Attachment to diplomatic missions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon the request of the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of State shall regularly and officially attach the officers or employees of the United States Department of Agriculture to the diplomatic mission of the United States in the country in which such officers or employees are to be assigned by the Secretary of Agriculture, and shall obtain for them diplomatic privileges and immunities equivalent to those enjoyed by Foreign Service personnel of comparable rank and salary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="ideefc1f4a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1762/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Assignment to United States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any officer or employee appointed and assigned to a post abroad pursuant to this subchapter may, in the discretion of the Secretary of Agriculture, be assigned for duty in the continental United States, without regard to the civil service laws (and without reduction in grade if an appropriate position at the employee’s grade is not available in any agency of the Department of Agriculture), for a period of not more than three years: <i>Provided,</i> That the total number of such employees assigned for duty in the continental United States under this provision shall not exceed fifteen at any one time: <i>Provided further,</i> That this Act shall not increase the number of persons employed at grade GS–16, GS–17, or GS–18.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ideefc1f4b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-28/ch1041">Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title VI, § 602(a)–(d), formerly § 602(a)–(c), (e), <ref href="/us/stat/68/908">68 Stat. 908</ref>, 909; amended <ref href="/us/act/1955-06-28/ch189/s12/c/13">June 28, 1955, ch. 189, § 12(c)(13)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/182">69 Stat. 182</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/106/s4">Pub. L. 89–106, § 4</ref>, <date date="1965-08-04">Aug. 4, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/431">79 Stat. 431</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/449">Pub. L. 94–449</ref>, <date date="1976-10-01">Oct. 1, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1500">90 Stat. 1500</ref>; renumbered § 602(a)–(d) and amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/501/tIII/s301/4">Pub. L. 95–501, title III, § 301(4)</ref>, (5), title IV, § 401(3), (5), <date date="1978-10-21">Oct. 21, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1688">92 Stat. 1688</ref>, 1691.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ideefc1f4c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ideefc1f4d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="ideefc1f4e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (d), is <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-28/ch1041">act Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/897">68 Stat. 897</ref>, known as the Agricultural Act of 1954. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1741">section 1741 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ideefc1f4f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/501/s301/4">Pub. L. 95–501, § 301(4)</ref>, substituted “this subchapter” for “this chapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/501/s301/5">Pub. L. 95–501, § 301(5)</ref>, inserted provisions relating to appointment of Agricultural Counselors and rank and privileges to be accorded such counselors or other officers or employees assigned abroad.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/95/501">Pub. L. 95–501</ref>, §§ 301(4), 401(5), redesignated subsec. (e) as (d) and substituted “this subchapter” for “this chapter”. Former subsec. (d), relating to Presidential regulations, was redesignated section 606B of act <date date="1954-08-28">Aug. 28, 1954</date>, by <ref href="/us/pl/95/501/s401/3">section 401(3) of Pub. L. 95–501</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1766a">section 1766a of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/95/501/s401/3">Pub. L. 95–501, § 401(3)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (f), relating to language training for families of officers and employees assigned abroad, as section 606C of act <date date="1954-08-28">Aug. 28, 1954</date>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1766b">section 1766b of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/94/449">Pub. L. 94–449</ref> added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/89/106">Pub. L. 89–106</ref> added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1955—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1955-06-28">June 28, 1955</date>, repealed provisions authorizing the Secretary of Agriculture to place not more than eight positions in grade 16 and two in grade 17 of the General Schedule of the Classification Act of 1949.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ideefc1f50-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ideefc1f51-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1955 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by act <date date="1955-06-28">June 28, 1955</date>, effective <date date="1955-06-28">June 28, 1955</date>, see section 13 of act of <date date="1955-06-28">June 28, 1955</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ideefc1f52-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Other Laws to GS–16, 17, or 18 Pay Rates</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References in laws to the rates of pay for GS–16, 17, or 18, or to maximum rates of pay under the General Schedule, to be considered references to rates payable under specified sections of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, see section 529 [title I, § 101(c)(1)] of <ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref>, set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5376">section 5376 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="ideefc1f53-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="ideefc1f54-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 10624. Regulations for Department of Agriculture Personnel Abroad</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 10624, <date date="1955-07-28">July 28, 1955</date>, 20 F.R. 5445, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 10903, <date date="1961-01-09">Jan. 9, 1961</date>, 26 F.R. 217; Ex. Ord. No. 11530, <date date="1970-05-26">May 26, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 8335; Ex. Ord. No. 12292, <date date="1981-02-23">Feb. 23, 1981</date>, 46 F.R. 13967; Ex. Ord. No. 12608, <date date="1987-09-09">Sept. 9, 1987</date>, 52 F.R. 34617, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By virtue of the authority vested in me by sections 605, 606B and 606D of Title VI of the Act of <date date="1954-08-28">August 28, 1954</date>, as amended, (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1765">7 U.S.C. 1765</ref>, 1766a, and 1766c), and by <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref> of the United States Code, and as President of the United States, I hereby prescribe the following regulations relating to personnel of the Department of Agriculture assigned to service abroad:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. (a) The provisions of section 207 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3927">22 U.S.C. 3927</ref>) shall be applicable to the official activities of persons assigned abroad under authority of Title VI of the said act of <date date="1954-08-28">August 28, 1954</date> [this chapter].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Secretary of Agriculture shall institute and maintain such measures consistent with the said Part II as may be necessary to insure that the official activities of persons assigned abroad under the said Title VI are carried on consonant with United States foreign-policy objectives as defined by the Secretary of State and are effectively coordinated with the activities of representatives of other United States agencies, under the leadership of the Chief of the United States Diplomatic Mission.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) Consistent with subsections (a) and (b) of this section, the Secretary of Agriculture shall issue instructions on agricultural matters to persons assigned abroad under authority of the said Title VI.</p>
<p><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. In addition to rules and regulations pertaining to allowances and benefits otherwise applicable to personnel assigned abroad by the Secretary of Agriculture under Title VI of the Act of <date date="1954-08-28">August 28, 1954</date> [this chapter], or other authority, there shall be applicable to such personnel the rules and regulations prescribed by the Secretary of State in pursuance of (1) so much of the authority vested in the President by subchapter III of chapter 59 of title 5 of the United States Code [section 5921 et seq. of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees], or by any amendment thereof as relates to quarters allowances or cost-of-living allowances, and (2) so much of the authority vested in the Secretary of State by chapter 9 of Title I of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 [section 4081 et seq. of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse], as relates to allowances and benefits under the said chapter 9 of Title I: <i>Provided</i>, (1) that the Secretary of State, upon request of the Secretary of Agriculture, may prescribe, within existing authority of law and when deemed necessary, special rules and regulations for such personnel; and (2) that the Secretary of Agriculture may, within the limitation of such rules and regulations, prescribe necessary implementing directions. The Secretary of Agriculture may designate employees of the Department of Agriculture to make specific determinations and take specific actions in the application of such rules and regulations to the activities of the Department of Agriculture.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. Such provisions in annual appropriation acts of the Department of State, including such acts hereafter enacted, facilitating the work of the Foreign Service of the United States as the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall from time to time determine appropriate shall be applicable to activities authorized under Title VI of the said act of <date date="1954-08-28">August 28, 1954</date> [this chapter].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This order shall be effective as of <date date="1954-09-01">September 1, 1954</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
