<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idef080643-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927"><num value="1927">§ 1927.</num><heading> Repayment requirements</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef080644-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Period of repayment; interest rates</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef080645-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The period for repayment of loans under this subchapter shall not exceed forty years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef080646-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Except as otherwise provided in paragraphs (3), (4), (5), and (6) of this subsection, the interest rates on loans under this subchapter shall be as determined by the Secretary, but not in excess of the current average market yield on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States with remaining periods to maturity comparable to the average maturities of such loans, plus not to exceed 1 per centum, as determined by the Secretary, and adjusted to the nearest one-eighth of 1 per centum.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef080647-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef080648-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Notwithstanding the provisions of the constitution or laws of any State limiting the rate or amount of interest that may be charged, taken, received, or reserved, except as provided in paragraph (6), the interest rates on loans (other than guaranteed loans), to public bodies or nonprofit associations (including Indian tribes on Federal and State reservations and other federally recognized Indian tribal groups) for water and waste disposal facilities and essential community facilities shall be set by the Secretary at rates not to exceed the current market yield for outstanding municipal obligations with remaining periods to maturity comparable to the average maturity for such loans, and adjusted to the nearest one-eighth of 1 per centum; and not in excess of 5 per centum per annum for any such loans which are for the upgrading of existing facilities or construction of new facilities as required to meet applicable health or sanitary standards in areas where the median household income of the persons to be served by such facility is below the higher of 80 per centum of the statewide nonmetropolitan median household income or the poverty line established by the Office of Management and Budget, as revised under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9902/2">section 9902(2) of title 42</ref> and in other areas as the Secretary may designate where a significant percentage of the persons to be served by such facilities are of low income, as determined by the Secretary; and not in excess of 7 per centum per annum on loans for such facilities that do not qualify for the 5 per centum per annum interest rate but are located in areas where the median household income of the persons to be served by the facility does not exceed 100 per centum of the statewide nonmetropolitan median household income.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef080649-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in subparagraph (D) and in paragraph (6), the interest rate on loans (other than guaranteed loans) under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1934">section 1934 of this title</ref> shall not be—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idef08064a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> greater than the sum of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef08064b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/3/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> an amount that does not exceed one-half of the current average market yield on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States with maturities of 5 years; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef08064c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/3/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> an amount not exceeding 1 percent per year, as the Secretary determines is appropriate; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idef08064d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> less than 5 percent per year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef08064e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall establish loan rates for health care and related facilities based solely on the income of the area to be served, and such rates shall be otherwise consistent with such subparagraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef08064f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Joint financing arrangements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If a direct farm ownership loan is made under this subchapter as part of a joint financing arrangement and the amount of the direct farm ownership loan does not exceed 50 percent of the total principal amount financed under the arrangement, the interest rate on the direct farm ownership loan shall be a rate equal to the greater of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idef080650-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/3/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> the difference between—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef080651-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/3/D/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> 2 percent; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef080652-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/3/D/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the interest rate for farm ownership loans under this subchapter; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idef080653-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/3/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> 2.5 percent.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef080654-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Interest rates for water and waste disposal facilities loans.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idef080655-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/3/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Except as provided in clause (ii) and notwithstanding subparagraph (A), in the case of a direct loan for a water or waste disposal facility—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef080656-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/3/E/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> in the case of a loan that would be subject to the 5 percent interest rate limitation under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall establish the interest rate at a rate that is equal to 60 percent of the current market yield for outstanding municipal obligations with remaining periods to maturity comparable to the average maturity of the loan, adjusted to the nearest ⅛ of 1 percent; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef080657-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/3/E/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> in the case of a loan that would be subject to the 7 percent limitation under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall establish the interest rate at a rate that is equal to 80 percent of the current market yield for outstanding municipal obligations with remaining periods to maturity comparable to the average maturity of the loan, adjusted to the nearest ⅛ of 1 percent.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idef080658-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/3/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading><content>Clause (i) does not apply to a loan for a specific project that is the subject of a loan that has been approved, but not closed, as of the date of enactment of this subparagraph.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef080659-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (6), the interest rates on loans under sections 1926(a)(1) and 1932 of this title (other than guaranteed loans and loans as described in paragraph (3) of this subsection) shall be as determined by the Secretary, but not less than such rates as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury taking into consideration the current average market yield on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States with remaining periods to maturity comparable to the average maturities of such loans, adjusted in the judgment of the Secretary of the Treasury to provide for rates comparable to the rates prevailing in the private market for similar loans and considering the Secretary’s insurance of the loans, plus an additional charge, prescribed by the Secretary, to cover the Secretary’s losses and cost of administration, which charge shall be deposited in the Rural Development Insurance Fund, and further adjusted to the nearest one-eighth of 1 per centum.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef08065a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef08065b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the interest rate on any loan made under this subchapter as a guaranteed loan shall be such rate as may be agreed upon by the borrower and the lender, but not in excess of a rate as may be determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef08065c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In the case of a loan made under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1932">section 1932 of this title</ref> as a guaranteed loan, subparagraph (A) shall apply notwithstanding the provisions of the constitution or laws of any State limiting the rate or amount of interest that may be charged, taken, received, or reserved.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef08065d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef08065e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, in the case of loans (other than guaranteed loans) made or insured under the authorities of this chapter specified in subparagraph (B) for activities that involve the use of prime farmland as defined in subparagraph (C), the interest rates shall be the interest rates otherwise applicable under this section increased by 2 per centum per annum. Wherever practicable, construction by a State, municipality, or other political subdivision of local government that is supported by loans described in the preceding sentence shall be placed on land that is not prime farmland, in order to preserve the maximum practicable amount of prime farmlands for production of food and fiber. Where other options exist for the siting of such construction and where the governmental authority still desires to carry out such construction on prime farmland, the 2 per centum interest rate increase provided by this clause shall apply, but such increased interest rate shall not apply where such other options do not exist.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef08065f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> The authorities referred to in subparagraph (A) are—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idef080660-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/6/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1926/a/1">section 1926(a)(1) of this title</ref> relating to loans for recreational developments and essential community facilities,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idef080661-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/6/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1932/a/2/A">section 1932(a)(2)(A) of this title</ref>; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002209">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002209"><num>1</num> So in original. The semicolon probably should be a comma.</note> and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idef080662-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/6/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1932/d">section 1932(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef080663-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/a/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> For purposes of this paragraph, the term “prime farmland” means prime farmlands and unique farmland as those terms are defined in sections 657.5(a) and (b) of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations (1980).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef080664-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment of charges; prepayment of taxes and insurance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The borrower shall pay such fees and other charges as the Secretary may require, and borrowers under this chapter shall prepay to the Secretary such taxes and insurance as the Secretary may require, on such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef080665-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Mortgages, liens, and other security</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall take as security for the obligations entered into in connection with loans, mortgages on farms with respect to which such loans are made or such other security as the Secretary may require, and for obligations in connection with loans to associations under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1926">section 1926 of this title</ref>, shall take liens on the facility or such other security as he may determine to be necessary. Such security instruments may constitute liens running to the United States notwithstanding the fact that the notes may be held by lenders other than the United States. A borrower may use the same collateral to secure two or more loans made, insured, or guaranteed under this subchapter, except that the outstanding amount of such loans may not exceed the total value of the collateral so used.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef080666-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional collateral</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may not—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idef080667-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> require any borrower to provide additional collateral to secure a farmer program loan made or insured under this chapter, if the borrower is current in the payment of principal and interest on the loan; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idef080668-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1927/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> bring any action to foreclose, or otherwise liquidate, any such loan as a result of the failure of a borrower to provide additional collateral to secure a loan, if the borrower was current in the payment of principal and interest on the loan at the time the additional collateral was requested.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idef080669-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/128/tIII/s307">Pub. L. 87–128, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="1961-08-08">Aug. 8, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/308">75 Stat. 308</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/419/tI">Pub. L. 92–419, title I</ref>, §§ 113, 114, 128(b), <date date="1972-08-30">Aug. 30, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/660">86 Stat. 660</ref>, 666; <ref href="/us/pl/95/334/tI/s108">Pub. L. 95–334, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="1978-08-04">Aug. 4, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/422">92 Stat. 422</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tI/s160/a">Pub. L. 97–35, title I, § 160(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/376">95 Stat. 376</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/198/tXIII">Pub. L. 99–198, title XIII</ref>, §§ 1304A, 1305, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1521">99 Stat. 1521</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/233/tVI">Pub. L. 100–233, title VI</ref>, §§ 603, 604, <date date="1988-01-06">Jan. 6, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1665">101 Stat. 1665</ref>, 1666; <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/tXVIII/s1803/a">Pub. L. 101–624, title XVIII, § 1803(a)</ref>, title XXIII, § 2383, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3818">104 Stat. 3818</ref>, 4050; <ref href="/us/pl/102/552/tV/s516/c/1">Pub. L. 102–552, title V, § 516(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4137">106 Stat. 4137</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/328/tI/s113/a">Pub. L. 103–328, title I, § 113(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-29">Sept. 29, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2366">108 Stat. 2366</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/tVI">Pub. L. 104–127, title VI</ref>, §§ 604, 661(a), title VII, § 747(b)(1), <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1086">110 Stat. 1086</ref>, 1106, 1128; <ref href="/us/pl/110/234/tVI">Pub. L. 110–234, title VI</ref>, §§ 6011, 6012(b)(1), <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1163">122 Stat. 1163</ref>, 1165; <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VI, §§ 6011, 6012(b)(1), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1664">122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1925, 1927; <ref href="/us/pl/113/79/tV">Pub. L. 113–79, title V</ref>, §§ 5003, 5004, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/834">128 Stat. 834</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idef08066a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idef08066b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idef08066c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of enactment of this subparagraph, referred to in subsec. (a)(3)(E)(ii), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref>, which was approved <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a)(6)(A), (b), and (d)(1), was in the original “this title”, meaning title III of <ref href="/us/pl/87/128">Pub. L. 87–128</ref>, <date date="1961-08-08">Aug. 8, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/307">75 Stat. 307</ref>, known as the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of title III to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1921">section 1921 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idef08066d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> made identical amendments to this section. The amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> were repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idef08066e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (a)(3)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/113/79/s5003">Pub. L. 113–79, § 5003</ref>, added subpar. (D) and struck out former subpar. (D). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “If a direct farm ownership loan is made under this subchapter as part of a joint financing arrangement and the amount of the direct farm ownership loan does not exceed 50 percent of the total principal amount financed under the arrangement, the interest rate on the direct farm ownership loan shall be at least 4 percent annually.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/113/79/s5004">Pub. L. 113–79, § 5004</ref>, redesignated subsec. (e) as (d) and struck out former subsec. (d). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “With respect to a farm ownership loan made after <date date="1985-12-23">December 23, 1985</date>, unless appraised values of the rights to oil, gas, or other minerals are specifically included as part of the appraised value of collateral securing the loan, the rights to oil, gas, or other minerals located under the property shall not be considered part of the collateral securing the loan. Nothing in this subsection shall prevent the inclusion of, as part of the collateral securing the loan, any payment or other compensation the borrower may receive for damages to the surface of the collateral real estate resulting from the exploration for or recovery of minerals.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (a)(3)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s6011">Pub. L. 110–246, § 6011</ref>, added subpar. (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s6012/b/1">Pub. L. 110–246, § 6012(b)(1)</ref>, added cl. (ii) and struck out former cl. (ii) which read as follows: “clause (1) of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1932/a">section 1932(a) of this title</ref>, and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s604/1">Pub. L. 104–127, § 604(1)</ref>, inserted “subparagraph (D) and in” after “Except as provided in”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s604/2">Pub. L. 104–127, § 604(2)</ref>, added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s661/a/1">Pub. L. 104–127, § 661(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “1926(a)(1) and 1932 of this title” for “1924(b), 1926(a)(1), and 1932 of this title”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s661/a/2">Pub. L. 104–127, § 661(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “and” at end of cl. (v), substituted a period for “, and” at end of cl. (vi), redesignated cls. (iii), (v), and (vi) as (i), (ii), and (iii), respectively, and struck out cls. (i), (ii), (iv), and (vii) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(i) clauses (2) and (3) of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1923/a">section 1923(a) of this title</ref>,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(ii) <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1924/b">section 1924(b) of this title</ref>,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(iv) <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1926/a/15">section 1926(a)(15) of this title</ref>,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(vii) <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1934/a">section 1934(a) of this title</ref> as it relates to the making or insuring of loans under clauses (2) and (3) of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1923/a">section 1923(a) of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s747/b/1">Pub. L. 104–127, § 747(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1932/d">section 1932(d) of this title</ref>” for “subsections (d) and (e) of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1932">section 1932 of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/103/328/s113/a/1">Pub. L. 103–328, § 113(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Notwithstanding the provisions of the constitution or laws of any State limiting the rate or amount of interest that may be charged, taken, received, or reserved, except” for “Except”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/103/328/s113/a/2">Pub. L. 103–328, § 113(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “(5)(A) Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the” for “(5) The” and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a)(6)(B)(ii) to (viii). <ref href="/us/pl/102/552">Pub. L. 102–552</ref> redesignated cls. (iii) to (viii) as (ii) to (vii) and struck out former cl. (ii) which read as follows: “the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1924/a">section 1924(a) of this title</ref>, relating to the financing of outdoor recreational enterprises or the conversion of farming or ranching operations to recreational uses,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s2383/1">Pub. L. 101–624, § 2383(1)</ref>, substituted “guaranteed” for “guranteed”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s1803/a">Pub. L. 101–624, § 1803(a)</ref>, amended subpar. (B) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (B) read as follows: “Except as provided in paragraph (6), the interest rates on loans (other than guaranteed loans) under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1934">section 1934 of this title</ref> shall be as determined by the Secretary, but not in excess of one-half of the current average market yield on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States with remaining periods to maturity comparable to the average maturities of such loans, nor less than 5 per centum per annum.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s2383/2">Pub. L. 101–624, § 2383(2)</ref>, added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/100/233/s603">Pub. L. 100–233, § 603</ref>, inserted provisions at end relating to use of same collateral to secure two or more loans made, insured, or guaranteed under this subchapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/100/233/s604">Pub. L. 100–233, § 604</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (a)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/99/198/s1304A">Pub. L. 99–198, § 1304A</ref>, substituted “where the median household income of the persons to be served by such facility is below the higher of 80 per centum of the statewide nonmetropolitan median household income or the poverty line established by the Office of Management and Budget, as revised under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9902/2">section 9902(2) of title 42</ref>” for “where the median family income of the persons to be served by such facility is below the poverty line prescribed by the Office of Management and Budget as adjusted under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2971d">section 2971d of title 42</ref>” and prescribed a 7 per centum per annum ceiling on loans for facilities that do not qualify for the 5 per centum per annum interest rate but are located in areas where the median household income of the persons to be served by the facility does not exceed 100 per centum of the statewide nonmetropolitan median household income.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/99/198/s1305">Pub. L. 99–198, § 1305</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> in par. (2) inserted reference to par. (6), in par. (3) designated existing provisions as subpar. (A), expanded provisions to take into account provisions of par. (6) and revised criteria for determination of applicable interest rates, and added subpar. (B), in par. (4) inserted exception for par. (6), and added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/334/s108/1">Pub. L. 95–334, § 108(1)</ref>, substituted provisions relating to determination of interest rates on loans, except as provided in pars. (3) to (5), as not in excess of the current average market yield on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States, with comparable remaining periods of maturity to the average maturities of such loans plus additional adjusted amounts, for provisions relating to establishment of interest rates on loans, except as specifically provided, but not in excess of 5 per centum per annum.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/334/s108/2">Pub. L. 95–334, § 108(2)</ref>, (3), added subsec. (b) and redesignated former subsec. (b) as (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1972—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/92/419">Pub. L. 92–419</ref>, §§ 113, 114, prescribed interest rates on rural development other than guaranteed and guaranteed loans and escrow payment of taxes and insurance, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/92/419/s128/b">Pub. L. 92–419, § 128(b)</ref>, substituted “may” for “shall” in second sentence.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idef08066f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idef080670-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment of this section and repeal of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> effective <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8701">section 8701 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idef080671-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/328/tI/s113/b">Pub. L. 103–328, title I, § 113(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-29">Sept. 29, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2366">108 Stat. 2366</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/328/tI/s113/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), the amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to a loan made, insured, or guaranteed under the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1921">7 U.S.C. 1921</ref> et seq.) in a State on or after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1994-09-29">Sept. 29, 1994</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State option</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in paragraph (3), the amendments made by subsection (a) shall not apply to a loan made, insured, or guaranteed under the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act in a State after the date (that occurs during the 3-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act) on which the State adopts a law or certifies that the voters of the State have voted in favor of a provision of the constitution or law of the State that states that the State does not want the amendments made by subsection (a) to apply with respect to loans made, insured, or guaranteed under such Act in the State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transitional period</inline>.—</heading><content>In any case in which a State takes an action described in paragraph (2), the amendments made by subsection (a) shall continue to apply to a loan made, insured, or guaranteed under the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act in the State after the date the action was taken pursuant to a commitment for the loan that was entered into during the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, and ending on the date on which the State takes the action.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idef080672-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/552/tV/s516/c/2">Pub. L. 102–552, title V, § 516(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4137">106 Stat. 4137</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/552/tV/s516/c/2">“The amendments made by paragraph (1) of this subsection [amending this section] shall take effect at the same time as the amendments made by section 501(a) of the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act Amendments of 1991 (<ref href="/us/pl/102/237">Public Law 102–237</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/105/1865">105 Stat. 1865</ref>) [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1924">section 1924 of this title</ref>] took effect.</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idef080673-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tI/s160/c">Pub. L. 97–35, title I, § 160(c)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/378">95 Stat. 378</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/35/tI/s160/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1946">section 1946 of this title</ref>] shall apply to loans approved after <date date="1981-09-30">September 30, 1981</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
