<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idef1d8a37-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1986"><num value="1986">§ 1986.</num><heading> Conflicts of interests</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef1d8a38-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1986/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Acceptance of fees, commissions, gifts, or other considerations prohibited</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No officer, attorney, or other employee of the Secretary shall, directly or indirectly, be the beneficiary of or receive any fee, commission, gift, or other consideration for or in connection with any transaction or business under this chapter other than such salary, fee, or other compensation as he may receive as such officer, attorney, or employee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef1d8a39-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1986/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Acquisition of interest in land by certain officers or employees of Department of Agriculture prohibited; 3-year period</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, no officer or employee of the Department of Agriculture who acts on or reviews an application made by any person under this chapter for a loan to purchase land may acquire, directly or indirectly, any interest in such land for a period of three years after the date on which such action is taken or such review is made. This prohibition shall not apply to a former member of a county committee upon a determination by the Secretary, prior to the acquisition of such interest, that such former member acted in good faith when acting on or reviewing such application.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef1d8a3a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1986/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Certifications on loans to family members prohibited</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No member of a county committee shall knowingly make or join in making any certification with respect to a loan to purchase any land in which he or any person related to him within the second degree of consanguinity or affinity has or may acquire any interest or with respect to any applicant related to him within the second degree of consanguinity or affinity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef1d8a3b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s1986/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Penalties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any persons violating any provision of this section shall, upon conviction thereof, be punished by a fine of not more than $2,000 or imprisonment for not more than two years, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idef1d8a3c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/128/tIII/s336">Pub. L. 87–128, title III, § 336</ref>, <date date="1961-08-08">Aug. 8, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/316">75 Stat. 316</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/258/tVI/s606">Pub. L. 98–258, title VI, § 606</ref>, <date date="1984-04-10">Apr. 10, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/140">98 Stat. 140</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/171/tV/s5501/b">Pub. L. 107–171, title V, § 5501(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/351">116 Stat. 351</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idef1d8a3d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idef1d8a3e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idef1d8a3f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), was in the original “this title”, meaning title III of <ref href="/us/pl/87/128">Pub. L. 87–128</ref>, <date date="1961-08-08">Aug. 8, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/307">75 Stat. 307</ref>, known as the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of title III to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1921">section 1921 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idef1d8a40-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/107/171">Pub. L. 107–171</ref> struck out “provided for in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1982">section 1982 of this title</ref>” after “former member of a county committee”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—<ref href="/us/pl/98/258">Pub. L. 98–258</ref> designated first, second, and third sentences of existing provisions as subsecs. (a), (c), and (d), respectively, and added subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
