<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idef4adbfd-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2019"><num value="2019">§ 2019.</num><heading> Redemption of program benefits</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Regulations issued pursuant to this chapter shall provide for the redemption of benefits accepted by retail food stores through approved wholesale food concerns or through financial institutions which are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, or which are insured under the Federal Credit Union Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1751">12 U.S.C. 1751</ref> et seq.] and have retail food stores or wholesale food concerns in their field of membership, with the cooperation of the Treasury Department, except that retail food stores defined in section 2012(<i>o</i>)(4) of this title shall be authorized to redeem their members’ food benefits prior to receipt by the members of the food so purchased, retail food stores authorized to accept and redeem benefits through on-line transactions shall be authorized to accept benefits prior to the delivery of food if the delivery occurs within a reasonable time of the purchase, as determined by the Secretary, and publicly operated community mental health centers or private nonprofit organizations or institutions which serve meals to narcotics addicts or alcoholics in drug addiction or alcoholic treatment and rehabilitation programs, public and private nonprofit shelters that prepare and serve meals for battered women and children, and public or private nonprofit group living arrangements that serve meals to disabled or blind residents, shall not be authorized to redeem benefits through financial institutions which are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation or the Federal Credit Union Act. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, a center, organization, institution, shelter, group living arrangement, or establishment described in that sentence may be authorized to redeem benefits through a financial institution described in that sentence if the center, organization, institution, shelter, group living arrangement, or establishment is equipped with 1 or more point-of-sale devices and is operating in an area in which an electronic benefit transfer system described in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2016/h">section 2016(h) of this title</ref> has been implemented. No financial institution may impose on or collect from a retail food store a fee or other charge for the redemption of benefits that are submitted to the financial institution in a manner consistent with the requirements, other than any requirements relating to cancellation of benefits, for the presentation of benefits by financial institutions to the Federal Reserve banks.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idef4d25ee-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/88/525/s10">Pub. L. 88–525, § 10</ref>, <date date="1964-08-31">Aug. 31, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/706">78 Stat. 706</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/671/s6">Pub. L. 91–671, § 6</ref>, <date date="1971-01-11">Jan. 11, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/2051">84 Stat. 2051</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/603/tIV/s411/c">Pub. L. 92–603, title IV, § 411(c)</ref>–(e), <date date="1972-10-30">Oct. 30, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1491">86 Stat. 1491</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/86/s3/f">Pub. L. 93–86, § 3(f)</ref>, (i), (k), <date date="1973-08-10">Aug. 10, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/247">87 Stat. 247</ref>, 248; <ref href="/us/pl/93/125/s1/j">Pub. L. 93–125, § 1(j)</ref>, <date date="1973-10-18">Oct. 18, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/450">87 Stat. 450</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/113/tXIII/s1301">Pub. L. 95–113, title XIII, § 1301</ref>, <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/969">91 Stat. 969</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/58/s8">Pub. L. 96–58, § 8</ref>, <date date="1979-08-14">Aug. 14, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/392">93 Stat. 392</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/249/tI/s101/b">Pub. L. 96–249, title I, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="1980-05-26">May 26, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/357">94 Stat. 357</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/tXIII/s1315">Pub. L. 97–98, title XIII, § 1315</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1285">95 Stat. 1285</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/198/tXV">Pub. L. 99–198, title XV</ref>, §§ 1501(b), 1522, 1523(a), <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1566">99 Stat. 1566</ref>, 1580; <ref href="/us/pl/99/570/tXI/s11002/e">Pub. L. 99–570, title XI, § 11002(e)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-27">Oct. 27, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3207-168">100 Stat. 3207–168</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/171/tIV/s4113/a">Pub. L. 107–171, title IV, § 4113(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/313">116 Stat. 313</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/234/tIV/s4115/b/7">Pub. L. 110–234, title IV, § 4115(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1107">122 Stat. 1107</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title IV, § 4115(b)(7), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1664">122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1868; <ref href="/us/pl/113/79/tIV/s4011/b/2/B">Pub. L. 113–79, title IV, § 4011(b)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/793">128 Stat. 793</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/334/tIV/s4022/4">Pub. L. 115–334, title IV, § 4022(4)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4653">132 Stat. 4653</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idef4d25ef-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idef4d25f0-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idef4d25f1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Credit Union Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-26/ch750">act June 26, 1934, ch. 750</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1216">48 Stat. 1216</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 14 (§ 1751 et seq.) of Title 12, Banks and Banking. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1751">section 1751 of Title 12</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idef4d25f2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> made identical amendments to this section. The amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> were repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idef4d25f3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—<ref href="/us/pl/115/334">Pub. L. 115–334</ref>, in first sentence, struck out “or the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation” after “the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation” in two places and substituted “2012(<i>o</i>)(4)” for “2012(p)(4)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—<ref href="/us/pl/113/79">Pub. L. 113–79</ref> inserted “retail food stores authorized to accept and redeem benefits through on-line transactions shall be authorized to accept benefits prior to the delivery of food if the delivery occurs within a reasonable time of the purchase, as determined by the Secretary,” after “food so purchased,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—<ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4115/b/7">Pub. L. 110–246, § 4115(b)(7)</ref>, in section catchline, substituted “program benefits” for “coupons” and, in text, substituted “section 2012(p)(4)” for “section 2012(k)(4)” and “section 2016(h)” for “section 2016(i)” and substituted “benefits” for “coupons” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—<ref href="/us/pl/107/171">Pub. L. 107–171</ref> inserted after first sentence “Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, a center, organization, institution, shelter, group living arrangement, or establishment described in that sentence may be authorized to redeem coupons through a financial institution described in that sentence if the center, organization, institution, shelter, group living arrangement, or establishment is equipped with 1 or more point-of-sale devices and is operating in an area in which an electronic benefit transfer system described in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2016/i">section 2016(i) of this title</ref> has been implemented.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—<ref href="/us/pl/99/570/s11002/e">Pub. L. 99–570, § 11002(e)</ref>, (f), temporarily struck out “and” after “battered women and children,” and inserted “, and public or private nonprofit establishments, or public or private nonprofit shelters that feed individuals who do not reside in permanent dwellings and individuals who have no fixed mailing addresses”. See Effective and Termination Dates of 1986 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—<ref href="/us/pl/99/198/s1501/b">Pub. L. 99–198, § 1501(b)</ref>, inserted reference to publicly operated community mental health centers.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/198/s1522">Pub. L. 99–198, § 1522</ref>, inserted “, or which are insured under the Federal Credit Union Act and have retail food stores or wholesale food concerns in their field of membership” and “or the Federal Credit Union Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/198/s1523/a">Pub. L. 99–198, § 1523(a)</ref>, inserted sentence providing that no financial institution may impose on or collect from a retail food store a fee or other charge for the redemption of coupons that are submitted to the financial institution in a manner consistent with the requirements, other than any requirements relating to cancellation of coupons, for the presentation of coupons by financial institutions to the Federal Reserve banks.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—<ref href="/us/pl/97/98">Pub. L. 97–98</ref> substituted “financial institutions which are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation or the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation” for “banks” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—<ref href="/us/pl/96/249">Pub. L. 96–249</ref> substituted “purchased,” for “purchased” and “residents” for “residents,” and inserted “, public and private nonprofit shelters that prepare and serve meals for battered women and children” after “programs”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—<ref href="/us/pl/96/58">Pub. L. 96–58</ref> inserted provisions relating to public and private nonprofit group living arrangements that serve meals to disabled or blind residents.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—<ref href="/us/pl/95/113">Pub. L. 95–113</ref> substituted revised provisions covering redemption of coupons for provisions relating to administration of program which are now covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2020">section 2020 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/93/86/s3/i">Pub. L. 93–86, § 3(i)</ref>, inserted cls. (6) and (7), designated former cl. (6) as (8), and inserted provision relating to time for submission of plan of operation to Secretary for approval and time for Secretary to make a determination of approval or disapproval of such plan.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/93/125">Pub. L. 93–125</ref> inserted “members of” after “the Secretary shall permit”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/93/86/s3/k">Pub. L. 93–86, § 3(k)</ref>, inserted provisions authorizing meal purchases from senior citizens’ centers, apartment buildings occupied primarily by elderly persons, any public or nonprofit private school which prepares meals especially for elderly persons, any public or nonprofit private eating establishment which prepares meals especially for elderly persons during special hours, and any other public or nonprofit private establishment approved for such purpose by the Secretary.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/93/86/s3/f">Pub. L. 93–86, § 3(f)</ref>, added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1972—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/92/603/s411/c">Pub. L. 92–603, § 411(c)</ref>, struck out provisions relating to filing of an affidavit by household for certification of eligibility for public assistance.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/92/603/s411/d">Pub. L. 92–603, § 411(d)</ref>, (e), substituted “prescribed by the Secretary in the regulations issued pursuant to this chapter” for “used by them in the certification of applicants for benefits under the federally aided public assistance programs” in cl. (2), and struck out provisions requiring the State agency to institute procedures under which any household participating in the food stamp program shall be entitled to have the charges for its coupon allotment deducted from grants or payments such household is entitled to receive and have its coupon allotment distributed to it with such grant or payment.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1971—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/91/671/s6/a">Pub. L. 91–671, § 6(a)</ref>, inserted provisions respecting certification of eligibility for benefits by execution of an affidavit and duration of validity of a certification upon removal of a household from one political subdivision to another.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/91/671/s6/b">Pub. L. 91–671, § 6(b)</ref>, substituted “regulations” for “regulation” in second sentence preceding cl. (1) and “from time to time may” for “may from time to time”, and added cls. (5) and (6) and provision for withholding in the State plan.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/91/671/s6/c">Pub. L. 91–671, § 6(c)</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idef4d25f4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idef4d25f5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment of this section and repeal of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> effective <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8701">section 8701 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4115/b/7">section 4115(b)(7) of Pub. L. 110–246</ref> effective <date date="2008-10-01">Oct. 1, 2008</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4407">section 4407 of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1161">section 1161 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idef4d25f6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2002 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/171/tIV/s4113/b">Pub. L. 107–171, title IV, § 4113(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/314">116 Stat. 314</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/171/tIV/s4113/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] takes effect on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idef4d25f7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective and Termination Dates of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/570">Pub. L. 99–570</ref> effective, and to be implemented by issuance of final regulations, not later than <date date="1987-04-01">Apr. 1, 1987</date>, and cease to be effective after <date date="1990-09-30">Sept. 30, 1990</date>, see section 11002(f)(1), (2) of <ref href="/us/pl/99/570">Pub. L. 99–570</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2012">section 2012 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idef4d25f8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/98">Pub. L. 97–98</ref> effective on earlier of <date date="1982-09-08">Sept. 8, 1982</date>, or date such amendment became effective pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/s1338">section 1338 of Pub. L. 97–98</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2012">section 2012 of this title</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/253/s192/b">section 192(b) of Pub. L. 97–253</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2012">section 2012 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/98">Pub. L. 97–98</ref> effective upon such date as Secretary of Agriculture may prescribe, taking into account need for orderly implementation, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/s1338">section 1338 of Pub. L. 97–98</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2012">section 2012 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idef4d25f9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1979 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/58">Pub. L. 96–58</ref> to be implemented in all States by <date date="1980-07-01">July 1, 1980</date>, but not to affect the rights or liabilities of Secretary, States, and applicant or participant households under provisions of this chapter as in effect on <date date="1979-07-01">July 1, 1979</date>, until implemented, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/58/s10/c">section 10(c) of Pub. L. 96–58</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2012">section 2012 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idef4d25fa-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1977 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/113/tXIII/s1301">Pub. L. 95–113, title XIII, § 1301</ref>, <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/958">91 Stat. 958</ref>, provided that the amendment made by section 1301 is effective <date date="1977-10-01">Oct. 1, 1977</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idef4d25fb-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1972 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/92/603">Pub. L. 92–603</ref> effective <date date="1973-01-01">Jan. 1, 1973</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/92/603/s411/h">section 411(h) of Pub. L. 92–603</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2012">section 2012 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idef4d25fc-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/198/tXV/s1523/b">Pub. L. 99–198, title XV, § 1523(b)</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1580">99 Stat. 1580</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/198/tXV/s1523/b">“The Secretary of Agriculture, in consultation with the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, shall issue regulations implementing the amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idef4d25fd-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Publicly Operated Community Health Centers</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions of this section concerning private, nonprofit drug addiction or alcoholic treatment and rehabilitation programs to be applicable to publicly operated community health centers, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/107/s101/b">section 101(b) of Pub. L. 98–107</ref>, set out in part as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2012">section 2012 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idef4d25fe-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Extension Until <date date="1976-10-01">October 1, 1976</date>, of Final Date for Compliance With Regulations Governing Use of Food Stamps by AFDC Families</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/94/182/tII/s201">Pub. L. 94–182, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1975-12-31">Dec. 31, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/1056">89 Stat. 1056</ref>, permitted the final date for compliance with regulations implementing former subsec. (e)(7) of this section to be extended until <date date="1976-10-01">Oct. 1, 1976</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
