<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idef54517a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2023"><num value="2023">§ 2023.</num><heading> Administrative and judicial review; restoration of rights</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef54517b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2023/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef54517c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2023/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Whenever an application of a retail food store or wholesale food concern to participate in the supplemental nutrition assistance program is denied pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2018">section 2018 of this title</ref>, or a retail food store or wholesale food concern is disqualified or subjected to a civil money penalty under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2021">section 2021 of this title</ref>, or a retail food store or wholesale food concern forfeits a bond under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2021/d">section 2021(d) of this title</ref>, or all or part of any claim of a retail food store or wholesale food concern is denied under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2022">section 2022 of this title</ref>, or a claim against a State agency is stated pursuant to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2022">section 2022 of this title</ref>, notice of such administrative action shall be issued to the retail food store, wholesale food concern, or State agency involved.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef54517d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2023/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Delivery of notices</inline>.—</heading><content>A notice under paragraph (1) shall be delivered by any form of delivery that the Secretary determines will provide evidence of the delivery.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef54517e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2023/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If such store, concern, or State agency is aggrieved by such action, it may, in accordance with regulations promulgated under this chapter, within ten days of the date of delivery of such notice, file a written request for an opportunity to submit information in support of its position to such person or persons as the regulations may designate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef54517f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2023/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> If such a request is not made or if such store, concern, or State agency fails to submit information in support of its position after filing a request, the administrative determination shall be final.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef545180-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2023/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> If such request is made by such store, concern, or State agency, such information as may be submitted by the store, concern, or State agency, as well as such other information as may be available, shall be reviewed by the person or persons designated by the Secretary, who shall, subject to the right of judicial review hereinafter provided, make a determination which shall be final and which shall take effect thirty days after the date of the delivery or service of such final notice of determination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef545181-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2023/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Determinations regarding claims made pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2025/c">section 2025(c) of this title</ref> (including determinations as to whether there is good cause for not imposing all or a portion of the penalty) shall be made on the record after opportunity for an agency hearing in accordance with section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002237">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002237"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “sections”.</note> 556 and 557 of title 5 in which one or more administrative law judges appointed pursuant to section 3105 of such title shall preside over the taking of evidence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef545182-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2023/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Such judges shall have authority to issue and enforce subpoenas in the manner prescribed in sections <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002238">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002238"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “section”.</note> 499m(c) and (d) of this title and to appoint expert witnesses under the provisions of Rule 706 of the Federal Rules of Evidence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef545183-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2023/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> The Secretary may not limit the authority of such judges presiding over determinations regarding claims made pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2025/c">section 2025(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef545184-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2023/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> The Secretary shall provide a summary procedure for determinations regarding claims made pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2025/c">section 2025(c) of this title</ref> in amounts less than $50,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef545185-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2023/a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> Such summary procedure need not include an oral hearing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef545186-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2023/a/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> On a petition by the State agency or sua sponte, the Secretary may permit the full administrative review procedure to be used in lieu of such summary review procedure for a claim of less than $50,000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef545187-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2023/a/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> Subject to the right of judicial review hereinafter provided, a determination made by an administrative law judge regarding a claim made pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2025/c">section 2025(c) of this title</ref> shall be final and shall take effect thirty days after the date of the delivery or service of final notice of such determination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef545188-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2023/a/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> If the store, concern, or State agency feels aggrieved by such final determination, it may obtain judicial review thereof by filing a complaint against the United States in the United States court for the district in which it resides or is engaged in business, or, in the case of a retail food store or wholesale food concern, in any court of record of the State having competent jurisdiction, within thirty days after the date of delivery or service of the final notice of determination upon it, requesting the court to set aside such determination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef545189-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2023/a/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> The copy of the summons and complaint required to be delivered to the official or agency whose order is being attacked shall be sent to the Secretary or such person or persons as the Secretary may designate to receive service of process.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef54518a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2023/a/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content> The suit in the United States district court or State court shall be a trial de novo by the court in which the court shall determine the validity of the questioned administrative action in issue, except that judicial review of determinations regarding claims made pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2025/c">section 2025(c) of this title</ref> shall be a review on the administrative record.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef54518b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2023/a/16"><num value="16">(16)</num><content> If the court determines that such administrative action is invalid, it shall enter such judgment or order as it determines is in accordance with the law and the evidence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef54518c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2023/a/17"><num value="17">(17)</num><content> During the pendency of such judicial review, or any appeal therefrom, the administrative action under review shall be and remain in full force and effect, unless on application to the court on not less than ten days’ notice, and after hearing thereon and a consideration by the court of the applicant’s likelihood of prevailing on the merits and of irreparable injury, the court temporarily stays such administrative action pending disposition of such trial or appeal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef54518d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2023/a/18"><num value="18">(18)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Suspension of stores pending review</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, any permanent disqualification of a retail food store or wholesale food concern under paragraph (3) or (4) of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2021/b">section 2021(b) of this title</ref> shall be effective from the date of receipt of the notice of disqualification. If the disqualification is reversed through administrative or judicial review, the Secretary shall not be liable for the value of any sales lost during the disqualification period.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef54518e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2023/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> In any judicial action arising under this chapter, any allotments found to have been wrongfully withheld shall be restored only for periods of not more than one year prior to the date of the commencement of such action, or in the case of an action seeking review of a final State agency determination, not more than one year prior to the date of the filing of a request with the State for the restoration of such allotments or, in either case, not more than one year prior to the date the State agency is notified or otherwise discovers the possible loss to a household.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idef54518f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/88/525/s14">Pub. L. 88–525, § 14</ref>, <date date="1964-08-31">Aug. 31, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/708">78 Stat. 708</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/671/s7">Pub. L. 91–671, § 7</ref>, <date date="1971-01-11">Jan. 11, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/2052">84 Stat. 2052</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/603/tIV/s411/f">Pub. L. 92–603, title IV, § 411(f)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-30">Oct. 30, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1492">86 Stat. 1492</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/113/tXIII/s1301">Pub. L. 95–113, title XIII, § 1301</ref>, <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/974">91 Stat. 974</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/tXIII/s1320/b">Pub. L. 97–98, title XIII, § 1320(b)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1286">95 Stat. 1286</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/253/tI/s176/b">Pub. L. 97–253, title I, § 176(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-08">Sept. 8, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/781">96 Stat. 781</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/198/tXV/s1536">Pub. L. 99–198, title XV, § 1536</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1585">99 Stat. 1585</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/435/tVI/s603">Pub. L. 100–435, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="1988-09-19">Sept. 19, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1674">102 Stat. 1674</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/tXIII/s13951/b">Pub. L. 103–66, title XIII, § 13951(b)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-10">Aug. 10, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/678">107 Stat. 678</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/tVIII/s845">Pub. L. 104–193, title VIII, § 845</ref>, <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2333">110 Stat. 2333</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/171/tIV/s4117/a">Pub. L. 107–171, title IV, § 4117(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/316">116 Stat. 316</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/234/tIV">Pub. L. 110–234, title IV</ref>, §§ 4001(b), 4002(a)(7), <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1092">122 Stat. 1092</ref>, 1094; <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title IV, §§ 4001(b), 4002(a)(7), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1664">122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1853, 1855.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idef545190-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idef545191-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idef545192-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Rules of Evidence, referred to in subsec. (a)(7), are set out in the Appendix to Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idef545193-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> made identical amendments to this section. The amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> were repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idef545194-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4001/b">Pub. L. 110–246, § 4001(b)</ref>, substituted “supplemental nutrition assistance program” for “food stamp program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4002/a/7">Pub. L. 110–246, § 4002(a)(7)</ref>, substituted “any allotments” for “any food stamp allotments”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/107/171">Pub. L. 107–171</ref> added heading and text of par. (2) and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows: “Such notice shall be delivered by certified mail or personal service.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/193">Pub. L. 104–193</ref> designated first through seventeenth sentences as pars. (1) to (17), respectively, and added par. (18).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/66">Pub. L. 103–66</ref> inserted “(including determinations as to whether there is good cause for not imposing all or a portion of the penalty)” after “Determinations regarding claims made pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2025/c">section 2025(c) of this title</ref>” in sixth sentence and struck out at end “Notwithstanding the administrative or judicial review procedures set forth in this subsection, determinations by the Secretary concerning whether a State agency had good cause for its failure to meet error rate tolerance levels established under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2025/c">section 2025(c) of this title</ref> are final.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/435">Pub. L. 100–435</ref> inserted provisions relating to judicial review and determinations regarding excessive payment error rate claims pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2025/c">section 2025(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/198">Pub. L. 99–198</ref> substituted “on application” for “an application” and “consideration by the court of the applicant’s likelihood of prevailing on the merits and of irreparable injury” for “showing of irreparable injury”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/253">Pub. L. 97–253</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2021">section 2021 of this title</ref>, or a retail food store or wholesale food concern forfeits a bond under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2021/d">section 2021(d) of this title</ref>,” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2021">section 2021 of this title</ref>,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—<ref href="/us/pl/97/98">Pub. L. 97–98</ref> designated existing provision as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—<ref href="/us/pl/95/113">Pub. L. 95–113</ref> substituted revised provisions for administrative and judicial review for provisions relating to violations and enforcement which are now covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2024">section 2024 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1972—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/92/603">Pub. L. 92–603</ref> struck out subsec. (e) which provided that no person be charged with violation of this chapter or any other law on the basis of statements or information contained in affidavits filed under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2019/c">section 2019(c) of this title</ref>, except for fraud.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1971—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/91/671/s7/a">Pub. L. 91–671, § 7(a)</ref>, provided for purchase of coupons.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/91/671/s7/a">Pub. L. 91–671, § 7(a)</ref>, included alteration as an offense and made authorization to purchase cards the subject matter of the enumerated offenses.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/91/671/s7/b">Pub. L. 91–671, § 7(b)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idef545195-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idef545196-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment of this section and repeal of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> effective <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8701">section 8701 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by sections 4001(b) and 4002(a)(7) of <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> effective <date date="2008-10-01">Oct. 1, 2008</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4407">section 4407 of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1161">section 1161 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idef545197-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2002 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/171/tIV/s4117/b">Pub. L. 107–171, title IV, § 4117(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/316">116 Stat. 316</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/171/tIV/s4117/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] takes effect on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idef545198-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1993 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/66">Pub. L. 103–66</ref> effective <date date="1991-10-01">Oct. 1, 1991</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/s13971/b/1/A">section 13971(b)(1)(A) of Pub. L. 103–66</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2025">section 2025 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idef545199-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/435">Pub. L. 100–435</ref> effective <date date="1985-10-01">Oct. 1, 1985</date>, with respect to claims under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2025/c">section 2025(c) of this title</ref> for quality control review periods after such date, except as otherwise provided, see section 701(b)(5)(C), (D) of <ref href="/us/pl/100/435">Pub. L. 100–435</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2012">section 2012 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idef54519a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/253">Pub. L. 97–253</ref> effective <date date="1982-09-08">Sept. 8, 1982</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/253/s193/a">section 193(a) of Pub. L. 97–253</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2012">section 2012 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idef54519b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/98">Pub. L. 97–98</ref> effective on earlier of <date date="1982-09-08">Sept. 8, 1982</date>, or date such amendment became effective pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/s1338">section 1338 of Pub. L. 97–98</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2012">section 2012 of this title</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/253/s192/b">section 192(b) of Pub. L. 97–253</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2012">section 2012 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/98">Pub. L. 97–98</ref> effective upon such date as Secretary of Agriculture may prescribe, taking into account need for orderly implementation, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/s1338">section 1338 of Pub. L. 97–98</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2012">section 2012 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idef54519c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1977 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/113/tXIII/s1301">Pub. L. 95–113, title XIII, § 1301</ref>, <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/958">91 Stat. 958</ref>, provided that the amendment made by section 1301 is effective <date date="1977-10-01">Oct. 1, 1977</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idef54519d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1972 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/92/603">Pub. L. 92–603</ref> effective <date date="1973-01-01">Jan. 1, 1973</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/92/603/s411/h">section 411(h) of Pub. L. 92–603</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2012">section 2012 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
