<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idee1e430d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s205"><num value="205">§ 205.</num><heading> General duty as to services; revocation of registration</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All stockyard services furnished pursuant to reasonable request made to a stockyard owner or market agency at such stockyard shall be reasonable and nondiscriminatory and stockyard services which are furnished shall not be refused on any basis that is unreasonable or unjustly discriminatory: <i>Provided</i>, That in any State where the weighing of livestock at a stockyard is conducted by a duly authorized department or agency of the State, the Secretary, upon application of such department or agency, may register it as a market agency for the weighing of livestock received in such stockyard, and upon such registration such department or agency and the members thereof shall be amenable to all the requirements of this chapter, and upon failure of such department or agency or the members thereof to comply with the orders of the Secretary under this chapter he is authorized to revoke the registration of such department or agency and to enforce such revocation as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s216">section 216 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idee1e430e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1921-08-15/ch64">Aug. 15, 1921, ch. 64</ref>, title III, § 304, <ref href="/us/stat/42/164">42 Stat. 164</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1926-05-05/ch240">May 5, 1926, ch. 240</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/397">44 Stat. 397</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/446/s1/c">Pub. L. 90–446, § 1(c)</ref>, <date date="1968-07-31">July 31, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/474">82 Stat. 474</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idee1e430f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idee1e4310-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idee1e4311-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—<ref href="/us/pl/90/446">Pub. L. 90–446</ref> inserted provision requiring that stockyard services which are furnished not be refused on any basis that is unreasonable or unjustly discriminatory.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1926—Act <date date="1926-05-05">May 5, 1926</date>, inserted proviso.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
