<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idef6c1f5e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2133"><num value="2133">§ 2133.</num><heading> Licensing of dealers and exhibitors</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall issue licenses to dealers and exhibitors upon application therefor in such form and manner as he may prescribe and upon payment of such fee established pursuant to 2153 of this title: <i>Provided</i>, That no such license shall be issued until the dealer or exhibitor shall have demonstrated that his facilities comply with the standards promulgated by the Secretary pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2143">section 2143 of this title</ref>: <i>Provided, however</i>, That a dealer or exhibitor shall not be required to obtain a license as a dealer or exhibitor under this chapter if the size of the business is determined by the Secretary to be de minimis. The Secretary is further authorized to license, as dealers or exhibitors, persons who do not qualify as dealers or exhibitors within the meaning of this chapter upon such persons’ complying with the requirements specified above and agreeing, in writing, to comply with all the requirements of this chapter and the regulations promulgated by the Secretary hereunder.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idef6c1f5f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/544/s3">Pub. L. 89–544, § 3</ref>, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/351">80 Stat. 351</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/579/s4">Pub. L. 91–579, § 4</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1561">84 Stat. 1561</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/79/tXII/s12308/a/2">Pub. L. 113–79, title XII, § 12308(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/990">128 Stat. 990</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idef6c1f60-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idef6c1f61-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idef6c1f62-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—<ref href="/us/pl/113/79">Pub. L. 113–79</ref> substituted “: <i>Provided, however</i>, That a dealer or exhibitor shall not be required to obtain a license as a dealer or exhibitor under this chapter if the size of the business is determined by the Secretary to be de minimis.” for “: <i>Provided, however</i>, That any retail pet store or other person who derives less than a substantial portion of his income (as determined by the Secretary) from the breeding and raising of dogs or cats on his own premises and sells any such dog or cat to a dealer or research facility shall not be required to obtain a license as a dealer or exhibitor under this chapter.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—<ref href="/us/pl/91/579">Pub. L. 91–579</ref> inserted references to exhibitors and retail pet stores.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idef6c1f63-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idef6c1f64-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1970 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/579">Pub. L. 91–579</ref> effective one year after <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/579/s23">section 23 of Pub. L. 91–579</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2131">section 2131 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
