<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idef6e9016-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2146a"><num value="2146a">§ 2146a.</num><heading> Searchable database requirements</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service shall, notwithstanding any other provision of law:</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idef6e9017-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2146a/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> within 60 calendar days, restore on its website the searchable database and its contents that were available on <date date="2017-01-30">January 30, 2017</date>, and all content generated since that date; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idef6e9018-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2146a/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> hereafter, make publicly available via searchable database, in their entirety without redactions except signatures, the following records:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef6e9019-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2146a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> all final Animal Welfare Act inspection reports, including all reports documenting all Animal Welfare Act violations and non-compliances observed by USDA officials and all animal inventories for the current year and the preceding three years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef6e901a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2146a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> all final Animal Welfare Act and Horse Protection Act enforcement records for the current year and the preceding three years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef6e901b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2146a/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> all reports or other materials documenting any violations and non-compliances observed by USDA officials for the current year and the preceding three years; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef6e901c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2146a/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> within six months of receipt by the agency, all final Animal Welfare Act research facility annual reports, including their attachments with appropriate redactions made for confidential business information that USDA could withhold under FOIA Exemption 4.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idef6e901d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dB/tVII/s788">Pub. L. 116–94, div. B, title VII, § 788</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2657">133 Stat. 2657</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dA/tVII/s765">Pub. L. 117–103, div. A, title VII, § 765</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/98">136 Stat. 98</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idef6e901e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idef6e901f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idef6e9020-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Animal Welfare Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), (2), (4), is <ref href="/us/pl/89/544">Pub. L. 89–544</ref>, <date date="1966-08-24">Aug. 24, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/350">80 Stat. 350</ref>, which is classified generally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2131">section 2131 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Horse Protection Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/91/540">Pub. L. 91–540</ref>, <date date="1970-12-09">Dec. 9, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1404">84 Stat. 1404</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 44 (§ 1821 et seq.) of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s1821">section 1821 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idef6e9021-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2020, and also as part of the Further Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2020, and not as part of the Animal Welfare Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idef6e9022-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/117/103">Pub. L. 117–103</ref> amended subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (b) read as follows: “hereafter, make publicly available via searchable database, in their entirety without redactions except signatures, the following records after enactment of this Act for a subsequent period of three years:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) all final Animal Welfare Act inspection reports, including all reports documenting all Animal Welfare Act non-compliances observed by USDA officials and all animal inventories;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) all final Animal Welfare Act and Horse Protection Act enforcement records;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(3) all reports or other materials documenting any non-compliances observed by USDA officials; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(4) within six months of receipt by the agency, all final Animal Welfare Act research facility annual reports, including their attachments with appropriate redactions made for confidential business information that USDA could withhold under FOIA Exemption 4.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
