<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idef75bcb2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2207c"><num value="2207c">§ 2207c.</num><heading> Annual report on work of agricultural experiment stations and of college extension work; publication and distribution</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There shall be prepared by the Department of Agriculture an annual report on the work and expenditures of the agricultural experiment stations established under the Act of Congress of March second, eighteen hundred and eighty-seven [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s361a">7 U.S.C. 361a</ref> et seq.], on the work and expenditures of the Department of Agriculture in connection therewith, and on the cooperative agricultural extension work and expenditures of the Department of Agriculture and of agricultural colleges under the Act of May eighth, nineteen hundred and fourteen [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s341">7 U.S.C. 341</ref> et seq.], and there shall be printed annually eight thousand copies of said report, of which one thousand copies shall be for the use of the Senate, two thousand copies for the use of the House of Representatives, and five thousand copies for the use of the Department of Agriculture.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idef75bcb3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1915-03-04/ch144">Mar. 4, 1915, ch. 144</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/1110">38 Stat. 1110</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idef75bcb4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idef75bcb5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idef75bcb6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act of Congress of March second, eighteen hundred and eighty-seven, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1887-03-02/ch314">act Mar. 2, 1887, ch. 314</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/24/440">24 Stat. 440</ref>, known as the Hatch Act, which is classified generally to sections 361a to 361i of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s361a">section 361a of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act of May eighth, nineteen hundred and fourteen, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1914-05-08/ch79">act May 8, 1914, ch. 79</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/372">38 Stat. 372</ref>, known as the “Smith-Lever Act”, and also known as the “Agricultural Work Extension Act”, which is classified generally to subchapter IV (§ 341 et seq.) of chapter 13 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s341">section 341 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idef75bcb7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s418">section 418 of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idef75bcb8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idef75bcb9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of all officers, agencies, and employees of Department of Agriculture transferred, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of Agriculture by 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 1, eff. <date date="1953-06-04">June 4, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 3219, <ref href="/us/stat/67/633">67 Stat. 633</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2201">section 2201 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
