<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idef780692-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2225c"><num value="2225c">§ 2225c.</num><heading> Employment contracts for services abroad</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">On and after <date date="2000-10-28">October 28, 2000</date>, funds appropriated to the Department of Agriculture may be used to employ individuals by contract for services outside the United States as determined by the agencies to be necessary or appropriate for carrying out programs and activities abroad; and such contracts are authorized to be negotiated, the terms of the contract to be prescribed, and the work to be performed, where necessary, without regard to such statutory provisions as relate to the negotiation, making and performance of contracts and performance of work in the United States. Individuals employed by contract to perform such services outside the United States shall not by virtue of such employment be considered to be employees of the United States Government for purposes of any law administered by the Office of Personnel Management. Such individuals may be considered employees within the meaning of the Federal Employee Compensation Act, <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8101">5 U.S.C. 8101</ref> et seq. Further, that <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002255">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002255"><num>1</num> So in original.</note> Government service credit shall be accrued for the time employed under a Personal Service Agreement (PSA) should the individual later be hired into a permanent United States Government position within FAS or another United States Government agency if the authorities of the hiring agency so permit.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idef780693-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/106/387/s1/a/tVII/s740">Pub. L. 106–387, § 1(a) [title VII, § 740]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1549">114 Stat. 1549</ref>, 1549A–34.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idef780694-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idef780695-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idef780696-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Employee Compensation Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1916-09-07/ch458">act Sept. 7, 1916, ch. 458</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/742">39 Stat. 742</ref>, which was repealed and the provisions thereof were reenacted as subchapter I (§ 8101 et seq.) of chapter 81 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554">Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/378">80 Stat. 378</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idef780697-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idef780698-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Availability of Foreign Agricultural Service Funds</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101/k/tIV">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(k) [title IV]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1329-322">101 Stat. 1329–322</ref>, 1329–350, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dA/s101/a/tVII/s750">Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(a) [title VII, § 750]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681">112 Stat. 2681</ref>, 2681–32, provided in part: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/277/dA/s101/a/tVII/s750">“That funds available to the Foreign Agricultural Service under this and subsequent appropriations Acts shall be available to contract with individuals for services to be performed outside the United States as determined by the Service to be necessary or appropriate for carrying out programs and activities abroad. On or after <date date="1998-08-01">August 1, 1998</date> such individuals employed by contract to perform such services shall not, by virtue of such employment, be considered to be employees of the United States Government for purposes of any law administered by the Office of Personnel Management. Such individuals may be considered employees within the meaning of the Federal Employee Compensation Act, <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8101">5 U.S.C. 8101</ref> et seq.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
