<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idef7a776f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2250b"><num value="2250b">§ 2250b.</num><heading> Nonrecurring expenses fund</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as the “Nonrecurring expenses fund” (the Fund): <i>Provided</i>, That unobligated balances of expired discretionary funds appropriated in this or any succeeding fiscal year from the General Fund of the Treasury to the Department of Agriculture (except the Forest Service) by this or any other Act may be transferred (not later than the end of the fifth fiscal year after the last fiscal year for which such funds are available for the purposes for which appropriated) into the Fund: <i>Provided further</i>, That amounts deposited in the Fund shall be available until expended, and in addition to such other funds as may be available for such purposes, for facilities infrastructure and information technology services.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002256">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002256"><num>1</num> So in original.</note> necessary for the operation of the Department of Agriculture, subject to approval by the Office of Management and Budget: <i> Provided further</i>, That amounts in the Fund may be obligated only after the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate are notified at least 15 days in advance of the planned use of funds.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idef7a7770-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/113/235/dA/tVII/s742">Pub. L. 113–235, div. A, title VII, § 742</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2170">128 Stat. 2170</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/42/dB/tVII/s779">Pub. L. 118–42, div. B, title VII, § 779</ref>, <date date="2024-03-09">Mar. 9, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/117">138 Stat. 117</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idef7a7771-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idef7a7772-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idef7a7773-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in text, is div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/113/235">Pub. L. 113–235</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2135">128 Stat. 2135</ref>, known as the Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2015. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idef7a7774-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/118/42">Pub. L. 118–42</ref>, which directed the amendment of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2250b">section 2250b of title 7</ref>, United States Code, was executed by making the amendment to <ref href="/us/pl/113/235/s742">section 742 of Pub. L. 113–235</ref>, which is classified to this section, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idef7a7775-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—<ref href="/us/pl/118/42">Pub. L. 118–42</ref> substituted “infrastructure and information technology services. necessary” for “infrastructure capital acquisition necessary”. See Codification note above.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
