<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idef7a777d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2252"><num value="2252">§ 2252.</num><heading> Reimbursement of Production and Marketing Administration appropriations for costs of procuring agricultural commodities for nongovernmental agencies or foreign governments</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Applicable appropriations available to the Production and Marketing Administration current at the time services are rendered or payment therefore is received may be reimbursed by nongovernmental agencies or foreign governments (by advance credits or reimbursements) for the actual or estimated costs, as determined by the Production and Marketing Administration, incident to procuring agricultural commodities for such nongovernmental agencies or foreign governments.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idef7a777e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-09-21/ch412">Sept. 21, 1944, ch. 412</ref>, title IV, § 402, <ref href="/us/stat/58/738">58 Stat. 738</ref>; Ex. Ord. No. 9577, <date date="1945-06-29">June 29, 1945</date>, 10 F.R. 4253.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idef7a777f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idef7a7780-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idef7a7781-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section was enacted as part of the Department of Agriculture Organic Act of 1944.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s569">section 569 of Title 5</ref> prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s1">Pub. L. 89–554, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/378">80 Stat. 378</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idef7a7782-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idef7a7783-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Production and Marketing Administration functions transferred to other units in Department of Agriculture under Secretary’s memorandum 1320, supp. 4, of <date date="1953-11-02">Nov. 2, 1953</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of all officers, agencies, and employees of Department of Agriculture transferred, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of Agriculture by 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 1, eff. <date date="1953-06-04">June 4, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 3219, <ref href="/us/stat/67/633">67 Stat. 633</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2201">section 2201 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">War Food Administration terminated by Ex. Ord. No. 9577, and all functions transferred to Secretary of Agriculture, who established Production and Marketing Administration, under authority of said Ex. Ord. No. 9577, to administer functions of many of marketing and production agencies, including those functions of former War Food Administration.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
