<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idee20b3bd-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s227"><num value="227">§ 227.</num><heading> Powers of Federal Trade Commission and Secretary of Agriculture</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee20b3be-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s227/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee20b3bf-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s227/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction of Federal Trade Commission</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Federal Trade Commission shall have power and jurisdiction over any matter involving meat, meat food products, livestock products in unmanufactured form, or poultry products, which by this chapter is made subject to the power or jurisdiction of the Secretary, as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee20b3c0-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s227/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> When the Secretary in the exercise of his duties requests of the Commission that it make investigations and reports in any case.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee20b3c1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s227/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In any investigation of, or proceeding for the prevention of, an alleged violation of any Act administered by the Commission, arising out of acts or transactions involving meat, meat food products, or livestock products in unmanufactured form, if the Commission determines that effective exercise of its power or jurisdiction with respect to retail sales of any such commodities is or will be impaired by the absence of power or jurisdiction over all acts or transactions involving such commodities in such investigation or proceeding. In order to avoid unnecessary duplication of effort by the Government and burdens upon the industry, the Commissioner shall notify the Secretary of such determination, the reasons therefor, and the acts or transactions involved, and shall not exercise power or jurisdiction with regard to acts or transactions (other than retail sales) involving such commodities if the Secretary within ten days from the date of receipt of the notice notifies the Commission that there is pending in his Department an investigation of, or proceeding for the prevention of, an alleged violation of this chapter involving the same subject matter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee20b3c2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s227/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Over all transactions in commerce in margarine, oleomargarine, or poultry products and over retail sales of meat, meat food products and livestock products in unmanufactured form.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee20b3c3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s227/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation of Federal Trade Commission jurisdiction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Federal Trade Commission shall have no power or jurisdiction over any matter which by this chapter is made subject to the jurisdiction of the Secretary, except as provided in subsection (b) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee20b3c4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s227/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction of Secretary of Agriculture except for poultry products</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall exercise power or jurisdiction over oleomargarine or retail sales of meat, meat food products, or livestock products in unmanufactured form only when he determines, in any investigation of, or any proceeding for the prevention of, an alleged violation of this chapter, that such action is necessary to avoid impairment of his power or jurisdiction over acts or transactions involving livestock, meat, meat food products, livestock products in unmanufactured form, or poultry other than retail sales thereof. In order to avoid unnecessary duplication of effort by the Government and burdens upon the industry, the Secretary shall notify the Federal Trade Commission of such determination, the reasons therefor, and the acts or transactions involved, and shall not exercise power or jurisdiction with respect to acts or transactions involving oleomargarine or retail sales of meat, meat food products, or livestock products in unmanufactured form if the Commission within 10 days from the date of receipt of such notice notifies the Secretary that there is pending in the Commission an investigation of, or proceeding for the prevention of, an alleged violation of any Act administered by the Commission involving the same subject matter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee20b3c5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s227/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction of Secretary of Agriculture regarding poultry products</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall exercise jurisdiction over poultry products only in a proceeding brought under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s197">section 197 of this title</ref> or <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s228b–1">section 228b–1 of this title</ref> when such action is necessary to avoid impairment of his jurisdiction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee20b3c6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s227/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Information to be included in annual reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture and the Federal Trade Commission shall include in their respective annual reports information with respect to the administration of subsections (b), (d), and (e) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idee20b3c7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1921-08-15/ch64">Aug. 15, 1921, ch. 64</ref>, title IV, § 406, <ref href="/us/stat/42/169">42 Stat. 169</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/909/s1/2">Pub. L. 85–909, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1749">72 Stat. 1749</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/173/s7">Pub. L. 100–173, § 7</ref>, <date date="1987-11-23">Nov. 23, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/919">101 Stat. 919</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/237/tX/s1008/2">Pub. L. 102–237, title X, § 1008(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1898">105 Stat. 1898</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idee20b3c8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idee20b3c9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idee20b3ca-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (a) of section 406 is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s226">section 226 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idee20b3cb-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/237">Pub. L. 102–237</ref> struck out comma after “unmanufactured form,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/173/s7/1/A/ii">Pub. L. 100–173, § 7(1)(A)(ii)</ref>, which directed insertion of “or” before “livestock products in unmanufactured form.” was executed by making insertion before “livestock products in unmanufactured form,” as the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/173/s7/1/A/i">Pub. L. 100–173, § 7(1)(A)(i)</ref>, struck out “or poultry products” after “in unmanufactured form,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/173/s7/1/B">Pub. L. 100–173, § 7(1)(B)</ref>, amended par. (3) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (3) read as follows: “Over all transactions in commerce in margarine or oleomargarine and over retail sales of meat, meat food products, livestock products in unmanufactured form, and poultry products.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/100/173/s7/2">Pub. L. 100–173, § 7(2)</ref>, amended subsec. (d) generally, striking out reference to poultry products in two places and substituting “10 days” for “ten days”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/100/173/s7/3">Pub. L. 100–173, § 7(3)</ref>, (4), added subsec. (e) and redesignated former subsec. (e) as (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/100/173/s7/3">Pub. L. 100–173, § 7(3)</ref>, (5), redesignated former subsec. (e) as (f) and substituted “subsections (b), (d), and (e)” for “subsections (b) and (d)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—<ref href="/us/pl/85/909">Pub. L. 85–909</ref> substituted subsecs. (b) to (e) for former provisions providing that Federal Trade Commission shall have no power or jurisdiction over matters within jurisdiction of Secretary of Agriculture except when Secretary requests Commission to make investigations and reports in any case, which were incorporated in subsecs. (b)(1) and (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idee20b3cc-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idee20b3cd-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1987 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/173">Pub. L. 100–173</ref> effective 90 days after <date date="1987-11-23">Nov. 23, 1987</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/173/s12">section 12 of Pub. L. 100–173</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s182">section 182 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idee20b3ce-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Construction of 1987 Amendments</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/173/s11">Pub. L. 100–173, § 11</ref>, <date date="1987-11-23">Nov. 23, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/922">101 Stat. 922</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/173/s11">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">General Rule</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The amendments made by this Act [see Short Title of 1987 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s181">section 181 of this title</ref>] to the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921 [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s181">7 U.S.C. 181</ref> et seq.], shall not be construed to limit or otherwise affect the power or jurisdiction of the Federal Trade Commission under the Federal Trade Commission Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s41">15 U.S.C. 41</ref> et seq.] to prevent the use of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> unfair methods of competition in or affecting commerce, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> unfair and deceptive acts or practices in or affecting commerce,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">involving poultry products.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secretary’s Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>Subsection (a) shall not be construed to limit or otherwise affect the authority of the Secretary of Agriculture under section 406(e), as amended, of the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921 [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s227/e">7 U.S.C. 227(e)</ref>].”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idee20b3cf-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idee20b3d0-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive and administrative functions of Federal Trade Commission, with certain reservations, transferred to Chairman of such Commission by 1950 Reorg. Plan No. 8, § 1, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3175, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1264">64 Stat. 1264</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
