<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idef7f331c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2279i"><num value="2279i">§ 2279i.</num><heading> Cooperation with State and other agencies; expenditures</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying on the activities of the Department of Agriculture involving cooperation with State, county, and municipal agencies, associations of farmers, individual farmers, universities, colleges, boards of trade, chambers of commerce, or other local associations of business men, business organizations, and individuals within the State, Territory, district, or insular possession in which such activities are to be carried on, moneys contributed from such outside sources, except in the case of the authorized activities of the Forest Service, shall be paid only through the Secretary of Agriculture or through State, county, or municipal agencies, or local farm bureaus or like organizations, cooperating for the purpose with the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idef7f331d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1919-07-24/ch26">July 24, 1919, ch. 26</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/41/270">41 Stat. 270</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idef7f331e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idef7f331f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idef7f3320-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s450b">section 450b of this title</ref> prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section, and to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s563">section 563 of Title 5</ref> prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s1">Pub. L. 89–554, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/378">80 Stat. 378</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
