<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idef7f328d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2279a"><num value="2279a">§ 2279a.</num><heading> Fair and equitable treatment of socially disadvantaged producers</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef7f328e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2279a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Fair crop acreage bases and farm program payment yields</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Secretary of Agriculture determines that crop acreage bases or farm program payment yields established for farms owned or operated by socially disadvantaged producers are not established in accordance with title V of the Agricultural Act of 1949 (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1461">7 U.S.C. 1461</ref> et seq.), the Secretary shall adjust the bases and yields to conform to the requirements of such title and make available any appropriate commodity program benefits.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef7f328f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2279a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Fair application of Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Secretary of Agriculture determines that application of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1921">7 U.S.C. 1921</ref> et seq.) with respect to socially disadvantaged producers is not consistent with the requirements of such Act, the Secretary shall make such changes in the administration of such Act as the Secretary considers necessary to provide for the fair and equitable treatment of socially disadvantaged producers under such Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef7f3290-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2279a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Report on treatment of socially disadvantaged producers</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idef7f3291-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2279a/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Report required</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Comptroller General of the United States shall prepare a report to determine—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef7f3292-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2279a/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> whether socially disadvantaged producers are underrepresented on State, county, area, or local committees established under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s590h/b/5">section 590h(b)(5) of title 16</ref> or local review committees established under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1363">section 1363 of this title</ref> because of racial, ethnic, or gender prejudice; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef7f3293-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2279a/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if such underrepresentation exists, whether it inhibits or interferes with the participation of socially disadvantaged producers in programs of the Department of Agriculture.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idef7f3294-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2279a/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission of report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than <date date="1995-02-01">February 1, 1995</date>, the Comptroller General shall submit the report required by this subsection to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef7f3295-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2279a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> “Socially disadvantaged producer” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “socially disadvantaged producer” means a producer who is a member of a group whose members have been subjected to racial, ethnic, or gender prejudice because of their identity as members of a group without regard to their individual qualities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idef7f3296-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/354/tIII/s305">Pub. L. 103–354, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3240">108 Stat. 3240</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idef7f3297-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idef7f3298-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idef7f3299-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Agricultural Act of 1949, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1949-10-31/ch792">act Oct. 31, 1949, ch. 792</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/1051">63 Stat. 1051</ref>. Title V of the Act, which was classified generally to subchapter IV (§ 1461 et seq.) of chapter 35A of this title, was omitted from the Code. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1421">section 1421 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is title III of <ref href="/us/pl/87/128">Pub. L. 87–128</ref>, <date date="1961-08-08">Aug. 8, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/307">75 Stat. 307</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 50 (§ 1921 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1921">section 1921 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
