<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idef81a3a3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2303"><num value="2303">§ 2303.</num><heading> Prohibited practices</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any handler knowingly to engage or permit any employee or agent to engage in the following practices:</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef81a3a4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2303/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> To coerce any producer in the exercise of his right to join and belong to or to refrain from joining or belonging to an association of producers, or to refuse to deal with any producer because of the exercise of his right to join and belong to such an association; or</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef81a3a5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2303/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> To discriminate against any producer with respect to price, quantity, quality, or other terms of purchase, acquisition, or other handling of agricultural products because of his membership in or contract with an association of producers; or</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef81a3a6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2303/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> To coerce or intimidate any producer to enter into, maintain, breach, cancel, or terminate a membership agreement or marketing contract with an association of producers or a contract with a handler; or</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef81a3a7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2303/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> To pay or loan money, give any thing of value, or offer any other inducement or reward to a producer for refusing to or ceasing to belong to an association of producers; or</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef81a3a8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2303/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> To make false reports about the finances, management, or activities of associations of producers or handlers; or</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idef81a3a9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2303/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> To conspire, combine, agree, or arrange with any other person to do, or aid or abet the doing of, any act made unlawful by this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idef81a3aa-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/288/s4">Pub. L. 90–288, § 4</ref>, <date date="1968-04-16">Apr. 16, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/94">82 Stat. 94</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
