<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idef865eae-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2613"><num value="2613">§ 2613.</num><heading> Authority for issuance and amendment of plan</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To effectuate the declared policy of this chapter, the Secretary shall, subject to the provisions of this chapter, issue and from time to time amend, orders applicable to handlers and importers and shall have authority to issue orders authorizing the collection of assessments on potatoes handled or imported under the provisions of this chapter, and to authorize the use of such funds to provide research, development, advertising, and promotion of potatoes in a manner prescribed in this chapter. Any order issued by the Secretary under this chapter shall hereinafter in this chapter be referred to as a “plan”. Any such plan shall be applicable to potatoes produced in the 50 States of the United States and in foreign countries, if importers are subject to a plan and such potatoes are imported into the United States.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idef865eaf-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/670/tIII/s304">Pub. L. 91–670, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1971-01-11">Jan. 11, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/2042">84 Stat. 2042</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/tXIX/s1938">Pub. L. 101–624, title XIX, § 1938</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3866">104 Stat. 3866</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idef865eb0-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idef865eb1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idef865eb2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—<ref href="/us/pl/101/624">Pub. L. 101–624</ref> substituted “handlers and importers” for “persons engaged in the handling of potatoes (hereinafter referred to as handlers)”, inserted “or imported”, substituted “50” for “forty-eight contiguous”, and inserted before period at end “and in foreign countries, if importers are subject to a plan and such potatoes are imported into the United States”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
