<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idef88cf01-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2623"><num value="2623">§ 2623.</num><heading> Referendum</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cf02-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2623/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretary’s duty to conduct; purpose of referendum</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall conduct a referendum among producers, who during a representative period determined by the Secretary have been engaged in the production of potatoes, for the purpose of ascertaining whether the issuance of a plan is approved or favored by such producers. When the issuance of a plan would subject importers to the terms and conditions of a plan, the Secretary also shall conduct the referendum among importers, who during a representative period determined by the Secretary have been engaged in the importation of potatoes, for the purpose of ascertaining whether the issuance of such plan is approved or favored by such importers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cf03-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2623/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Required margin of approval</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No plan issued under this chapter shall be effective unless the Secretary determines that the issuance of such plan is approved or favored by not less than a majority of the producers voting in such referendum or a majority of the producers and importers when the issuance of a plan would subject importers to the terms and conditions of a plan, voting in such referendum.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cf04-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2623/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Amendments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The failure of potato producers and importers to approve an amendment to any plan issued under this chapter shall not be deemed to invalidate such plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cf05-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2623/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Penalties for disclosure of confidential information, ballots and reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The ballots and other information or reports which reveal or tend to reveal the vote of any producer or his production of potatoes, or any importer or the volume of potatoes imported by such importer, shall be held strictly confidential and shall not be disclosed. Any officer or employee of the Department of Agriculture violating the provisions hereof shall upon conviction be subject to the penalties provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2619/c">section 2619(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idef88cf06-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/670/tIII/s314">Pub. L. 91–670, title III, § 314</ref>, <date date="1971-01-11">Jan. 11, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/2046">84 Stat. 2046</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/244/s4">Pub. L. 97–244, § 4</ref>, <date date="1982-08-26">Aug. 26, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/311">96 Stat. 311</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/tXIX/s1944">Pub. L. 101–624, title XIX, § 1944</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3868">104 Stat. 3868</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idef88cf07-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idef88cf08-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idef88cf09-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s1944/1">Pub. L. 101–624, § 1944(1)</ref>, inserted at end “When the issuance of a plan would subject importers to the terms and conditions of a plan, the Secretary also shall conduct the referendum among importers, who during a representative period determined by the Secretary have been engaged in the importation of potatoes, for the purpose of ascertaining whether the issuance of such plan is approved or favored by such importers.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s1944/2">Pub. L. 101–624, § 1944(2)</ref>, substituted “a majority of the producers voting in such referendum or a majority of the producers and importers when the issuance of a plan would subject importers to the terms and conditions of a plan, voting in such referendum” for “two-thirds of the producers voting in such referendum, or by the producers of not less than two-thirds of the potatoes produced during the representative period by producers voting in such referendum, and by not less than a majority of the producers voting in such referendum”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s1944/3">Pub. L. 101–624, § 1944(3)</ref>, inserted “and importers” after “producers”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s1944/4">Pub. L. 101–624, § 1944(4)</ref>, inserted “, or any importer or the volume of potatoes imported by such importer,” after “potatoes”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—<ref href="/us/pl/97/244">Pub. L. 97–244</ref> designated existing provisions as subsecs. (a), (b) and (d), in subsec. (a), as so redesignated, inserted commas after “referendum among producers” and “production of potatoes”, struck out commas after “who” and “determined by the Secretary”, and substituted “by such producers” for “by producers”, in subsec. (b), as so redesignated, substituted “under this chapter” for “pursuant to this chapter”, and added subsec. (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idef88cf0a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idef88cf0b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Construction of 1982 Referendum on Amendments to Plan</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/171/s2/b">Pub. L. 98–171, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1983-11-29">Nov. 29, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1118">97 Stat. 1118</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/171/s2/b">“The failure of potato producers in December 1982 to approve amendments to the plan issued under this title [probably means title III of <ref href="/us/pl/91/670">Pub. L. 91–670</ref> which is classified to this chapter] shall not be deemed to invalidate the plan.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
