<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idef88cf15-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2625"><num value="2625">§ 2625.</num><heading> Amendment procedure</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of this chapter applicable to plans shall be applicable to amendments to plans.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idef88cf16-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/670/tIII/s316">Pub. L. 91–670, title III, § 316</ref>, <date date="1971-01-11">Jan. 11, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/2047">84 Stat. 2047</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idef88cf17-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idef88cf18-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idef88cf19-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendment Procedure</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/624/tXIX/s1946">Pub. L. 101–624, title XIX, § 1946</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3869">104 Stat. 3869</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/624/tXIX/s1946">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding any provision of the Potato Research and Promotion Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2611">7 U.S.C. 2611</ref> et seq.] (hereafter in this section referred to as the ‘Act’), the procedure specified in this section shall apply if a producer or a producer organization requests the Secretary of Agriculture (hereafter in this section referred to as the ‘Secretary’) to amend the plan in effect under that Act (hereafter in this section referred to as the ‘plan’) to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> subject importers to the terms and conditions of a plan, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> eliminate provisions for refunds of assessments for those not in favor of supporting the research and promotion program as provided under that Act.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The procedure under this section shall apply only in the case of the first such request received after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>].</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Publication of Proposed Amendments</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall publish for public comment such proposed amendments to the plan within 60 days.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Issuance of Final Amendments</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 150 days after publication of such amendment, and after notice and opportunity for public comment, the Secretary shall issue the amendments to the plan, as described in subsection (a), if the Secretary has reason to believe that such amendments will tend to effectuate the declared policy of this subtitle [see Short Title of 1990 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2611">section 2611 of this title</ref>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Referendum</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 24 months after the date of issuance of such amendments to the plan, the Secretary shall conduct a referendum among producers and importers who, during a representative period determined by the Secretary, have been engaged in the production or importation of potatoes. The amendments shall be continued only if the Secretary determines that the amendments to the plan have been approved by a majority of the total number of producers and importers voting in the referendum.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Refunds</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The board shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> establish an escrow account to be used for assessment refunds, and place funds in such account in accordance with paragraph (2) during the period beginning on the effective date of the amendments to the plan issued under subsection (c) and ending on the date of the referendum on the amendments to the plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> place in the account established under paragraph (1), from assessments collected under the plan during the period referred to in paragraph (1), an amount equal to the product obtained by multiplying the total amount of assessments collected during such period by 10 percent;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> subject to paragraphs (4), (5), and (6), provide that for the period referred to in paragraph (1) any producer or importer shall have the right to demand and receive from the board a one-time refund of assessments collected from such producer or importer during such period if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> such producer or importer is responsible for paying such assessments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> such producer or importer does not support the program established under the plan; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the amendments to the plan to eliminate provisions for refunds of assessments are not approved pursuant to a referendum conducted under subsection (d);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> require such demand to be made in accordance with regulations, on a form, and within a time period prescribed by the board;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> require such refund to be made on submission of proof satisfactory to the board that such producer or importer paid the assessment for which refund is demanded; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> if the amount in the escrow account required to be established by paragraph (1) is not sufficient to refund the total amount of assessments demanded by all eligible producers and importers under this subsection, prorate the amount of such refunds among all eligible producers and importers who demand such refund.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading><content>If such amendments to the plan are not approved, the Secretary shall terminate the amendments and the plan shall continue in effect without the amendments.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Amendment to Include the</inline> 50 <inline class="small-caps">States</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding any provision of the Act, the Secretary shall, upon request of a producer or a producer organization, issue an amendment to the plan to include the 50 States of the United States. Such amendment shall not be subject to a referendum.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
