<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idef88cf78-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662"><num value="2662">§ 2662.</num><heading> Programs authorized</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture (referred to in this subchapter as the “Secretary”) may conduct, in cooperation and coordination with colleges and universities, the following programs to carry out the purposes and achieve the goals of this subchapter.</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cf79-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Rural development extension programs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Rural development extension programs shall consist of the collection, interpretation, and dissemination of useful information and knowledge from research and other sources to units of multistate regional agencies, State, county, municipal, and other units of government, multicounty planning and development districts, organizations of citizens contributing to community and rural development, businesses, Indian tribes on Federal or State reservations or other federally recognized Indian tribal groups, and industries that employ or may employ people in rural areas. The rural development extension programs shall also promote coordinated and integrated rural community initiatives that advance and empower capacity building through leadership development, entrepreneurship, business development and management training, and strategic planning to increase jobs, income, and quality of life in rural communities. These programs also shall include technical services and educational activities, including instruction for persons not enrolled as students in colleges or universities, to facilitate and encourage the use and practical application of this information. These programs may also include feasibility studies and planning assistance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cf7a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Rural development research</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Rural development research shall consist of research, investigations, and basic feasibility studies in any field or discipline that may develop principles, facts, scientific and technical knowledge, new technology, and other information that may be useful to agencies of Federal, State, and local government, industries in rural areas, Indian tribes on Federal and State reservations or other federally recognized Indian tribal groups, and other organizations involved in community and rural development programs and activities in planning and carrying out such programs and activities or otherwise be practical and useful in achieving the purposes and goals of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cf7b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Small farm research programs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Small farm research programs shall consist of programs of research to develop new approaches for initiating and upgrading small farm operations through management techniques, agricultural production techniques, farm machinery technology, new products, new marketing techniques, and small farm finance; to develop new enterprises that can use labor, skills, or natural resources available to the small farm family; or that will help to increase the quality and availability of services and facilities needed by the small farm family.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cf7c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Small farm extension programs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Small farm extension programs shall consist of extension programs to improve small farm operations, including management techniques, agricultural production techniques, farm machinery technology, marketing techniques and small farm finance; to increase use by small farm families of existing services offered by the Department of Agriculture and other public and private agencies and organizations; to assist small farm families in establishing and operating cooperatives for the purpose of improving their family income from farming or other economic activities; to increase the quality and availability of services and facilities needed by small farm families; and to develop new enterprises that can use labor, skills, or natural resources available to the small farm family.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cf7d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Special grants programs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Special grants programs shall consist of extension and research programs to strengthen research and education on national and regional issues in rural development, including the assessment of alternative policies and strategies for rural development and balanced growth; to develop alternative strategies for national and regional investment, and the creation of employment, in rural areas; to develop alternative energy policies to meet rural development needs; and to strengthen rural development programs of agencies of the Department of Agriculture and those in other Federal departments and agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cf7e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold">, (g) Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/tVII/s792/a">Pub. L. 104–127, title VII, § 792(a)</ref>, title VIII, § 871, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1152">110 Stat. 1152</ref>, 1175</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cf7f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Rural development extension work</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cf80-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> National program</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish a national program, to be administered by the National Institute of Food and Agriculture, to provide rural citizens with training in, technical and management assistance regarding, and educational opportunities to enhance their knowledge of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef88cf81-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> beginning businesses through entrepreneurship;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef88cf82-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the procedures necessary to establish new businesses in rural areas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef88cf83-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> self-employment opportunities in rural areas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef88cf84-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the uses of modern telecommunications and computer technologies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef88cf85-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> business and financial planning; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef88cf86-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> such other training, assistance, and educational opportunities as the Secretary determines are necessary to carry out the program established under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cf87-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Leadership abilities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The program established under this subsection shall provide assistance designed to increase the leadership abilities of residents in rural areas. Such assistance shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef88cf88-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> information relevant to the development of community goals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef88cf89-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> instruction regarding the methods by which State or Federal funding for rural development projects might be obtained;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef88cf8a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> instruction regarding the successful writing of applications for loan or grant funds from government and private sources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef88cf8b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> an updated listing of State, Federal, and other economic development programs available to rural areas; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef88cf8c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> such other training, information, and assistance as the Secretary determines necessary to increase the leadership abilities of residents in rural areas.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cf8d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Catalog of programs</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The National Rural Information Center Clearinghouse of the National Agricultural Library, in cooperation with the Extension Service in each State, should develop, maintain, and provide to each community, and make accessible to any other interested party, a catalog of available State, Federal, or private programs that provide leadership training or other information or services similar or complementary to the training or services required by this subsection. Such catalog should include, at a minimum, the following entities within the State that provide such training or services:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef88cf8e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Any rural electric cooperative.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef88cf8f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any nonprofit company development corporation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef88cf90-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Any economic development district that serves a rural community.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef88cf91-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Any nonprofit subsidiary of any private entity.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef88cf92-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Any nonprofit organization whose principal purpose is to promote economic development in rural areas.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef88cf93-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/3/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> Any investor or publicly owned electric utility.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef88cf94-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/3/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> Any small business development center or small business investment company.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef88cf95-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/3/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> Any regional development organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef88cf96-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/3/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> Any vocational or technical school.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef88cf97-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/3/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><content> Any Federal, State, or local government agency or department.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idef88cf98-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/3/K"><num value="K">(K)</num><content> Any other entity that the Secretary deems appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">The extension service in each State should include in the catalog information on the specific training or services provided by each entity in the catalog.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cf99-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Employee training</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall provide training for appropriate State extension service employees, assigned to programs other than rural development, to ensure that such employees understand the availability of rural development programs in their respective States and the availability of National Institute of Food and Agriculture staff qualified to provide to rural citizens and to State extension staff training and materials for technical, management, and educational assistance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cf9a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/h/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination of assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall ensure, to the extent practicable, that assistance provided under this subsection is coordinated with and delivered in cooperation with similar services or assistance provided by other Federal agencies or programs for rural residents.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cf9b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Rural health and safety education programs</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cf9c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Programs authorized</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cf9d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Individual and family health education</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary may make grants for the establishment of individual and family health education programs that shall provide individuals and families with—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idef88cf9e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> information concerning the value of good health;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idef88cf9f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> information to increase the individual or families motivation to take more responsibility for their own health;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idef88cfa0-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> access to health promotion activities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idef88cfa1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i/1/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> training for volunteers and health services providers concerning health promotion and health care services, in cooperation with the Department of Health and Human Services.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cfa2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Farm safety education</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary may make grants for the establishment of farm safety education programs that shall provide information and training to farm workers, timber harvesters, and farm families concerning safety in the work place, including information and training concerning—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idef88cfa3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the reduction of occupational injury and death rates;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idef88cfa4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the reduction and prevention of exposure to farm chemicals;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idef88cfa5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the reduction of agricultural respiratory diseases and dermititis; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002264">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002264"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “dermatitis;”.</note></content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idef88cfa6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i/1/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the reduction and prevention of noise induced hearing loss;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idef88cfa7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i/1/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> the occupational rehabilitation of farmers and timber harvesters with physical disabilities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idef88cfa8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i/1/B/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> farm accident rescue procedures.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cfa9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i/1/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Rural health leadership development</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary, in consultation with the Office of Rural Health Policy of the Department of Health and Human Services, may make grants to academic medical centers or land grant colleges and universities, or any combination thereof, for the establishment of rural health leadership development education programs that shall assist rural communities in developing health care services and facilities that will provide the maximum benefit for the resources invested and assist community leaders and public officials in understanding their roles and responsibilities relative to rural health services and facilities, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idef88cfaa-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> community decisions regarding funding for and retention of rural hospitals;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idef88cfab-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> rural physician and allied health professionals recruitment and retention;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idef88cfac-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i/1/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the aging rural population and senior services required to care for the population;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idef88cfad-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i/1/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the establishment and maintenance of rural emergency medical services systems; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idef88cfae-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i/1/C/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> the application of computer-assisted capital budgeting decision aids for rural health services and facilities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cfaf-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination of programs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Educational programs conducted with grants awarded under this subsection shall be coordinated with the State offices of rural health and other appropriate programs of the Department of Health and Human Services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cfb0-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Dissemination of information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Educational programs conducted with grants awarded under this subsection shall provide leadership within the State for the dissemination of appropriate rural health and safety information resources possessed by the Rural Information Center established at the National Agricultural Library.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cfb1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedures and limitations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish policies, procedures and limitations that shall apply to States or entities described in paragraph (1)(C) that desire to receive a grant under this subsection. In States with land-grant colleges and universities that are eligible to receive funds under the Act of <date date="1862-07-02">July 2, 1862</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s301">7 U.S.C. 301</ref> et seq.), and the Act of <date date="1890-08-30">August 30, 1890</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s321">7 U.S.C. 321</ref> et seq.), including Tuskegee University, and universities which receive Rural Health Research Center grants, such eligible institutions shall mutually determine the type of rural health and safety education program needed in the State within which such institutions reside.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idef88cfb2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2662/i/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations on authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For grants under this subsection, there are authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for fiscal year 1991, $10,000,000 for fiscal year 1992, $15,000,000 for fiscal year 1993, and $20,000,000 for fiscal year 1994 and each subsequent fiscal year. Amounts appropriated under this subsection shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idef88cfb3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/419/tV/s502">Pub. L. 92–419, title V, § 502</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/tXIV/s1444/a">Pub. L. 97–98, title XIV, § 1444(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1323">95 Stat. 1323</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/99/198/tXIV/s1440/a">Pub. L. 99–198, title XIV, § 1440(a)</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1560">99 Stat. 1560</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/219/s2">Pub. L. 100–219, § 2</ref>, <date date="1987-12-29">Dec. 29, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1456">101 Stat. 1456</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/tXXIII">Pub. L. 101–624, title XXIII</ref>, §§ 2346, 2349, 2389(a)–(c)(1), 2390(b)(1), <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4032">104 Stat. 4032</ref>, 4037, 4053–4055; <ref href="/us/pl/102/237/tIV/s403/a">Pub. L. 102–237, title IV, § 403(a)</ref>, title VII, § 704, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1863">105 Stat. 1863</ref>, 1881; <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/tVII/s792/a">Pub. L. 104–127, title VII, § 792(a)</ref>, title VIII, §§ 871, 886, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1152">110 Stat. 1152</ref>, 1175, 1180; <ref href="/us/pl/110/234/tVII/s7511/c/6">Pub. L. 110–234, title VII, § 7511(c)(6)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1267">122 Stat. 1267</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VII, § 7511(c)(6), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1664">122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2029; <ref href="/us/pl/115/334/tVI/s6101/a/3">Pub. L. 115–334, title VI, § 6101(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4727">132 Stat. 4727</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idef88cfb4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idef88cfb5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idef88cfb6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1862-07-02">July 2, 1862</date>, referred to in subsec. (i)(4), is <ref href="/us/act/1862-07-02/ch130">act July 2, 1862, ch. 130</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/12/503">12 Stat. 503</ref>, popularly known as the “Morrill Act” and also as the “First Morrill Act”, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 301 et seq.) of chapter 13 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s301">section 301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1890-08-30">August 30, 1890</date>, referred to in subsec. (i)(4), is <ref href="/us/act/1890-08-30/ch841">act Aug. 30, 1890, ch. 841</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/26/417">26 Stat. 417</ref>, as amended, popularly known as the “Agricultural College Act of 1890” and also as the “Second Morrill Act”, which is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 321 et seq.) of chapter 13 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s321">section 321 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idef88cfb7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> made identical amendments to this section. The amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> were repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idef88cfb8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 2662, <ref href="/us/pl/92/419/tV/s502">Pub. L. 92–419, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="1972-08-30">Aug. 30, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/671">86 Stat. 671</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/113/tXIV/s1440">Pub. L. 95–113, title XIV, § 1440</ref>, <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1005">91 Stat. 1005</ref>, related to programs authorization and cooperation and coordination with colleges and universities, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/tXIV/s1444/a">Pub. L. 97–98, title XIV, § 1444(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1326">95 Stat. 1326</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idef88cfb9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—<ref href="/us/pl/115/334/s6101/a/3/A">Pub. L. 115–334, § 6101(a)(3)(A)</ref>, inserted “(referred to in this subchapter as the ‘Secretary’)” after “Agriculture” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/115/334/s6101/a/3/B">Pub. L. 115–334, § 6101(a)(3)(B)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” for “Secretary of Agriculture” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (h)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s7511/c/6/A">Pub. L. 110–246, § 7511(c)(6)(A)</ref>, substituted “National Institute of Food and Agriculture” for “Extension Service” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s7511/c/6/B">Pub. L. 110–246, § 7511(c)(6)(B)</ref>, substituted “National Institute of Food and Agriculture staff” for “Extension Service staff”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s886">Pub. L. 104–127, § 886</ref>, inserted after first sentence “The rural development extension programs shall also promote coordinated and integrated rural community initiatives that advance and empower capacity building through leadership development, entrepreneurship, business development and management training, and strategic planning to increase jobs, income, and quality of life in rural communities.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s792/a">Pub. L. 104–127, § 792(a)</ref>, struck out subsec. (f), which related to competitive grants for financially stressed farmers, dislocated farmers, and rural families.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s871">Pub. L. 104–127, § 871</ref>, struck out subsec. (g), which authorized establishment of Extension Service rural economic and business development program to enable States or counties to employ specialists as Cooperative Extension Service staff to assist individuals in creating new businesses, or to assist existing businesses.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s871">Pub. L. 104–127, § 871</ref>, struck out subsec. (j), which authorized program to award competitive grants to carry out rural development research.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/237/s403/a/2/A">Pub. L. 102–237, § 403(a)(2)(A)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (b), relating to rural development extension work, as (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/102/237/s403/a/1">Pub. L. 102–237, § 403(a)(1)</ref>, amended heading generally and in par. (2) substituted “until” for “during the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and ending on”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/102/237/s403/a/2">Pub. L. 102–237, § 403(a)(2)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (b), relating to rural development extension work, as (h), redesignated former subsec. (h), relating to rural health and safety education programs, as (i) and former subsec. (h), relating to research grants, as (j), and moved such subsecs. to appear in proper order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/102/237/s403/a/2/B">Pub. L. 102–237, § 403(a)(2)(B)</ref>, (D), redesignated subsec. (h), relating to rural health and safety education programs, as (i) and moved such subsec. to appear in proper order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/102/237/s704/a">Pub. L. 102–237, § 704(a)</ref>, added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/102/237/s704/b">Pub. L. 102–237, § 704(b)</ref>, inserted “or entities described in paragraph (1)(C)” after “to States”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/102/237/s403/a/2/C">Pub. L. 102–237, § 403(a)(2)(C)</ref>, (D), redesignated subsec. (h), relating to research grants, as (j) and moved such subsec. to appear in proper order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s2346">Pub. L. 101–624, § 2346</ref>, added subsec. (b), relating to rural development extension work, following subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s2389/c/1">Pub. L. 101–624, § 2389(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “Competitive” for “Special” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s2389/b/1">Pub. L. 101–624, § 2389(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “competitive grants for programs that meet the criteria specified in subparagraph (B) to develop counseling, retraining, and educational” for “special grants for programs to develop educational, retraining, and counseling”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s2389/b/3">Pub. L. 101–624, § 2389(b)(3)</ref>, (4), added subpar. (B), struck out heading, introductory provisions, and cl. (i) of former subpar. (B), and redesignated cls. (ii) to (viii) of former subpar. (B) as cls. (i) to (vii) of subpar. (D). Prior to amendment, introductory provisions and cl. (i) read as follows: “Such programs shall provide the following services:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) Clinical outreach counseling and crisis management assistance through appropriate State officials.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s2389/b/2">Pub. L. 101–624, § 2389(b)(2)</ref>, (4), added subpar. (C) and redesignated former subpar. (C) as (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s2389/b/2">Pub. L. 101–624, § 2389(b)(2)</ref>, (4), added heading and introductory provisions of subpar. (D) and redesignated former subpar. (D) as (F).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1)(D)(i) to (vii). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s2389/b/3/B">Pub. L. 101–624, § 2389(b)(3)(B)</ref>, redesignated former subpar. (B)(ii) to (viii) as subpar. (D)(i) to (vii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1)(D)(viii). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s2389/b/5">Pub. L. 101–624, § 2389(b)(5)</ref>, added cl. (viii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s2389/b/2">Pub. L. 101–624, § 2389(b)(2)</ref>, redesignated former subpar. (C) as (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s2389/b/6">Pub. L. 101–624, § 2389(b)(6)</ref>, substituted “shall work with the appropriate State office of rural health, State department or agency of mental health, and other” for “is encouraged to work with” and “an annual comprehensive plan” for “a comprehensive plan”, struck out “special” before “grant funds”, and inserted at end “For recipients in a State to be eligible for a grant under this subsection in any fiscal year, the Cooperative Extension Service within the State must develop and sign a Memorandum of Agreement with the appropriate State department or agency of mental health and other State agencies as may be appropriate to carry out the comprehensive plan. Such agreement and plan must emphasize the development and delivery of counseling and outreach programs as provided under subparagraph (B).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s2389/b/2">Pub. L. 101–624, § 2389(b)(2)</ref>, redesignated former subpar. (D) as (F).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s2389/a">Pub. L. 101–624, § 2389(a)</ref>, inserted “to eligible applicants in any State applying for such grants” after “under paragraph (1)”, and substituted “1995” for “1990”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s2346">Pub. L. 101–624, § 2346</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s2349">Pub. L. 101–624, § 2349</ref>, added subsec. (h) relating to research grants.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s2390/b/1">Pub. L. 101–624, § 2390(b)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (h) relating to rural health and safety education programs.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/100/219">Pub. L. 100–219</ref> amended subsec. (f) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (f) read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(1)(A) The Secretary shall provide special grants for programs to develop income alternatives for farmers who have been adversely affected by the current farm and rural economic crisis and those displaced from farming.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) Such programs shall consist of educational and counseling services to farmers to—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) assess human and nonhuman resources;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) assess income earning alternatives;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(iii) identify resources and opportunities available to the farmer in the local community, county, and State;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(iv) implement financial planning and management strategies; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(v) provide linkages to specific resources and opportunities that are available to the farmer, such as reentering agriculture, new business opportunities, other off-farm jobs, job search programs, and retraining skills.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(C) The Secretary also may provide support to mental health officials in developing outreach programs in rural areas.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2) Grants may be made under paragraph (1) during the period beginning on <date date="1985-12-23">December 23, 1985</date>, and ending 3 years after such date.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/99/198">Pub. L. 99–198</ref> added subsec. (f).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idef88cfba-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idef88cfbb-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment of this section and repeal of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> effective <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8701">section 8701 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s7511/c/6">section 7511(c)(6) of Pub. L. 110–246</ref> effective <date date="2009-10-01">Oct. 1, 2009</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s7511/c">section 7511(c) of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1522">section 1522 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idef88cfbc-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/s1801">section 1801 of Pub. L. 97–98</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s4301">section 4301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idef88cfbd-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effect of Amendments on Current Grant Recipients</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/624/tXXIII/s2389/d">Pub. L. 101–624, title XXIII, § 2389(d)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4055">104 Stat. 4055</ref>, provided that 8 States receiving grants under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2662/f">7 U.S.C. 2662(f)</ref> during fiscal year 1990 could continue to be eligible to receive grants (in an amount not to exceed the amount received during that fiscal year) under that section notwithstanding that such grants be awarded competitively, so long as such States complied with requirement that not less than one-half of such grant amount was to be used for clinical outreach counseling and crisis management assistance, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/tVII/s792/b/1">Pub. L. 104–127, title VII, § 792(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1152">100 Stat. 1152</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idef88cfbe-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Rural Health Infrastructure Improvement</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/624/tXXIII/s2391">Pub. L. 101–624, title XXIII, § 2391</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4057">104 Stat. 4057</ref>, provided for award of grant for establishment of project to demonstrate model approach to improving rural health infrastructure, which was to carry out systematic, community-based rural health needs assessments, identify and coordinate available health services resources, improve community infrastructure through health education and information and leadership development and training, and develop community generated health improvement strategies, and further provided for project implementation and limitations on authorization of appropriations, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/tVII/s709">Pub. L. 104–127, title VII, § 709</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1112">110 Stat. 1112</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
