<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idef8ffb67-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2906"><num value="2906">§ 2906.</num><heading> Requirement of referendum</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef8ffb68-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2906/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Continuation or termination of order</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of determining whether the initial order shall be continued, not later than 22 months after the issuance of the order (or any earlier date recommended by the Board), the Secretary shall conduct a referendum among persons who have been producers or importers during a representative period, as determined by the Secretary. The order shall be continued only if the Secretary determines that it has been approved by not less than a majority of the producers voting in the referendum who, during a representative period as determined by the Secretary, have been engaged in the production of cattle. If continuation of the order is not approved by a majority of those voting in the referendum, the Secretary shall terminate collection of assessments under the order within six months after the Secretary determines that continuation of the order is not favored by a majority voting in the referendum and shall terminate the order in an orderly manner as soon as practicable after such determination.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef8ffb69-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2906/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional referendum to determine suspension or termination of order</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After the initial referendum, the Secretary may conduct a referendum on the request of a representative group comprising 10 per centum or more of the number of cattle producers to determine whether cattle producers favor the termination or suspension of the order. The Secretary shall suspend or terminate collection of assessments under the order within six months after the Secretary determines that suspension or termination of the order is favored by a majority of the producers voting in the referendum who, during a representative period as determined by the Secretary, have been engaged in the production of cattle and shall terminate or suspend the order in an orderly manner as soon as practicable after such determination.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef8ffb6a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s2906/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Reimbursement for cost of referendum; time and place of referendum; certification by producers; absentee mail ballot</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Department shall be reimbursed from assessments collected by the Board for any expenses incurred by the Department in connection with conducting any referendum under this section, except for the salaries of Government employees. Any referendum conducted under this section shall be conducted on a date established by the Secretary, whereby producers shall certify that they were engaged in the production of cattle during the representative period and, on the same day, shall be provided an opportunity to vote in the referendum. Each referendum shall be conducted at county extension offices, and there shall be provision for an absentee mail ballot on request.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idef8ffb6b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/294/s7">Pub. L. 94–294, § 7</ref>, <date date="1976-05-28">May 28, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/531">90 Stat. 531</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/198/tXVI/s1601/b">Pub. L. 99–198, title XVI, § 1601(b)</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1604">99 Stat. 1604</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idef8ffb6c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idef8ffb6d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idef8ffb6e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—<ref href="/us/pl/99/198">Pub. L. 99–198</ref> amended section generally, substituting provisions relating to requirement of referendum for provisions relating to permissive terms and conditions in orders.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idef8ffb6f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idef8ffb70-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1985 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/198">Pub. L. 99–198</ref> effective <date date="1986-01-01">Jan. 1, 1986</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/198/s1601/c">section 1601(c) of Pub. L. 99–198</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2901">section 2901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
