<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idef9be2c4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3173"><num value="3173">§ 3173.</num><heading> Research by Department of Agriculture</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef9be2c5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3173/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Increase in level of support</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish research into food and human nutrition as a separate and distinct mission of the Department of Agriculture, and the Secretary shall increase support for such research to a level that provides resources adequate to meet the policy of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idef9be2c6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3173/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Periodic consultation with administrators of other Federal departments and agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, in administering the food and human nutrition research program, shall periodically consult with the administrators of the other Federal departments and agencies that have responsibility for programs dealing with human food and nutrition, as to the specific research needs of those departments and agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idef9be2c7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/113/tXIV/s1423">Pub. L. 95–113, title XIV, § 1423</ref>, <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/999">91 Stat. 999</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idef9be2c8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idef9be2c9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idef9be2ca-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1977-10-01">Oct. 1, 1977</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/113/s1901">section 1901 of Pub. L. 95–113</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1977 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1307">section 1307 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idef9be2cb-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">National Food and Human Nutrition Research Program; Congressional Findings; Comprehensive Plan; Annual Report; Joint Dietary Assessment, Studies and Reports; Submission of Plan and Reports to Congressional Committees</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/198/tXIV">Pub. L. 99–198, title XIV</ref>, subtitle B, §§ 1451–1453, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1561">99 Stat. 1561</ref>, 1562, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/tVIII/s872">Pub. L. 104–127, title VIII, § 872</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1175">110 Stat. 1175</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/127/tVIII/s872">
<level style="-uslm-lc:I74"><heading class="centered small-caps">“findings</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="1451">“Sec. 1451.</num><chapeau> Congress finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> nutrition and health considerations are important to United States agricultural policy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> section 1405 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s3121">7 U.S.C. 3121</ref>) designates the Department of Agriculture as the lead agency of the Federal Government for human nutrition research (except with respect to the biomedical aspects of human nutrition concerned with diagnosis or treatment of disease);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> section 1423 of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s3173">7 U.S.C. 3173</ref>) requires the Secretary of Agriculture to establish research into food and human nutrition as a separate and distinct mission of the Department of Agriculture;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the Secretary has established a nutrition education program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> nutrition research continues to be of great importance to those involved in agricultural production.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21" status="repealed"><num value="1452">“[Sec. 1452.</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/tVIII/s872">Pub. L. 104–127, title VIII, § 872</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1175">110 Stat. 1175</ref>.]</content>
</section>
</level>
<level style="-uslm-lc:I74"><heading class="centered small-caps">“dietary assessment and studies</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="1453">“Sec. 1453.</num><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a"> (a)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall jointly conduct an assessment of existing scientific literature and research relating to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the relationship between dietary cholesterol and blood cholesterol and human health and nutrition; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> dietary calcium and its importance in human health and nutrition.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">In conducting the assessments under this subsection, the Secretaries shall consult with agencies of the Federal Government involved in related research. On completion of such assessments, the Secretaries shall each recommend such further studies as the Secretaries consider useful.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>], the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall each submit to the House Committees on Agriculture and Energy and Commerce and the Senate Committees on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry and Labor and Human Resources a report that shall include the results of the assessments conducted under subsection (a) and recommendations made under such subsection, for more complete studies of the issues examined under such subsection, including a protocol, feasibility assessment, budget estimates and a timetable for such research as each Secretary shall consider appropriate.”</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</level>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
