<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idefa09d05-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221"><num value="3221">§ 3221.</num><heading> Extension at 1890 land-grant colleges, including Tuskegee University</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d06-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d07-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There are hereby authorized to be appropriated annually such sums as Congress may determine necessary to support continuing agricultural and forestry extension at colleges eligible to receive funds under the Act of <date date="1890-08-30">August 30, 1890</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/26/417-419">26 Stat. 417–419</ref>, as amended; <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s321–326">7 U.S.C. 321–326</ref> and 328), including Tuskegee University (hereinafter in this section referred to as “eligible institutions”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d08-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Minimum amount</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Beginning with fiscal year 2003, there shall be appropriated under this section for each fiscal year an amount that is not less than 20 percent of the total appropriations for such year under the Act of <date date="1914-05-08">May 8, 1914</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s341">7 U.S.C. 341</ref> et seq.), and related acts pertaining to cooperative extension work at the land-grant institutions identified in the Act of <date date="1914-05-08">May 8, 1914</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/38/372">38 Stat. 372</ref>, chapter 79; <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s341">7 U.S.C. 341</ref> et seq.), except that for the purpose of this calculation, the total appropriations shall not include amounts made available under section 3(d) of that Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s343/d">7 U.S.C. 343(d)</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d09-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Uses</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Funds appropriated under this section shall be used for expenses of conducting extension programs and activities, and for contributing to the retirement of employees subject to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s331">section 331 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d0a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Distribution of funds</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d0b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Funds made available under this section shall be distributed among eligible institutions in accordance with this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d0c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Base amount</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any funds annually appropriated under this section up to the amount appropriated for the fiscal year ending <date date="1978-09-30">September 30, 1978</date>, pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s343/d">section 343(d) of this title</ref>, for eligible institutions, shall be allocated among the eligible institutions in the same proportion as funds appropriated under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s343/d">section 343(d) of this title</ref> for the fiscal year ending <date date="1978-09-30">September 30, 1978</date>, were allocated among the eligible institutions, as so designated as of that date.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d0d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional amount</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any funds appropriated annually under this section in excess of an amount equal to the amount appropriated under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s343/d">section 343(d) of this title</ref>, for the fiscal year ending <date date="1978-09-30">September 30, 1978</date>, for eligible institutions, shall be distributed as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idefa09d0e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A sum equal to 4 per centum of the total amount appropriated each fiscal year under this section shall be allotted to the National Institute of Food and Agriculture of the Department of Agriculture for administrative, technical, and other services, and for coordinating the extension work of the Department of Agriculture and the several States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idefa09d0f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (4), of the remainder, 20 per centum shall be allotted among the eligible institutions in equal proportions; 40 per centum shall be allotted among the eligible institutions in the proportion that the rural population of the State in which each eligible institution is located bears to the total rural population of all the States in which eligible institutions are located, as determined by the last preceding decennial census current at the time each such additional sum is first appropriated; and the balance shall be allotted among the eligible institutions in the proportion that the farm population of the State in which each eligible institution is located bears to the total farm population of all the States in which the eligible institutions are located, as determined by the last preceding decennial census current at the time each such additional sum is first appropriated.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idefa09d10-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> In computing the distribution of funds allocated under this paragraph, the allotments to Tuskegee University and Alabama Agricultural and Mechanical University shall be determined as if each institution were in a separate State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d11-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Special amounts</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d12-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/b/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In this paragraph:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d13-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/b/4/A/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Covered fiscal year</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The term “covered fiscal year” means the fiscal year for which the qualified eligible institution first received an allocation of $3,000,000 under subparagraph (B)(i).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d14-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/b/4/A/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Other eligible institution</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The term “other eligible institution” means an eligible institution, other than the qualified eligible institution, receiving an allocation of funds under this section.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d15-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/b/4/A/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Qualified eligible institution</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The term “qualified eligible institution” means the eligible institution described in subparagraph (B)(i).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d16-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/b/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Fiscal year 2019, 2020, 2021, or 2022</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d17-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/b/4/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Subject to clause (ii), for 1 of fiscal year 2019, 2020, 2021, or 2022, if the calculation under paragraph (3)(B) would result in a distribution for a fiscal year of less than $3,000,000 to an eligible institution that first received funds under this section on a date occurring after <date date="2014-02-07">February 7, 2014</date>, and before <date date="2018-09-30">September 30, 2018</date>, that institution shall receive an allocation of $3,000,000 for that fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d18-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/b/4/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Clause (i) shall apply only if amounts are appropriated under this section in an amount sufficient to provide that each other eligible institution receiving an allocation of funds under this section for fiscal year 2019, 2020, 2021, or 2022, as applicable, receives not less than the amount of funds received by that other eligible institution under this section for the preceding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d19-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/b/4/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Subsequent fiscal years</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d1a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/b/4/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Minimum additional funding amounts</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Subject to clauses (ii) and (iii), for each fiscal year following the covered fiscal year—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idefa09d1b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/b/4/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the qualified eligible institution shall receive an allocation under this subsection of at least $3,000,000; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idefa09d1c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/b/4/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> each other eligible institution shall receive an allocation under this subsection of at least the amount received by such other eligible institution under this subsection for the covered fiscal year.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d1d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/b/4/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Shortfall of special amounts</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d1e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/b/4/C/ii/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">This clause shall apply to any fiscal year following the covered fiscal year and for which the total amount appropriated under this section is insufficient to provide for the minimum additional funding amounts described in clause (i).</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d1f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/b/4/C/ii/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Reductions in allocations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">In the case of a fiscal year to which this clause applies, reductions in allocations shall be made proportionally from the qualified eligible institution and from each other eligible institution based on the increased amounts (if any) that the qualified eligible institution and each other eligible institution were allocated for the covered fiscal year as compared to the fiscal year immediately preceding the covered fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d20-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/b/4/C/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of census</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Clauses (i) and (ii) shall not apply in any fiscal year for which a shortfall in the minimum additional funding amounts described in clause (i) is attributable to the incorporation of new census data into the calculation under paragraph (3), as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d21-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Comprehensive program of extension for each State</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The State director of the cooperative extension service and the extension administrator at the eligible institution in each State where an eligible institution is located shall jointly develop, by mutual agreement, a comprehensive program of extension for such State to be submitted for approval by the Secretary within one year after <date date="1977-09-29">September 29, 1977</date> and each five years thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d22-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Ascertainment of entitlement to funds; time and manner of payment; State reporting requirements; plans of work</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d23-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Ascertainment of entitlement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">On or about the first day of October in each year after <date date="1977-09-29">September 29, 1977</date>, the Secretary shall ascertain whether each eligible institution is entitled to receive its share of the annual appropriation for extension work under this section and the amount which it is entitled to receive. Before the funds herein provided shall become available to any eligible institution for any fiscal year, plans for the work to be carried out under this section shall be submitted, as part of the State plan of work, and approved by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d24-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Time and manner of payment; related reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The amount to which an eligible institution is entitled shall be paid in equal quarterly payments on or about October 1, January 1, April 1, and July 1 of each year to the treasurer or other officer of the eligible institution duly authorized to receive such payments and such officer shall be required to report to the Secretary on or about the first day of December of each year a detailed statement of the amount so received during the previous fiscal year and its disbursement, on forms prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d25-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements related to plan of work</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each plan of work for an eligible institution required under this section shall contain descriptions of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idefa09d26-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A summary of planned projects or programs in the State using formula funds.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idefa09d27-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A description of matching funds provided by the State with respect to the previous fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d28-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Extension protocols</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d29-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/d/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall develop protocols to be used to evaluate the success of multistate, multi-institutional, and multidisciplinary extension activities and joint research and extension activities in addressing critical agricultural issues identified in the plans of work submitted under this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d2a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/d/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall develop the protocols in consultation with the Advisory Board and land-grant colleges and universities.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d2b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/d/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of plans of work for other purposes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall consider a plan of work submitted under this section to satisfy other appropriate Federal reporting requirements.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d2c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Diminution, loss, or misapplication of funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If any portion of the moneys received by any eligible institution for the support and maintenance of extension work as provided in this section shall by any action or contingency be diminished or lost or be misapplied, it shall be replaced by such institution and until so replaced no subsequent appropriation shall be apportioned or paid to such institution. No portion of such moneys shall be applied, directly or indirectly, to the purchase, erection, preservation, or repair of any building or buildings, or the purchase or rental of land, or in college course teaching, lectures in college, or any other purpose not specified in this section. It shall be the duty of such institution, annually, on or about the first day of January, to make to the Governor of the State in which it is located a full and detailed report of its operations in extension work, including a detailed statement of receipts and expenditures from all sources for this purpose, a copy of which report shall be sent to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefa09d2d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3221/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Mailing of correspondence, bulletins, and reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To the extent that the official mail consists of correspondence, bulletins, and reports for furtherance of the purposes of this section, it shall be transmitted in the mails of the United States. Such items may be mailed from a principal place of business of each eligible institution or from an established subunit of such institution.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idefa09d2e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/113/tXIV/s1444">Pub. L. 95–113, title XIV, § 1444</ref>, <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1007">91 Stat. 1007</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/tXIV/s1431">Pub. L. 97–98, title XIV, § 1431</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1310">95 Stat. 1310</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/198/tXIV/s1415">Pub. L. 99–198, title XIV, § 1415</ref>, <date date="1985-12-23">Dec. 23, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1549">99 Stat. 1549</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/tVIII/s883/b">Pub. L. 104–127, title VIII, § 883(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1176">110 Stat. 1176</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/185/tI/s103/f/3/A">Pub. L. 105–185, title I, § 103(f)(3)(A)</ref>, title II, §§ 225(a), 226(c)(2), <date date="1998-06-23">June 23, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/528">112 Stat. 528</ref>, 540, 543; <ref href="/us/pl/107/171/tVII/s7203/a">Pub. L. 107–171, title VII, § 7203(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/438">116 Stat. 438</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/234/tVII">Pub. L. 110–234, title VII</ref>, §§ 7121, 7403(c), 7404(b)(2)(A)(i), 7511(c)(12), <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1222">122 Stat. 1222</ref>, 1246, 1247, 1268; <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title VII, §§ 7121, 7403(c), 7404(b)(2)(A)(i), 7511(c)(12), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1664">122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 1983, 2008, 2029; <ref href="/us/pl/115/334/tVII">Pub. L. 115–334, title VII</ref>, §§ 7114, 7115(a), 7612(c)(1), <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4785">132 Stat. 4785</ref>, 4832.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idefa09d2f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idefa09d30-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idefa09d31-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1890-08-30">August 30, 1890</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/26/417">26 Stat. 417</ref>, as amended, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is popularly known as the “Agricultural College Act of 1890” and also as the “Second Morrill Act”, and is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 321 et seq.) of chapter 13 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s321">section 321 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1914-05-08">May 8, 1914</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/372">38 Stat. 372</ref>, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), is popularly known as the “Smith-Lever Act”, and is classified generally to subchapter IV (§ 341 et seq.) of chapter 13 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s341">section 341 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idefa09d32-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> made identical amendments to this section. The amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> were repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idefa09d33-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/115/334/s7114">Pub. L. 115–334, § 7114</ref>, struck out par. (4). Text read as follows: “No more than 20 per centum of the funds received by an institution in any fiscal year may be carried forward to the succeeding fiscal year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/115/334/s7115/a/4">Pub. L. 115–334, § 7115(a)(4)</ref>, inserted heading and struck out introductory provisions which read as follows: “Beginning with the fiscal year ending <date date="1979-09-30">September 30, 1979</date>—”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/115/334/s7115/a/4">Pub. L. 115–334, § 7115(a)(4)</ref>, added par. (1). Former par. (1) redesignated (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/115/334/s7115/a/3">Pub. L. 115–334, § 7115(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “were allocated” for “are allocated” and “, as so designated as of that date.” for “; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/334/s7115/a/4">Pub. L. 115–334, § 7115(a)(4)</ref>, redesignated par. (1) as (2), inserted heading, and substituted “Any funds” for “any funds”. Former par. (2) redesignated (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/115/334/s7115/a/2/A">Pub. L. 115–334, § 7115(a)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “Except as provided in paragraph (4), of the remainder” for “Of the remainder”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/115/334/s7115/a/1">Pub. L. 115–334, § 7115(a)(1)</ref>, redesignated concluding provisions of subsec. (b) as subpar. (C) of par. (2) and substituted “this paragraph” for “paragraph (2) of this subsection”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/115/334/s7115/a/2/B">Pub. L. 115–334, § 7115(a)(2)(B)</ref>, redesignated par. (2) as (3), inserted heading, and substituted “Any funds” for “any funds” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/115/334/s7115/a/5">Pub. L. 115–334, § 7115(a)(5)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/115/334/s7612/c/1">Pub. L. 115–334, § 7612(c)(1)</ref>, added subpars. (A) and (B) and struck out former subpars. (A) to (E) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(A) The critical short-term, intermediate, and long-term agricultural issues in the State in which the eligible institution is located and the current and planned extension programs and projects targeted to address the issues.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) The process established to consult with extension users regarding the identification of critical agricultural issues in the State and the development of extension programs and projects targeted to address the issues.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(C) The efforts made to identify and collaborate with other colleges and universities within the State, and within other States, that have a unique capacity to address the identified agricultural issues in the State and the extent of current and emerging efforts (including regional extension efforts) to work with those other institutions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(D) The manner in which research and extension, including research and extension activities funded other than through formula funds, will cooperate to address the critical issues in the State, including the activities to be carried out separately, the activities to be carried out sequentially, and the activities to be carried out jointly.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(E) The education and outreach programs already underway to convey currently available research results that are pertinent to a critical agricultural issue, including efforts to encourage multicounty cooperation in the dissemination of research results.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref>, §§ 7121, 7403(c), substituted “20 percent” for “15 percent” and “under section 3(d) of that Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s343/d">7 U.S.C. 343(d)</ref>)” for “after <date date="1995-09-30">September 30, 1995</date>, under section 3(d) of that Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s343/d">7 U.S.C. 343(d)</ref>), to carry out programs or initiatives for which no funds were made available under section 3(d) of that Act for fiscal year 1995, or any previous fiscal year, as determined by the Secretary, and shall not include amounts made available after <date date="1995-09-30">September 30, 1995</date>, to carry out programs or initiatives funded under section 3(d) of that Act prior to that date that are in excess of the highest amount made available for the programs or initiatives for fiscal year 1995, or any previous fiscal year, as determined by the Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s7511/c/12">Pub. L. 110–246, § 7511(c)(12)</ref>, substituted “National Institute of Food and Agriculture” for “Extension Service”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s7404/b/2/A/i">Pub. L. 110–246, § 7404(b)(2)(A)(i)</ref>, struck out “under penalty indicia: <i>Provided</i>, That each item shall bear such indicia as are prescribed by the Postmaster General and shall be mailed under such regulations as the Postmaster General may from time to time prescribe” after “United States”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/107/171">Pub. L. 107–171</ref> inserted subsec. heading, designated first, third, fourth, and fifth sentences as pars. (1) to (4), respectively, inserted headings, struck out “Beginning with the fiscal year ending <date date="1979-09-30">September 30, 1979</date>, and ending with the fiscal year ending <date date="1981-09-30">September 30, 1981</date>, there shall be appropriated under this section for each fiscal year an amount not less than 4 per centum of the total appropriations for such year under the Act of <date date="1914-05-08">May 8, 1914</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/38/372-374">38 Stat. 372–374</ref>, as amended; <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s341–349">7 U.S.C. 341–349</ref>): <i>Provided</i>, That the amount appropriated for the fiscal year ending <date date="1979-09-30">September 30, 1979</date>, shall not be less than the amount made available for the fiscal year ending <date date="1978-09-30">September 30, 1978</date>, to such eligible institutions under <ref href="/us/act/1914-05-08/s3/d">section 3(d) of the Act of May 8, 1914</ref> (<ref href="/us/stat/38/373">38 Stat. 373</ref>, as amended; <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s343/d">7 U.S.C. 343(d)</ref>.” after “(hereinafter in this section referred to as ‘eligible institutions’).” in par. (1), and substituted “Beginning with fiscal year 2003, there shall be appropriated under this section for each fiscal year an amount that is not less than 15 percent” for “Beginning with the fiscal year ending <date date="1982-09-30">September 30, 1982</date>, there shall be appropriated under this section an amount not less than 5½ per centum, and for each fiscal year thereafter an amount not less than 6 per centum” in par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—<ref href="/us/pl/105/185/s226/c/2/A">Pub. L. 105–185, § 226(c)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “University” for “Institute” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (a), (b). <ref href="/us/pl/105/185/s226/c/2/B">Pub. L. 105–185, § 226(c)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “Tuskegee University” for “Tuskegee Institute” in first sentence of subsec. (a) and concluding provisions of subsec. (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/105/185/s225/a">Pub. L. 105–185, § 225(a)</ref>, inserted subsec. heading, designated existing provisions as pars. (1) and (2) and inserted par. headings, in par. (2) substituted “The amount to which an eligible institution is entitled” for “Such sums”, and added pars. (3) to (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (f), (g). <ref href="/us/pl/105/185/s103/f/3/A">Pub. L. 105–185, § 103(f)(3)(A)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (g) as (f) and struck out former subsec. (f) which read as follows: “If the Secretary finds that an eligible institution is not entitled to receive its share of the annual appropriation, the facts and reasons therefor shall be reported to the President, and the amount involved shall be kept separate in the Treasury until the expiration of the next Congress in order that the institution may, if it should so desire, appeal to Congress from the determination of the Secretary. If the next Congress does not direct such sum to be paid, it shall be carried to surplus.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127">Pub. L. 104–127</ref> inserted before period at end of third sentence “, except that for the purpose of this calculation, the total appropriations shall not include amounts made available after <date date="1995-09-30">September 30, 1995</date>, under section 3(d) of that Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s343/d">7 U.S.C. 343(d)</ref>), to carry out programs or initiatives for which no funds were made available under section 3(d) of that Act for fiscal year 1995, or any previous fiscal year, as determined by the Secretary, and shall not include amounts made available after <date date="1995-09-30">September 30, 1995</date>, to carry out programs or initiatives funded under section 3(d) of that Act prior to that date that are in excess of the highest amount made available for the programs or initiatives for fiscal year 1995, or any previous fiscal year, as determined by the Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/198">Pub. L. 99–198</ref> in third sentence, struck out “, through the fiscal year ending <date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>,” after “fiscal year thereafter” and inserted at end “, and related acts pertaining to cooperative extension work at the land-grant institutions identified in the Act of <date date="1914-05-08">May 8, 1914</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/38/372">38 Stat. 372</ref>, chapter 79; <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s341">7 U.S.C. 341</ref> et seq.)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/s1431/1">Pub. L. 97–98, § 1431(1)</ref>, (2), inserted provisions designating the fiscal year ending <date date="1981-09-30">Sept. 30, 1981</date>, as the last of the fiscal years for which the appropriation under this section had to be 4 per centum or more of the total appropriation for each year under the Act of <date date="1914-05-08">May 8, 1914</date>, and inserted provisions that, beginning with the fiscal year ending <date date="1982-09-30">Sept. 30, 1982</date>, there must be appropriated under this section an amount not less than 5½ per centum and for each fiscal year thereafter, through the fiscal year ending <date date="1985-09-30">Sept. 30, 1985</date>, an amount not less than 6 per centum of the total appropriations for such year under the Act of <date date="1914-05-08">May 8, 1914</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(B). Pub. L., 97–98, § 1431(3), inserted “current at the time each such additional sum is first appropriated” after “the last preceding decennial census” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/s1431/4">Pub. L. 97–98, § 1431(4)</ref>, substituted “extension administrator” for “administrative head for extension” and inserted provision for the submission of a comprehensive program of extension for approval by the Secretary each five years after <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/s1431/5">Pub. L. 97–98, § 1431(5)</ref>, substituted “submitted, as part of the State plan of work,” for “submitted by the proper officials of each institution”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idefa09d34-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idefa09d35-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment of this section and repeal of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> effective <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8701">section 8701 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s7511/c/12">section 7511(c)(12) of Pub. L. 110–246</ref> effective <date date="2009-10-01">Oct. 1, 2009</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s7511/c">section 7511(c) of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1522">section 1522 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idefa09d36-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/185/tII/s225/c">Pub. L. 105–185, title II, § 225(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-06-23">June 23, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/542">112 Stat. 542</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/185/tII/s225/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s3222">section 3222 of this title</ref>] take effect on <date date="1999-10-01">October 1, 1999</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idefa09d37-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/98">Pub. L. 97–98</ref> effective <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/s1801">section 1801 of Pub. L. 97–98</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s4301">section 4301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idefa09d38-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1977-10-01">Oct. 1, 1977</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/113/s1901">section 1901 of Pub. L. 95–113</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1977 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1307">section 1307 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idefa09d39-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">West Virginia State College, Institute, West Virginia</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/78/tI">Pub. L. 106–78, title I</ref>, <date date="1999-10-22">Oct. 22, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1141">113 Stat. 1141</ref>, provided in part that West Virginia State College in Institute, West Virginia: <quotedContent>“for fiscal year 2000 and thereafter shall be designated as an eligible institution under section 1444 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s3221">7 U.S.C. 3221</ref>)”.</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
