<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idefaef4c5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3413"><num value="3413">§ 3413.</num><heading> Certification of organizations</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The eligibility of any organization to represent wheat producers, processors, end product manufacturers, or consumers to request the issuance of an order under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s3403/a">section 3403(a) of this title</ref> and to participate in the making of nominations under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s3405/b">section 3405(b) of this title</ref>, shall be certified by the Secretary. The Secretary shall certify any organization which the Secretary finds to be eligible under this section and the Secretary’s determination as to eligibility shall be final. Certification shall be based, in addition to other available information, upon a factual report submitted by the organization which shall contain information deemed relevant and specified by the Secretary for the making of such determination, including, but not limited to, the following:</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefaef4c6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3413/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> geographic territory covered by the organization’s active membership,</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefaef4c7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3413/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> nature and size of the organization’s active membership, including, in the case of an organization other than a consumer organization, the proportion of the total number of active wheat producers, processors, or end product manufacturers represented by the organization,</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefaef4c8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3413/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> evidence of stability and permanency of the organization,</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefaef4c9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3413/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> sources from which the organization’s operating funds are derived,</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefaef4ca-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3413/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> functions of the organization, and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefaef4cb-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3413/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> the organization’s ability and willingness to further the aims and objectives of this title: <i>Provided</i>, That the primary consideration in determining the eligibility of an organization, other than a consumer organization, shall be whether its membership consists primarily of wheat producers, processors, or end product manufacturers who produce a substantial volume of wheat, processed wheat, or end products, respectively, and whether the organization is based on a primary or overriding interest in the production, processing, or end manufacture of wheat or wheat products, and the nutritional attributes thereof: <i>Provided further</i>, That the primary consideration in determining the eligibility of a consumer organization shall be whether (1) a principal purpose of the organization is to promote consumer interests, consumer research, or consumer education, (2) such organization has a broadly representative constituency of consumers, with active membership participation on a regular basis, and (3) the organization has demonstrated to the Secretary’s satisfaction its commitment to the achievement of the objectives of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idefaef4cc-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/113/tXVII/s1714">Pub. L. 95–113, title XVII, § 1714</ref>, <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1039">91 Stat. 1039</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idefaef4cd-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idefaef4ce-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idefaef4cf-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1977-10-01">Oct. 1, 1977</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/113/s1901">section 1901 of Pub. L. 95–113</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1977 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1307">section 1307 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
