<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idefb13ec6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3809"><num value="3809">§ 3809.</num><heading> Primary enforcement responsibility</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13ec7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3809/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> State obligation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter, a State shall have the primary enforcement responsibility for violations of laws and regulations relating to the treatment of garbage to be fed to swine and the feeding thereof during any period for which the Secretary determines that such State—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefb13ec8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3809/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> has adopted adequate laws and regulations regulating the treatment of garbage to be fed to swine and the feeding thereof which laws and regulations meet the minimum standards of this chapter and the regulations hereunder: <i>Provided</i>, That the Secretary may not require a State to have laws that are more stringent than this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefb13ec9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3809/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> has adopted and is implementing adequate procedures for the effective enforcement of such State laws and regulations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefb13eca-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3809/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> will keep such records and make such reports showing compliance with paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection as the Secretary may require by regulation.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Except as provided in subsection (c), the Secretary shall not enforce this chapter or the regulations hereunder in any State which has primary enforcement responsibility pursuant to this section.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13ecb-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3809/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Inadequate enforcement or administration by State; termination of responsibility by Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever the Secretary determines that a State having primary enforcement responsibility pursuant to this section does not have adequate laws or regulations or is not effectively enforcing such laws or regulations, the Secretary shall notify the State. Such notice shall specify those aspects of the administration or enforcement of the State program that are determined to be inadequate. The State shall have ninety days after receipt of the notice to correct any deficiencies. If after that time the Secretary determines that the State program remains inadequate, the Secretary may terminate, in whole or in part, the State’s primary enforcement responsibility under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13ecc-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3809/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Request of State official</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13ecd-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3809/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">On request of the Governor or other appropriate official of a State, the Secretary may terminate, effective as soon as the Secretary determines is practicable, the primary enforcement responsibility of a State under subsection (a). In terminating the primary enforcement responsibility under this subsection, the Secretary shall work with the appropriate State official to determine the level of support to be provided to the Secretary by the State under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13ece-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3809/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Reassumption</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection shall prevent a State from reassuming primary enforcement responsibility if the Secretary determines that the State meets the requirements of subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13ecf-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s3809/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Emergency conditions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall limit the authority of the Secretary to enforce this chapter whenever the Secretary determines that emergency conditions exist that require immediate action on the part of the Secretary and the State authority is unwilling or unable adequately to respond to the emergency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idefb13ed0-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/468/s10">Pub. L. 96–468, § 10</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2233">94 Stat. 2233</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/tIX/s914/a">Pub. L. 104–127, title IX, § 914(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1186">110 Stat. 1186</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idefb13ed1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idefb13ed2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idefb13ed3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/104/127">Pub. L. 104–127</ref> added subsec. (c) and redesignated former subsec. (c) as (d).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
