<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idee2c9b42-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s389"><num value="389">§ 389.</num><heading> Transfer of certain dry land and irrigation field stations to States</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized, at such times as he deems appropriate, to convey by appropriate conveyances, without consideration, the interest of the United States in the lands, including water rights, buildings, and improvements presently comprising or appurtenant to the following dry land and irrigation field stations, to the States in which such stations are located, when, in the opinion of the Secretary of Agriculture, the transfer of any such station will result in establishing a more effective program in the cooperative agricultural experimental work of the Department of Agriculture and the respective State and the furtherance of agricultural experimental work on a national or regional basis will be better served by such transfer: Huntley, Montana; Mitchell, Nebraska; Fallon, Nevada; Tucumcari, New Mexico; Hermiston, Oregon; Sheridan, Wyoming: <i>Provided</i>, That when any or all of the land, including water rights, comprising any such station is public-domain land, only the Secretary of the Interior may by patent or other appropriate conveyance transfer such lands to the respective States: <i>Provided further</i>, That when any easement necessary to a station conveyed or patented hereunder is on public-domain lands, only the Secretary of the Interior may grant such easements to the State to which the station has been conveyed.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idee2c9b43-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1950-09-23/ch1005/s1">Sept. 23, 1950, ch. 1005, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/981">64 Stat. 981</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idee2c9b44-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idee2c9b45-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idee2c9b46-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of all officers, agencies, and employees of Department of Agriculture transferred, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of Agriculture by 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 1, eff. <date date="1953-06-04">June 4, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 3219, <ref href="/us/stat/67/633">67 Stat. 633</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2201">section 2201 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
