<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idefb13f16-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4002"><num value="4002">§ 4002.</num><heading> Alcohol processor grain reserve program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13f17-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4002/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefb13f18-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4002/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefb13f19-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4002/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “processor” means any person engaged within the United States in the business of manufacturing grain into alcohol for use as a fuel either by itself or in combination with some other product.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefb13f1a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4002/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The terms “agricultural grain” and “grain” mean any agricultural commodity (A) that is suitable for processing into alcohol for use as a fuel, and (B) with respect to which a price support operation is in effect.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefb13f1b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4002/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The term “producer storage program” means the producer storage program provided for under section 1445e <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002285">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002285"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefb13f1c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4002/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The term “small scale biomass energy project” shall have the same meaning as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8802/19">section 8802(19) of title 42</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13f1d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4002/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Loans on stored grain; processors eligible</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To assist processors in obtaining a dependable supply of grain at reasonable prices, the Secretary may formulate and administer a program under which processors purchasing and storing grain needed by them for manufacturing into alcohol for use as a fuel may obtain a loan from the Secretary on such grain. Loans under this section may be made available only to processors that (1) operate small scale biomass energy projects financed in whole or in part by the United States Government or any agency thereof, and (2) as determined by the Secretary, are otherwise unable to obtain a dependable supply of grain at reasonable prices for use in such projects.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13f1e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4002/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Terms and conditions of processor grain reserve program and producer storage program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this section, loans made under this section to carry out the processor grain reserve program may be made on the same terms and conditions as loans made to carry out the producer storage program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13f1f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4002/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount of loan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The amount of the loan that the Secretary may make to an eligible processor at any time on any quantity of grain purchased by the processor shall be determined by multiplying the price support loan rate in effect for such grain at the time the loan is made times the quantity of grain purchased by the proc­essor. The quantity of grain on which one or more loans may be outstanding at any time in the case of any processor may not exceed the estimated quantity of grain needed by such processor for one year of operation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13f20-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4002/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Replacement of removed grain</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever any quantity of grain stored in the processor grain reserve under this section is removed from storage by a processor, the processor may be required to replace such grain with an equal quantity, within such period of time as the Secretary shall prescribe by regulation, or repay that portion of the loan represented by the quantity of grain removed from storage.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13f21-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4002/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Purposes for which grain to be used</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Grain on which an eligible processor has received a loan under this section may not be used for any purpose other than the manufacture of alcohol for use as a fuel, and the Secretary shall establish such safeguards as the Secretary deems necessary to assure that such grain is not used for any other purpose and is not used in any manner that would unduly depress, manipulate, or curtail the free market in such grain.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13f22-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4002/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Terms and conditions of loan; security; non­recourse loans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Loans made under this section shall be made subject to such terms and conditions and subject to such security as the Secretary deems appropriate, except that such loans may not be made as nonrecourse loans.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13f23-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4002/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment for cost of storage; repayment of loans</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out the processor grain reserve program under this section, the Secretary may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefb13f24-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4002/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> provide for the payment to processors of such amounts as the Secretary determines appropriate to cover the cost of storing grain held in the processor grain reserve, except that in no event may the rate of the payment paid under this clause for any period exceed the rate paid by the Secretary under the producer storage program for the same period; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefb13f25-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4002/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> prescribe conditions under which the Secretary may require processors to repay loans made under this section, plus accrued interest thereon, refund amounts paid to the processors for storage, and require the processors to pay such additional interest and other charges as may be required by regulation in the event any processor fails to abide by the terms and conditions of the loan or any regulation prescribed under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13f26-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4002/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Announcement of terms and conditions of program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall announce the terms and conditions of the processor grain reserve program as far in advance of making loans as practicable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13f27-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4002/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of Commodity Credit Corporation facilities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may use the facilities of the Commodity Credit Corporation to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13f28-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4002/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations; appropriation acts as determining amount and extent of loans; expiration of authority to make loans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section. Any loans made under this section shall be made to such extent and such amounts as provided in appropriation Acts. The authority to make loans under this section shall expire five years after <date date="1980-12-03">December 3, 1980</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idefb13f29-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/494/tII/s209">Pub. L. 96–494, title II, § 209</ref>, <date date="1980-12-03">Dec. 3, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2575">94 Stat. 2575</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idefb13f2a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idefb13f2b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idefb13f2c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The producer storage program provided for under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1445e">section 1445e of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (a)(4), refers to section 1445e prior to the general amendment of such section by <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/tXI/s1123">Pub. L. 101–624, title XI, § 1123</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3503">104 Stat. 3503</ref>. As amended, section 1445e now provides for a farmer owned reserve program.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idefb13f2d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idefb13f2e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1980-12-03">Dec. 3, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/494/s213">section 213 of Pub. L. 96–494</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s4001">section 4001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
