<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idefb13f3b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4004"><num value="4004">§ 4004.</num><heading> Food bank special nutrition projects</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13f3c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4004/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Distribution of agricultural commodities to community food banks for emergency distribution; availability of agricultural commodities; use of currently used distributorship systems; selection of food banks</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall carry out special nutrition projects to provide agricultural commodities and other foods that might not otherwise be used, or might be more effectively used by organizations assisted under this section, to community food banks for emergency food box distribution to needy individuals and families. Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, the Secretary shall make available for purposes of such special nutrition projects, agricultural commodities and other foods available to the Secretary under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1431">section 1431 of this title</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1446a–1">section 1446a–1 of this title</ref>, and <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s612c">section 612c of this title</ref>. For purposes of distributing agricultural commodities and other foods to community food banks under this section, the Secretary may, in consultation with State agencies, use food distribution systems currently used to distribute agricultural commodities and other foods under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1751">42 U.S.C. 1751</ref> et seq.] and Child Nutrition Act of 1966 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1771">42 U.S.C. 1771</ref> et seq.]. The Secretary shall select food banks, in consultation with the Director of the Community Services Administration, for participation in the special nutrition projects under this section. Food banks shall be selected for participation so as to ensure adequate geographic distribution of emergency food box programs in at least two but not more than seven Department of Agriculture regions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13f3d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4004/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Application by food bank; recordkeeping and internal procedures</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idefb13f3e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4004/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> No food bank may participate in the special nutrition projects conducted under this section unless an application therefor is submitted to and approved by the Secretary. Such application shall be submitted in such form and manner and shall contain such information as the Secretary shall prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idefb13f3f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4004/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Each food bank participating in the special nutrition projects under this section shall establish a recordkeeping system and internal procedures to monitor the use of agricultural commodities and other foods provided under this section. The Secretary shall develop standards by which the feasibility and effectiveness of the projects shall be measured, and shall conduct an ongoing review of the effectiveness of the projects.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13f40-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4004/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Quantities and types of agricultural commodities; regulations for designation of eligible participants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall determine the quantities and types of agricultural commodities and other foods to be made available under this section. The Secretary may prescribe regulations regarding the designation of eligible participants in the projects and any other regulations necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13f41-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4004/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Report to Congress; contents; recommendations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall submit to Congress a progress report on <date date="1983-07-01">July 1, 1983</date>, and a final report on <date date="1984-01-01">January 1, 1984</date>, regarding the special nutrition projects carried out under this section. Such report shall include an analysis and evaluation of Federal participation in food bank emergency food programs, the effectiveness of such participation, and the feasibility of continuing such participation. The Secretary shall also include in such report any recommendations regarding improvements in Federal assistance to community food banks, including assistance for administrative expenses and transportation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13f42-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4004/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Sale of food prohibited; fines and penalties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The sale of food provided under this section shall be prohibited and any person who receives any remuneration in exchange for food provided under this section shall be subject to a fine of not more than $1,000 or imprisonment for not more than six months, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13f43-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4004/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Paperwork minimization and encouragement of participation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall minimize paperwork requirements placed on food banks which participate in the special nutrition projects established under this section and shall otherwise encourage food banks to participate in such projects.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb13f44-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4004/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idefb13f45-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/494/tII/s211">Pub. L. 96–494, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="1980-12-03">Dec. 3, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2577">94 Stat. 2577</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/tXI/s1114/b">Pub. L. 97–98, title XI, § 1114(b)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1269">95 Stat. 1269</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/78/tVII/s752/b/4">Pub. L. 106–78, title VII, § 752(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-22">Oct. 22, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1169">113 Stat. 1169</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idefb13f46-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idefb13f47-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idefb13f48-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1946-06-04/ch281">act June 4, 1946, ch. 281</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/230">60 Stat. 230</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 13 (§ 1751 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1751">section 1751 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Child Nutrition Act of 1966, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/89/642">Pub. L. 89–642</ref>, <date date="1966-10-11">Oct. 11, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/885">80 Stat. 885</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 13A (§ 1771 et seq.) of Title 42. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1771">section 1771 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idefb13f49-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/106/78">Pub. L. 106–78</ref> substituted “Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act” for “National School Lunch Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsecs. (a), (b). <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/s1114/b/1">Pub. L. 97–98, § 1114(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “special nutrition projects” for “demonstration projects” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/s1114/b/2">Pub. L. 97–98, § 1114(b)(2)</ref>, (3), substituted “to Congress a progress report on <date date="1983-07-01">July 1, 1983</date>, and a final report on <date date="1984-01-01">January 1, 1984</date>” for “a report to Congress on <date date="1982-10-01">October 1, 1982</date>” and “special nutrition projects” for “demonstration projects”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (f), (g). <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/s1114/b/4">Pub. L. 97–98, § 1114(b)(4)</ref>, (5), added subsec. (f), redesignated former subsec. (f) as (g), and substituted “such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section” for “to carry out this section $356,000”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idefb13f4a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idefb13f4b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/98">Pub. L. 97–98</ref> effective <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/s1801">section 1801 of Pub. L. 97–98</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s4301">section 4301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idefb13f4c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1980-12-03">Dec. 3, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/494/s213">section 213 of Pub. L. 96–494</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s4001">section 4001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="idefb13f4d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Community Services Administration</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Community Services Administration, which was established by section 601 of Economic Opportunity Act of 1964, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2941">42 U.S.C. 2941</ref>), terminated when Economic Opportunity Act of 1964, <ref href="/us/pl/88/452">Pub. L. 88–452</ref>, <date date="1964-08-20">Aug. 20, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/508">78 Stat. 508</ref>, as amended, was repealed, except for titles VIII and X, effective <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s683/a">section 683(a) of Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, title VI, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/519">95 Stat. 519</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9912/a">42 U.S.C. 9912(a)</ref>. An Office of Community Services, headed by a Director, was established in the Department of Health and Human Services by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s676">section 676 of Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9905">42 U.S.C. 9905</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
