<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idefb86ab1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4505"><num value="4505">§ 4505.</num><heading> Certification of organizations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idefb86ab2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4505/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The eligibility of any organization to represent milk producers, and to participate in the making of nominations under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s4504">section 4504 of this title</ref> shall be certified by the Secretary. The Secretary shall certify any organization that the Secretary determines meets the eligibility criteria established by the Secretary under this section and the Secretary’s determination as to eligibility shall be final.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idefb86ab3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4505/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> Certification shall be based, in addition to other available information, on a factual report submitted by the organization, which shall contain information deemed relevant and specified by the Secretary, including, but not limited to, the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefb86ab4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4505/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> geographic territory covered by the organization’s active membership;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefb86ab5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4505/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> nature and size of the organization’s active membership including the proportion of the total number of active milk producers represented by the organization;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefb86ab6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4505/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> evidence of stability and permanency of the organization;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefb86ab7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4505/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> sources from which the organization’s operating funds are derived;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefb86ab8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4505/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> functions of the organization; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefb86ab9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4505/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> the organization’s ability and willingness to further the aims and objectives of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The primary considerations in determining the eligibility of an organization shall be whether its membership consists primarily of milk producers who produce a substantial volume of milk and whether the primary or overriding interest of the organization is in the production or processing of fluid milk and dairy products and promotion of the nutritional attributes of fluid milk and dairy products.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idefb86aba-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/180/tI/s114">Pub. L. 98–180, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="1983-11-29">Nov. 29, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1140">97 Stat. 1140</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
