<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idefb86abf-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4507"><num value="4507">§ 4507.</num><heading> Suspension and termination of orders</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb86ac0-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4507/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination by Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After <date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>, the Secretary shall, whenever the Secretary finds that any order issued under this subchapter or any provision thereof obstructs or does not tend to effectuate the declared policy of this subchapter, terminate or suspend the operation of such order or such provisions thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb86ac1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4507/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Referendum</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After <date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>, the Secretary may conduct a referendum at any time, and shall hold a referendum on request of a representative group comprising 10 per centum or more of the number of producers and importers subject to the order, to determine whether the producers and importers favor the termination or suspension of the order. The Secretary shall suspend or terminate collection of assessments under the order within six months after the Secretary determines that suspension or termination of the order is favored by a majority of the producers voting in the referendum who, during a representative period (as determined by the Secretary), have been engaged in the production of milk for commercial use and importers voting in the referendum (who have been engaged in the importation of dairy products during the same representative period, as determined by the Secretary) and shall terminate the order in an orderly manner as soon as practicable after such determination.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefb86ac2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s4507/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Action not considered an order</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The termination or suspension of any order, or any provision thereof, shall not be considered an order within the meaning of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idefb86ac3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/180/tI/s116">Pub. L. 98–180, title I, § 116</ref>, <date date="1983-11-29">Nov. 29, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1141">97 Stat. 1141</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/171/tI/s1505/f">Pub. L. 107–171, title I, § 1505(f)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/209">116 Stat. 209</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idefb86ac4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idefb86ac5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idefb86ac6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/107/171">Pub. L. 107–171</ref>, which directed amendment of section 116(b) of the Dairy Promotion Stabilization Act of 1983 by inserting “and importers” after “of producers” and after “whether the producers” in first sentence and inserting “and importers voting in the referendum (who have been engaged in the importation of dairy products during the same representative period, as determined by the Secretary)” after “commercial use” in second sentence, was executed by making the insertions in subsec. (b) of this section, section 116 of the Dairy Production Stabilization Act of 1983, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
