<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idee31566b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s452"><num value="452">§ 452.</num><heading> Supervision of division of cooperative marketing</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The division of cooperative marketing shall be under the direction and supervision of the Secretary of Agriculture.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idee31566c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1926-07-02/ch725/s2">July 2, 1926, ch. 725, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/802">44 Stat. 802</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idee31566d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idee31566e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idee31566f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">First sentence of section, which provided that “The Secretary of Agriculture is hereby authorized and directed to establish a division of cooperative marketing with suitable personnel in the Bureau of Agricultural Economics of the Department of Agriculture or in such bureau in the Department of Agriculture as may hereafter be concerned with the marketing and distribution of farm products” was omitted from the Code as executed.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idee315670-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="idee315671-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer to Secretary of Agriculture</heading>
<p><ref href="/us/act/1953-08-06/ch335/s9">Act Aug. 6, 1953, ch. 335, § 9</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/394">67 Stat. 394</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1953-08-06/ch335/s9">“There is hereby transferred from the Farm Credit Administration to the jurisdiction and control of the Secretary of Agriculture the Division of Cooperative Marketing (by whatever name now called) authorized and created under and by virtue of an Act of Congress of <date date="1926-07-02">July 2, 1926</date> (Public, Numbered 450, Sixty-ninth Congress), entitled ‘An Act to create a Division of Cooperative Marketing in the Department of Agriculture; to provide for the acquisition and dissemination of information pertaining to cooperation; to promote the knowledge of cooperative principles and practices; to provide for calling advisers to counsel with the Secretary of Agriculture on cooperative activities; to authorize cooperative associations to acquire, interpret, and disseminate crop and market information, and for other purposes [this chapter]’, together with all functions pertaining to the work and services of such Division, its personnel, property (including office equipment), assets, funds, contracts, and records used and employed in the execution of its functions, powers, and duties, and so much of the unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds available or to be made available for salaries, expenses, and all other administrative expenditures as the Director of the Bureau of the Budget [now Director of the Office of Management and Budget] shall determine, for use in the execution of the functions, powers, and duties of said Division.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idee315672-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idee315673-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Farmer Cooperative Service established in Department of Agriculture <date date="1953-12-04">Dec. 4, 1953</date>, pursuant to Secretary’s Memorandum 1320, Supp. 4, 1953, as successor to functions of Cooperative Research and Service Division, Farm Credit Administration.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 9322, <date date="1943-03-26">Mar. 26, 1943</date>, 8 F.R. 3807, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 9334, <date date="1943-04-19">Apr. 19, 1943</date>, 8 F.R. 5423, removed Farm Credit Administration from Food Production Administration of Department of Agriculture and returned it to its former status as a separate agency of Department.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 9280, <date date="1942-12-05">Dec. 5, 1942</date>, 7 F.R. 10179, made Farm Credit Administration a part of Food Production Administration of Department of Agriculture.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Farm Credit Administration transferred to Department of Agriculture by 1939 Reorg. Plan No. I, § 401, 4 F.R. 2727, <ref href="/us/stat/53/1423">53 Stat. 1423</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 6084, <date date="1933-03-27">Mar. 27, 1933</date>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s2241">section 2241 of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking, changed name of Federal Farm Board to Farm Credit Administration and name of office of Chairman of Federal Farm Board to Governor of Farm Credit Administration.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 5200, <date date="1929-10-01">Oct. 1, 1929</date>, transferred, eff. <date date="1929-10-01">Oct. 1, 1929</date>, from Department of Agriculture to jurisdiction and control of Federal Farm Board the whole of Division of Cooperative Marketing in Bureau of Agricultural Economics of Department of Agriculture, all functions pertaining to work and services of such division, its records, property, including office equipment, personnel, and unexpended balances of appropriation, pertaining to such work or services.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="idee315674-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Exceptions From Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of Corporations of Department of Agriculture, boards of directors and officers of such corporations; Advisory Board of Commodity Credit Corporation; and Farm Credit Administration or any agency, officer, or entity of, under, or subject to supervision of said Administration excepted from functions of officers, agencies, and employees transferred to Secretary of Agriculture by 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 1, eff. <date date="1953-06-04">June 4, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 3219, <ref href="/us/stat/67/633">67 Stat. 633</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2201">section 2201 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
