<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idee33c708-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499a"><num value="499a">§ 499a.</num><heading> Short title and definitions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee33c709-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Short title</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This chapter may be cited as the “Perishable Agricultural Commodities Act, 1930”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee33c70a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this chapter:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee33c70b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “person” includes individuals, partnerships, corporations, and associations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee33c70c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee33c70d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499a/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “interstate or foreign commerce” means commerce between any State or Territory, or the District of Columbia and any place outside thereof; or between points within the same State or Territory, or the District of Columbia but through any place outside thereof; or within the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee33c70e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499a/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> The term “perishable agricultural commodity”—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idee33c70f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499a/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Means any of the following, whether or not frozen or packed in ice: Fresh fruits and fresh vegetables of every kind and character; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idee33c710-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499a/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Includes cherries in brine as defined by the Secretary in accordance with trade usages.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee33c711-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499a/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The term “commission merchant” means any person engaged in the business of receiving in interstate or foreign commerce any perishable agricultural commodity for sale, on commission, or for or on behalf of another.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee33c712-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499a/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The term “dealer” means any person engaged in the business of buying or selling in wholesale or jobbing quantities, as defined by the Secretary, any perishable agricultural commodity in interstate or foreign commerce, except that (A) no producer shall be considered as a “dealer” in respect to sales of any such commodity of his own raising; (B) no person buying any such commodity solely for sale at retail shall be considered as a “dealer” until the invoice cost of his purchases of perishable agricultural commodities in any calendar year are in excess of $230,000; and (C) no person buying any commodity other than potatoes for canning and/or processing within the State where grown shall be considered a “dealer” whether or not the canned or processed product is to be shipped in interstate or foreign commerce, unless such product is frozen or packed in ice, or consists of cherries in brine, within the meaning of paragraph (4) of this section. Any person not considered as a “dealer” under clauses (A), (B), and (C) may elect to secure a license under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s499c">section 499c of this title</ref>, and in such case and while the license is in effect such person shall be considered as a “dealer”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee33c713-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499a/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The term “broker” means any person engaged in the business of negotiating sales and purchases of any perishable agricultural commodity in interstate or foreign commerce for or on behalf of the vendor or the purchaser, respectively, except that no person shall be deemed to be a “broker” if such person is an independent agent negotiating sales for and on behalf of the vendor and if the only sales of such commodities negotiated by such person are sales of frozen fruits and vegetables having an invoice value not in excess of $230,000 in any calendar year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee33c714-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499a/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> A transaction in respect of any perishable agricultural commodity shall be considered in interstate or foreign commerce if such commodity is part of that current of commerce usual in the trade in that commodity whereby such commodity and/or the products of such commodity are sent from one State with the expectation that they will end their transit, after purchase, in another, including, in addition to cases within the above general description, all cases where sale is either for shipment to another State, or for processing within the State and the shipment outside the State of the products resulting from such processing. Commodities normally in such current of commerce shall not be considered out of such commerce through resort being had to any means or device intended to remove transactions in respect thereto from the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee33c715-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499a/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> The term “responsibly connected” means affiliated or connected with a commission merchant, dealer, or broker as (A) partner in a partnership, or (B) officer, director, or holder of more than 10 per centum of the outstanding stock of a corporation or association. A person shall not be deemed to be responsibly connected if the person demonstrates by a preponderance of the evidence that the person was not actively involved in the activities resulting in a violation of this chapter and that the person either was only nominally a partner, officer, director, or shareholder of a violating licensee or entity subject to license or was not an owner of a violating licensee or entity subject to license which was the alter ego of its owners.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee33c716-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499a/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> The terms “employ” and “employment” mean any affiliation of any person with the business operations of a licensee, with or without compensation, including ownership or self-employment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee33c717-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499a/b/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> The term “retailer” means a person that is a dealer engaged in the business of selling any perishable agricultural commodity at retail.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee33c718-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499a/b/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> The term “grocery wholesaler” means a person that is a dealer primarily engaged in the full-line wholesale distribution and resale of grocery and related nonfood items (such as perishable agricultural commodities, dry groceries, general merchandise, meat, poultry, and seafood, and health and beauty care items) to retailers. However, such term does not include a person described in the preceding sentence if the person is primarily engaged in the wholesale distribution and resale of perishable agricultural commodities rather than other grocery and related nonfood items.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee33c719-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499a/b/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> The term “collateral fees and expenses” means any promotional allowances, rebates, service or materials fees paid or provided, directly or indirectly, in connection with the distribution or marketing of any perishable agricultural commodity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idee33c71a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1930-06-10/ch436/s1">June 10, 1930, ch. 436, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/531">46 Stat. 531</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1934-04-13/ch120/s1">Apr. 13, 1934, ch. 120, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/584">48 Stat. 584</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1937-08-20/ch719/s1">Aug. 20, 1937, ch. 719, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/50/725">50 Stat. 725</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1940-06-29/ch456">June 29, 1940, ch. 456</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <ref href="/us/stat/54/696">54 Stat. 696</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/725">Pub. L. 87–725</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <date date="1962-10-01">Oct. 1, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/673">76 Stat. 673</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/107">Pub. L. 91–107</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <date date="1969-11-04">Nov. 4, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/182">83 Stat. 182</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/562/s1">Pub. L. 95–562, § 1</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2381">92 Stat. 2381</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/tXI/s1115/a">Pub. L. 97–98, title XI, § 1115(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1269">95 Stat. 1269</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/237/tX/s1011/1">Pub. L. 102–237, title X, § 1011(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1898">105 Stat. 1898</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/48">Pub. L. 104–48</ref>, §§ 2, 9(a), 12(a), <date date="1995-11-15">Nov. 15, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/424">109 Stat. 424</ref>, 429, 430.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idee33c71b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idee33c71c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idee33c71d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s551">section 551 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idee33c71e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—Subsec. (b)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/104/48/s12/a">Pub. L. 104–48, § 12(a)</ref>, inserted at end “A person shall not be deemed to be responsibly connected if the person demonstrates by a preponderance of the evidence that the person was not actively involved in the activities resulting in a violation of this chapter and that the person either was only nominally a partner, officer, director, or shareholder of a violating licensee or entity subject to license or was not an owner of a violating licensee or entity subject to license which was the alter ego of its owners.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(11), (12). <ref href="/us/pl/104/48/s2">Pub. L. 104–48, § 2</ref>, added pars. (11) and (12).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(13). <ref href="/us/pl/104/48/s9/a">Pub. L. 104–48, § 9(a)</ref>, added par. (13).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—<ref href="/us/pl/102/237">Pub. L. 102–237</ref> inserted section catchline, added subsec. (a), designated existing provisions as subsec. (b), and in subsec. (b), inserted heading, substituted “For purposes of this chapter:” for “When used in this chapter—” and periods for semicolons at the end of pars. (1) to (6) and (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Pars. (6), (7). <ref href="/us/pl/97/98">Pub. L. 97–98</ref> substituted “$230,000” for “$200,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Par. (6)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/95/562/s1/a/1">Pub. L. 95–562, § 1(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “$200,000” for “$100,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (6)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/95/562/s1/b">Pub. L. 95–562, § 1(b)</ref>, inserted “other than potatoes” after “commodity”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (7). <ref href="/us/pl/95/562/s1/a/2">Pub. L. 95–562, § 1(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “$200,000” for “$100,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1969—Par. (6)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/91/107/s1">Pub. L. 91–107, § 1</ref>, substituted “$100,000” for “$90,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (7). <ref href="/us/pl/91/107/s2">Pub. L. 91–107, § 2</ref>, substituted “$100,000” for “$90,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Par. (6). <ref href="/us/pl/87/725/s1">Pub. L. 87–725, § 1</ref>, substituted “wholesale or jobbing quantities” for “carloads”, the requirement that the dealer’s invoice cost of his purchases in any calendar year exceed $90,000 for the requirement that his purchases in such year exceed 20 carloads, and struck out definition of “in carloads”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (7). <ref href="/us/pl/87/725/s1">Pub. L. 87–725, § 1</ref>, excluded from definition of “broker”, persons who are independent agents negotiating sales for vendors and whose sales are of frozen fruits and vegetables having an invoice value not exceeding $90,000 in any calendar year.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Pars. (9), (10). <ref href="/us/pl/87/725/s2">Pub. L. 87–725, § 2</ref>, added pars. (9) and (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1940—Par. (4). Act <date date="1940-06-29">June 29, 1940</date>, § 1, designated existing provisions as cl. (A) and added cl. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (6)(C). Act <date date="1940-06-29">June 29, 1940</date>, § 2, inserted “, or consists of cherries in brine,” after “ice”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1937—Par. (6)(C). Act <date date="1937-08-20">Aug. 20, 1937</date>, inserted “unless such product is frozen or packed in ice within the meaning of paragraph 4 of this section” after “foreign commerce”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1934—Par. (6)(C). Act <date date="1934-04-13">Apr. 13, 1934</date>, added cl. (C).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idee33c71f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idee33c720-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/98">Pub. L. 97–98</ref> effective <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/s1801">section 1801 of Pub. L. 97–98</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s4301">section 4301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idee33c721-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/562/s1/a">Pub. L. 95–562, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2381">92 Stat. 2381</ref>, provided that the amendment made by <ref href="/us/pl/95/562/s1/a">section 1(a) of Pub. L. 95–562</ref> is effective <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="idee33c722-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1995 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/48/s1/a">Pub. L. 104–48, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-11-15">Nov. 15, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/424">109 Stat. 424</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/48/s1/a">“This Act [amending this section and sections 499b, 499c to 499f, and 499h of this title and repealing provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s499f">section 499f of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Perishable Agricultural Commodities Act Amendments of 1995’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idee33c723-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study of Domestic Fruit and Vegetable Industry</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/624/tXIII">Pub. L. 101–624, title XIII</ref>, §§ 1301–1305, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3559">104 Stat. 3559</ref>, 3560, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/624/tXIII">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1301">“SEC. 1301.</num><heading> FINDINGS.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Congress finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> fruits, vegetables, and specialty crops are a vital and important source of nutrition for the general health and welfare of the people of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> fruits and vegetables are recommended as an essential part of a healthy, nutritious diet by numerous health officials and organizations including the Surgeon General of the United States; the National Institutes of Health; the National Cancer Institute; the American Heart Association; the Committee on Diet, Nutrition and Cancer of the National Academy of Sciences; the Department of Agriculture; and the Department of Health and Human Services.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1302">“SEC. 1302.</num><heading> PURPOSES.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“The purposes of this subtitle [subtitle A (§§ 1301–1309) of <ref href="/us/pl/101/624">Pub. L. 101–624</ref>, enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s499b–1">section 499b–1 of this title</ref>, amending sections 608c and 608e–1 of this title, and enacting this note] are to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> improve the Nation’s dietary and nutritional standards by promoting domestically produced wholesome and nutritious fruit and vegetable products;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> increase the public awareness as to the difficulties domestic producers experience regarding the production, harvesting, and marketing of these products; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> aid in the development of new technology and techniques that will assist domestic producers in meeting the challenges of increased demands for fruit and vegetable products in the future.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1303">“SEC. 1303.</num><heading> DECLARATION.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Congress declares that the domestic production of fruits and vegetables is an integral part of this Nation’s farm policy.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1304">“SEC. 1304.</num><heading> STUDY OF THE FRUIT AND VEGETABLE INDUSTRY.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Agriculture shall conduct a study to determine the state of the domestic fruit and vegetable industry. In conducting such study, the Secretary of Agriculture shall consult with such agencies or departments, as determined necessary by the Secretary of Agriculture, including the Environmental Protection Agency, the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of Commerce, the Department of Labor, and the Department of Education.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The study conducted under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a review of the availability of an adequate labor supply for maintaining and harvesting of fruits and vegetables;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a review of the availability of crop insurance or disaster assistance for fruit and vegetable producers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> a review of scientific and technological advances in the areas of genetics, biotechnology, integrated pest management, post harvest protection, and other scientific developments related to the production and marketing of fruits and vegetables;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> an examination of the availability of safe and effective chemicals for use in the production of fruits and vegetables, and an evaluation of the value of national uniformity to both consumers and producers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> a review of the requirements and cost of labeling fruits and vegetables in the industry, and the benefits that would result from the labeling of such products; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> a review of Federal educational programs that teach the importance of fruits and vegetables to a proper diet.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this title [<date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>], the Secretary of Agriculture shall prepare and submit, to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate, a report containing the results of the study described in subsection (a). Such report shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the recommendations of the Secretary concerning the manner in which producers of domestic fruit and vegetable commodities that are not receiving assistance under the programs that provide market enhancement assistance (such as the export enhancement program under subtitle B of title XI of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1736p">7 U.S.C. 1736p</ref> et seq.) to producers of domestic fruit and vegetable commodities, could participate in such programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the recommendations to the Secretary concerning the establishment of additional programs of the type described in paragraph (1) to assist producers of domestic fruit and vegetable commodities in increasing their production and in expanding domestic and foreign markets for the products of such producers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1305">“SEC. 1305.</num><heading> COUNTRY OF ORIGIN LABELING PROGRAMS.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Grown in the U.S. Program</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Agriculture (hereafter referred to in this section as the ‘Secretary’) shall implement a program defining the conditions under which non-perishable agricultural products may be designated as ‘grown in the U.S.’.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pilot Program.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall implement a 2-year pilot program during which time perishable agricultural products (fresh fruits and vegetables) are labeled or marked as to their country of origin. This program shall be conducted nationwide. After the 2-year period, the Secretary shall conduct a study to determine the results of the program. The Secretary shall submit to the Congress the results of the study within 18 months from the date of completion of the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Details of the pilot program.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Designation of country of origin</inline>.—</heading><content>The program shall require that the country of origin of perishable agricultural products be indicated on any such products or on the package, display, holding unit, or bin by means of a label, stamp, mark, placard, or other clear and visible indication at the point of sale by any commission merchant, dealer, broker, or grocer. A sign near the products shall be an acceptable indication of the country of origin.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Application of program.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Imported and domestic products</inline>.—</heading><content>The program shall apply to imported and domestic perishable agricultural products (including fresh fruits and vegetables).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Imported perishable agricultural products</inline>.—</heading><content>The labeling program shall apply to imported perishable agricultural products that enter the United States marked as to the country of origin and that are in compliance with section 304(a) of the Tariff Act of 1930 [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1304/a">19 U.S.C. 1304(a)</ref>].</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exemptions</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may provide for exemptions for products that are exempted, under section 304(a)(3)(J) of the Tariff Act of 1930, from the country of origin marking requirements of that Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1202">19 U.S.C. 1202</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this section.”</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idee33c724-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Potato Dealers</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/562/s1/b">Pub. L. 95–562, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2381">92 Stat. 2381</ref>, provided in part that no person buying potatoes for processing solely within the State where grown shall be deemed or considered to be a dealer under par. (6) of this section, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/95/562/s1/b">section 1(b) of Pub. L. 95–562</ref>, until <date date="1982-01-01">Jan. 1, 1982</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
