<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idee363778-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499f"><num value="499f">§ 499f.</num><heading> Complaints, written notifications, and investigations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee363779-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499f/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Reparation complaints</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idee36377a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499f/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Petition; process</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any person complaining of any violation of any provision of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s499b">section 499b of this title</ref> by any commission merchant, dealer, or broker may, at any time within nine months after the cause of action accrues, apply to the Secretary by petition, which shall briefly state the facts, whereupon, if, in the opinion of the Secretary, the facts therein contained warrant such action, a copy of the complaint thus made shall be forwarded by the Secretary to the commission merchant, dealer, or broker, who shall be called upon to satisfy the complaint, or to answer it in writing, within a reasonable time to be prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idee36377b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499f/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Filing and handling fees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A person submitting a petition to the Secretary under paragraph (1) shall include a filing fee of $60 per petition. If the Secretary determines under paragraph (1) that the facts contained in the petition warrant further action, the person or persons submitting the petition shall submit to the Secretary a handling fee of $300. The Secretary may not forward a copy of the complaint to the commission merchant, dealer, or broker involved until after the Secretary receives the required handling fee. The Secretary shall deposit fees submitted under this paragraph into the Perishable Agricultural Commodities Act Fund provided for by <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s499c/b">section 499c(b) of this title</ref>. The Secretary may alter the fees specified in this paragraph by rulemaking under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee36377c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499f/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Disciplinary violations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any officer or agency of any State or Territory having jurisdiction over commission merchants, dealers, or brokers in such State or Territory and any other interested person (other than an employee of an agency of the Department of Agriculture administering this chapter) may file, in accordance with rules prescribed by the Secretary, a written notification of any alleged violation of this chapter by any commission merchant, dealer, or broker. In addition, any official certificates of the United States Government or States or Territories of the United States and trust notices filed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s499e">section 499e of this title</ref> shall constitute written notification for the purposes of conducting an investigation under subsection (c). The identity of any person filing a written notification under this subsection shall be considered to be confidential information. The identity of such person, and any portion of the notification to the extent that it would indicate the identity of such person, are specifically exempt from disclosure under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">section 552 of title 5</ref> (commonly known as the Freedom of Information Act), as provided in subsection (b)(3) of such section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee38816d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499f/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Investigation of complaints and notifications</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idee38816e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499f/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Commencing or expanding an investigation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If there appears to be, in the opinion of the Secretary, reasonable grounds for investigating a complaint made under subsection (a) or a written notification made under subsection (b), the Secretary shall investigate such complaint or notification. In the course of the investigation, if the Secretary determines that violations of this chapter are indicated other than the alleged violations specified in the complaint or notification that served as the basis for the investigation, the Secretary may expand the investigation to include such additional violations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idee38816f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499f/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Issuance of complaint by Secretary; process</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the opinion of the Secretary, if an investigation under this subsection substantiates the existence of violations of this chapter, the Secretary may cause a complaint to be issued. The Secretary shall have the complaint served by registered mail or certified mail or otherwise on the person concerned and afford such person an opportunity for a hearing thereon before a duly authorized examiner of the Secretary in any place in which the subject of the complaint is engaged in business. However, in complaints wherein the amount claimed as damages does not exceed $30,000, a hearing need not be held and proof in support of the complaint and in support of respondent’s answer may be supplied in the form of depositions or verified statements of fact.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idee388170-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499f/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Special notification requirements for certain investigations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Whenever the Secretary initiates an investigation on the basis of a written notification made under subsection (b) or expands such an investigation, the Secretary shall promptly notify the subject of the investigation of the existence of the investigation and the nature of the alleged violations of this chapter to be investigated. Not later than 180 days after providing the initial notification, the Secretary shall provide the subject of the investigation with notice of the status of the investigation, including whether the Secretary intends to issue a complaint under paragraph (2), terminate the investigation, or continue or expand the investigation. The Secretary shall provide additional status reports at the request of the subject of the investigation and shall promptly notify the subject of the investigation whenever the Secretary terminates the investigation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee388171-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499f/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Decisions on complaints</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After opportunity for hearing on complaints where the damages claimed exceed the sum of $30,000 has been provided or waived and on complaints where damages claimed do not exceed the sum of $30,000 not requiring hearing as provided herein, the Secretary shall determine whether or not the commission merchant, dealer, or broker has violated any provision of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s499b">section 499b of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee388172-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s499f/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Bond required for certain complaints</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In case a complaint is made by a nonresident of the United States, or by a resident of the United States to whom the claim of a nonresident of the United States has been assigned, the complainant shall be required, before any formal action is taken on his complaint, to furnish a bond in double the amount of the claim conditioned upon the payment of costs, including a reasonable attorney’s fee for the respondent if the respondent shall prevail, and any reparation award that may be issued by the Secretary of Agriculture against the complainant on any counter claim by respondent: <i>Provided</i>, That the Secretary shall have authority to waive the furnishing of a bond by a complainant who is a resident of a country which permits the filing of a complaint by a resident of the United States without the furnishing of a bond.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idee388173-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1930-06-10/ch436/s6">June 10, 1930, ch. 436, § 6</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/534">46 Stat. 534</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1934-04-13/ch120">Apr. 13, 1934, ch. 120</ref>, §§ 8–10, <ref href="/us/stat/48/586">48 Stat. 586</ref>, 587; <ref href="/us/act/1937-08-20/ch719">Aug. 20, 1937, ch. 719</ref>, §§ 8, 9, <ref href="/us/stat/50/728">50 Stat. 728</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/507/s1/4">Pub. L. 86–507, § 1(4)</ref>, <date date="1960-06-11">June 11, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/200">74 Stat. 200</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/725/s8">Pub. L. 87–725, § 8</ref>, <date date="1962-10-01">Oct. 1, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/675">76 Stat. 675</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/231/s1">Pub. L. 92–231, § 1</ref>, <date date="1972-02-15">Feb. 15, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/38">86 Stat. 38</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/tXI/s1115/c">Pub. L. 97–98, title XI, § 1115(c)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1270">95 Stat. 1270</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/352/s2">Pub. L. 97–352, § 2</ref>, <date date="1982-10-18">Oct. 18, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1667">96 Stat. 1667</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/237/tX/s1011/4">Pub. L. 102–237, title X, § 1011(4)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-13">Dec. 13, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1898">105 Stat. 1898</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/48">Pub. L. 104–48</ref>, §§ 7, 8(a), <date date="1995-11-15">Nov. 15, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/428">109 Stat. 428</ref>, 429.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idee388174-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idee388175-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idee388176-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s556">section 556 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idee388177-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—<ref href="/us/pl/104/48/s7/d/1">Pub. L. 104–48, § 7(d)(1)</ref>, substituted “Complaints, written notifications, and investigations” for “Complaint and investigation” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/48/s8/a">Pub. L. 104–48, § 8(a)</ref>, inserted subsec. heading, designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted par. (1) heading, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/104/48/s7/a">Pub. L. 104–48, § 7(a)</ref>, inserted heading and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Any officer or agency of any State or Territory having jurisdiction over commission merchants, dealers, or brokers in such State or Territory and any employee of the United States Department of Agriculture or any interested person may file, in accordance with rules and regulations of the Secretary, a complaint of any violation of any provision of this chapter by any commission merchant, dealer, or broker and may request an investigation of such complaint by the Secretary.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/48/s7/b">Pub. L. 104–48, § 7(b)</ref>, inserted heading and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “If there appear to be, in the opinion of the Secretary, any reasonable grounds for investigating any complaint made under this section, the Secretary shall investigate such complaint and may, if in his opinion the facts warrant such action, have said complaint served by registered mail or by certified mail or otherwise on the person concerned and afford such person an opportunity for a hearing thereon before a duly authorized examiner of the Secretary in any place in which the said person is engaged in business: <i>Provided</i>, That in complaints wherein the amount claimed as damages does not exceed the sum of $15,000, a hearing need not be held and proof in support of the complaint and in support of respondent’s answer may be supplied in the form of depositions or verified statements of fact.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/104/48/s7/c">Pub. L. 104–48, § 7(c)</ref>, (d)(2), inserted heading and substituted “$30,000” for “$15,000” in two places in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/104/48/s7/d/3">Pub. L. 104–48, § 7(d)(3)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/102/237">Pub. L. 102–237</ref> inserted a period at end of subsec. (c) and substituted a period for semicolon at end of subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/97/352">Pub. L. 97–352</ref> inserted “or by a resident of the United States to whom the claim of a nonresident of the United States has been assigned,” after “In case a complaint is made by a nonresident of the United States,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/98">Pub. L. 97–98</ref> substituted “$15,000” for “$3,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1972—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/92/231">Pub. L. 92–231</ref> substituted “$3,000” for “$1,500”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/92/231">Pub. L. 92–231</ref> substituted “$3,000” for “$1,500” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/87/725">Pub. L. 87–725</ref> substituted “$1,500” for “$500”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/87/725">Pub. L. 87–725</ref> substituted “$1,500” for “$500” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1960—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/86/507">Pub. L. 86–507</ref> inserted “or by certified mail” after “registered mail”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1937—Subsec. (b). Act <date date="1937-08-20">Aug. 20, 1937</date>, § 8, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s499b">section 499b of this title</ref>” for “this chapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). Act <date date="1937-08-20">Aug. 20, 1937</date>, § 9, inserted “and any reparation award that may be issued by the Secretary of Agriculture against the complainant on any counter claim by respondent” and proviso.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1934—Subsec. (c). Act <date date="1934-04-13">Apr. 13, 1934</date>, § 8, inserted proviso.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). Act <date date="1934-04-13">Apr. 13, 1934</date>, § 9, substituted “complaints” for “a complaint” after “on” and inserted “where damages claimed do not exceed the sum of $500 not requiring hearing as provided herein” after “complaints”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). Act <date date="1934-04-13">Apr. 13, 1934</date>, § 10, among other changes, inserted “formal” before “action”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idee388178-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idee388179-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/352/s3">Pub. L. 97–352, § 3</ref>, <date date="1982-10-18">Oct. 18, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1667">96 Stat. 1667</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/352/s3">“The amendment made by section 2 [amending this section] shall not apply with respect to complaints made under section 6(e) of the Perishable Agricultural Commodities Act, 1930 [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s499f/e">7 U.S.C. 499f(e)</ref>], before the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1982-10-18">Oct. 18, 1982</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idee38817a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/98">Pub. L. 97–98</ref> effective <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/s1801">section 1801 of Pub. L. 97–98</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s4301">section 4301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idee38817b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Filing and Handling Fees During Fiscal Years 1995 and 1996</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/276/s1">Pub. L. 103–276, § 1</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1406">108 Stat. 1406</ref>, during fiscal years 1995 and 1996, directed Secretary of Agriculture to require filing fee of $60 per petition for petitions alleging violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s499b">section 499b of this title</ref> and handling fee of $300 for petitions that warrant further action, which handling fee was to be included in determining amount of damages, with both fees to be deposited into the Perishable Agricultural Commodities Act Fund, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/104/48/s8/c">Pub. L. 104–48, § 8(c)</ref>, <date date="1995-11-15">Nov. 15, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/429">109 Stat. 429</ref>. See subsec. (a)(2) of this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
