<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idee3af2e1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s501"><num value="501">§ 501.</num><heading> Collection and publication; facts required; deteriorated tobacco</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized and directed to collect and publish statistics of the quantity of leaf tobacco in all forms in the United States and Puerto Rico, owned by or in the possession of dealers, manufacturers, quasi-manufacturers, growers’ cooperative associations, warehousemen, brokers, holders, or owners, other than the original growers of tobacco. The statistics shall show the quantity of tobacco in such detail as to types, groups of grades, and such other subdivisions as to quality, color, and/or grade for particular types, as the Secretary of Agriculture shall deem to be practical and necessary for the purposes of this chapter, shall be summarized as of January 1, April 1, July 1, and October 1 of each year, and an annual report on tobacco statistics shall be issued: <i>Provided</i>, That the Secretary of Agriculture shall not be required to collect statistics of leaf tobacco from any manufacturer of tobacco who, in the first three quarters of the preceding calendar year, according to the returns of the Commissioner of Internal Revenue or the record of the Treasurer of Puerto Rico, manufactured less than thirty-five thousand pounds of tobacco, or from any manufacturer of cigars who, during the first three quarters of the preceding calendar year, manufactured less than one hundred and eighty-five thousand cigars, or from any manufacturer of cigarettes who, during the first three quarters of the preceding year, manufactured less than seven hundred and fifty thousand cigarettes: <i>And provided further</i>, That the Secretary of Agriculture may omit the collection of statistics from any dealer, manufacturer, growers’ cooperative association, warehouseman, broker, holder, or owner who does not own and/or have in stock, in the aggregate, fifty thousand pounds or more of leaf tobacco on the date as of which the reports are made. For the purposes of this chapter, any tobacco which has deteriorated on account of age or other causes to the extent that it is not merchantable or is unsuitable for use in manufacturing tobacco products shall be classified with other nondescript tobacco and reported in the “N” group of the type to which it belongs.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idee3af2e2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1929-01-14/ch69/s1">Jan. 14, 1929, ch. 69, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/45/1079">45 Stat. 1079</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1932-07-14/ch480/s1">July 14, 1932, ch. 480, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/47/662">47 Stat. 662</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-27/ch749/s1">Aug. 27, 1935, ch. 749, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/893">49 Stat. 893</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idee3af2e3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idee3af2e4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idee3af2e5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1935—Act <date date="1935-08-27">Aug. 27, 1935</date>, inserted “and Puerto Rico” after “United States”, substituted “seven hundred and fifty thousand cigarettes” for “one million cigarettes” before second proviso and inserted second proviso.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1932—Act <date date="1932-07-14">July 14, 1932</date>, substituted “thirty-five” for “fifty” and “one hundred and eighty-five thousand cigars” and “one million” for “seven hundred and fifty thousand cigarettes”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idee3af2e6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idee3af2e7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Porto Rico” changed to “Puerto Rico” by <ref href="/us/act/1932-05-17/ch190">act May 17, 1932, ch. 190</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/47/158">47 Stat. 158</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="separability" id="idee3af2e8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Separability</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1935-08-27/ch749/s4">Act Aug. 27, 1935, ch. 749, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/894">49 Stat. 894</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1935-08-27/ch749/s4">“If any provision of this Act [amending this section and sections 502 and 505 of this title], or the application of such provision to any person or circumstances, is held invalid, the remainder of the Act and the application of such provisions to persons or circumstances other than those as to which it is held invalid, shall not be affected thereby.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
