<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idefcb7de8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s5671"><num value="5671">§ 5671.</num><heading> Agricultural embargo protection</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefcb7de9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s5671/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Prerequisites; scope of compensation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefcb7dea-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s5671/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the President or other member of the executive branch of the Federal Government causes the export of any agricultural commodity to any country or area of the world to be suspended or restricted for reasons of national security or foreign policy under the Export Administration Act of 1979 (50 U.S.C. App. 2401 et seq.) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002307">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002307"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> or under any other provision of law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefcb7deb-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s5671/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> such suspension or restriction of the export of such agricultural commodity is imposed other than in connection with a suspension or restriction of all exports from the United States to such country or area of the world; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefcb7dec-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s5671/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> sales of such agricultural commodity for export from the United States to such country or area of the world during the year preceding the year in which the suspension or restriction is imposed exceeds 3 percent of the total sales of such commodity for export from the United States to all foreign countries during the year preceding the year in which the suspension or restriction is in effect;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Secretary shall compensate producers of the commodity involved by making payments available to such producers, as provided in subsection (b) of this section.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefcb7ded-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s5671/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount of payments</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Secretary makes payments available to producers under subsection (a), the amount of such payment shall be determined—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefcb7dee-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s5671/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> in the case of an agricultural commodity for which payments are authorized to be made to producers under Title I of the Agricultural Act of 1949 (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1441">7 U.S.C. 1441</ref> et seq.), by multiplying—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idefcb7def-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s5671/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the farm program payment yield for the producer or the yield established for the farm for the commodity involved; by</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idefcb7df0-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s5671/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the crop acreage base established for the commodity; by</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idefcb7df1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s5671/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the amount by which the average market price per unit of such commodity received by producers during the 60-day period immediately following the date of the imposition of the suspension or restriction is less than 100 percent of the parity price for such commodity, as determined by the Secretary on the date of the imposition of the suspension or restriction; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefcb7df2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s5671/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> in the case of other agricultural commodities for which price support is authorized for producers under the Agricultural Act of 1949 (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1421">7 U.S.C. 1421</ref> et seq.), by multiplying the amount by which the average market price per unit of such commodity received by the producers during the 60-day period immediately following the date of the imposition of the suspension or restriction is less than 100 percent of the parity price for such commodity, as determined by the Secretary on the date of the imposition of the suspension or restriction, by the quantity of such commodity sold by the producer during the period that the suspension or restriction is in effect.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefcb7df3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s5671/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Time for payments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Payments under paragraph (1) of subsection (b) shall be made for each marketing year or part thereof during which the suspension or restriction is in effect and shall be made in equal amounts at 90-day intervals, beginning 90 days after the date of the imposition of the suspension or restriction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefcb7df4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s5671/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Commodity Credit Corporation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall use the Commodity Credit Corporation in carrying out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefcb7df5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s5671/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may issue such regulations as are determined necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idefcb7df6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/501/tIV/s411">Pub. L. 95–501, title IV, § 411</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/tXV/s1531">Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1531</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3682">104 Stat. 3682</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idefcb7df7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idefcb7df8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idefcb7df9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Export Administration Act of 1979, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is <ref href="/us/pl/96/72">Pub. L. 96–72</ref>, <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/503">93 Stat. 503</ref>, which was classified principally to section 2401 et seq. of the former Appendix to Title 50, War and National Defense, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as chapter 56 (§ 4601 et seq.) of Title 50, and was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tXVII/s1766/a">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XVII, § 1766(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/2232">132 Stat. 2232</ref>, except for sections 11A, 11B, and 11C thereof (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4611">50 U.S.C. 4611</ref>, 4612, 4613).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Agricultural Act of 1949, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), (2), is <ref href="/us/act/1949-10-31/ch792">act Oct. 31, 1949, ch. 792</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/1051">63 Stat. 1051</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 35A (§ 1421 et seq.) of this title. Title I of the Act is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 1441 et seq.) of chapter 35A of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1421">section 1421 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
