<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idefd06002-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s5851"><num value="5851">§ 5851.</num><heading> Short title and purposes</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefd06003-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s5851/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Short title</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This subchapter may be cited as the “National Agricultural Weather Information System Act of 1990”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idefd06004-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s5851/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The purposes of this subchapter are—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefd06005-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s5851/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to provide a nationally coordinated agricultural weather information system, based on the participation of universities, State programs, Federal agencies, and the private weather consulting sector, and aimed at meeting the weather and climate information needs of agricultural producers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefd06006-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s5851/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to facilitate the collection, organization, and dissemination of advisory weather and climate information relevant to agricultural producers, through the participation of the private sector and otherwise;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefd06007-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s5851/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to provide for research and education on agricultural weather and climate information, aimed at improving the quality and quantity of weather and climate information available to agricultural producers, including research on short-term forecasts of thunderstorms and on extended weather forecasting techniques and models;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefd06008-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s5851/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to encourage, where feasible, greater private sector participation in providing agricultural weather and climate information, to encourage private sector participation in educating and training farmers and others in the proper utilization of agricultural weather and climate information, and to strengthen their ability to provide site-specific weather forecasting for farmers and the agricultural sector in general; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idefd06009-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s5851/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> to ensure that the weather and climate data bases needed by the agricultural sector are of the highest scientific accuracy and thoroughly documented, and that such data bases are easily accessible for remote computer access.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idefd0600a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/624/tXVI/s1637">Pub. L. 101–624, title XVI, § 1637</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3747">104 Stat. 3747</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
