<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idedbc9b0a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6"><num value="6">§ 6.</num><heading> Regulation of futures trading and foreign transactions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idedbc9b0b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Restriction on futures trading</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Unless exempted by the Commission pursuant to subsection (c) or by subsection (e), it shall be unlawful for any person to offer to enter into, to enter into, to execute, to confirm the execution of, or to conduct any office or business anywhere in the United States, its territories or possessions, for the purpose of soliciting or accepting any order for, or otherwise dealing in, any transaction in, or in connection with, a contract for the purchase or sale of a commodity for future delivery (other than a contract which is made on or subject to the rules of a board of trade, exchange, or market located outside the United States, its territories or possessions) unless—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b0c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> such transaction is conducted on or subject to the rules of a board of trade which has been designated or registered by the Commission as a contract market or derivatives transaction execution facility for such commodity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b0d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> such contract is executed or consummated by or through a contract market; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b0e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> such contract is evidenced by a record in writing which shows the date, the parties to such contract and their addresses, the property covered and its price, and the terms of delivery: <i>Provided</i>, That each contract market or derivatives transaction execution facility member shall keep such record for a period of three years from the date thereof, or for a longer period if the Commission shall so direct, which record shall at all times be open to the inspection of any representative of the Commission or the Department of Justice.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idedbc9b0f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulation of foreign transactions by United States persons</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idedbc9b10-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Foreign boards of trade</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idedbc9b11-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Registration</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Commission may adopt rules and regulations requiring registration with the Commission for a foreign board of trade that provides the members of the foreign board of trade or other participants located in the United States with direct access to the electronic trading and order matching system of the foreign board of trade, including rules and regulations prescribing procedures and requirements applicable to the registration of such foreign boards of trade. For purposes of this paragraph, “direct access” refers to an explicit grant of authority by a foreign board of trade to an identified member or other participant located in the United States to enter trades directly into the trade matching system of the foreign board of trade. In adopting such rules and regulations, the commission <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002015">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002015"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “Commission”.</note> shall consider—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idedbc9b12-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> whether any such foreign board of trade is subject to comparable, comprehensive supervision and regulation by the appropriate governmental authorities in the foreign board of trade’s home country; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idedbc9b13-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any previous commission <sup>1</sup> findings that the foreign board of trade is subject to comparable comprehensive supervision and regulation by the appropriate government authorities in the foreign board of trade’s home country.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idedbc9b14-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Linked contracts</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Commission may not permit a foreign board of trade to provide to the members of the foreign board of trade or other participants located in the United States direct access to the electronic trading and order-matching system of the foreign board of trade with respect to an agreement, contract, or transaction that settles against any price (including the daily or final settlement price) of 1 or more contracts listed for trading on a registered entity, unless the Commission determines that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idedbc9b15-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the foreign board of trade makes public daily trading information regarding the agreement, contract, or transaction that is comparable to the daily trading information published by the registered entity for the 1 or more contracts against which the agreement, contract, or transaction traded on the foreign board of trade settles; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idedbc9b16-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> the foreign board of trade (or the foreign futures authority that oversees the foreign board of trade)—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idedbc9b17-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b/1/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> adopts position limits (including related hedge exemption provisions) for the agreement, contract, or transaction that are comparable to the position limits (including related hedge exemption provisions) adopted by the registered entity for the 1 or more contracts against which the agreement, contract, or transaction traded on the foreign board of trade settles;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idedbc9b18-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b/1/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> has the authority to require or direct market participants to limit, reduce, or liquidate any position the foreign board of trade (or the foreign futures authority that oversees the foreign board of trade) determines to be necessary to prevent or reduce the threat of price manipulation, excessive speculation as described in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s6a">section 6a of this title</ref>, price distortion, or disruption of delivery or the cash settlement process;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idedbc9b19-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b/1/B/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><chapeau> agrees to promptly notify the Commission, with regard to the agreement, contract, or transaction that settles against any price (including the daily or final settlement price) of 1 or more contracts listed for trading on a registered entity, of any change regarding—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idedbc9b1a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b/1/B/ii/III/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> the information that the foreign board of trade will make publicly available;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idedbc9b1b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b/1/B/ii/III/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> the position limits that the foreign board of trade or foreign futures authority will adopt and enforce;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idedbc9b1c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b/1/B/ii/III/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content> the position reductions required to prevent manipulation, excessive speculation as described in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s6a">section 6a of this title</ref>, price distortion, or disruption of delivery or the cash settlement process; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idedbc9b1d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b/1/B/ii/III/dd"><num value="dd">(dd)</num><content> any other area of interest expressed by the Commission to the foreign board of trade or foreign futures authority;</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idedbc9b1e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b/1/B/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> provides information to the Commission regarding large trader positions in the agreement, contract, or transaction that is comparable to the large trader position information collected by the Commission for the 1 or more contracts against which the agreement, contract, or transaction traded on the foreign board of trade settles; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idedbc9b1f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b/1/B/ii/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> provides the Commission such information as is necessary to publish reports on aggregate trader positions for the agreement, contract, or transaction traded on the foreign board of trade that are comparable to such reports on aggregate trader positions for the 1 or more contracts against which the agreement, contract, or transaction traded on the foreign board of trade settles.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idedbc9b20-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b/1/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Existing foreign boards of trade</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subparagraphs (A) and (B) shall not be effective with respect to any foreign board of trade to which, prior to <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, the Commission granted direct access permission until the date that is 180 days after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idedbc9b21-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Persons located in the United States</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idedbc9b22-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Commission may adopt rules and regulations proscribing fraud and requiring minimum financial standards, the disclosure of risk, the filing of reports, the keeping of books and records, the safeguarding of customers’ funds, and registration with the Commission by any person located in the United States, its territories or possessions, who engages in the offer or sale of any contract of sale of a commodity for future delivery that is made or to be made on or subject to the rules of a board of trade, exchange, or market located outside the United States, its territories or possessions.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idedbc9b23-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Different requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Rules and regulations described in subparagraph (A) may impose different requirements for such persons depending upon the particular foreign board of trade, exchange, or market involved.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idedbc9b24-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Except as provided in paragraphs (1) and (2), no rule or regulation may be adopted by the Commission under this subsection that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idedbc9b25-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> requires Commission approval of any contract, rule, regulation, or action of any foreign board of trade, exchange, or market, or clearinghouse for such board of trade, exchange, or market; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idedbc9b26-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/b/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> governs in any way any rule or contract term or action of any foreign board of trade, exchange, or market, or clearinghouse for such board of trade, exchange, or market.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idedbc9b27-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Public interest exemptions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idedbc9b28-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In order to promote responsible economic or financial innovation and fair competition, the Commission by rule, regulation, or order, after notice and opportunity for hearing, may (on its own initiative or on application of any person, including any board of trade designated or registered as a contract market or derivatives transaction execution facility for transactions for future delivery in any commodity under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7">section 7 of this title</ref>) exempt any agreement, contract, or transaction (or class thereof) that is otherwise subject to subsection (a) (including any person or class of persons offering, entering into, rendering advice or rendering other services with respect to, the agreement, contract, or transaction), either unconditionally or on stated terms or conditions or for stated periods and either retroactively or prospectively, or both, from any of the requirements of subsection (a), or from any other provision of this chapter (except subparagraphs (C)(ii) and (D) of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2/a/1">section 2(a)(1) of this title</ref>,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002016">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002016"><num>2</num> So in original. A closing parenthesis probably should precede the comma.</note> except that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b29-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> unless the Commission is expressly authorized by any provision described in this subparagraph to grant exemptions, with respect to amendments made by subtitle A of the Wall Street Transparency and Accountability Act of 2010—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idedbc9b2a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> with respect to—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idedbc9b2b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/1/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> paragraphs (2), (3), (4), (5), and (7), paragraph (18)(A)(vii)(III), paragraphs (23), (24), (31), (32), (38), (39), (41), (42), (46), (47), (48), and (49) of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1a">section 1a of this title</ref>, and sections 2(a)(13), 2(c)(1)(D), 6a(a), 6a(b), 6d(c), 6d(d), 6r, 6s, 7a–1(a), 7a–1(b), 7(d), 7(g), 7(h),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002017">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002017"><num>3</num> So in original. <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7">Section 7 of this title</ref> does not contain subsecs. (g) and (h).</note> 7a–1(c), 7a–1(i), 12(e),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002018">4</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002018"><num>4</num> See References in Text note below.</note> and 24a of this title; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idedbc9b2c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/1/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> section 206(e) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002019">5</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002019"><num>5</num> So in original. Section 206 of the Act does not contain a subsec. (e).</note> of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (<ref href="/us/pl/106/102">Public Law 106–102</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78c">15 U.S.C. 78c</ref> note); and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idedbc9b2d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in sections 721(c) and 742 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b2e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Commission and the Securities and Exchange Commission may by rule, regulation, or order jointly exclude any agreement, contract, or transaction from <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2/a/1/D">section 2(a)(1)(D) of this title</ref>) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002020">6</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002020"><num>6</num> So in original. The closing parenthesis probably should not appear.</note> if the Commissions determine that the exemption would be consistent with the public interest.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idedbc9b2f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Commission shall not grant any exemption under paragraph (1) from any of the requirements of subsection (a) unless the Commission determines that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b30-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the requirement should not be applied to the agreement, contract, or transaction for which the exemption is sought and that the exemption would be consistent with the public interest and the purposes of this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b31-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> the agreement, contract, or transaction—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idedbc9b32-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> will be entered into solely between appropriate persons; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idedbc9b33-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> will not have a material adverse effect on the ability of the Commission or any contract market or derivatives transaction execution facility to discharge its regulatory or self-regulatory duties under this chapter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idedbc9b34-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this subsection, the term “appropriate person” shall be limited to the following persons or classes thereof:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b35-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A bank or trust company (acting in an individual or fiduciary capacity).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b36-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A savings association.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b37-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> An insurance company.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b38-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> An investment company subject to regulation under the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–1">15 U.S.C. 80a–1</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b39-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> A commodity pool formed or operated by a person subject to regulation under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b3a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/3/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> A corporation, partnership, proprietorship, organization, trust, or other business entity with a net worth exceeding $1,000,000 or total assets exceeding $5,000,000, or the obligations of which under the agreement, contract or transaction are guaranteed or otherwise supported by a letter of credit or keepwell, support, or other agreement by any such entity or by an entity referred to in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (H), (I), or (K) of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b3b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/3/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> An employee benefit plan with assets exceeding $1,000,000, or whose investment decisions are made by a bank, trust company, insurance company, investment adviser registered under the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80b–1">15 U.S.C. 80b–1</ref> et seq.], or a commodity trading advisor subject to regulation under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b3c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/3/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> Any governmental entity (including the United States, any state,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002021">7</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002021"><num>7</num> So in original. Probably should be capitalized.</note> or any foreign government) or political subdivision thereof, or any multinational or supranational entity or any instrumentality, agency, or department of any of the foregoing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b3d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/3/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> A broker-dealer subject to regulation under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78a">15 U.S.C. 78a</ref> et seq.) acting on its own behalf or on behalf of another appropriate person.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b3e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/3/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><content> A futures commission merchant, floor broker, or floor trader subject to regulation under this chapter acting on its own behalf or on behalf of another appropriate person.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b3f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/3/K"><num value="K">(K)</num><content> Such other persons that the Commission determines to be appropriate in light of their financial or other qualifications, or the applicability of appropriate regulatory protections.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idedbc9b40-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> During the pendency of an application for an order granting an exemption under paragraph (1), the Commission may limit the public availability of any information received from the applicant if the applicant submits a written request to limit disclosure contemporaneous with the application, and the Commission determines that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b41-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the information sought to be restricted constitutes a trade secret; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b42-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> public disclosure of the information would result in material competitive harm to the applicant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idedbc9b43-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> The Commission may—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b44-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> promptly following <date date="1992-10-28">October 28, 1992</date>, or upon application by any person, exercise the exemptive authority granted under paragraph (1) with respect to classes of hybrid instruments that are predominantly securities or depository instruments, to the extent that such instruments may be regarded as subject to the provisions of this chapter; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b45-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> promptly following <date date="1992-10-28">October 28, 1992</date>, or upon application by any person, exercise the exemptive authority granted under paragraph (1) effective as of <date date="1974-10-23">October 23, 1974</date>, with respect to classes of swap agreements (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of title 11</ref>) that are not part of a fungible class of agreements that are standardized as to their material economic terms, to the extent that such agreements may be regarded as subject to the provisions of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Any exemption pursuant to this paragraph shall be subject to such terms and conditions as the Commission shall determine to be appropriate pursuant to paragraph (1).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idedbc9b46-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> If the Commission determines that the exemption would be consistent with the public interest and the purposes of this chapter, the Commission shall, in accordance with paragraphs (1) and (2), exempt from the requirements of this chapter an agreement, contract, or transaction that is entered into—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b47-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> pursuant to a tariff or rate schedule approved or permitted to take effect by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b48-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> pursuant to a tariff or rate schedule establishing rates or charges for, or protocols governing, the sale of electric energy approved or permitted to take effect by the regulatory authority of the State or municipality having jurisdiction to regulate rates and charges for the sale of electric energy within the State or municipality; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbc9b49-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/c/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> between entities described in <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s824/f">section 824(f) of title 16</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idedbc9b4a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of exemption on investigative authority of Commission</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The granting of an exemption under this section shall not affect the authority of the Commission under any other provision of this chapter to conduct investigations in order to determine compliance with the requirements or conditions of such exemption or to take enforcement action for any violation of any provision of this chapter or any rule, regulation or order thereunder caused by the failure to comply with or satisfy such conditions or requirements.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idedbc9b4b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Liability of registered persons trading on a foreign board of trade</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idedbc9b4c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A person registered with the Commission, or exempt from registration by the Commission, under this chapter may not be found to have violated subsection (a) with respect to a transaction in, or in connection with, a contract of sale of a commodity for future delivery if the person—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idedbc9b4d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> has reason to believe that the transaction and the contract is made on or subject to the rules of a foreign board of trade that is—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idedbc9b4e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/e/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> legally organized under the laws of a foreign country;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idedbc9b4f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/e/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> authorized to act as a board of trade by a foreign futures authority; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idedbc9b50-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/e/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> subject to regulation by the foreign futures authority; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idedbc9b51-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> has not been determined by the Commission to be operating in violation of subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idedbc9b52-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as implying or creating any presumption that a board of trade, exchange, or market is located outside the United States, or its territories or possessions, for purposes of subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idedbc9b53-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1922-09-21/ch369/s4">Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 369, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/999">42 Stat. 999</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1936-06-15/ch545">June 15, 1936, ch. 545</ref>, §§ 2, 4, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1491">49 Stat. 1491</ref>, 1492; <ref href="/us/pl/93/463/tI/s103/a">Pub. L. 93–463, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, (f), <date date="1974-10-23">Oct. 23, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1392">88 Stat. 1392</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/444/tII/s204">Pub. L. 97–444, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1983-01-11">Jan. 11, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2299">96 Stat. 2299</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/546/tV/s502/a">Pub. L. 102–546, title V, § 502(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3629">106 Stat. 3629</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tI/s123/a/3">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title I, § 123(a)(3)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2763">114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–406; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tVII">Pub. L. 111–203, title VII</ref>, §§ 721(d), 722(f), 738(a), (b), <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1671">124 Stat. 1671</ref>, 1674, 1726, 1728.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idedbc9b54-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idedbc9b55-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idedbc9b56-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subtitle A of the Wall Street Transparency and Accountability Act of 2010, referred to in subsec. (c)(1)(A), is subtitle A (§§ 721–754) of title VII of <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1641">124 Stat. 1641</ref>. For complete classification of subtitle A to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t7/s12/e">Section 12(e) of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (c)(1)(A)(i)(I), was in the original a reference to section “8e” and has been translated as if the reference had been to section “8(e)” to reflect the probable intent of Congress. Section 8e of act <date date="1922-09-21">Sept. 21, 1922</date>, which was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s12e">section 12e of this title</ref>, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tI/s123/a/21">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title I, § 123(a)(21)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2763">114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–410.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, referred to in subsec. (c)(1)(A)(ii), is <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1376">124 Stat. 1376</ref>. Section 721(c) of the Act is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s8321/b">section 8321(b) of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade. Section 742 of the Act amended <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2">section 2 of this title</ref> and provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78c">section 78c of Title 15</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s5301">section 5301 of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking, and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Investment Company Act of 1940, referred to in subsec. (c)(3)(D), is title I of <ref href="/us/act/1940-08-22/ch686">act Aug. 22, 1940, ch. 686</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/54/789">54 Stat. 789</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 80a–1 et seq.) of chapter 2D of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80a–51">section 80a–51 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Investment Advisers Act of 1940, referred to in subsec. (c)(3)(G), is title II of <ref href="/us/act/1940-08-22/ch686">act Aug. 22, 1940, ch. 686</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/54/847">54 Stat. 847</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 80b–1 et seq.) of chapter 2D of Title 15. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s80b–20">section 80b–20 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Securities Exchange Act of 1934, referred to in subsec. (c)(3)(I), is <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-06/ch404">act June 6, 1934, ch. 404</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/881">48 Stat. 881</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 2B (§ 78a et seq.) of Title 15. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78a">section 78a of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idedbc9b57-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s738/b/1">Pub. L. 111–203, § 738(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “or by subsection (e)” after “Unless exempted by the Commission pursuant to subsection (c)” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s738/a/1">Pub. L. 111–203, § 738(a)(1)</ref>–(3), designated existing provisions as par. (2), designated the first to third sentences as subpars. (A) to (C), respectively, redesignated former pars. (1) and (2) as cls. (i) and (ii), respectively, of subpar. (C), inserted headings, in subpar. (B), substituted “Rules and regulations described in subparagraph (A)” for “Such rules and regulations”, in the introductory provisions of subpar. (C), substituted “Except as provided in paragraphs (1) and (2), no rule or regulation” for “No rule or regulation” and “that—” for “that”, and, in subpar. (C)(i), substituted “market; or” for “market, or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s738/a/4">Pub. L. 111–203, § 738(a)(4)</ref>, added par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s721/d">Pub. L. 111–203, § 721(d)</ref>, substituted “except that—” for “except that the Commission and the Securities and Exchange Commission may by rule, regulation, or order jointly exclude any agreement, contract, or transaction from <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2/a/1/D">section 2(a)(1)(D) of this title</ref>), if the Commission determines that the exemption would be consistent with the public interest.” and added subpars. (A) and (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s722/f">Pub. L. 111–203, § 722(f)</ref>, added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s738/b/2">Pub. L. 111–203, § 738(b)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tI/s123/a/3/A/i">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title I, § 123(a)(3)(A)(i)]</ref>, substituted “designated or registered by the Commission as a contract market or derivatives transaction execution facility for” for “designated by the Commission as a ‘contract market’ for”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tI/s123/a/3/A/ii">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title I, § 123(a)(3)(A)(ii)]</ref>, struck out “member of such” after “by or through a”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tI/s123/a/3/A/iii">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title I, § 123(a)(3)(A)(iii)]</ref>, inserted “or derivatives transaction execution facility” after “contract market”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tI/s123/a/3/B/i">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title I, § 123(a)(3)(B)(i)]</ref>, substituted “designated or registered as a contract market or derivatives transaction execution facility” for “designated as a contract market” and “subparagraphs (C)(ii) and (D) of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2/a/1">section 2(a)(1) of this title</ref>, except that the Commission and the Securities and Exchange Commission may by rule, regulation, or order jointly exclude any agreement, contract, or transaction from <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2/a/1/D">section 2(a)(1)(D) of this title</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2a">section 2a of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tI/s123/a/3/B/ii">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title I, § 123(a)(3)(B)(ii)]</ref>, inserted “or derivatives transaction execution facility” after “contract market”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/546/s502/a/1">Pub. L. 102–546, § 502(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Unless exempted by the Commission pursuant to subsection (c) of this section, it shall be unlawful” for “It shall be unlawful”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/102/546/s502/a/2">Pub. L. 102–546, § 502(a)(2)</ref>, added subsecs. (c) and (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—<ref href="/us/pl/97/444">Pub. L. 97–444</ref> amended section generally, combining into subsec. (a) existing provisions of this section together with provisions formerly contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s6h/1">section 6h(1) of this title</ref>, relating to the conduct of offices or places of business anywhere in the United States or its territories that are used for dealing in commodities for future delivery unless such dealings are executed or consummated by or through a member of a contract market, and adding subsec. (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—<ref href="/us/pl/93/463">Pub. L. 93–463</ref> substituted “Commission” for “Secretary of Agriculture” and “United States Department of Agriculture”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1936—Act <date date="1936-06-15">June 15, 1936</date>, § 2, substituted “commodity” for “grain” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act <date date="1936-06-15">June 15, 1936</date>, § 4, struck out par. (a) and combined par. (b) with first par.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idedbc9b58-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedbc9b59-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective on the later of 360 days after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, or, to the extent a provision of subtitle A (§§ 711–754) of title VII of <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> requires a rulemaking, not less than 60 days after publication of the final rule or regulation implementing such provision of subtitle A, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s754">section 754 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1a">section 1a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedbc9b5a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1983 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/444">Pub. L. 97–444</ref> effective <date date="1983-01-11">Jan. 11, 1983</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/444/s239">section 239 of Pub. L. 97–444</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedbc9b5b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1974 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/93/463">Pub. L. 93–463</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/463/s418">section 418 of Pub. L. 93–463</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedbc9b5c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1936 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by act <date date="1936-06-15">June 15, 1936</date>, effective 90 days after <date date="1936-06-15">June 15, 1936</date>, see section 13 of that act, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
