<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idee4949e9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s608e–1"><num value="608e–1">§ 608e–1.</num><heading> Import prohibitions on specified foreign produce</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee4949ea-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s608e–1/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Import prohibitions on tomatoes, avocados, limes, etc.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to the provisions of subsections (c) and (d) and notwithstanding any other provision of law, whenever a marketing order issued by the Secretary of Agriculture pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s608c">section 608c of this title</ref> contains any terms or conditions regulating the grade, size, quality, or maturity of tomatoes, raisins, olives (other than Spanish-style green olives), prunes, avocados, mangoes, limes, grapefruit, green peppers, Irish potatoes, cucumbers, oranges, onions, walnuts, cherries, pecans, dates, filberts, table grapes, eggplants, kiwifruit, nectarines, clementines, plums, pistachios, apples, or caneberries (including raspberries, blackberries, and loganberries) produced in the United States the importation into the United States of any such commodity, other than dates for processing, during the period of time such order is in effect shall be prohibited unless it complies with the grade, size, quality, and maturity provisions of such order or comparable restrictions promulgated hereunder: <i>Provided</i>, That this prohibition shall not apply to such commodities when shipped into continental United States from the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico or any Territory or possession of the United States where this chapter has force and effect: <i>Provided further</i>, That whenever two or more such marketing orders regulating the same agricultural commodity produced in different areas of the United States are concurrently in effect, the importation into the United States of any such commodity, other than dates for processing, shall be prohibited unless it complies with the grade, size, quality, and maturity provisions of the order which, as determined by the Secretary of Agriculture, regulates the commodity produced in the area with which the imported commodity is in most direct competition. Such prohibition shall not become effective until after the giving of such notice as the Secretary of Agriculture determines reasonable, which shall not be less than three days. In determining the amount of notice that is reasonable in the case of tomatoes the Secretary of Agriculture shall give due consideration to the time required for their transportation and entry into the United States after picking. Whenever the Secretary of Agriculture finds that the application of the restrictions under a marketing order to an imported commodity is not practicable because of variations in characteristics between the domestic and imported commodity he shall establish with respect to the imported commodity, other than dates for processing, such grade, size, quality, and maturity restrictions by varieties, types, or other classifications as he finds will be equivalent or comparable to those imposed upon the domestic commodity under such order. The Secretary of Agriculture may promulgate such rules and regulations as he deems necessary, to carry out the provisions of this section. Any person who violates any provision if <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002113">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002113"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “of”.</note> this section or of any rule, regulation, or order promulgated hereunder shall be subject to a forfeiture in the amount prescribed in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s608a/5">section 608a(5) of this title</ref> or, upon conviction, a penalty in the amount prescribed in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s608c/14">section 608c(14) of this title</ref>, or to both such forfeiture and penalty.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee4949eb-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s608e–1/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Extension of time for marketing order; factors; review</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idee4949ec-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s608e–1/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary may provide for a period of time (not to exceed 35 days) in addition to the period of time covered by a marketing order during which the marketing order requirements would be in effect for a particular commodity during any year if the Secretary determines that such additional period of time is necessary—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee4949ed-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s608e–1/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to effectuate the purposes of this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee4949ee-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s608e–1/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to prevent the circumvention of the grade, size, quality, or maturity standards of a seasonal marketing order applicable to a commodity produced in the United States by imports of such commodity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idee4949ef-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s608e–1/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> In making the determination required by paragraph (1), the Secretary, through notice and comment procedures, shall consider—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee4949f0-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s608e–1/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to what extent, during the previous year, imports of a commodity that did not meet the requirements of a marketing order applicable to such commodity were marketed in the United States during the period that such marketing order requirements were in effect for available domestic commodities (or would have been marketed during such time if not for any additional period established by the Secretary);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee4949f1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s608e–1/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if the importation into the United States of such commodity did, or was likely to, circumvent the grade, size, quality or maturity standards of a seasonal marketing order applicable to such commodity produced in the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee4949f2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s608e–1/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the availability and price of commodities of the variety covered by the marketing order during any additional period the marketing order requirements are to be in effect.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idee4949f3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s608e–1/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> An additional period established by the Secretary in accordance with this subsection shall be—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee4949f4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s608e–1/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> announced not later than 30 days before the date such additional period is to be in effect; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee4949f5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s608e–1/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> reviewed by the Secretary on request, through notice and comment procedures, at least every 3 years in order to determine if the additional period is still needed to prevent circumvention of the seasonal marketing order by imported commodities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idee4949f6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s608e–1/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> For the purposes of carrying out this subsection, the Secretary is authorized to make such reasonable inspections as may be necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee4949f7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s608e–1/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification of United States Trade Representative of import restrictions; advisement of Secretary of Agriculture</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Prior to any import prohibition or regulation under this section being made effective with respect to any commodity—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee4949f8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s608e–1/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Secretary of Agriculture shall notify the United States Trade Representative of such import prohibition or regulation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee4949f9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s608e–1/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the United States Trade Representative shall advise the Secretary of Agriculture, within 60 days of the notification under paragraph (1), to ensure that the application of the grade, size, quality, and maturity provisions of the relevant marketing order, or comparable restrictions, to imports is not inconsistent with United States international obligations under any trade agreement, including the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idee4949fa-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s608e–1/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Proposed prohibition or regulation; authority of Secretary of Agriculture to proceed</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may proceed with the proposed prohibition or regulation if the Secretary receives the advice and concurrence of the United States Trade Representative within 60 days of the notification under subsection (c)(1).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idee4949fb-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1933-05-12/ch25">May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 8e, as added <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-28/ch1041">Aug. 28, 1954, ch. 1041</ref>, title IV, § 401(e), <ref href="/us/stat/68/907">68 Stat. 907</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-31/ch1172/s3/a">Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1172, § 3(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/1047">68 Stat. 1047</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/128/tI/s141/5">Pub. L. 87–128, title I, § 141(5)</ref>, <date date="1961-08-08">Aug. 8, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/305">75 Stat. 305</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/670/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 91–670, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1971-01-11">Jan. 11, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/2047">84 Stat. 2047</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/113/tX/s1006">Pub. L. 95–113, title X, § 1006</ref>, <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/951">91 Stat. 951</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/312/s2">Pub. L. 97–312, § 2</ref>, <date date="1982-10-14">Oct. 14, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1461">96 Stat. 1461</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tIV/s4603">Pub. L. 100–418, title IV, § 4603</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1407">102 Stat. 1407</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/tXIII">Pub. L. 101–624, title XIII</ref>, §§ 1307, 1308, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3561">104 Stat. 3561</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/171/tX/s10601/b">Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10601(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/511">116 Stat. 511</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/234/tX/s10102">Pub. L. 110–234, title X, § 10102</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1335">122 Stat. 1335</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title X, § 10102, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1664">122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2097; <ref href="/us/pl/115/334/tXII/s12503">Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12503</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4987">132 Stat. 4987</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idee4949fc-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idee4949fd-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idee4949fe-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> made identical amendments to this section. The amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> were repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idee4949ff-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/115/334">Pub. L. 115–334</ref> inserted “cherries, pecans,” after “walnuts,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s10102">Pub. L. 110–246, § 10102</ref>, inserted “clementines,” after “nectarines,” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/107/171">Pub. L. 107–171</ref> substituted “apples, or caneberries (including raspberries, blackberries, and loganberries)” for “or apples” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624">Pub. L. 101–624</ref>, §§ 1307, 1308(1), substituted “Subject to the provisions of subsections (c) and (d) of this section and notwithstanding any other provision of law,” for “Notwithstanding any other provision of law,” and “eggplants, kiwifruit, nectarines, plums, pistachios, or apples” for “or eggplants”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s1308/2">Pub. L. 101–624, § 1308(2)</ref>, added subsecs. (c) and (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—<ref href="/us/pl/97/312">Pub. L. 97–312</ref> extended import prohibition to table grapes.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—<ref href="/us/pl/95/113">Pub. L. 95–113</ref> extended import prohibition to filberts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1971—<ref href="/us/pl/91/670">Pub. L. 91–670</ref> extended import prohibition to raisins, olives (other than Spanish-style green olives), and prunes.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1961—<ref href="/us/pl/87/128">Pub. L. 87–128</ref> extended importation prohibition to oranges, onions, walnuts and dates, other than dates for processing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1954—Act <date date="1954-08-31">Aug. 31, 1954</date>, made section applicable to mangoes.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idee494a00-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idee494a01-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment of this section and repeal of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> effective <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8701">section 8701 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idee494a02-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1977 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/113">Pub. L. 95–113</ref> effective <date date="1977-10-01">Oct. 1, 1977</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/113/s1901">section 1901 of Pub. L. 95–113</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1307">section 1307 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idee494a03-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1954 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1954-08-31/ch1172/s3/b">Act Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1172, § 3(b)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/1047">68 Stat. 1047</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1954-08-31/ch1172/s3/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall become effective upon the enactment of this Act [<date date="1954-08-31">Aug. 31, 1954</date>] or upon the enactment of the Agricultural Act of 1954 [<date date="1954-08-28">Aug. 28, 1954</date>], whichever occurs later.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
