<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idee52bfee-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s616"><num value="616">§ 616.</num><heading> Stock on hand when tax takes effect or terminates</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idee52bfef-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s616/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> Upon the sale or other disposition of any article processed wholly or in chief value from any commodity with respect to which a processing tax is to be levied, that on the date the tax first takes effect or wholly terminates with respect to the commodity, is held for sale or other disposition (including articles in transit) by any person, there shall be made a tax adjustment as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee52bff0-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s616/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Whenever the processing tax first takes effect, there shall be levied, assessed, and collected a tax to be paid by such person equivalent to the amount of the processing tax which would be payable with respect to the commodity from which processed if the processing had occurred on such date. Such tax upon articles imported prior to, but in customs custody or control on, the effective date, shall be paid prior to release therefrom. In the case of sugar, the tax on floor stocks, except the retail stocks of persons engaged in retail trade, shall be paid for the month in which the stocks are sold, or used in the manufacture of other articles, under rules and regulations prescribed by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee52bff1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s616/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Whenever the processing tax is wholly terminated, (A) there shall be refunded or credited in the case of a person holding such stocks with respect to which a tax under this chapter has been paid, or (B) there shall be credited or abated in the case of a person holding such stocks with respect to which a tax under this chapter is payable, where such person is the processor liable for the payment of such tax, or (C) there shall be refunded or credited (but not before the tax has been paid) in the case of a person holding such stocks with respect to which a tax under this chapter is payable, where such person is not the processor liable for the payment of such tax, a sum in an amount equivalent to the processing tax which would have been payable with respect to the commodity from which processed if the processing had occurred on such date: <i>Provided</i>, That in the case of any commodity with respect to which there was any increase, effective prior to <date date="1934-06-01">June 1, 1934</date>, in the rate of the processing tax, no such refund, credit, or abatement, shall be in an amount which exceeds the equivalent of the initial rate of the processing tax in effect with respect to such commodity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idee52bff2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s616/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The tax imposed by subsection (a) of this section shall not apply to the retail stocks of persons engaged in retail trade, held at the date the processing tax first takes effect; but such retail stocks shall not be deemed to include stocks held in a warehouse on such date, or such portion of other stocks held on such date as are not sold or otherwise disposed of within thirty days thereafter. Except as to flour and prepared flour, and cereal preparations made chiefly from wheat, as classified in Wheat Regulations, Series 1, Supplement 1, and as to any article processed wholly or in chief value from cotton, the tax refund, credit, or abatement provided in subsection (a) of this section shall not apply to the retail stocks of persons engaged in retail trade, nor to any article (except sugar) processed wholly or in chief value from sugar beets, sugarcane, or any product thereof, nor to any article (except flour, prepared flour and cereal preparations made chiefly from wheat, as classified in Wheat Regulations, Series 1, Supplement 1) processed wholly or in chief value from wheat, held on the date the processing tax is wholly terminated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idee52bff3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s616/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idee52bff4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s616/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any sugar, imported prior to the effective date of a processing tax on sugar beets and sugarcane, with respect to which it is established (under regulations prescribed by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue, with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury) that there was paid at the time of importation a duty at the rate in effect on <date date="1934-01-01">January 1, 1934</date>, and (2) any sugar held on <date date="1934-04-25">April 25, 1934</date>, by, or to be delivered under a bona fide contract of sale entered into prior to <date date="1934-04-25">April 25, 1934</date>, to, any manufacturer or converter, for use in the production of any article (except sugar) and not for ultimate consumption as sugar, and (3) any article (except sugar) processed wholly or in chief value from sugar beets, sugarcane, or any product thereof, shall be exempt from taxation under subsection (a) of this section, but sugar held in customs custody or control on <date date="1934-04-25">April 25, 1934</date>, shall not be exempt from taxation under subsection (a) of this section, unless the rate of duty paid upon the withdrawal thereof was the rate of duty in effect on <date date="1934-01-01">January 1, 1934</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idee52bff5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s616/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to purchase, out of such proceeds of taxes as are available therefor, during the period this chapter is in effect with respect to sugar beets and sugarcane, not in excess of three hundred thousand tons of sugar raw value from the surplus stocks of direct-consumption sugar produced in the United States beet-sugar area, at a price not in excess of the market price for direct consumption sugar on the date of purchase, and to dispose of such sugar by sale or otherwise, including distribution to any organization for the relief of the unemployed, under such conditions and at such times as will tend to effectuate the declared policy of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s608a">section 608a of this title</ref>. The sugar so purchased shall not be included in the quota for the United States beet-sugar area. All proceeds received by the Secretary of Agriculture, in the exercise of the powers granted, are appropriated to be available to the Secretary of Agriculture for the purposes described in subsections (a) and (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s612">section 612 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idee52bff6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s616/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><chapeau> Upon the sale or other disposition of any article processed wholly or in chief value from any commodity with respect to which the existing rate of the processing tax is to be increased, or decreased, that on the date such increase, or decrease, first takes effect with respect to the commodity, is held for sale or other disposition (including articles in transit) by any person, and upon the production of any article from a commodity in process on the date on which the rate of the processing tax is to be increased or decreased, there shall be made a tax adjustment as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee52bff7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s616/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Whenever, on or after <date date="1934-06-01">June 1, 1934</date>, the rate of the processing tax on the processing of the commodity generally or for any designated use or uses, or as to any designated product or products thereof for any designated use or uses, or as to any class of products, is decreased, there shall be credited or refunded to such person an amount equivalent to the difference between the rate of the processing tax payable or paid at the time immediately preceding the decrease in rate and the rate of the processing tax which would have been payable with respect to the commodity from which processed, if the processing had occurred on such date: <i>Provided, however</i>, That no such credit or refund shall be made in the case of hogs unless the rate of the processing tax immediately preceding said decrease is equal to, or less than, the rate of the processing tax in effect on the date on which any floor stocks tax was paid prior to the adoption of this subsection. In the case of wheat the provisions of this paragraph and of paragraph (2) of this subsection shall apply to flour, prepared flour and cereal preparations made chiefly from wheat, as classified in Wheat Regulations, Series 1, Supplement 1 only; in the case of sugarcane and sugar beets the provisions of this paragraph and of paragraph (2) of this subsection shall apply to sugar only.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee52bff8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s616/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Whenever the rate of the processing tax on the processing of the commodity generally, or for any designated use or uses, or as to any designated product or products thereof for any designated use or uses, or as to any class of products, is increased, there shall be levied, assessed and collected a tax to be paid by such person equivalent to the difference between the rate of the processing tax payable or paid at the time immediately preceding the increase in rate and the rate of the processing tax which would be payable with respect to the commodity from which processed, if the processing had occurred on such date.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee52bff9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s616/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Whenever the processing tax is suspended or is to be refunded pursuant to a certification of the Secretary of Agriculture to the Secretary of the Treasury, under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s615/a">section 615(a) of this title</ref>, the provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection shall become applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee52bffa-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s616/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Whenever the Secretary of Agriculture revokes any certification to the Secretary of the Treasury under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s615/a">section 615(a) of this title</ref>, the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection shall become applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idee52bffb-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s616/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The provisions of this subsection shall be effective on and after <date date="1934-06-01">June 1, 1934</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idee52bffc-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s616/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> The provisions of this section shall not be applicable with respect to rice.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idee52bffd-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1933-05-12/ch25">May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 16, <ref href="/us/stat/48/40">48 Stat. 40</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1934-05-09/ch263">May 9, 1934, ch. 263</ref>, §§ 10, 17, <ref href="/us/stat/48/676">48 Stat. 676</ref>, 678; <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-26/ch759/s1">June 26, 1934, ch. 759, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1241">48 Stat. 1241</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-03-18/ch32/s10">Mar. 18, 1935, ch. 32, § 10</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/48">49 Stat. 48</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-24/ch641">Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641</ref>, §§ 20(b), 25–27, <ref href="/us/stat/49/768">49 Stat. 768</ref>, 769; <ref href="/us/act/1936-06-04/ch501">June 4, 1936, ch. 501</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1464">49 Stat. 1464</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1936-06-22/ch690/s601/a">June 22, 1936, ch. 690, § 601(a)</ref>, (c), (g), <ref href="/us/stat/49/1739">49 Stat. 1739</ref>, 1740.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idee52bffe-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idee52bfff-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="constitutionality" id="idee52c000-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Constitutionality</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section may be obsolete in view of the Supreme Court’s holding that the processing and floor stock taxes provided for by the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1933 are unconstitutional. See U.S. v. Butler, Mass. 1936, 56 S.Ct. 312, 297 U.S. 1, 80 L.Ed. 477, 102 A.L.R. 914.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idee52c001-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1936—Subsec. (e)(1). Act <date date="1936-06-22">June 22, 1936</date>, § 601(a), (g), reenacted par. (1) for certain refund purposes only and substituted “on or after <date date="1934-06-01">June 1, 1934</date>” for “subsequent to <date date="1934-06-26">June 26, 1934</date>”, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act <date date="1936-06-04">June 4, 1936</date>, substituted “on or after <date date="1934-06-01">June 1, 1934</date>” for “subsequent to <date date="1934-06-26">June 26, 1934</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). Act <date date="1936-06-22">June 22, 1936</date>, § 601(a), reenacted par. (3) for certain refund purposes only.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). Act <date date="1936-06-22">June 22, 1936</date>, § 601(c), repealed subsec. (g) which related to the time for filing refunds.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1935—Subsec. (a)(2). Act <date date="1935-08-24">Aug. 24, 1935</date>, § 25, substituted a new par. (2) for former par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). Act <date date="1935-08-24">Aug. 24, 1935</date>, § 26, amended second sentence generally.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). Act <date date="1935-08-24">Aug. 24, 1935</date>, § 20(b), struck out last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). Act <date date="1935-03-18">Mar. 18, 1935</date>, redesignated former subsec. (c) as (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). Act <date date="1935-08-24">Aug. 24, 1935</date>, § 27(a), inserted “subsequent to <date date="1934-06-26">June 26, 1934</date>” at beginning of paragraph, and “in the case of hogs” after “made” in proviso and inserted “In the case of wheat the provisions of this paragraph and of paragraph (2) of this subsection shall apply to flour, prepared flour and cereal preparations made chiefly from wheat, as classified in Wheat Regulations, Series 1, Supplement 1 only; in the case of sugarcane and sugar beets the provisions of this paragraph and of paragraph (2) of this subsection shall apply to sugar only.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). Act <date date="1935-03-18">Mar. 18, 1935</date>, added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). Act <date date="1935-08-24">Aug. 24, 1935</date>, § 27(b), added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1934—Subsec. (a)(1). Act <date date="1934-05-09">May 9, 1934</date>, § 10, inserted second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). Act <date date="1934-06-26">June 26, 1934</date>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). Act <date date="1934-05-09">May 9, 1934</date>, § 17, added par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). Act <date date="1934-05-09">May 9, 1934</date>, § 17, added subsec. (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idee52c002-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="separability" id="idee52c003-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Separability</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Validity of remainder of this chapter as not affected should any of the provisions of this chapter be declared unconstitutional. See <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s614">section 614 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idee52c004-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Appropriations</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Appropriations for refunds, etc., see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s610">section 610 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idee52c005-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idee52c006-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of all officers of Department of the Treasury, and functions of all agencies and employees of such Department, transferred, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of the Treasury, with power vested in him to authorize their performance or performance of any of his functions, by any of such officers, agencies, and employees, by 1950 Reorg. Plan No. 26, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-07-31">July 31, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 4935, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1280">64 Stat. 1280</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees. Commissioner of Internal Revenue, referred to in this section, is an officer of Department of the Treasury.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
