<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idee52c007-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s617"><num value="617">§ 617.</num><heading> Refund on goods exported; bond to suspend tax on commodity intended for export</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idee52c008-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s617/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Upon the exportation to any foreign country (and/or to the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, the Canal Zone, and the island of Guam) of any product processed wholly or partly from a commodity with respect to which product or commodity a tax has been paid or is payable under this chapter, the tax due and payable or due and paid shall be credited or refunded. Under regulations prescribed by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue, with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury, the credit or refund shall be allowed to the consignor named in the bill of lading under which the product is exported or to the shipper or to the person liable for the tax provided the consignor waives any claim thereto in favor of such shipper or person liable for the tax. In the case of rice, a tax due under this chapter which has been paid by a tax-payment warrant shall be deemed for the purposes of this subsection to have been paid; and with respect to any refund authorized under this section, the amount scheduled by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue for refunding shall be paid, any provision of law notwithstanding. In the case of sugar beets and sugarcane, this subsection shall be applicable to exports of products thereof to the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, the Canal Zone, and/or the island of Guam only if this chapter with respect to sugar beets and sugarcane is not made applicable thereto. The term “product” includes any product exported as merchandise, or as a container for merchandise, or otherwise.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idee52c009-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s617/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Upon the giving of bond satisfactory to the Secretary of the Treasury for the faithful observance of the provisions of this chapter requiring the payment of taxes, any person shall be entitled, without payment of the tax, to process for such exportation any commodity with respect to which a tax is imposed by this chapter, or to hold for such exportation any article processed wholly or partly therefrom.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idee52c00a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1933-05-12/ch25">May 12, 1933, ch. 25</ref>, title I, § 17, <ref href="/us/stat/48/40">48 Stat. 40</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1934-05-09/ch263">May 9, 1934, ch. 263</ref>, §§ 12, 13, <ref href="/us/stat/48/676">48 Stat. 676</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-03-18/ch32/s11">Mar. 18, 1935, ch. 32, § 11</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/48">49 Stat. 48</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-24/ch641/s28">Aug. 24, 1935, ch. 641, § 28</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/770">49 Stat. 770</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1936-06-22/ch690/s601/a">June 22, 1936, ch. 690, § 601(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1739">49 Stat. 1739</ref>; Proc. No. 2695, eff. <date date="1946-07-04">July 4, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 7871, <ref href="/us/stat/60/1352">60 Stat. 1352</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idee52c00b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idee52c00c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idee52c00d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definition of Canal Zone, referred to in subsec. (a), see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3602/b">section 3602(b) of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idee52c00e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References to the Philippine Islands in subsec. (a) were omitted from the Code as obsolete in view of the independence proclaimed by the President of the United States by Proc. No. 2695, cited to text, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1394">section 1394 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="constitutionality" id="idee52c00f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Constitutionality</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Unconstitutionality of processing and floor stock taxes, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s616">section 616 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idee52c010-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1936—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1936-06-22">June 22, 1936</date>, reenacted subsec. (a) for refund purposes only.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1935—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1935-08-24">Aug. 24, 1935</date>, struck out first two sentences and substituted “Upon the exportation to any foreign country (and/or to the Philippine Islands, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, the Canal Zone, and the island of Guam) of any product processed wholly or partly from a commodity with respect to which product or commodity a tax has been paid or is payable under this chapter, the tax due and payable or due and paid shall be credited or refunded. Under regulations prescribed by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue, with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury, the credit or refund shall be allowed to the consignor named in the bill of lading under which the product is exported or to the shipper or to the person liable for the tax provided the consignor waives any claim thereto in favor of such shipper or person liable for the tax.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act <date date="1935-03-18">Mar. 18, 1935</date>, inserted third sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1934—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1934-05-09">May 9, 1934</date>, amended subsec. (a) generally.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). Act <date date="1934-05-09">May 9, 1934</date>, § 13, substituted “partly” for “in chief value”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idee52c011-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="separability" id="idee52c012-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Separability</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Validity of remainder of this chapter as not affected should any of the provisions of this chapter be declared unconstitutional, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s614">section 614 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idee52c013-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Appropriations</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Appropriations for refunds, etc., see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s610">section 610 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idee52c014-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idee52c015-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of all officers of Department of the Treasury, and functions of all agencies and employees of such Department, transferred, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of the Treasury, with power vested in him to authorize their performance or performance of any of his functions, by any of such officers, agencies, and employees, by 1950 Reorg. Plan. No. 26, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-07-31">July 31, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 4935, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1280">64 Stat. 1280</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees. Commissioner of Internal Revenue, referred to in this section, is an officer of Department of the Treasury.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
