<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idede50a29-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s61a"><num value="61a">§ 61a.</num><heading> Annual review meetings with cotton industry representatives; purposes, etc.</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall hold annual meetings with representatives of the cotton industry to review (1) activities and operations under the Cotton Standards Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s51">7 U.S.C. 51</ref> et seq.], and the Cotton Statistics and Estimates Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s471">7 U.S.C. 471</ref> et seq.], (2) activities and operations relating to cotton under the United States Warehouse Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s241">7 U.S.C. 241</ref> et seq.], and (3) the effect of such activities and operations on prices received by producers and sales to domestic and foreign users, for the purpose of improving procedures for financing and administering such activities and operations for the benefit of the industry and the Government. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall take such action as may be necessary to insure that the universal cotton standards system and the licensing and inspection procedures for cotton warehouses are preserved and that the Government cotton classification system continues to operate so that the United States cotton crop is provided an official quality description.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idede50a2a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tI/s156/d">Pub. L. 97–35, title I, § 156(d)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/374">95 Stat. 374</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idede50a2b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idede50a2c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idede50a2d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Cotton Standards Act, referred to in text, probably meaning the United States Cotton Standards Act, is <ref href="/us/act/1923-03-04/ch288">act Mar. 4, 1923, ch. 288</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/1517">42 Stat. 1517</ref>, which is classified generally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s51">section 51 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Cotton Statistics and Estimates Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1927-03-03/ch337">act Mar. 3, 1927, ch. 337</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/1372">44 Stat. 1372</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 19 (§ 471 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s471">section 471 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The United States Warehouse Act, referred to in text, is part C of <ref href="/us/act/1916-08-11/ch313">act Aug. 11, 1916, ch. 313</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/486">39 Stat. 486</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 10 (§ 241 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s241">section 241 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idede50a2e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1981, and not as part of the United States Cotton Standards Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idede50a2f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idede50a30-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tI/s156/e">Pub. L. 97–35, title I, § 156(e)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/374">95 Stat. 374</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/35/tI/s156/e">“The provisions of this section [enacting this section, amending sections 15b, 55, and 473a of this title, and enacting provision set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s473a">section 473a of this title</ref>] shall become effective <date date="1981-10-01">October 1, 1981</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
