<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ideff1a3d8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6922"><num value="6922">§ 6922.</num><heading> Office of Homeland Security</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="ideff1a3d9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6922/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition of agriculture and food defense</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “agriculture and food defense” means any action to prevent, protect against, mitigate the effects of, respond to, or recover from a naturally occurring, unintentional, or intentional threat to the agriculture and food system.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="ideff1a3da-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6922/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish in the Department the Office of Homeland Security.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="ideff1a3db-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6922/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Executive Director</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Office of Homeland Security shall be headed by an Executive Director, who shall be known as the Executive Director of Homeland Security.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="ideff1a3dc-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6922/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Executive Director of Homeland Security shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ideff1a3dd-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6922/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> serve as the principal advisor to the Secretary on homeland security, including emergency management and agriculture and food defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ideff1a3de-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6922/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> coordinate activities of the Department, including policies, processes, budget needs, and oversight relating to homeland security, including emergency management and agriculture and food defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ideff1a3df-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6922/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> act as the primary liaison on behalf of the Department with other Federal departments and agencies in activities relating to homeland security, including emergency management and agriculture and food defense, and provide for interagency coordination and data sharing;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ideff1a3e0-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6922/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ideff1a3e1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6922/d/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> coordinate in the Department the gathering of information relevant to early warning and awareness of threats and risks to the food and agriculture critical infrastructure sector; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ideff1a3e2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6922/d/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> share that information with, and provide assistance with interpretation and risk characterization of that information to, the intelligence community (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of title 50</ref>), law enforcement agencies, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and State fusion centers (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s124h/j">section 124h(j) of title 6</ref> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002319">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002319"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by a closing parenthesis.</note> ;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ideff1a3e3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6922/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> liaise with the Director of National Intelligence to assist in the development of periodic assessments and intelligence estimates, or other intelligence products, that support the defense of the food and agriculture critical infrastructure sector;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ideff1a3e4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6922/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> coordinate the conduct, evaluation, and improvement of exercises to identify and eliminate gaps in preparedness and response;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ideff1a3e5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6922/d/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> produce a Department-wide centralized strategic coordination plan to provide a high-level perspective of the operations of the Department relating to homeland security, including emergency management and agriculture and food defense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ideff1a3e6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6922/d/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> carry out other appropriate duties, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="ideff1a3e7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6922/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Agriculture and food threat awareness partnership program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="ideff1a3e8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6922/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Interagency exchange program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary, in partnership with the intelligence community (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of title 50</ref>) and fusion centers (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s124h/j">section 124h(j) of title 6</ref> <sup>1</sup> that have analysis and intelligence capabilities relating to the defense of the food and agriculture critical infrastructure sector, shall establish and carry out an interagency exchange program of personnel and information to improve communication and analysis for the defense of the food and agriculture critical infrastructure sector.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="ideff1a3e9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6922/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Collaboration with Federal, State, and local authorities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">To carry out the program established under paragraph (1), the Secretary may—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ideff1a3ea-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6922/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> enter into 1 or more cooperative agreements or contracts with Federal, State, or local authorities that have analysis and intelligence capabilities and expertise relating to the defense of the food and agriculture critical infrastructure sector; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ideff1a3eb-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6922/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> carry out any other activity under any other authority of the Secretary that is appropriate to engage the authorities described in subparagraph (A) for the defense of the food and agriculture critical infrastructure sector, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ideff1a3ec-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/354/tII/s221">Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 221</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/115/334/tXII/s12202">Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12202</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4944">132 Stat. 4944</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
