<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idedbee48d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6b"><num value="6b">§ 6b.</num><heading> Contracts designed to defraud or mislead</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idedbee48e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6b/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Unlawful actions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be unlawful—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbee48f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6b/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> for any person, in or in connection with any order to make, or the making of, any contract of sale of any commodity in interstate commerce or for future delivery that is made, or to be made, on or subject to the rules of a designated contract market, for or on behalf of any other person; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbee490-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6b/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> for any person, in or in connection with any order to make, or the making of, any contract of sale of any commodity for future delivery, or swap, that is made, or to be made, for or on behalf of, or with, any other person, other than on or subject to the rules of a designated contract market—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idedbee491-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6b/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to cheat or defraud or attempt to cheat or defraud the other person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idedbee492-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6b/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> willfully to make or cause to be made to the other person any false report or statement or willfully to enter or cause to be entered for the other person any false record;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idedbee493-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6b/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> willfully to deceive or attempt to deceive the other person by any means whatsoever in regard to any order or contract or the disposition or execution of any order or contract, or in regard to any act of agency performed, with respect to any order or contract for or, in the case of paragraph (2), with the other person; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idedbee494-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6b/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idedbee495-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6b/a/2/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to bucket an order if the order is either represented by the person as an order to be executed, or is required to be executed, on or subject to the rules of a designated contract market; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idedbee496-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6b/a/2/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to fill an order by offset against the order or orders of any other person, or willfully and knowingly and without the prior consent of the other person to become the buyer in respect to any selling order of the other person, or become the seller in respect to any buying order of the other person, if the order is either represented by the person as an order to be executed, or is required to be executed, on or subject to the rules of a designated contract market unless the order is executed in accordance with the rules of the designated contract market.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idedbee497-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6b/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Clarification</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subsection (a)(2) of this section shall not obligate any person, in or in connection with a transaction in a contract of sale of a commodity for future delivery, or swap, with another person, to disclose to the other person nonpublic information that may be material to the market price, rate, or level of the commodity or transaction, except as necessary to make any statement made to the other person in or in connection with the transaction not misleading in any material respect.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idedbee498-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6b/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Buying and selling orders for commodity</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section or in any other section of this chapter shall be construed to prevent a futures commission merchant or floor broker who shall have in hand, simultaneously, buying and selling orders at the market for different principals for a like quantity of a commodity for future delivery in the same month executing such buying and selling orders at the market price: <i>Provided</i>, That any such execution shall take place on the floor of the exchange where such orders are to be executed at public outcry across the ring and shall be duly reported, recorded, and cleared in the same manner as other orders executed on such exchange: <i>And provided further</i>, That such transactions shall be made in accordance with such rules and regulations as the Commission may promulgate regarding the manner of the execution of such transactions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idedbee499-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6b/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Inapplicability to transactions on foreign exchanges</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall apply to any activity that occurs on a board of trade, exchange, or market, or clearinghouse for such board of trade, exchange, or market, located outside the United States, or territories or possessions of the United States, involving any contract of sale of a commodity for future delivery that is made, or to be made, on or subject to the rules of such board of trade, exchange, or market.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idedbee49a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6b/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Contracts of sale on group or index of securities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person, directly or indirectly, by the use of any means or instrumentality of interstate commerce, or of the mails, or of any facility of any registered entity, in or in connection with any order to make, or the making of, any contract of sale of any commodity for future delivery (or option on such a contract), or any swap, on a group or index of securities (or any interest therein or based on the value thereof)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbee49b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6b/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to employ any device, scheme, or artifice to defraud;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbee49c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6b/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to make any untrue statement of a material fact or to omit to state a material fact necessary in order to make the statements made, in the light of the circumstances under which they were made, not misleading; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedbee49d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6b/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to engage in any act, practice, or course of business which operates or would operate as a fraud or deceit upon any person.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idedbee49e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1922-09-21/ch369/s4b">Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 369, § 4b</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/act/1936-06-15/ch545/s5">June 15, 1936, ch. 545, § 5</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1493">49 Stat. 1493</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/90/258/s5">Pub. L. 90–258, § 5</ref>, <date date="1968-02-19">Feb. 19, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/27">82 Stat. 27</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/463/tIV/s405">Pub. L. 93–463, title IV, § 405</ref>, <date date="1974-10-23">Oct. 23, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1413">88 Stat. 1413</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/641/tI/s101">Pub. L. 99–641, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1986-11-10">Nov. 10, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3557">100 Stat. 3557</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/546/tIV/s402/3">Pub. L. 102–546, title IV, § 402(3)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3624">106 Stat. 3624</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tI/s123/a/5">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title I, § 123(a)(5)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2763">114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–407; <ref href="/us/pl/110/234/tXIII/s13102">Pub. L. 110–234, title XIII, § 13102</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1432">122 Stat. 1432</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XIII, § 13102, <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1664">122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2194; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tVII/s741/b/1">Pub. L. 111–203, title VII, § 741(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1730">124 Stat. 1730</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idedbee49f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idedbee4a0-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idedbee4a1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> made identical amendments to this section. The amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> were repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idedbee4a2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s741/b/1/A">Pub. L. 111–203, § 741(b)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “or swap,” for “or other agreement, contract, or transaction subject to paragraphs (1) and (2) of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7a/g">section 7a(g) of this title</ref>,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s741/b/1/B">Pub. L. 111–203, § 741(b)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “or swap,” for “or other agreement, contract or transaction subject to paragraphs (1) and (2) of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7a/g">section 7a(g) of this title</ref>,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s741/b/1/C">Pub. L. 111–203, § 741(b)(1)(C)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—<ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s13102">Pub. L. 110–246, § 13102</ref>, inserted section catchline, added subsecs. (a) and (b), redesignated former subsecs. (b) and (c) as (c) and (d), respectively, and struck out former subsec. (a) which related to contracts designed to defraud or mislead and bucketing orders.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/106/554">Pub. L. 106–554</ref> substituted “registered entity” for “contract market” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—<ref href="/us/pl/102/546">Pub. L. 102–546</ref> designated first par. as subsec. (a), redesignated cls. (a) to (c) as subpars. (A) to (C), respectively, and subpars. (A) to (D) as cls. (i) to (iv), respectively, and designated second and third undesignated pars. as subsecs. (b) and (c), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—<ref href="/us/pl/99/641">Pub. L. 99–641</ref> struck out “on or subject to the rules of any contract market,” after “to be made” in cl. (2) of first par. and added concluding paragraph that this section not apply to activity on board of trade, exchange, market, or clearinghouse located outside United States involving contract of sale of commodity for future delivery.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—<ref href="/us/pl/93/463">Pub. L. 93–463</ref> substituted “a commodity” for “cotton” in provisions following subpar. (D) and inserted requirement that execution of buying and selling orders for commodities held simultaneously by the same merchant or broker be carried out in accordance with such rules and regulations as the Commission may promulgate regarding the manner of the execution of such transactions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—<ref href="/us/pl/90/258">Pub. L. 90–258</ref> relocated cl. (1) designation in first par. to follow “unlawful” rather than to precede “any contract of sale”, provided in such cl. (1) for orders to make or making of contracts of sale “made, or to be made on or subject to the rules of any contract market, for or on behalf of any other person” and in cl. (2) “for any person, in or in connection with any order to make, or the making of,” any contract of sale of any commodity for future delivery for or on behalf of any “other” person; and inserted “other” before “person” in subpar. (A) and in subpars. (B) and (C) where appearing for first time, respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idedbee4a3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedbee4a4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective on the later of 360 days after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, or, to the extent a provision of subtitle A (§§ 711–754) of title VII of <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> requires a rulemaking, not less than 60 days after publication of the final rule or regulation implementing such provision of subtitle A, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s754">section 754 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1a">section 1a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedbee4a5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment of this section and repeal of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> effective <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8701">section 8701 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedbee4a6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1974 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/93/463">Pub. L. 93–463</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/463/s418">section 418 of Pub. L. 93–463</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedbee4a7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1968 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/90/258">Pub. L. 90–258</ref> effective 120 days after <date date="1968-02-19">Feb. 19, 1968</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/258/s28">section 28 of Pub. L. 90–258</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idedbee4a8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of section, see section 13 of act <date date="1936-06-15">June 15, 1936</date>, set out as an Effective Date of 1936 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
