<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idedc61086-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6i"><num value="6i">§ 6i.</num><heading> Reports of deals equal to or in excess of trading limits; books and records; cash and controlled transactions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be unlawful for any person to make any contract for the purchase or sale of any commodity for future delivery on or subject to the rules of any contract market or derivatives transaction execution facility, or any significant price discovery contract traded or executed on an electronic trading facility or any agreement, contract, or transaction that is treated by a derivatives clearing organization, whether registered or not registered, as fungible with a significant price discovery contract—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedc61087-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> if such person shall directly or indirectly make such contracts with respect to any commodity or any future of such commodity during any one day in an amount equal to or in excess of such amount as shall be fixed from time to time by the Commission, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedc61088-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> if such person shall directly or indirectly have or obtain a long or short position in any commodity or any future of such commodity equal to or in excess of such amount as shall be fixed from time to time by the Commission,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">unless such person files or causes to be filed with the properly designated officer of the Commission such reports regarding any transactions or positions described in clauses (1) and (2) hereof as the Commission may by rule or regulation require and unless, in accordance with rules and regulations of the Commission, such person shall keep books and records of all such transactions and positions and transactions and positions in any such commodity traded on or subject to the rules of any other board of trade or electronic trading facility, and of cash or spot transactions in, and inventories and purchase and sale commitments of such commodity. Such books and records shall show complete details concerning all such transactions, positions, inventories, and commitments, including the names and addresses of all persons having any interest therein, and shall be open at all times to inspection by any representative of the Commission or the Department of Justice. For the purposes of this section, the futures and cash or spot transactions and positions of any person shall include such transactions and positions of any persons directly or indirectly controlled by such person.</continuation>
<sourceCredit id="idedc61089-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1922-09-21/ch369/s4i">Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 369, § 4i</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/act/1936-06-15/ch545/s5">June 15, 1936, ch. 545, § 5</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1496">49 Stat. 1496</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/90/258/s9">Pub. L. 90–258, § 9</ref>, <date date="1968-02-19">Feb. 19, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/28">82 Stat. 28</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/463/tI/s103/a">Pub. L. 93–463, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, (f), <date date="1974-10-23">Oct. 23, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1392">88 Stat. 1392</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/444/tII/s211">Pub. L. 97–444, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="1983-01-11">Jan. 11, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2303">96 Stat. 2303</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tI/s123/a/9">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title I, § 123(a)(9)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2763">114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–407; <ref href="/us/pl/110/234/tXIII/s13202/b">Pub. L. 110–234, title XIII, § 13202(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1439">122 Stat. 1439</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a)</ref>, title XIII, § 13202(b), <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/1664">122 Stat. 1664</ref>, 2201.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idedc6108a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idedc6108b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idedc6108c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> made identical amendments to this section. The amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> were repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4/a">section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idedc6108d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—<ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s13202/b">Pub. L. 110–246, § 13202(b)</ref>, in introductory provisions, inserted “, or any significant price discovery contract traded or executed on an electronic trading facility or any agreement, contract, or transaction that is treated by a derivatives clearing organization, whether registered or not registered, as fungible with a significant price discovery contract” after “derivatives transaction execution facility” and, in concluding provisions, inserted “or electronic trading facility” after “board of trade”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—<ref href="/us/pl/106/554">Pub. L. 106–554</ref> inserted “or derivatives transaction execution facility” after “contract market” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—<ref href="/us/pl/97/444">Pub. L. 97–444</ref> amended section generally by substantially restating provisions and inserting requirement that persons whose transactions and positions in any cash commodity or commodity future are equal to or in excess of amounts fixed by the Commission, must keep books and records of such transactions and positions as well as books and records of any such commodity traded on or subject to rules of any other board of trade, whether or not such person is required to file reports with the Commission concerning such transactions and positions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—<ref href="/us/pl/93/463">Pub. L. 93–463</ref> substituted “Commission” for “Secretary of Agriculture” and “United States Department of Agriculture”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—<ref href="/us/pl/90/258">Pub. L. 90–258</ref> required recordkeeping of positions and of cash or spot transactions in commodities entered into, and inventories and purchase and sale commitments of commodities held, in any month in which reports are required to be kept, including details concerning positions, inventories, and commitments, and included controlled transactions and positions in the futures and cash or spot transactions and positions of any person.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idedc6108e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedc6108f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment of this section and repeal of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246">Pub. L. 110–246</ref> effective <date date="2008-05-22">May 22, 2008</date>, the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/110/234">Pub. L. 110–234</ref>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8701">section 8701 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s13202/b">section 13202(b) of Pub. L. 110–246</ref> effective <date date="2008-06-18">June 18, 2008</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/246/s13204/a">section 13204(a) of Pub. L. 110–246</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedc61090-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1983 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/444">Pub. L. 97–444</ref> effective <date date="1983-01-11">Jan. 11, 1983</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/444/s239">section 239 of Pub. L. 97–444</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedc61091-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1974 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/93/463">Pub. L. 93–463</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/463/s418">section 418 of Pub. L. 93–463</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedc61092-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1968 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/90/258">Pub. L. 90–258</ref> effective 120 days after <date date="1968-02-19">Feb. 19, 1968</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/258/s28">section 28 of Pub. L. 90–258</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idedc61093-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of section, see section 13 of act <date date="1936-06-15">June 15, 1936</date>, set out as an Effective Date of 1936 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
