<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idedc610cf-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6m"><num value="6m">§ 6m.</num><heading> Use of mails or other means or instrumentalities of interstate commerce by commodity trading advisors and commodity pool operators; relation to other law</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idedc610d0-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6m/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> It shall be unlawful for any commodity trading advisor or commodity pool operator, unless registered under this chapter, to make use of the mails or any means or instrumentality of interstate commerce in connection with his business as such commodity trading advisor or commodity pool operator: <i>Provided</i>, That the provisions of this section shall not apply to any commodity trading advisor who, during the course of the preceding twelve months, has not furnished commodity trading advice to more than fifteen persons and who does not hold himself out generally to the public as a commodity trading advisor. The provisions of this section shall not apply to any commodity trading advisor who is a (1) dealer, processor, broker, or seller in cash market transactions of any commodity specifically set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2/a">section 2(a) of this title</ref> prior to <date date="1974-10-23">October 23, 1974</date>, (or products thereof) or (2) nonprofit, voluntary membership, general farm organization, who provides advice on the sale or purchase of any commodity specifically set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2/a">section 2(a) of this title</ref> prior to <date date="1974-10-23">October 23, 1974</date>; if the advice by the person described in clause (1) or (2) of this sentence as a commodity trading advisor is solely incidental to the conduct of that person’s business: <i>Provided</i>, That such person shall be subject to proceedings under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s18">section 18 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idedc610d1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6m/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Nothing in this chapter shall relieve any person of any obligation or duty, or affect the availability of any right or remedy available to the Securities and Exchange Commission or any private party arising under the Securities Act of 1933 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77a">15 U.S.C. 77a</ref> et seq.] or the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78a">15 U.S.C. 78a</ref> et seq.] governing the issuance, offer, purchase, or sale of securities of a commodity pool, or of persons engaged in transactions with respect to such securities, or reporting by a commodity pool.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idedc610d2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6m/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedc610d3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6m/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to any commodity trading advisor that is registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission as an investment adviser whose business does not consist primarily of acting as a commodity trading advisor, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1a">section 1a of this title</ref>, and that does not act as a commodity trading advisor to any commodity pool that is engaged primarily in trading commodity interests.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedc610d4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6m/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Engaged primarily</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of subparagraph (A), a commodity trading advisor or a commodity pool shall be considered to be “engaged primarily” in the business of being a commodity trading advisor or commodity pool if it is or holds itself out to the public as being engaged primarily, or proposes to engage primarily, in the business of advising on commodity interests or investing, reinvesting, owning, holding, or trading in commodity interests, respectively.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idedc610d5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s6m/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Commodity interests</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this paragraph, commodity interests shall include contracts of sale of a commodity for future delivery, options on such contracts, security futures, swaps, leverage contracts, foreign exchange, spot and forward contracts on physical commodities, and any monies held in an account used for trading commodity interests.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idedc610d6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1922-09-21/ch369/s4m">Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 369, § 4m</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/93/463/tII/s205/a">Pub. L. 93–463, title II, § 205(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-10-23">Oct. 23, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1398">88 Stat. 1398</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/405/s8">Pub. L. 95–405, § 8</ref>, <date date="1978-09-30">Sept. 30, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/870">92 Stat. 870</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/444/tI/s103">Pub. L. 97–444, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1983-01-11">Jan. 11, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2296">96 Stat. 2296</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/5/tII/s251/d">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title II, § 251(d)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2763">114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–443; <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/tVII">Pub. L. 111–203, title VII</ref>, §§ 721(e)(2), 749(b), <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1671">124 Stat. 1671</ref>, 1747.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idedc610d7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idedc610d8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idedc610d9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Securities Act of 1933, referred to in par. (2), is title I of <ref href="/us/act/1933-05-27/ch38">act May 27, 1933, ch. 38</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/74">48 Stat. 74</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 77a et seq.) of chapter 2A of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77a">section 77a of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Securities Exchange Act of 1934, referred to in par. (2), is <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-06/ch404">act June 6, 1934, ch. 404</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/881">48 Stat. 881</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 2B (§ 78a et seq.) of Title 15. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78a">section 78a of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idedc610da-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Par. (3). <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s749/b">Pub. L. 111–203, § 749(b)</ref>, inserted heading, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A) and inserted heading, substituted “Paragraph (1)” for “Subsection (1) of this section” and “to any commodity pool that is engaged primarily in trading commodity interests.” for “to any investment trust, syndicate, or similar form of enterprise that is engaged primarily in trading in any commodity for future delivery on or subject to the rules of any contract market or registered derivatives transaction execution facility.”, and added subpars. (B) and (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s721/e/2">Pub. L. 111–203, § 721(e)(2)</ref>, substituted “section 1a” for “section 1a(6)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Par. (3). <ref href="/us/pl/106/554">Pub. L. 106–554</ref> added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—<ref href="/us/pl/97/444">Pub. L. 97–444</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—<ref href="/us/pl/95/405">Pub. L. 95–405</ref> inserted provisions relating to applicability of this section to commodity trading advisors who are dealers, processors, brokers, or sellers in cash market transactions of specifically listed commodities or nonprofit, voluntary membership, general farm organizations who provide advice on sale or purchase of specifically listed commodities if the advice by the person described in cl. (1) or (2) of this sentence is incidental solely to the conduct to the person’s business and that such person be subject to proceedings under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s18">section 18 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idedc610db-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedc610dc-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> effective on the later of 360 days after <date date="2010-07-21">July 21, 2010</date>, or, to the extent a provision of subtitle A (§§ 711–754) of title VII of <ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref> requires a rulemaking, not less than 60 days after publication of the final rule or regulation implementing such provision of subtitle A, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/203/s754">section 754 of Pub. L. 111–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1a">section 1a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedc610dd-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1983 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/444">Pub. L. 97–444</ref> effective <date date="1983-01-11">Jan. 11, 1983</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/444/s239">section 239 of Pub. L. 97–444</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedc610de-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/405">Pub. L. 95–405</ref> effective <date date="1978-10-01">Oct. 1, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/405/s28">section 28 of Pub. L. 95–405</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idedc610df-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of section, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/463/s418">section 418 of Pub. L. 93–463</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1974 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2">section 2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
