<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ideffffbb6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7253"><num value="7253">§ 7253.</num><heading> Consolidation and reform of Federal milk marketing orders</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="ideffffbb7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7253/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Amendment of orders</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="ideffffbb8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7253/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Required consolidation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall amend Federal milk marketing orders issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s608c">section 608c of this title</ref> to limit the number of Federal milk marketing orders to not less than 10 and not more than 14 orders.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="ideffffbb9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7253/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Inclusion of California as separate order</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon the petition and approval of California dairy producers in the manner provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s608c">section 608c of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall designate the State of California as a separate Federal milk marketing order. The order covering California shall have the right to reblend and distribute order receipts to recognize quota value. Subsection (b) does not apply to the authority of the Secretary under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="ideffffbba-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7253/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Related issues addressed in consolidation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Among the issues the Secretary is authorized to implement as part of the consolidation of Federal milk marketing orders are the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ideffffbbb-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7253/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The use of utilization rates and multiple basing points for the pricing of fluid milk.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ideffffbbc-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7253/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The use of uniform multiple component pricing when developing 1 or more basic formula prices for manufacturing milk.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="ideffffbbd-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7253/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of existing law</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In implementing the consolidation of Federal milk marketing orders and related reforms under this subsection, the Secretary may not consider, or base any decision on, the table contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s608c/5/A">section 608c(5)(A) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="ideffffbbe-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7253/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Expedited process</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="ideffffbbf-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7253/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of informal rulemaking</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">To implement the consolidation of Federal milk marketing orders and related reforms under subsection (a), the Secretary shall use the notice and comment procedures provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="ideffffbc0-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7253/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Time limitations</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="ideffffbc1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7253/b/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Proposed amendments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall announce the proposed amendments to be made under subsection (a) not later than 2 years after <date date="1996-04-04">April 4, 1996</date>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="ideffffbc2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7253/b/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Final amendments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall implement the amendments not later than 3 years after <date date="1996-04-04">April 4, 1996</date>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="ideffffbc3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7253/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of court order</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The actions authorized by this subsection are intended to ensure the timely publication and implementation of new and amended Federal milk marketing orders. In the event that the Secretary is enjoined or otherwise restrained by a court order from publishing or implementing the consolidation and related reforms under subsection (a), the length of time for which that injunction or other restraining order is effective shall be added to the time limitations specified in paragraph (2) thereby extending those time limitations by a period of time equal to the period of time for which the injunction or other restraining order is effective.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="ideffffbc4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7253/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to timely consolidate orders</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Secretary fails to implement the consolidation required under subsection (a)(1) within the time period required under subsection (b)(2)(B) (plus any additional period provided under subsection (b)(3)), the Secretary may not assess or collect assessments from milk producers or handlers under such <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s608c">section 608c of this title</ref> for marketing order administration and services provided under such section after the end of that period until the consolidation is completed. The Secretary may not reduce the level of services provided under the section on account of the prohibition against assessments, but shall rather cover the cost of marketing order administration and services through funds available for the Agricultural Marketing Service of the Department.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="ideffffbc5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7253/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Report regarding further reforms</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="ideffffbc6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7253/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Report required</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than <date date="1997-04-01">April 1, 1997</date>, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ideffffbc7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7253/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> reviewing the Federal milk marketing order system established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s608c">section 608c of this title</ref> in light of the reforms required by subsection (a);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ideffffbc8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7253/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> describing the efforts underway and the progress made in implementing the reforms required by subsection (a); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ideffffbc9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7253/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> containing such recommendations as the Secretary considers appropriate for further improvements and reforms to the Federal milk marketing order system.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="ideffffbca-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7253/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of other laws</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any limitation imposed by Act of Congress on the conduct or completion of reports to Congress shall not apply to the report required under this section, unless the limitation specifically refers to this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ideffffbcb-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/104/127/tI/s143">Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 143</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/915">110 Stat. 915</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/79/tI/s1410/d">Pub. L. 113–79, title I, § 1410(d)</ref>, <date date="2014-02-07">Feb. 7, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/693">128 Stat. 693</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ideffffbcc-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ideffffbcd-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ideffffbce-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/113/79">Pub. L. 113–79</ref> inserted at end “Subsection (b) does not apply to the authority of the Secretary under this subsection.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ideffffbcf-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ideffffbd0-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Use of Option 1A as Price Structure for Class I Milk Under Consolidated Federal Milk Marketing Orders</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/8/s1">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(8) [§ 1]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–517, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/8/s1">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Final Rule Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘final rule’ means the final rule for the consolidation and reform of Federal milk marketing orders that was published in the Federal Register on <date date="1999-09-01">September 1, 1999</date> (64 Fed. Reg. 47897–48021), to comply with section 143 of the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7253">7 U.S.C. 7253</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation of Final Rule for Milk Order Reform</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to subsection (c), the final rule shall take effect, and be implemented by the Secretary of Agriculture, on the first day of the first month beginning at least 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Option</inline> 1A <inline class="small-caps">for Pricing Class I Milk</inline>.—</heading><content>In lieu of the Class I price differentials specified in the final rule, the Secretary of Agriculture shall price fluid or Class I milk under the Federal milk marketing orders using the Class I price differentials identified as Option 1A ‘Location-Specific Differentials Analysis’ in the proposed rule published in the Federal Register on <date date="1998-01-30">January 30, 1998</date> (63 Fed. Reg. 4802, 4809), except that the Secretary shall include the corrections and modifications to such Class I differentials made by the Secretary through <date date="1999-04-02">April 2, 1999</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effect of Prior Announcement of Minimum Prices</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Secretary of Agriculture announces minimum prices for milk under Federal milk marketing orders pursuant to section 1000.50 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations, before the effective date specified in subsection (b), the minimum prices so announced before that date shall be the only applicable minimum prices under Federal milk marketing orders for the month or months for which the prices have been announced.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation of Requirement</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The implementation of the final rule, as modified by subsection (c), shall not be subject to any of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The notice and hearing requirements of section 8c(3) of the Agricultural Adjustment Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s608c/3">7 U.S.C. 608c(3)</ref>), reenacted with amendments by the Agricultural Marketing Agreement Act of 1937, or the notice and comment provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> A referendum conducted by the Secretary of Agriculture pursuant to subsections (17) or (19) of section 8c of the Agricultural Adjustment Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s608c">7 U.S.C. 608c</ref>), reenacted with amendments by the Agricultural Marketing Agreement Act of 1937.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The Statement of Policy of the Secretary of Agriculture effective <date date="1971-07-24">July 24, 1971</date> (36 Fed. Reg. 13804), relating to notices of proposed rulemaking and public participation in rulemaking.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Chapter 35 of title 44, United States Code (commonly known as the Paperwork Reduction Act).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Any decision, restraining order, or injunction issued by a United States court before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>].”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ideffffbd1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Further Rulemaking To Develop Pricing Methods for Class III and Class IV Milk Under Marketing Orders</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/8/s2">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(8) [§ 2]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–518, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/8/s2">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Congressional Finding</inline>.—</heading><content>The Class III and Class IV milk pricing formulas included in the final decision for the consolidation and reform of Federal milk marketing orders, as published in the Federal Register on <date date="1999-04-02">April 2, 1999</date> (64 Fed. Reg. 16025), do not adequately reflect public comment on the original proposed rule published in the Federal Register on <date date="1998-01-30">January 30, 1998</date> (63 Fed. Reg. 4802), and are sufficiently different from the proposed rule and any comments submitted with regard to the proposed rule that further emergency rulemaking is merited.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rulemaking Required</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Agriculture shall conduct rulemaking, on the record after an opportunity for an agency hearing, to reconsider the Class III and Class IV milk pricing formulas included in the final rule for the consolidation and reform of Federal milk marketing orders that was published in the Federal Register on <date date="1999-09-01">September 1, 1999</date> (64 Fed. Reg. 47897–48021).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Time Period for Rulemaking</inline>.—</heading><content>On <date date="2000-12-01">December 1, 2000</date>, the Secretary of Agriculture shall publish in the Federal Register a final decision on the Class III and Class IV milk pricing formulas. The resulting formulas shall take effect, and be implemented by the Secretary, on <date date="2001-01-01">January 1, 2001</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effect of Court Order</inline>.—</heading><content>The actions authorized by subsections (b) and (c) are intended to ensure the timely publication and implementation of new pricing formulas for Class III and Class IV milk. In the event that the Secretary of Agriculture is enjoined or otherwise restrained by a court order from implementing a final decision within the time period specified in subsection (c), the length of time for which that injunction or other restraining order is effective shall be added to the time limitations specified in subsection (c) thereby extending those time limitations by a period of time equal to the period of time for which the injunction or other restraining order is effective.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Failure To Timely Complete Rulemaking</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Secretary of Agriculture fails to implement new Class III and Class IV milk pricing formulas within the time period required under subsection (c) (plus any additional period provided under subsection (d)), the Secretary may not assess or collect assessments from milk producers or handlers under section 8c of the Agricultural Adjustment Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s608c">7 U.S.C. 608c</ref>), reenacted with amendments by the Agricultural Marketing Agreement Act of 1937, for marketing order administration and services provided under such section after the end of that period until the pricing formulas are implemented. The Secretary may not reduce the level of services provided under that section on account of the prohibition against assessments, but shall rather cover the cost of marketing order administration and services through funds available for the Agricultural Marketing Service of the Department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation of Requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>The implementation of the final decision on new Class III and Class IV milk pricing formulas shall not be subject to congressional review under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
