<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idf0026be3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7256"><num value="7256">§ 7256.</num><heading> Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Congress hereby consents to the Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact entered into among the States of Connecticut, Maine, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, Rhode Island and Vermont as specified in section 1(b) Senate <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002331">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002331"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be preceded by “of”.</note> Joint Resolution 28 of the 104th Congress, as placed on the calendar of the Senate, subject to the following conditions:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf0026be4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7256/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Finding of compelling public interest</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Based upon a finding by the Secretary of a compelling public interest in the Compact region, the Secretary may grant the States that have ratified the Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact, as of <date date="1996-04-04">April 4, 1996</date>, the authority to implement the Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf0026be5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7256/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on manufacturing price</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact Commission shall not regulate Class II, Class III, or Class III–A milk used for manufacturing purposes or any other milk, other than Class I (fluid) milk, as defined by a Federal milk marketing order issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s608c">section 608c of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf0026be6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7256/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Duration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Consent for the Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact shall terminate on <date date="2001-09-30">September 30, 2001</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf0026be7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7256/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Delaware, New Jersey, New York, Pennsylvania, Maryland, and Virginia are the only additional States that may join the Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact, individually or otherwise, if upon entry the State is contiguous to a participating State and if Congress consents to the entry of the State into the Compact after <date date="1996-04-04">April 4, 1996</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf0026be8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7256/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation of Commodity Credit Corporation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Before the end of each fiscal year that a Compact price regulation is in effect, the Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact Commission shall compensate the Commodity Credit Corporation for the cost of any purchases of milk and milk products by the Corporation that result from the projected rate of increase in milk production for the fiscal year within the Compact region in excess of the projected national average rate of the increase in milk production, as determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf0026be9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7256/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Milk marketing order Administrator</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">At the request of the Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact Commission, the Administrator of the applicable Federal milk marketing order issued under section 608c(5) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002332">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002332"><num>2</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title shall provide technical assistance to the Compact Commission and be compensated for that assistance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf0026bea-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7256/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Further conditions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact Commission shall not prohibit or in any way limit the marketing in the Compact region of any milk or milk product produced in any other production area in the United States. The Compact Commission shall respect and abide by the ongoing procedures between Federal milk marketing orders with respect to the sharing of proceeds from sales within the Compact region of bulk milk, packaged milk, or producer milk originating from outside of the Compact region. The Compact Commission shall not use compensatory payments under section 10(6) of the Compact as a barrier to the entry of milk into the Compact region or for any other purpose. Establishment of a Compact over-order price, in itself, shall not be considered a compensatory payment or a limitation or prohibition on the marketing of milk.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idf0026beb-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/104/127/tI/s147">Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 147</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/919">110 Stat. 919</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/8/s4">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(8) [§ 4]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–520.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idf0026bec-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idf0026bed-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idf0026bee-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t7/s608c/5">Section 608c(5) of this title</ref>, referred to in par. (6), was in the original “section 8(c)5 of the Agricultural Adjustment Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s608c">7 U.S.C. 608c</ref>), reenacted with amendments by the Agricultural Marketing Agreement Act of 1937,” which was translated as meaning section 8c(5) of the Agricultural Adjustment Act, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idf0026bef-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Par. (3). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref> substituted “on <date date="2001-09-30">September 30, 2001</date>.” for “concurrent with the Secretary’s implementation of the dairy pricing and Federal milk marketing order consolidation and reforms under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7253">section 7253 of this title</ref>.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
