<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idf010c4b9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7515"><num value="7515">§ 7515.</num><heading> Allotment and delivery of commodities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idf010c4ba-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7515/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Mandatory allotments</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In each fiscal year, the Secretary shall allot—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf010c4bb-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7515/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> 60 percent of the total value of additional commodities provided to States in a manner such that the value of additional commodities allocated to each State bears the same ratio to 60 percent of the total value of additional commodities as the number of persons in households within the State having incomes below the poverty line bears to the total number of persons in households within all States having incomes below such poverty line, and each State shall be entitled to receive such value of additional commodities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf010c4bc-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7515/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> 40 percent of the total value of additional commodities provided to States in a manner such that the value of additional commodities allocated to each State bears the same ratio to 40 percent of the total value of additional commodities as the average monthly number of unemployed persons within the State bears to the average monthly number of unemployed persons within all States during the same fiscal year, and each State shall be entitled to receive such value of additional commodities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idf010c4bd-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7515/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Reallocation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall notify each State of the amount of the additional commodities that such State is allotted to receive under subsection (a), and each State shall promptly notify the Secretary if such State determines that it will not accept any or all of the commodities made available under such allocation. On such a notification by a State, the Secretary shall reallocate and distribute the amount the State was allocated to receive under the formula prescribed in subsection (a) but declined to accept. The Secretary shall further establish procedures to permit States to decline to receive portions of such allocation during each fiscal year as the State determines is appropriate and the Secretary shall reallocate and distribute such allocation. In the event of any drought, flood, hurricane, or other natural disaster affecting substantial numbers of persons in a State, county or parish, the Secretary may request that States unaffected by such a disaster consider assisting affected States by allowing the Secretary to reallocate commodities to which each such unaffected State is entitled to States containing areas adversely affected by the disaster.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idf010c4be-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7515/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Administration</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf010c4bf-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7515/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Commodities made available for each fiscal year under this section shall be delivered at reasonable intervals to States based on the grants calculated under subsection (a), or reallocated under subsection (b), before December 31 of the following fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf010c4c0-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7515/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Entitlement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each State shall be entitled to receive the value of additional commodities determined under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idf010c4c1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7515/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Maintenance of effort</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If a State uses its own funds to provide commodities or services to organizations receiving funds or services under this section, such State shall not diminish the level of support it provides to such organizations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idf010c4c2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/8/tII/s214">Pub. L. 98–8, title II, § 214</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/100/435/tI/s104">Pub. L. 100–435, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1988-09-19">Sept. 19, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1648">102 Stat. 1648</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/tXVII/s1772/g">Pub. L. 101–624, title XVII, § 1772(g)</ref>, (h)(1), <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3809">104 Stat. 3809</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/tIV/s403/c">Pub. L. 104–127, title IV, § 403(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1029">110 Stat. 1029</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/tVIII/s871/d">Pub. L. 104–193, title VIII, § 871(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2345">110 Stat. 2345</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idf010c4c3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idf010c4c4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idf010c4c5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/s871/d/1">Pub. L. 104–193, § 871(d)(1)</ref>, (2), redesignated subsec. (f) as (a) and struck out former subsec. (a) which provided for purpose of section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s403/c/1">Pub. L. 104–127, § 403(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “2002” for “1995”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/s871/d/1">Pub. L. 104–193, § 871(d)(1)</ref>–(3), redesignated subsec. (g) as (b), substituted “subsection (a),” for “subsection (f) of this section or subsection (j) of this section if applicable,” and “subsection (a)” for “subsection (f) of this section”, and struck out former subsec. (b) which provided definitions for section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/s871/d/4">Pub. L. 104–193, § 871(d)(4)</ref>, added subsec. (c) and struck out heading and text of former subsec. (c). Text read as follows: “Subject to subsections (e) and (f) of this section, or subsection (j) of this section if applicable, purchases under this section shall be made by the Secretary at such times and under such conditions as the Secretary determines appropriate within each fiscal year. All such commodities purchased for each such fiscal year shall be delivered at reasonable intervals to States based on the allotments calculated under subsection (f) of this section, or reallocated under subsection (g) of this section, or calculated under subsection (j) of this section if applicable, before the end of such fiscal year. Each State shall be entitled to receive that value of additional commodities that results from the application of the formula set forth in this section to the total value of additional commodities.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/193/s871/d/1">Pub. L. 104–193, § 871(d)(1)</ref>, (2), redesignated subsec. (h) as (c) and struck out former subsec. (c) which authorized Secretary to purchase additional commodities to supplement commodities otherwise provided under program authorized by this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/s871/d/5">Pub. L. 104–193, § 871(d)(5)</ref>, struck out “or reduce the amount of funds available for other nutrition programs in the State in each fiscal year” after “such organizations”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/193/s871/d/1">Pub. L. 104–193, § 871(d)(1)</ref>, (2), redesignated subsec. (i) as (d) and struck out former subsec. (d) which provided for types and varieties of commodities which could be purchased under this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/s871/d/1">Pub. L. 104–193, § 871(d)(1)</ref>, struck out subsec. (e) which appropriated amounts through fiscal year 2002 for purchase of additional commodities under this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/127/s403/c/2">Pub. L. 104–127, § 403(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “2002” for “1995” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (f) to (i). <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/s871/d/2">Pub. L. 104–193, § 871(d)(2)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (f) to (i) as (a) to (d), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/s871/d/1">Pub. L. 104–193, § 871(d)(1)</ref>, struck out subsec. (j) which authorized Secretary to promulgate new formula for allocation of additional commodities to States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s1772/g/1">Pub. L. 101–624, § 1772(g)(1)</ref>, substituted “fiscal years 1991 through 1995” for “fiscal years 1989 and 1990”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s1772/g/2">Pub. L. 101–624, § 1772(g)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (e) and struck out heading and text of former subsec. (e). Text read as follows: “During each of the fiscal years 1989 and 1990, the Secretary shall spend $120,000,000 to purchase, process, and distribute additional commodities under this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s1772/h/1">Pub. L. 101–624, § 1772(h)(1)</ref>, struck out heading and text of subsec. (k). Text read as follows: “There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idf0130db6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idf0130db7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/193/tVIII/s871/h">Pub. L. 104–193, title VIII, § 871(h)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2346">110 Stat. 2346</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/193/tVIII/s871/h">“The amendments made by subsection (d) [amending this section] shall become effective on <date date="1996-10-01">October 1, 1996</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idf0130db8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s1772/g">section 1772(g) of Pub. L. 101–624</ref> effective <date date="1990-10-01">Oct. 1, 1990</date>, and amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/624/s1772/h/1">section 1772(h)(1) of Pub. L. 101–624</ref> effective <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, see section 1781(b)(1), (2) of <ref href="/us/pl/101/624">Pub. L. 101–624</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2012">section 2012 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idf0130db9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section to be effective and implemented on <date date="1988-10-01">Oct. 1, 1988</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/435/s701/a">section 701(a) of Pub. L. 100–435</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1988 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2012">section 2012 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
