<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idf01cab01-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7731"><num value="7731">§ 7731.</num><heading> Inspections, seizures, and warrants</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idf01cab02-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7731/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Role of Attorney General</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The activities authorized by this section shall be carried out consistent with guidelines approved by the Attorney General.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idf01cab03-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7731/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Warrantless inspections</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may stop and inspect, without a warrant, any person or means of conveyance moving—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf01cab04-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7731/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> into the United States to determine whether the person or means of conveyance is carrying any plant, plant product, biological control organism, plant pest, noxious weed, or article subject to this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf01cab05-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7731/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> in interstate commerce, upon probable cause to believe that the person or means of conveyance is carrying any plant, plant product, biological control organism, plant pest, noxious weed, or article subject to this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf01cab06-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7731/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> in intrastate commerce from or within any State, portion of a State, or premises quarantined as part of a extraordinary emergency declared under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7715">section 7715 of this title</ref> upon probable cause to believe that the person or means of conveyance is carrying any plant, plant product, biological control organism, plant pest, noxious weed, or article regulated under that section or is moving subject to that section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf01cab07-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7731/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Inspections with a warrant</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf01cab08-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7731/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> General authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may enter, with a warrant, any premises in the United States for the purpose of conducting investigations or making inspections and seizures under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf01cab09-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s7731/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Application and issuance of a warrant</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon proper oath or affirmation showing probable cause to believe that there is on certain premises any plant, plant product, biological control organism, plant pest, noxious weed, article, facility, or means of conveyance regulated under this chapter, a United States judge, a judge of a court of record in the United States, or a United States magistrate judge may, within the judge’s or magistrate’s <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002349">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002349"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “magistrate judges’s”.</note> jurisdiction, issue a warrant for the entry upon the premises to conduct any investigation or make any inspection or seizure under this chapter. The warrant may be applied for and executed by the Secretary or any United States Marshal.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idf01cab0a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/106/224/tIV/s421">Pub. L. 106–224, title IV, § 421</ref>, <date date="2000-06-20">June 20, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/448">114 Stat. 448</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idf01cab0b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idf01cab0c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idf01cab0d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (b)(1), (2) and (c), was in the original “this title”, meaning title IV of <ref href="/us/pl/106/224">Pub. L. 106–224</ref>, <date date="2000-06-20">June 20, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/438">114 Stat. 438</ref>, known as the Plant Protection Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of title IV to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7701">section 7701 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idf01cab0e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idf01cab0f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions of the Secretary of Agriculture relating to agricultural import and entry inspection activities under this chapter to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 231, 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
