<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idede9ec32-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a"><num value="79a">§ 79a.</num><heading> Weighing authority</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idede9ec33-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Official weighing in accordance with prescribed regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall cause official weighing under standards or procedures provided for in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s76">section 76 of this title</ref> to be made of all grain required to be officially weighed as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s77">section 77 of this title</ref>, in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idede9ec34-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Official weighing or supervision of weighing at grain elevators, warehouses, or other storage or handling facilities located other than at export elevators at export port locations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to cause official weighing or supervision of weighing under standards or procedures provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s76">section 76 of this title</ref> to be performed at any grain elevator, warehouse, or other storage or handling facility located other than at export elevators at export port locations at which official inspection is provided pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, in such manner as the Secretary deems appropriate and under such regulations as the Secretary may provide.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idede9ec35-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Personnel performing official weighing or supervision of weighing at locations at which official inspection is provided</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idede9ec36-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> With respect to official weighing or supervision of weighing for locations at which official inspection is provided by the Secretary, the Secretary shall cause such official weighing or supervision of weighing to be performed by official inspection personnel employed by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idede9ec37-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> With respect to official weighing or supervision of weighing for any location at which official inspection is provided other than by the Secretary, the Secretary is authorized, with respect to export port locations, to delegate authority to perform official weighing or supervision of weighing to the State agency providing official inspection service at such location, and with respect to any other location, to designate the agency or person providing official inspection service at such location to perform official weighing or supervision of weighing, if such agency or person qualifies for a delegation of authority or designation under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s79">section 79 of this title</ref>, except that where the term “official inspection” is used in such section it shall be deemed to refer to “official weighing” or “supervision of weighing” under this section. If such agency or person is not available to perform such weighing services, or the Secretary determines that such agency or person is not qualified to perform such weighing services, then (A) at export port locations official weighing or supervision of weighing shall be performed by official inspection personnel employed by the Secretary, and (B) at any other location, the Secretary is authorized to cause official weighing or supervision of weighing to be performed by official inspection personnel employed by the Secretary or designate any State or local governmental agency, or any person to perform official weighing or supervision of weighing, if such agency or person meets the same criteria that agencies must meet to be designated to perform official inspection as set out in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s79">section 79 of this title</ref>, except that where the term “official inspection” is used in such section it shall be deemed to refer to “official weighing” or “supervision of weighing” under this section. Delegations and designations made pursuant to this subsection shall be subject to the same provisions for delegations and designations set forth in subsections (e) and (g) of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s79">section 79 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idede9ec38-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Official weighing in Canadian ports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to cause official weighing under this chapter to be made, as provided in subsection (a) of <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s77">section 77 of this title</ref>, in Canadian ports of United States export grain transshipped through Canada; and pursuant thereto the Secretary is authorized to enter into an agreement with the Canadian Government for such official weighing. All or specified functions of such weighing shall be performed by official inspection personnel employed by the Secretary or, except for appeals, by persons operating under a contract with the Secretary or as otherwise provided by agreement with the Canadian Government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idede9ec39-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Official weighing or supervision of weighing upon request of operators of grain elevators, warehouses, or other storage or handling facilities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is further authorized to cause official weighing or supervision of weighing under standards or procedures provided for in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s76">section 76 of this title</ref> to be made at grain elevators, warehouses, or other storage or handling facilities not subject to subsection (a) or (b) of this section, upon request of the operator of such grain elevator, warehouse, or other storage or handling facility and in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idede9ec3a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Demonstrated willingness of operators of grain elevators, warehouses, or other storage or handling facilities to meet equipment and personnel requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No official weighing or supervision of weighing shall be provided for the purposes of this chapter at any grain elevator, warehouse, or other storage or handling facility until such time as the operator of the facility has demonstrated to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the operator (1) has and will maintain, in good order, suitable grain-handling equipment and accurate scales for all weighing of grain at the facility, in accordance with the regulations of the Secretary; (2) will permit only competent persons with a reputation for honesty and integrity and who are approved by the Secretary to operate the scales and to handle grain in connection with weighing of the grain, in accordance with this chapter; (3) when weighing is to be done by persons other than official inspection personnel, will require such persons to operate the scales in accordance with the regulations of the Secretary and to require that each lot of grain for delivery from any railroad car, truck, barge, vessel, or other means of conveyance at the facility is entirely removed from such means of conveyance and delivered to the scales without avoidable waste or loss, and each lot of grain weighed at the elevator for shipment from the facility is entirely delivered to the means of conveyance for which intended, and without avoidable waste or loss, in accordance with the regulations of the Secretary; (4) will provide all assistance needed by the Secretary for making any inspection or examination and carrying out other functions at the facility pursuant to this chapter; and (5) will comply with all other requirements of this chapter and the regulations hereunder.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idede9ec3b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Official certificates as evidence</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Official certificates setting out the results of official weighing or supervision of weighing, issued and not cancelled under this chapter, shall be received by all officers and all courts of the United States as prima facie evidence of the truth of the facts stated therein.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idede9ec3c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Weighing prohibited when not in accordance with prescribed procedures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No State or local governmental agency or person shall weigh or state in any document the weight of grain determined at a location where official weighing is required to be performed as provided for in this section except in accordance with the procedures prescribed pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idede9ec3d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Unauthorized weighing prohibited</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idede9ec3e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/i/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No State or local governmental agency or person other than an authorized employee of the Secretary shall perform official weighing or supervision of weighing for the purposes of this chapter except in accordance with the provisions of an unsuspended and unrevoked delegation of authority or designation by the Secretary as provided in this section or as otherwise provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s79/i">section 79(i) of this title</ref> and subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idede9ec3f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/i/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Geographic boundaries for official agencies</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idede9ec40-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/i/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), not more than one designated official agency referred to in paragraph (1) or State agency delegated authority pursuant to subsection (c)(2) to carry out the weighing provisions of this chapter shall be operative at the same time in any geographic area defined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idede9ec41-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/i/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the Secretary determines that the presence of more than one designated official agency in the same geographic area will not undermine the policy stated in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s74">section 74 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall allow a designated official agency to cross boundary lines to carry out weighing in another geographic area if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idede9ec42-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/i/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the current designated official agency for that geographic area is unable to provide weighing services in a timely manner;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idede9ec43-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/i/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a person requesting weighing services in that geographic area has not been receiving official weighing services from the current designated official agency for that geographic area; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idede9ec44-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/i/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the current official agency for that geographic area agrees in writing with the adjacent official agency to waive the current geographic area restriction at the request of the applicant for service.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idede9ec45-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/i/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Restoration of certain exceptions</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idede9ec46-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/i/2/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition of eligible grain handling facility</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In this subparagraph, the term “eligible grain handling facility” means a grain handling facility that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idede9ec47-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/i/2/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> was granted an exception under the final rule entitled “Exceptions to Geographic Areas for Official Agencies Under the USGSA” (68 Fed. Reg. 19137 (<date date="2003-04-18">April 18, 2003</date>)); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idede9ec48-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/i/2/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> had that exception revoked between <date date="2015-09-30">September 30, 2015</date> and <date date="2018-12-20">December 20, 2018</date>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idede9ec49-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/i/2/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Restoration of exceptions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Within 90 days of notification from an eligible grain handling facility, the Secretary shall restore an exception described in clause (i)(I) with an official agency if—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idede9ec4a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/i/2/C/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the eligible grain handling facility and the former excepted official agency agree to restore that exception; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idede9ec4b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/i/2/C/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the eligible grain handling facility notifies the Secretary of the preferred date for restoration of the exception within 90 days of <date date="2018-12-20">December 20, 2018</date>.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idede9ec4c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority under United States Warehouse Act not limited</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of this section shall not limit any authority vested in the Secretary under the United States Warehouse Act (<ref href="/us/stat/39/486">39 Stat. 486</ref>, as amended; <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s241">7 U.S.C. 241</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idede9ec4d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Access to elevators, warehouses, or their storage or handling facilities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The representatives of the Secretary shall be afforded access to any elevator, warehouse, or other storage or handling facility from which grain is delivered for shipment in interstate or foreign commerce or to which grain is delivered from shipment in interstate or foreign commerce and all facilities therein for weighing grain.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idede9ec4e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Fees</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idede9ec4f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/l/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Weighing fees.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idede9ec50-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/l/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall, under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, charge and collect reasonable fees to cover the estimated costs to the Secretary incident to the performance of the functions provided for under this section except as otherwise provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idede9ec51-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/l/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Amount of fees</inline>.—</heading><content>The fees authorized by this paragraph shall, as nearly as practicable, cover the costs of the Secretary incident to performance of its <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002065">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002065"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “the Secretary’s”.</note> functions related to weighing, including administrative and supervisory costs directly related thereto.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idede9ec52-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/l/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of fees</inline>.—</heading><content>Fees described in this paragraph shall be deposited into the fund created in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s79/j">section 79(j) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idede9ec53-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/l/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Export tonnage fees</inline>.—</heading><content>For an official weighing at an export facility performed by the Secretary, the portion of the fees based on export tonnage shall be based on the rolling 5-year average of export tonnage volumes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idede9ec54-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/l/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Each agency to which authority has been delegated under this section and each agency or other person which has been designated to perform functions related to weighing under this section shall pay to the Secretary fees in such amount as the Secretary determines fair and reasonable and as will cover the costs incurred by the Secretary relating to supervision of the agency personnel and supervision by the Secretary of the Secretary’s field office personnel incurred as a result of the functions performed by such agencies, except costs incurred under sections 79(g)(3), 85, 86, and 87c of this title. The fees shall be payable after the services are performed at such times as specified by the Secretary and shall be deposited in the fund created in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s79/j">section 79(j) of this title</ref>. Failure to pay the fee within thirty days after it is due shall result in automatic termination of the delegation or designation, which shall be reinstated upon payment, within such period as specified by the Secretary, of the fee currently due plus interest and any further expenses incurred by the Secretary because of such termination. The interest rate on overdue fees shall be as prescribed by the Secretary, but not less than the current average market yield on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States of comparable maturity, plus an additional charge of not to exceed 1 per centum per annum as determined by the Secretary, and adjusted to the nearest one-eighth of 1 per centum.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idede9ec55-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/l/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Adjustment of fees</inline>.—</heading><content>In order to maintain an operating reserve of not less than 3 and not more than 6 months, the Secretary shall adjust the fees described in paragraphs (1) and (2) not less frequently than annually.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idede9ec56-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s79a/l/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The authority provided to the Secretary by paragraph (1) and the duties imposed by paragraph (2) on agencies and other persons described in such paragraph shall expire on <date date="2025-09-30">September 30, 2025</date>.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002066">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002066"><num>2</num> See United States Grain Standards Act Extension note below.</note> After that date, the Secretary shall, under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, charge and collect reasonable fees to cover the estimated costs of official weighing and supervision of weighing except when the official weighing or supervision of weighing is performed by a designated official agency or by a State under a delegation of authority. The fees authorized by this paragraph shall, as nearly as practicable, cover the costs of the Secretary incident to its performance of official weighing and supervision of weighing services in the United States and on United States grain in Canadian ports, excluding administrative and supervisory costs. The fees authorized by this paragraph shall be deposited into a fund which shall be available without fiscal year limitation for the expenses of the Secretary incident to providing services under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idedec3647-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1916-08-11/ch313">Aug. 11, 1916, ch. 313</ref>, pt. B, § 7A, as added <ref href="/us/pl/94/582/s9">Pub. L. 94–582, § 9</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2875">90 Stat. 2875</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/113/tXVI">Pub. L. 95–113, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1602(b), 1604(e), 1606(e), <date date="1977-09-29">Sept. 29, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1025">91 Stat. 1025</ref>, 1027, 1030; <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tI/s155/2">Pub. L. 97–35, title I, § 155(2)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/371">95 Stat. 371</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/518/s2/2">Pub. L. 100–518, § 2(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-24">Oct. 24, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2585">102 Stat. 2585</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/156">Pub. L. 103–156</ref>, §§ 4(b), 5(b), 12(e), 14(b), <date date="1993-11-24">Nov. 24, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1526">107 Stat. 1526</ref>, 1528, 1530; <ref href="/us/pl/103/354/tII/s293/a/4">Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 293(a)(4)</ref>, (7), (8), <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3237">108 Stat. 3237</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/472/tI">Pub. L. 106–472, title I</ref>, §§ 102(b), 103(b), <date date="2000-11-09">Nov. 9, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2059">114 Stat. 2059</ref>, 2060; <ref href="/us/pl/109/83/s1/a">Pub. L. 109–83, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="2005-09-30">Sept. 30, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2053">119 Stat. 2053</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/54/tIII/s301/b/3/B">Pub. L. 114–54, title III, § 301(b)(3)(B)</ref>, (c), <date date="2015-09-30">Sept. 30, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/518">129 Stat. 518</ref>, 519; <ref href="/us/pl/115/334/tXII/s12610/b">Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12610(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5012">132 Stat. 5012</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/216/s3">Pub. L. 116–216, § 3</ref>, <date date="2020-12-11">Dec. 11, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/1048">134 Stat. 1048</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idedec3648-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idedec3649-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idedec364a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The United States Warehouse Act, referred to in subsec. (j), is part C of <ref href="/us/act/1916-08-11/ch313">act Aug. 11, 1916, ch. 313</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/486">39 Stat. 486</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 10 (§ 241 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s241">section 241 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idedec364b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsec. (<i>l</i>)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/116/216">Pub. L. 116–216</ref>, in first sentence, substituted “2025” for “2020”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (i)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/334">Pub. L. 115–334</ref> inserted subpar. (A) designation and heading before “Not more” and subpar. (B) designation and heading before “the Secretary determines” in introductory provisions, substituted “Subject to subparagraph (B), not more” for “Not more” and “Secretary.” for “Secretary, except that, if” in subpar. (A) and “If the Secretary determines” for “the Secretary determines” in subpar. (B), redesignated former subpars. (A) and (B) as cls. (i) and (iii), respectively, of subpar. (B), struck out “or” at end of cl. (i) of subpar. (B), added cl. (ii) of subpar. (B) and subpar. (C), and realigned margins.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/114/54/s301/c/1">Pub. L. 114–54, § 301(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “subsections (e) and (g) of section 79” for “subsection (g) of section 79”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/114/54/s301/b/3/B">Pub. L. 114–54, § 301(b)(3)(B)</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted “the Secretary shall allow a designated official agency to cross boundary lines to carry out weighing in another geographic area if—” for “the Secretary may—”, added subpars. (A) and (B), and struck out former subpars. (A) and (B) which related to more than one designated official agency providing weighing in the same geographic area and a designated official agency crossing boundary lines to provide weighing in another geographic area.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/114/54/s301/c/2/A">Pub. L. 114–54, § 301(c)(2)(A)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/114/54/s301/c/2/A">Pub. L. 114–54, § 301(c)(2)(A)</ref>, (B), inserted heading, designated first to third sentences as subpars. (A) to (C), respectively, and inserted subpar. headings, in subpar. (C), substituted “Fees described in this paragraph” for “Such fees”, and added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/114/54/s301/c/2/D">Pub. L. 114–54, § 301(c)(2)(D)</ref>, added par. (3). Former par. (3) redesignated (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/114/54/s301/c/2/C">Pub. L. 114–54, § 301(c)(2)(C)</ref>, (E), redesignated par. (3) as (4) and substituted “2020” for “2015”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (<i>l</i>)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/109/83">Pub. L. 109–83</ref> substituted “2015” for “2005”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/106/472/s102/b">Pub. L. 106–472, § 102(b)</ref>, inserted subsec. heading, designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted par. heading, struck out second sentence, which prohibited more than one official agency or State delegated authority from operating at one time in any geographic area except as permitted in pilot programs, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/106/472/s103/b">Pub. L. 106–472, § 103(b)</ref>, substituted “2005” for “2000” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/354">Pub. L. 103–354</ref> substituted “supervision by the Secretary of the Secretary’s field office personnel” for “supervision by Service personnel of its field office personnel” in first sentence of subsec. (<i>l</i>)(2) and substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator” and “Service” wherever appearing in subsecs. (a) to (f) and (i) to (<i>l</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/156/s4/b/1">Pub. L. 103–156, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, in second sentence, substituted “ ‘official weighing’ or ‘supervision of weighing’ ” for “ ‘supervision of weighing’ ”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/103/156/s4/b/2">Pub. L. 103–156, § 4(b)(2)</ref>, inserted before period at end of second sentence “or as otherwise provided by agreement with the Canadian Government”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/103/156/s12/e">Pub. L. 103–156, § 12(e)</ref>, which directed amendment of “Section 7A(e)” by substituting “regulations as the Administrator” for “regulations as he”, without specifying the name of the Act being amended, was executed to this section, which is section 7A of the United States Grain Standards Act, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/103/156">Pub. L. 103–156</ref>, §§ 4(b)(3), 5(b), inserted before period at end of first sentence “or as otherwise provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s79/i">section 79(i) of this title</ref> and subsection (d) of this section” and inserted before period at end of second sentence “, except that the Administrator may conduct pilot programs to allow more than 1 official agency to carry out the weighing provisions within a single geographic area without undermining the policy stated in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s74">section 74 of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/103/156/s14/b">Pub. L. 103–156, § 14(b)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/100/518">Pub. L. 100–518</ref> amended subsec. (<i>l</i>) generally, substituting “cover the costs of the Service” for “cover the costs of the service” in par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> temporarily designated existing provisions as par. (1), made changes in nomenclature, provided for inclusion, rather than exclusion, of administrative and supervisory costs, and struck out provisions respecting availability of deposited funds, and added par. (2). See Effective and Termination Dates of 1981 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/113/s1606/e">Pub. L. 95–113, § 1606(e)</ref>, substituted “standards or procedures” for “standards”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/113">Pub. L. 95–113</ref>, §§ 1604(e)(1), 1606(e), substituted “The Administrator is authorized to cause official weighing or supervision of weighing under standards or procedures” for “The Administrator is authorized to cause supervision of weighing under standards” and “other than at export elevators at export port locations” for “other than at export port locations”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/95/113/s1604/e/2">Pub. L. 95–113, § 1604(e)(2)</ref>, made technical amendments to conform par. (2) to increased authority granted in subsec. (b) to cause official weighing as well as supervision of weighing at interior inspection points and corrected a typographical error in which “number” had been erroneously used for “under” in text as originally enacted by <ref href="/us/pl/94/582">Pub. L. 94–582</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/113/s1604/e/3">Pub. L. 95–113, § 1604(e)(3)</ref>, inserted requirement that all or specified functions of Canadian weighing be performed by official inspection personnel employed by the Service or, except for appeals, by persons operating under a contract with the Service.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/95/113">Pub. L. 95–113</ref>, §§ 1604(e)(4), 1606(e), substituted “under standards or procedures provided” for “under standards provided” and struck out provisions which had required that the weighing service not be provided for periods of less than a year, that the fees therefor be set separately from the fees provided for in subsec. (<i>l</i>), and that they be reasonable, nondiscriminatory, and equal, as nearly as possible, to the cost of providing the service.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/95/113/s1604/e/5/A">Pub. L. 95–113, § 1604(e)(5)(A)</ref>, substituted “permit only competent persons with a reputation for honesty and integrity and who are approved by the Administrator” for “employ only competent persons with a reputation for honesty and integrity”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/95/113/s1604/e/5/B">Pub. L. 95–113, § 1604(e)(5)(B)</ref>, substituted “when weighing is to be done by persons other than official inspection personnel, will require such persons to operate the scales” for “when weighing is to be done by employees of the facility, will require employees to operate the scales”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/95/113/s1604/e/6">Pub. L. 95–113, § 1604(e)(6)</ref>, substituted “official weighing or supervision of weighing” for “official weighing”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/95/113/s1604/e/7">Pub. L. 95–113, § 1604(e)(7)</ref>, (8), substituted “No State or local governmental agency” for “No State” and inserted provision that not more than one official agency or State delegated authority pursuant to subsection (c)(2) of this section for carrying out the weighing provisions of this chapter be operative at one time for any geographic area as determined by the Administrator to effectuate the objectives stated in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s74">section 74 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/95/113/s1602/b">Pub. L. 95–113, § 1602(b)</ref>, revised provisions relating to fees so as to remove requirement that field supervision of weighing be supported by fees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idedec364c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedec364d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2000 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/472/s103/b">section 103(b) of Pub. L. 106–472</ref> effective as if enacted <date date="2000-09-30">Sept. 30, 2000</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/106/472/s111">section 111 of Pub. L. 106–472</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s79">section 79 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedec364e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective and Termination Dates of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">That part of <ref href="/us/pl/100/518/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 100–518</ref> which provided that the amendment made by <ref href="/us/pl/100/518">Pub. L. 100–518</ref> was effective for period <date date="1988-10-01">Oct. 1, 1988</date>, through <date date="1993-09-30">Sept. 30, 1993</date>, inclusive, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/103/156">Pub. L. 103–156</ref>, §§ 13(a), 16(b), <date date="1993-11-24">Nov. 24, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1529">107 Stat. 1529</ref>, 1530, eff. <date date="1993-09-30">Sept. 30, 1993</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedec364f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective and Termination Dates of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tI/s155">Pub. L. 97–35, title I, § 155</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/371">95 Stat. 371</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/98/469/s1">Pub. L. 98–469, § 1</ref>, <date date="1984-10-11">Oct. 11, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1831">98 Stat. 1831</ref>, provided that the amendment made by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> is effective for period beginning <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, and ending <date date="1988-09-30">Sept. 30, 1988</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedec3650-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1977 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/113">Pub. L. 95–113</ref> effective <date date="1977-10-01">Oct. 1, 1977</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/113/s1901">section 1901 of Pub. L. 95–113</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1307">section 1307 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idedec3651-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 30 days after <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/582/s27">section 27 of Pub. L. 94–582</ref>, as amended, set out as an Effective Date of 1976 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s74">section 74 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idedec3652-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">United States Grain Standards Act Extension</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>)(4) of this section to be applied by substituting “<date date="2026-09-30">September 30, 2026</date>” for “<date date="2025-09-30">September 30, 2025</date>”, see <ref href="/us/pl/119/75/dI/s5001">section 5001 of div. I of Pub. L. 119–75</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s79">section 79 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
