<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idf02adc49-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8001"><num value="8001">§ 8001.</num><heading> Producer retention of erroneously paid loan deficiency payments and marketing loan gains</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary and the Commodity Credit Corporation shall not require producers in Erie County, Pennsylvania, to repay loan deficiency payments and marketing loan gains erroneously paid or determined to have been earned by the Commodity Credit Corporation for certain 1998 and 1999 crops under subtitle C of title I of the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7231">7 U.S.C. 7231</ref> et seq.). In the case of a producer who has already made the repayment on or before <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, the Commodity Credit Corporation shall reimburse the producer for the full amount of the repayment.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idf02adc4a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/107/171/tI/s1618">Pub. L. 107–171, title I, § 1618</ref>, <date date="2002-05-13">May 13, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/223">116 Stat. 223</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idf02adc4b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idf02adc4c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idf02adc4d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/104/127">Pub. L. 104–127</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/888">110 Stat. 888</ref>. Subtitle C of title I of the Act is classified generally to subchapter III (§ 7231 et seq.) of chapter 100 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7201">section 7201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
