<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idf03933f1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401"><num value="8401">§ 8401.</num><heading> Regulation of certain biological agents and toxins</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idf03933f2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulatory control of certain biological agents and toxins</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf03933f3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> List of biological agents and toxins</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idf03933f4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/a/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary of Agriculture shall by regulation establish and maintain a list of each biological agent and each toxin that the Secretary determines has the potential to pose a severe threat to animal or plant health, or to animal or plant products.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idf03933f5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/a/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Criteria</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In determining whether to include an agent or toxin on the list under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf03933f6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/a/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> consider—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf03933f7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/a/1/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the effect of exposure to the agent or toxin on animal or plant health, and on the production and marketability of animal or plant products;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf03933f8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/a/1/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the pathogenicity of the agent or the toxicity of the toxin and the methods by which the agent or toxin is transferred to animals or plants;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf03933f9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/a/1/B/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the availability and effectiveness of pharmacotherapies and prophylaxis to treat and prevent any illness caused by the agent or toxin;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf03933fa-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/a/1/B/i/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><item style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf03933fb-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/a/1/B/i/IV/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> whether such inclusion would have a substantial negative impact on the research and development of solutions for the animal or plant disease caused by the agent or toxin; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf03933fc-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/a/1/B/i/IV/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> whether the negative impact described in item (aa) would substantially outweigh the risk posed by the agent or toxin to animal or plant health if it is not included on the list; and</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf03933fd-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/a/1/B/i/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> any other criteria that the Secretary considers appropriate to protect animal or plant health, or animal or plant products; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf03933fe-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/a/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> consult with appropriate Federal departments and agencies and with scientific experts representing appropriate professional groups.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf03933ff-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Biennial review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall review and republish the list under paragraph (1) biennially, or more often as needed, and shall by regulation revise the list as necessary in accordance with such paragraph.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idf0393400-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulation of transfers of listed agents and toxins</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall by regulation provide for—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf0393401-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> the establishment and enforcement of safety procedures for the transfer of listed agents and toxins, including measures to ensure—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf0393402-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> proper training and appropriate skills to handle such agents and toxins; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf0393403-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> proper laboratory facilities to contain and dispose of such agents and toxins;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf0393404-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the establishment and enforcement of safeguard and security measures to prevent access to such agents and toxins for use in domestic or international terrorism or for any other criminal purpose;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf0393405-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the establishment of procedures to protect animal and plant health, and animal and plant products, in the event of a transfer or potential transfer of such an agent or toxin in violation of the safety procedures established under paragraph (1) or the safeguard and security measures established under paragraph (2); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf0393406-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> appropriate availability of biological agents and toxins for research, education, and other legitimate purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idf0393407-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Possession and use of listed agents and toxins</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall by regulation provide for the establishment and enforcement of standards and procedures governing the possession and use of listed agents and toxins, including the provisions described in paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (b), in order to protect animal and plant health, and animal and plant products.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idf0393408-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Registration; identification; database</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf0393409-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Registration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Regulations under subsections (b) and (c) shall require registration with the Secretary of the possession, use, and transfer of listed agents and toxins, and shall include provisions to ensure that persons seeking to register under such regulations have a lawful purpose to possess, use, or transfer such agents and toxins, including provisions in accordance with subsection (e)(6).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf039340a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Identification; database</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Regulations under subsections (b) and (c) shall require that registration include (if available to the person registering) information regarding the characterization of listed agents and toxins to facilitate their identification, including their source. The Secretary shall maintain a national database that includes the names and locations of registered persons, the listed agents and toxins such persons are possessing, using, or transferring, and information regarding the characterization of such agents and toxins.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idf039340b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Safeguard and security requirements for registered persons</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf039340c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Regulations under subsections (b) and (c) shall include appropriate safeguard and security requirements for persons possessing, using, or transferring a listed agent or toxin commensurate with the risk such agent or toxin poses to animal and plant health, and animal and plant products (including the risk of use in domestic or international terrorism). The Secretary shall establish such requirements in collaboration with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Attorney General, and shall ensure compliance with such requirements as part of the registration system under such regulations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf039340d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Limiting access to listed agents and toxins</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Requirements under paragraph (1) shall include provisions to ensure that registered persons—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf039340e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> provide access to listed agents and toxins to only those individuals whom the registered person involved determines have a legitimate need to handle or use such agents and toxins;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf039340f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> submit the names and other identifying information for such individuals to the Secretary and the Attorney General, promptly after first determining that the individuals need access under subparagraph (A), and periodically thereafter while the individuals have such access, not less frequently than once every five years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf0393410-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf0393411-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> in the case of listed agents and toxins that are not overlap agents and toxins (as defined in subsection (g)(1)(A)(ii)), limit or deny access to such agents and toxins by individuals whom the Attorney General has identified as within any category under paragraph (3)(B), if limiting or denying such access by the individuals involved is determined appropriate by the Secretary, in consultation with the Attorney General; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf0393412-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> in the case of listed agents and toxins that are overlap agents—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf0393413-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/2/C/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> deny access to such agents and toxins by individuals whom the Attorney General has identified as within any category referred to in paragraph (3)(B)(i); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf0393414-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/2/C/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> limit or deny access to such agents and toxins by individuals whom the Attorney General has identified as within any category under paragraph (3)(B)(ii), if limiting or denying such access by the individuals involved is determined appropriate by the Secretary, in consultation with the Attorney General.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf0393415-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Submitted names; use of databases by Attorney General</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idf0393416-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Upon the receipt of names and other identifying information under paragraph (2)(B), the Attorney General shall, for the sole purpose of identifying whether the individuals involved are within any of the categories specified in subparagraph (B), promptly use criminal, immigration, national security, and other electronic databases that are available to the Federal Government and are appropriate for such purpose.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idf0393417-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain individuals</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the categories specified in this subparagraph regarding an individual are that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf0393418-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the individual is within any of the categories described in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s175b/d/1">section 175b(d)(1) of title 18</ref> (relating to restricted persons); or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf0393419-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> the individual is reasonably suspected by any Federal law enforcement or intelligence agency of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf039341a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/3/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> committing a crime set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s2332b/g/5">section 2332b(g)(5) of title 18</ref>;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf039341b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/3/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> knowing involvement with an organization that engages in domestic or international terrorism (as defined in section 2331 of such title 18) or with any other organization that engages in intentional crimes of violence; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf039341c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/3/B/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> being an agent of a foreign power (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1801">section 1801 of title 50</ref>).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idf039341d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification by Attorney General regarding submitted names</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">After the receipt of a name and other identifying information under paragraph (2)(B), the Attorney General shall promptly notify the Secretary whether the individual is within any of the categories specified in subparagraph (B).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf039341e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Notifications by Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary, after receiving notice under paragraph (3) regarding an individual, shall promptly notify the registered person involved of whether the individual is granted or denied access under paragraph (2). If the individual is denied such access, the Secretary shall promptly notify the individual of the denial.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf039341f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Expedited review</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Regulations under subsections (b) and (c) shall provide for a procedure through which, upon request to the Secretary by a registered person who submits names and other identifying information under paragraph (2)(B) and who demonstrates good cause, the Secretary may, as determined appropriate by the Secretary—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf0393420-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> request the Attorney General to expedite the process of identification under paragraph (3)(A) and notification of the Secretary under paragraph (3)(C); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf0393421-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> expedite the notification of the registered person by the Secretary under paragraph (4).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf0393422-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Process regarding persons seeking to register</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idf0393423-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/6/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Individuals</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Regulations under subsections (b) and (c) shall provide that an individual who seeks to register under either of such subsections is subject to the same processes described in paragraphs (2) through (4) as apply to names and other identifying information submitted to the Attorney General under paragraph (2)(B). Paragraph (5) does not apply for purposes of this subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idf0393424-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/6/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Other persons</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Regulations under subsections (b) and (c) shall provide that, in determining whether to deny or revoke registration by a person other than an individual, the Secretary shall submit the name of such person to the Attorney General, who shall use criminal, immigration, national security, and other electronic databases available to the Federal Government, as appropriate for the purpose of promptly notifying the Secretary whether the person, or, where relevant, the individual who owns or controls such person, is within any of the categories described in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s175b/d/1">section 175b(d)(1) of title 18</ref> (relating to restricted persons), or is reasonably suspected by any Federal law enforcement or intelligence agency of being within any category specified in paragraph (3)(B)(ii) (as applied to persons, including individuals). Such regulations shall provide that a person who seeks to register under either of such subsections is subject to the same processes described in paragraphs (2) and (4) as apply to names and other identifying information submitted to the Attorney General under paragraph (2)(B). Paragraph (5) does not apply for purposes of this subparagraph. The Secretary may exempt Federal, State, or local governmental agencies from the requirements of this subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba425-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Review</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba426-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/7/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrative review</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba427-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/7/A/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Regulations under subsections (b) and (c) shall provide for an opportunity for a review by the Secretary—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf03ba428-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/7/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> when requested by the individual involved, of a determination under paragraph (2) to deny the individual access to listed agents and toxins; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf03ba429-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/7/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> when requested by the person involved, of a determination under under <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002366">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002366"><num>1</num> So in original.</note> paragraph (6) to deny or revoke registration for such person.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba42a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/7/A/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Ex parte review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">During a review under clause (i), the Secretary may consider information relevant to the review ex parte to the extent that disclosure of the information could compromise national security or an investigation by any law enforcement agency.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba42b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/7/A/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Final agency action</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The decision of the Secretary in a review under clause (i) constitutes final agency action for purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s702">section 702 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba42c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/7/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain procedures</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba42d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/7/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission of ex parte materials in judicial proceedings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">When reviewing a decision of the Secretary under subparagraph (A), and upon request made ex parte and in writing by the United States, a court, upon a sufficient showing, may review and consider ex parte documents containing information the disclosure of which could compromise national security or an investigation by any law enforcement agency. If the court determines that portions of the documents considered ex parte should be disclosed to the person involved to allow a response, the court shall authorize the United States to delete from such documents specified items of information the disclosure of which could compromise national security or an investigation by any law enforcement agency, or to substitute a summary of the information to which the person may respond. Any order by the court authorizing the disclosure of information that the United States believes could compromise national security or an investigation by any law enforcement agency shall be subject to the processes set forth in subparagraphs (A) and (B)(i) of <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s2339B/f/5">section 2339B(f)(5) of title 18</ref> (relating to interlocutory appeal and expedited consideration).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba42e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/7/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Disclosure of information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In a review under subparagraph (A), and in any judical <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002367">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002367"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “judicial”.</note> proceeding conducted pursuant to such review, neither the Secretary nor the Attorney General may be required to disclose to the public any information that under subsection (h) shall not be disclosed under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">section 552 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba42f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Notifications regarding theft or loss of agents</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Requirements under paragraph (1) shall include the prompt notification of the Secretary, and appropriate Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies, of the theft or loss of listed agents and toxins.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba430-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/e/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Technical assistance for registered persons</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary, in consultation with the Attorney General, may provide technical assistance to registered persons to improve security of the facilities of such persons.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba431-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Inspections</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall have the authority to inspect persons subject to regulations under subsection (b) or (c) to ensure their compliance with such regulations, including prohibitions on restricted persons and other provisions of subsection (e).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba432-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemptions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba433-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Overlap agents and toxins</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba434-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba435-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/A/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In the case of overlap agents and toxins, exemptions from the applicability of provisions of regulations under subsection (b) or (c) may be granted only to the extent provided in this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba436-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/A/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">For purposes of this section:</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf03ba437-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><chapeau> The term “overlap agents and toxins” means biological agents and toxins that—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idf03ba438-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/A/ii/I/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> are listed pursuant to subsection (a)(1); and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idf03ba439-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/A/ii/I/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> are listed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s262a/a/1">section 262a(a)(1) of title 42</ref>. <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002368">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002368"><num>3</num> See References in Text note below.</note></content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf03ba43a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><chapeau> The term “overlap agent or toxin” means a biological agent or toxin that—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idf03ba43b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/A/ii/II/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> is listed pursuant to subsection (a)(1); and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idf03ba43c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/A/ii/II/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> is listed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s262a/a/1">section 262a(a)(1) of title 42</ref>. <sup>3</sup></content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba43d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Clinical or diagnostic laboratories</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Regulations under subsections (b) and (c) shall exempt clinical or diagnostic laboratories and other persons who possess, use, or transfer overlap agents or toxins that are contained in specimens presented for diagnosis, verification, or proficiency testing, provided that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf03ba43e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the identification of such agents or toxins is reported to the Secretary, and when required under Federal, State, or local law, to other appropriate authorities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idf03ba43f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> such agents or toxins are transferred or destroyed in a manner set forth by the Secretary by regulation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba440-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Products</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba441-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Regulations under subsections (b) and (c) shall exempt products that are, bear, or contain overlap agents or toxins and are cleared, approved, licensed, or registered under any of the Acts specified in clause (ii), unless the Secretary by order determines that applying additional regulation under subsection (b) or (c) to a specific product is necessary to protect animal or plant health, or animal or plant products.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba442-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Relevant laws</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">For purposes of clause (i), the Acts specified in this clause are the following:</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf03ba443-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/C/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> The Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s301">21 U.S.C. 301</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf03ba444-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/C/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> Section 351 of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s262">42 U.S.C. 262</ref>].</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf03ba445-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/C/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> The Act commonly known as the Virus-Serum-Toxin Act (the eighth paragraph under the heading “Bureau of Animal Industry” in the Act of <date date="1913-03-04">March 4, 1913</date>; <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s151–159">21 U.S.C. 151–159</ref>).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idf03ba446-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/C/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> The Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s136">7 U.S.C. 136</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba447-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/C/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Investigational use</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba448-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/C/iii/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The Secretary may exempt an investigational product that is, bears, or contains an overlap agent or toxin from the applicability of provisions of regulations under subsection (b) or (c) when such product is being used in an investigation authorized under any Federal Act and the Secretary determines that applying additional regulation under subsection (b) or (c) to such product is not necessary to protect animal and plant health, and animal and plant products.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba449-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/C/iii/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain processes</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">Regulations under subsections (b) and (c) shall set forth the procedures for applying for an exemption under subclause (I). In the case of investigational products authorized under any of the Acts specified in clause (ii), the Secretary shall make a determination regarding a request for an exemption not later than 14 days after the first date on which both of the following conditions have been met by the person requesting the exemption:</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idf03ba44a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/C/iii/II/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> The person has submitted to the Secretary an application for the exemption meeting the requirements established by the Secretary.</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="idf03ba44b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/C/iii/II/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> The person has notified the Secretary that the investigation has been authorized under such an Act.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba44c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Agricultural emergencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary may temporarily exempt a person from the applicability of the requirements of this section with respect to an overlap agent or toxin, in whole or in part, if the Secretary determines that such exemption is necessary to provide for the timely participation of the person in a response to a domestic or foreign agricultural emergency that involves such an agent or toxin. With respect to the emergency involved, the exemption under this subparagraph for a person may not exceed 30 days, except that the Secretary, after review of whether such exemption remains necessary, may provide one extension of an additional 30 days.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba44d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/1/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Public health emergencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Upon request of the Secretary of Health and Human Services, after the granting by such Secretary of an exemption under 262a(g)(3) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002369">4</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002369"><num>4</num> So in original. Probably should be preceded by “section”.</note> of title 42 pursuant to a finding that there is a public health emergency, the Secretary of Agriculture may temporarily exempt a person from the applicability of the requirements of this section with respect to an overlap agent or toxin, in whole or in part, to provide for the timely participation of the person in a response to the public health emergency. With respect to the emergency involved, such exemption for a person may not exceed 30 days, except that upon request of the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Agriculture may, after review of whether such exemption remains necessary, provide one extension of an additional 30 days.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba44e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> General authority for exemptions not involving overlap agents or toxins</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of listed agents or toxins that are not overlap agents or toxins, the Secretary may grant exemptions from the applicability of provisions of regulations under subsection (b) or (c) if the Secretary determines that such exemptions are consistent with protecting animal and plant health, and animal and plant products.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba44f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Disclosure of information</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba450-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Nondisclosure of certain information</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No Federal agency specified in paragraph (2) shall disclose under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">section 552 of title 5</ref> any of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf03ba451-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Any registration or transfer documentation submitted under subsections (b) and (c), or permits issued prior to <date date="2002-06-12">June 12, 2002</date>, for the possession, use or transfer of a listed agent or toxin; or information derived therefrom to the extent that it identifies the listed agent or toxin possessed, used or transferred by a specific person or discloses the identity or location of a specific person.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf03ba452-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The national database developed pursuant to subsection (d), or any other compilation of the registration or transfer information submitted under subsections (b) and (c) to the extent that such compilation discloses site-specific registration or transfer information.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf03ba453-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/h/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Any portion of a record that discloses the site-specific or transfer-specific safeguard and security measures used by a registered person to prevent unauthorized access to listed agents and toxins.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf03ba454-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/h/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Any notification of a release of a listed agent or toxin submitted under subsections (b) and (c), or any notification of theft or loss submitted under such subsections.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf03ba455-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/h/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Any portion of an evaluation or report of an inspection of a specific registered person conducted under subsection (f) that identifies the listed agent or toxin possessed by a specific registered person or that discloses the identity or location of a specific registered person if the agency determines that public disclosure of the information would endanger animal or plant health, or animal or plant products.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba456-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Covered agencies</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of paragraph (1) only, the Federal agencies specified in this paragraph are the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf03ba457-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of Justice, the Department of Agriculture, and the Department of Transportation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf03ba458-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any Federal agency to which information specified in paragraph (1) is transferred by any agency specified in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf03ba459-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/h/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Any Federal agency that is a registered person, or has a sub-agency component that is a registered person.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf03ba45a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/h/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Any Federal agency that awards grants or enters into contracts or cooperative agreements involving listed agents and toxins to or with a registered person, and to which information specified in paragraph (1) is transferred by any such registered person.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba45b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/h/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Other exemptions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">This subsection may not be construed as altering the application of any exemptions to public disclosure under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">section 552 of title 5</ref>, except as to subsection <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002370">5</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002370"><num>5</num> So in original. Probably should be “section”.</note> 552(b)(3) of such title, to any of the information specified in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba45c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/h/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as specifically provided in paragraph (1), this subsection may not be construed as altering the authority of any Federal agency to withhold under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">section 552 of title 5</ref>, or the obligation of any Federal agency to disclose under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">section 552 of title 5</ref>, any information, including information relating to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf03ba45d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/h/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> listed agents and toxins, or individuals seeking access to such agents and toxins;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf03ba45e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/h/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> registered persons, or persons seeking to register their possession, use, or transfer of such agents and toxins;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf03ba45f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/h/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> general safeguard and security policies and requirements under regulations under subsections (b) and (c); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf03ba460-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/h/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> summary or statistical information concerning registrations, registrants, denials or revocations of registrations, listed agents and toxins, inspection evaluations and reports, or individuals seeking access to such agents and toxins.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba461-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/h/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Disclosures to Congress; other disclosures</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">This subsection may not be construed as providing any authority—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf03ba462-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/h/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to withhold information from the Congress or any committee or subcommittee thereof; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf03ba463-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/h/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to withhold information from any person under any other Federal law or treaty.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba464-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil money penalty</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba465-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/i/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In addition to any other penalties that may apply under law, any person who violates any provision of regulations under subsection (b) or (c) shall be subject to the United States for a civil money penalty in an amount not exceeding $250,000 in the case of an individual and $500,000 in the case of any other person.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba466-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/i/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability of certain provisions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The provisions of sections 423 and 425(2) of the Plant Protection Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7733">7 U.S.C. 7733</ref> and 7735(2)) shall apply to a civil money penalty or activity under paragraph (1) in the same manner as such provisions apply to a penalty or activity under the Plant Protection Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7701">7 U.S.C. 7701</ref> et seq.].</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba467-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification in event of release</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Regulations under subsections (b) and (c) shall require the prompt notification of the Secretary by a registered person whenever a release, meeting criteria established by the Secretary, of a listed agent or toxin has occurred outside of the biocontainment area of a facility of the registered person. Upon receipt of such notification and a finding by the Secretary that the release poses a threat to animal or plant health, or animal or plant products, the Secretary shall take appropriate action to notify relevant Federal, State, and local authorities, and, if necessary, other appropriate persons (including the public). If the released listed agent or toxin is an overlap agent or toxin, the Secretary shall promptly notify the Secretary of Health and Human Services upon notification by the registered person.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba468-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall report to the Congress annually on the number and nature of notifications received under subsection (e)(8) (relating to theft or loss) and subsection (j) (relating to releases).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba469-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf03ba46a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/l/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The terms “biological agent” and “toxin” have the meanings given such terms in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s178">section 178 of title 18</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf03ba46b-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/l/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “listed agents and toxins” means biological agents and toxins listed pursuant to subsection (a)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf03ba46c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/l/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “listed agents or toxins” means biological agents or toxins listed pursuant to subsection (a)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf03ba46d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/l/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The terms “overlap agents and toxins” and “overlap agent or toxin” have the meaning given such terms in subsection (g)(1)(A)(ii).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf03ba46e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/l/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The term “person” includes Federal, State, and local governmental entities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf03ba46f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/l/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The term “registered person” means a person registered under regulations under subsection (b) or (c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf03ba470-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/l/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idf03ba471-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s8401/m"><num value="m" class="bold">(m)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of carrying out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2002 through 2007, in addition to other funds that may be available.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idf03ba472-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/107/188/tII/s212">Pub. L. 107–188, title II, § 212</ref>, <date date="2002-06-12">June 12, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/647">116 Stat. 647</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/296/tXVII/s1709/b">Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1709(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2319">116 Stat. 2319</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/334/tXII/s12204">Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12204</ref>, <date date="2018-12-20">Dec. 20, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4949">132 Stat. 4949</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idf03ba473-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idf03ba474-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idf03ba475-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s262a/a/1">Section 262a(a)(1) of title 42</ref>, referred to in subsec. (g)(1)(A)(ii), was in the original “section 315A(a)(1) of the Public Health Service Act”, and was translated as meaning section 351A(a)(1) of that Act to reflect the probable intent of Congress, because the Public Health Service Act does not contain a section 315A and section 351A refers to a list of biological agents and toxins.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, referred to in subsec. (g)(1)(C)(ii)(I), is <ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch675">act June 25, 1938, ch. 675</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/1040">52 Stat. 1040</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 9 (§ 301 et seq.) of Title 21, Food and Drugs. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s301">section 301 of Title 21</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Act commonly known as the Virus-Serum-Toxin Act, referred to in subsec. (g)(1)(C)(ii)(III), is the eighth paragraph under the heading “Bureau of Animal Industry” of <ref href="/us/act/1913-03-04/ch145">act Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 145</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/37/832">37 Stat. 832</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 5 (§ 151 et seq.) of Title 21, Food and Drugs. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s151">section 151 of Title 21</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act, referred to in subsec. (g)(1)(C)(ii)(IV), is <ref href="/us/act/1947-06-25/ch125">act June 25, 1947, ch. 125</ref>, as amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/92/516">Pub. L. 92–516</ref>, <date date="1972-10-21">Oct. 21, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/973">86 Stat. 973</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 136 et seq.) of chapter 6 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s136">section 136 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Plant Protection Act, referred to in subsec. (i)(2), is title IV of <ref href="/us/pl/106/224">Pub. L. 106–224</ref>, <date date="2000-06-20">June 20, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/438">114 Stat. 438</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 104 (§ 7701 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7701">section 7701 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idf03ba476-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (a)(1)(B)(i)(IV), (V). <ref href="/us/pl/115/334">Pub. L. 115–334</ref> added subcl. (IV) and redesignated former subcl. (IV) as (V).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref> substituted “collaboration with the Secretary of Homeland Security and” for “consultation with”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idf03ba477-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idf03ba478-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2002 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref> effective 60 days after <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/296/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 107–296</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s101">section 101 of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="idf03ba479-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/188/tII/s211">Pub. L. 107–188, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="2002-06-12">June 12, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/647">116 Stat. 647</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/188/tII/s211">“This subtitle [subtitle B (§§ 211–213) of title II of <ref href="/us/pl/107/188">Pub. L. 107–188</ref>, enacting this subchapter] may be cited as the ‘Agricultural Bioterrorism Protection Act of 2002’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idf03ba47a-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Implementation by Department of Agriculture</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/188/tII/s213">Pub. L. 107–188, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="2002-06-12">June 12, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/656">116 Stat. 656</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/188/tII/s213">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Date Certain for Promulgation of List</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2002-06-12">June 12, 2002</date>], the Secretary of Agriculture (referred to in this section as the ‘Secretary’) shall promulgate an interim final rule that establishes the initial list under section 212(a)(1) [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8401/a/1">7 U.S.C. 8401(a)(1)</ref>]. In promulgating such rule, the Secretary shall provide written guidance on the manner in which the notice required in subsection (b) is to be provided to the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Date Certain for Notice of Possession</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the Secretary promulgates the interim final rule under subsection (a), all persons (unless exempt under section 212(g) [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8401/g">7 U.S.C. 8401(g)</ref>]) in possession of biological agents or toxins included on the list referred to in subsection (a) shall notify the Secretary of such possession.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Date Certain for Promulgation; Effective Date Regarding Criminal and Civil Penalties</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2002-06-12">June 12, 2002</date>], the Secretary shall promulgate an interim final rule for carrying out section 212 [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8401">7 U.S.C. 8401</ref>], other than for the list referred to in subsection (a) of this section (but such rule may incorporate by reference provisions promulgated pursuant to subsection (a)). Such interim final rule shall take effect 60 days after the date on which such rule is promulgated, including for purposes of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s175b/c">section 175b(c) of title 18</ref>, United States Code (relating to criminal penalties), as added by section 231(a)(5) of this Act; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> section 212(i) of this Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8401/i">7 U.S.C. 8401(i)</ref>] (relating to civil penalties).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transitional Provision Regarding Current Research and Education</inline>.—</heading><content>The interim final rule under subsection (c) shall include time frames for the applicability of the rule that minimize disruption of research or educational projects that involve biological agents and toxins listed pursuant to section 212(a)(1) [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8401/a/1">7 U.S.C. 8401(a)(1)</ref>] and that were underway as of the effective date of such rule.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
