<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idedeea6f2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s87c"><num value="87c">§ 87c.</num><heading> Criminal penalties</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idedeea6f3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s87c/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Any person who commits any offense prohibited by <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s87b">section 87b of this title</ref> (except an offense prohibited by paragraphs (a)(7), (a)(8), and (b)(4) in which case the person shall be subject to the general penal statutes in title 18 relating to crimes and offenses against the United States) shall be guilty of a felony and shall, on conviction thereof, be subject to imprisonment for not more than five years, or a fine of not more than $20,000, or both such imprisonment and fine.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idedeea6f4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s87c/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as requiring the Secretary to report minor violations of this chapter for criminal prosecution whenever the Secretary believes that the public interest will be adequately served by a suitable written notice or warning, or to report any violation of this chapter for prosecution when the Secretary believes that institution of a proceeding under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s86">section 86 of this title</ref> will obtain compliance with this chapter and the Secretary institutes such a proceeding.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idedeea6f5-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s87c/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> Any officer or employee of the Department of Agriculture assigned to perform weighing functions under this chapter shall be considered as an employee of the Department of Agriculture assigned to perform inspection functions for the purposes of sections 1114 and 111 of Title 18.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idedeea6f6-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1916-08-11/ch313">Aug. 11, 1916, ch. 313</ref>, pt. B, § 14, as added <ref href="/us/pl/90/487/s1">Pub. L. 90–487, § 1</ref>, <date date="1968-08-15">Aug. 15, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/767">82 Stat. 767</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/94/582/s17">Pub. L. 94–582, § 17</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2884">90 Stat. 2884</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/156">Pub. L. 103–156</ref>, §§ 8, 12(m), <date date="1993-11-24">Nov. 24, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1527">107 Stat. 1527</ref>, 1529; <ref href="/us/pl/103/354/tII/s293/a/7">Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 293(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3237">108 Stat. 3237</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idedeea6f7-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idedeea6f8-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idedeea6f9-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/354">Pub. L. 103–354</ref> substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—<ref href="/us/pl/103/156/s12/m">Pub. L. 103–156, § 12(m)</ref>, which directed amendment of “Section 14”, without specifying the name of the Act being amended, was executed to this section, which is section 14 of the United States Grain Standards Act, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/156">Pub. L. 103–156</ref>, §§ 8, 12(m)(1), substituted “the person” for “he”, and struck out “shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and shall, on conviction thereof, be subject to imprisonment for not more than twelve months, or a fine of not more than $10,000, or both such imprisonment and fine; but, for each subsequent offense subject to this subsection, such person” before “shall be guilty of a felony”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/156/s12/m/2">Pub. L. 103–156, § 12(m)(2)</ref>, substituted “the Administrator” for “he” in three places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/582">Pub. L. 94–582</ref> inserted “(except an offense prohibited by paragraphs (a)(7), (a)(8), and (b)(4) in which case he shall be subject to the general penal statutes in Title 18 relating to crimes and offenses against the United States)”, increased the punishment for misdemeanors from six months to twelve months and the fine from $3,000 to $10,000, and denominated subsequent offenses as felonies, substituting “but, for each subsequent offense subject to this subsection, such person shall be guilty of a felony and shall, on conviction thereof, be subject to imprisonment for not more than five years, or a fine of not more than $20,000, or both such imprisonment and fine” for “but if such offense is committed after one conviction of such person under this section has become final, such person shall be subject to imprisonment for not more than one year, or a fine of not more than $5,000, or both such imprisonment and fine”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/94/582">Pub. L. 94–582</ref> substituted “Administrator” for “Secretary” and inserted provision that nothing in this chapter shall be construed as requiring the Administrator to report any violation of this chapter for prosecution when he believes that institution of a proceeding under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s86">section 86 of this title</ref> will obtain compliance with this chapter and he institutes such a proceeding.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/94/582">Pub. L. 94–582</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idedeea6fa-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idedeea6fb-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/582">Pub. L. 94–582</ref> effective 30 days after <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/582/s27">section 27 of Pub. L. 94–582</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s74">section 74 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idedeea6fc-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of section, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/487/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 90–487</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1968 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s78">section 78 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
