<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idee59ec1c-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s906"><num value="906">§ 906.</num><heading> Funding for administrative expenses</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of administering this chapter and for the purpose of making the studies, investigations, publications, and reports herein provided for, there is authorized to be appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, such sums as shall be necessary.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idee59ec1d-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/act/1936-05-20/ch432">May 20, 1936, ch. 432</ref>, title I, § 6, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1365">49 Stat. 1365</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-10-28/ch776/s2">Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 776, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/948">63 Stat. 948</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/124/s3">Pub. L. 94–124, § 3</ref>, <date date="1975-11-04">Nov. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/677">89 Stat. 677</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/437/s4/a/3">Pub. L. 103–437, § 4(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4581">108 Stat. 4581</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/tVII/s775">Pub. L. 104–127, title VII, § 775</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1150">110 Stat. 1150</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idee59ec1e-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idee59ec1f-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idee59ec20-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—<ref href="/us/pl/104/127">Pub. L. 104–127</ref> struck out at end “On or before February 15, of each calendar year beginning with calendar year 1976, or such other date as may be specified by the appropriate committee, the Secretary of Agriculture shall testify before the House Committee on Agriculture and the Senate Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry and provide justification in detail of the amount requested in the budget to be appropriated for the next fiscal year for the purpose of administering this chapter and for the purpose of making the studies, investigations, publications, and reports herein authorized.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/437">Pub. L. 103–437</ref> substituted “Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry” for “Committee on Agriculture and Forestry”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—<ref href="/us/pl/94/124">Pub. L. 94–124</ref> inserted requirement that the Secretary of Agriculture testify before the House Committee on Agriculture and the Senate Committee on Agriculture and Forestry each calendar year on or before February 15th or other date specified by the Committees to provide justification in detail of the amount requested in the budget to be appropriated for the next fiscal year.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1949—Act <date date="1949-10-28">Oct. 28, 1949</date>, inserted “title I,” in credit of act <date date="1936-05-20">May 20, 1936</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
