<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idf05372ea-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s9204"><num value="9204">§ 9204.</num><heading> Availability of data and congressional briefings</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idf05372eb-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s9204/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Every 6 months until the date described in subsection (b), the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the heads of other appropriate Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate, shall provide to the Committees on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry and Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committees on Agriculture and Homeland Security of the House of Representatives a report and briefing describing—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf05372ec-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s9204/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> progress under each phase described in the memorandum of agreement entitled “Memorandum of Agreement Between the U.S. Department of Agriculture Marketing and Regulatory Programs, the U.S. Department of Agriculture Research, Education, and Economics, and the Department of Homeland Security Science and Technology Directorate” and dated <date date="2019-06-20">June 20, 2019</date>, that is not completed as of <date date="2020-12-27">December 27, 2020</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf05372ed-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s9204/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the status of the actions taken pursuant to the areas of collaborative opportunity and responsibilities as described in the memorandum of understanding entitled “Memorandum of Understanding Between the U.S. Department of Agriculture Marketing and Regulatory Programs, the U.S. Department of Agriculture Research, Education, and Economics, and the Department of Homeland Security Science and Technology Directorate for National Bio and Agro-Defense Facility Collaboration” and dated <date date="2020-01-07">January 7, 2020</date>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idf05372ee-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s9204/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> the operations and mission of the National Bio and Agro-Defense Facility, including the coordination and carrying out of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf05372ef-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s9204/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the memorandum of agreement and memorandum of understanding described in paragraphs (1) and (2), respectively;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf05372f0-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s9204/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any successor memoranda of agreement or understanding to the memorandum of agreement and memorandum of understanding described in paragraphs (1) and (2), respectively;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf05372f1-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s9204/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> any similar joint agreement or understanding between the Department of Agriculture and the Department of Homeland Security, or other relevant agencies, that documents the biodefense mission of the National Bio and Agro-Defense Facility; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idf05372f2-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s9204/a/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> research, including a description of the users of the National Bio and Agro-Defense Facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idf05372f3-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9" identifier="/us/usc/t7/s9204/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The reporting and briefing requirements under subsection (a) shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date on which the National Bio and Agro-Defense Facility attains full operating capability.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idf05372f4-3a6e-11f1-addd-bbaf0b3f68e9">(<ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dP/s5">Pub. L. 116–260, div. P, § 5</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2160">134 Stat. 2160</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
