<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc2c07259-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1524"><num value="1524">§ 1524.</num><heading> Vocational training for certain pension recipients</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2c0725a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1524/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2c0725b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1524/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In the case of a veteran under age 45 who is awarded a pension during the program period, the Secretary shall, based on information on file with the Department of Veterans Affairs, make a preliminary finding whether such veteran, with the assistance of a vocational training program under this section, has a good potential for achieving employment. If such potential is found to exist, the Secretary shall solicit from the veteran an application for vocational training under this section. If the veteran thereafter applies for such training, the Secretary shall provide the veteran with an evaluation, which may include a personal interview, to determine whether the achievement of a vocational goal is reasonably feasible.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2c0725c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1524/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If a veteran who is 45 years of age or older and is awarded pension during the program period, or a veteran who was awarded pension before the beginning of the program period, applies for vocational training under this section and the Secretary makes a preliminary finding on the basis of information in the application that, with the assistance of a vocational training program under subsection (b) of this section, the veteran has a good potential for achieving employment, the Secretary shall provide the veteran with an evaluation in order to determine whether the achievement of a vocational goal by the veteran is reasonably feasible. Any such evaluation shall include a personal interview by a Department employee trained in vocational counseling.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2c0725d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1524/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> For the purposes of this section, the term “program period” means the period beginning on <date date="1985-02-01">February 1, 1985</date>, and ending on <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2c0725e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1524/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2c0725f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1524/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If the Secretary, based upon an evaluation under subsection (a) of this section, determines that the achievement of a vocational goal by a veteran is reasonably feasible, the veteran shall be offered and may elect to pursue a vocational training program under this subsection. If the veteran elects to pursue such a program, the program shall be designed in consultation with the veteran in order to meet the veteran’s individual needs and shall be set forth in an individualized written plan of vocational rehabilitation of the kind described in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3107">section 3107 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2c07260-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1524/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2c07261-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1524/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Subject to subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, a vocational training program under this subsection shall consist of vocationally oriented services and assistance of the kind provided under chapter 31 of this title and such other services and assistance of the kind provided under that chapter as are necessary to enable the veteran to prepare for and participate in vocational training or employment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2c07262-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1524/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> A vocational training program under this subsection—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2c07263-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1524/b/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> may not exceed 24 months unless, based on a determination by the Secretary that an extension is necessary in order for the veteran to achieve a vocational goal identified (before the end of the first 24 months of such program) in the written plan formulated for the veteran, the Secretary grants an extension for a period not to exceed 24 months;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2c07264-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1524/b/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> may not include the provision of any loan or subsistence allowance or any automobile adaptive equipment of the kind provided under chapter 39 of this title; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2c07265-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1524/b/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> may include a program of education at an institution of higher learning (as defined in sections 3452(b) and 3452(f), respectively, of this title) only in a case in which the Secretary determines that the program involved is predominantly vocational in content.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2c07266-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1524/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> When a veteran completes a vocational training program under this subsection, the Secretary may provide the veteran with counseling of the kind described in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3104/a/2">section 3104(a)(2) of this title</ref>, placement and postplacement services of the kind described in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3104/a/5">section 3104(a)(5) of this title</ref>, and training of the kind described in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3104/a/6">section 3104(a)(6) of this title</ref> during a period not to exceed 18 months beginning on the date of such completion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2c07267-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1524/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> A veteran may not begin pursuit of a vocational training program under this subsection after the later of (A) <date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>, or (B) the end of a reasonable period of time, as determined by the Secretary, following either the evaluation of the veteran under subsection (a) of this section or the award of pension to the veteran as described in subsection (a)(2) of this section. Any determination by the Secretary of such a reasonable period of time shall be made pursuant to regulations which the Secretary shall prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2c07268-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1524/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> In the case of a veteran who has been determined to have a permanent and total non-service-connected disability and who, not later than one year after the date the veteran’s eligibility for counseling under subsection (b)(3) of this section expires, secures employment within the scope of a vocational goal identified in the veteran’s individualized written plan of vocational rehabilitation (or in a related field which requires reasonably developed skills and the use of some or all of the training or services furnished the veteran under such plan), the evaluation of the veteran as having a permanent and total disability may not be terminated by reason of the veteran’s capacity to engage in such employment until the veteran first maintains such employment for a period of not less than 12 consecutive months.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2c07269-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1524/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> A veteran who pursues a vocational training program under subsection (b) of this section shall have the benefit of the provisions of subsection (a) of <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1525">section 1525 of this title</ref> beginning at such time as the veteran’s entitlement to pension is terminated by reason of income from work or training (as defined in subsection (b)(1) of that section) without regard to the date on which the veteran’s entitlement to pension is terminated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2c0726a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1524/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> Payments by the Secretary for education, training, and other services and assistance under subsection (b) of this section (other than the services of Department employees) shall be made from the Department appropriations account from which payments for pension are made.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc2c0726b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/98/543/tIII/s301/a/1">Pub. L. 98–543, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-24">Oct. 24, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2744">98 Stat. 2744</ref>, § 524; amended <ref href="/us/pl/99/576/tVII/s703/b/1">Pub. L. 99–576, title VII, § 703(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-28">Oct. 28, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3303">100 Stat. 3303</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/227/tII/s202">Pub. L. 100–227, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1987-12-31">Dec. 31, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1555">101 Stat. 1555</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/687/dB/tXIII/s1303/a">Pub. L. 100–687, div. B, title XIII, § 1303(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4128">102 Stat. 4128</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/237/tI/s114">Pub. L. 101–237, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="1989-12-18">Dec. 18, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2065">103 Stat. 2065</ref>; renumbered § 1524 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/83">Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(a)(3), (4), (b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/404-406">105 Stat. 404–406</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/291/s2/b">Pub. L. 102–291, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-05-20">May 20, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/178">106 Stat. 178</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/568/tIV/s402/a">Pub. L. 102–568, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>–(c)(2)(A), <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4337">106 Stat. 4337</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/446/tXII/s1201/g/2">Pub. L. 103–446, title XII, § 1201(g)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4687">108 Stat. 4687</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc2c0726c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc2c0726d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc2c0726e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/446">Pub. L. 103–446</ref> substituted “If” for “Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, if”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—<ref href="/us/pl/102/568/s402/c/2/A">Pub. L. 102–568, § 402(c)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “Vocational training for certain pension recipients” for “Temporary program of vocational training for certain new pension recipients” as section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/568/s402/a">Pub. L. 102–568, § 402(a)</ref>, amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “Subject to paragraph (3) of this subsection, in the case of a veteran under the age of 45 who is awarded pension during the program period, the Secretary shall determine whether the achievement of a vocational goal by the veteran is reasonably feasible. Any such determination shall be made only after evaluation of the veteran’s potential for rehabilitation, and any such evaluation shall include a personal interview of the veteran by a Department employee who is trained in vocational counseling. If the veteran fails, for reasons other than those beyond the veteran’s control, to participate in the evaluation in the manner required by the Secretary in order to make such determination, the Secretary shall suspend the veteran’s pension for the duration of such failure.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/102/568/s402/b">Pub. L. 102–568, § 402(b)</ref>, redesignated par. (4) as (3), substituted “<date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>” for “<date date="1992-12-31">December 31, 1992</date>”, and struck out former par. (3) which read as follows: “Not more than 3,500 veterans may be given evaluations under this subsection during any 12-month period beginning on February 1 of a year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/102/568/s402/b/2">Pub. L. 102–568, § 402(b)(2)</ref>, redesignated par. (4) as (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/291">Pub. L. 102–291</ref> substituted “<date date="1992-12-31">December 31, 1992</date>” for “<date date="1992-01-31">January 31, 1992</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/102/568/s402/c/1">Pub. L. 102–568, § 402(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “<date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>” for “<date date="1992-01-31">January 31, 1992</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—<ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/a">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s524">section 524 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s4/b/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, (2)(E), substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator” wherever appearing in pars. (1) and (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s4/a/3">Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(a)(3)</ref>, (4), substituted “Department” for “Veterans’ Administration” in pars. (1) and (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/c/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “3107” for “1507”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s4/b/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, (2)(E), substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s4/b/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, (2)(E), substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/c/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “3452(b) and 3452(f)” for “1652(b) and 1652(f)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s4/b/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, (2)(E), substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/c/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “3104(a)(2)” for “1504(a)(2)”, “3104(a)(5)” for “1504(a)(5)”, and “3104(a)(6)” for “1504(a)(6)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s4/b/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, (2)(E), substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s4/b/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, (2)(E), substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/c/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “1525” for “525”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s4/b/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, (2)(E), substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s4/a/3">Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(a)(3)</ref>, (4), substituted “Department” for “Veterans’ Administration” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (a)(1), (2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/237/s114/a">Pub. L. 101–237, § 114(a)</ref>, substituted “45” for “50”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c) to (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/237/s114/b">Pub. L. 101–237, § 114(b)</ref>, added subsec. (c) and redesignated former subsecs. (c) and (d) as (d) and (e), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/687/s1303/a">Pub. L. 100–687, § 1303(a)</ref>, substituted “is awarded pension during the program period, or a veteran who was awarded pension before the beginning of the program period,” for “who is awarded pension during the program period”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (a)(4), (b)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/100/687/s1303/b">Pub. L. 100–687, § 1303(b)</ref>, substituted “1992” for “1989”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/227">Pub. L. 100–227</ref> substituted “3,500” for “2,500”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/576/s703/b/1/A">Pub. L. 99–576, § 703(b)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “subsection (b) of this section” for “subsection (d) of this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/99/576/s703/b/1/B">Pub. L. 99–576, § 703(b)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “subsection (a) of this section” for “subsection (a)(1) of this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/576/s703/b/1/C">Pub. L. 99–576, § 703(b)(1)(C)</ref>, substituted “A veteran” for “Notwithstanding subsection (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s525">section 525 of this title</ref>, a veteran” and “defined in subsection (b)(1) of that section” for “defined in subsection (b) of that section”, and inserted “without regard to the date on which the veteran’s entitlement to pension is terminated.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc2c0726f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc2c07270-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/291">Pub. L. 102–291</ref> effective <date date="1992-01-31">Jan. 31, 1992</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/291/s2/d">section 2(d) of Pub. L. 102–291</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1163">section 1163 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc2c07271-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/576">Pub. L. 99–576</ref> effective as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/98/543">Pub. L. 98–543</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/576/s703/c">section 703(c) of Pub. L. 99–576</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1313">section 1313 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc2c07272-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Ratification of Actions of Secretary of Veterans Affairs During Lapsed Period</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provision of a vocational training program to a veteran under this section and the making of related determinations under this section ratified with respect to period beginning <date date="1992-02-01">Feb. 1, 1992</date>, and ending <date date="1992-05-20">May 20, 1992</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/291/s2/e">section 2(e) of Pub. L. 102–291</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1163">section 1163 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc2c07273-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report to Congressional Committees; New Pension Recipients; Health-Care Eligibility</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/543/s301/b">Section 301(b) of Pub. L. 98–543</ref> directed Administrator of Veterans’ Affairs to submit to Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of Senate and House of Representatives not later than <date date="1988-04-15">Apr. 15, 1988</date>, a report on results of implementation of this section and section 525 [now 1525] of this title during period beginning on <date date="1985-02-01">Feb. 1, 1985</date>, and ending on <date date="1988-01-31">Jan. 31, 1988</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
