<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc2dd21cf-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A"><num value="1704A">§ 1704A.</num><heading> Independent assessments of health care delivery systems and management processes</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2dd21d0-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Independent Assessments</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2dd21d1-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not less frequently than once every 10 years, the Secretary shall enter into one or more contracts with a private sector entity or entities described in subsection (d) to conduct an independent assessment of the hospital care, medical services, and other health care furnished by the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2dd21d2-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Each assessment required under paragraph (1) shall address each of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2dd21d3-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Current and projected demographics and unique health care needs of the patient population served by the Department.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2dd21d4-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The accuracy of models and forecasting methods used by the Department to project health care demand, including with respect to veteran demographics, rates of use of health care furnished by the Department, the inflation of health care costs, and such other factors as may be determined relevant by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2dd21d5-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The reliability and accuracy of models and forecasting methods used by the Department to project the budgetary needs of the Veterans Health Administration and how such models and forecasting methods inform budgetary trends.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2dd21d6-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The authorities and mechanisms under which the Secretary may furnish hospital care, medical services, and other health care at facilities of the Department and non-Department facilities, including through Federal and private sector partners and at joint medical facilities, and the effect of such authorities and mechanisms on eligibility and access to care.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2dd21d7-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> The organization, workflow processes, and tools used by the Department to support clinical staffing, access to care, effective length-of-stay management and care transitions, positive patient experience, accurate documentation, and subsequent coding of inpatient services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2dd21d8-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> The efforts of the Department to recruit and retain staff at levels necessary to carry out the functions of the Veterans Health Administration and the process used by the Department to determine staffing levels necessary for such functions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2dd21d9-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><chapeau> The staffing level at each medical facility of the Department and the productivity of each health care provider at the medical facility, compared with health care industry performance metrics, which may include the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc2dd21da-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/G/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> An assessment of the case load of, and number of patients treated by, each health care provider at such medical facility during an average week.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc2dd21db-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/G/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> An assessment of the time spent by each such health care provider on matters other than the case load of the health care provider, including time spent by the health care provider as follows:</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc2dd21dc-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/G/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> At a medical facility that is affiliated with the Department.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc2dd21dd-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/G/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> Conducting research.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc2dd21de-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/G/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> Training or supervising other health care professionals of the Department.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc2dd21df-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/G/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> An assessment of the complexity of health care conditions per patient treated by each health care provider at such medical facility during an average week.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2dd21e0-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> The information technology strategies of the Department with respect to furnishing and managing health care, including an identification of any weaknesses or opportunities with respect to the technology used by the Department, especially those strategies with respect to clinical documentation of hospital care, medical services, and other health care, including any clinical images and associated textual reports, furnished by the Department in facilities of the Department or non-Department facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2dd21e1-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><chapeau> Business processes of the Veterans Health Administration, including processes relating to furnishing non-Department health care, insurance identification, third-party revenue collection, and vendor reimbursement, including an identification of mechanisms as follows:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc2dd21e2-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/I/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> To avoid the payment of penalties to vendors.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc2dd21e3-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/I/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> To increase the collection of amounts owed to the Department for hospital care, medical services, or other health care provided by the Department for which reimbursement from a third party is authorized and to ensure that such amounts collected are accurate.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc2dd21e4-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/I/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> To increase the collection of any other amounts owed to the Department with respect to hospital care, medical services, or other health care and to ensure that such amounts collected are accurate.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc2dd21e5-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/I/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> To increase the accuracy and timeliness of payments by the Department to vendors and providers.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc2dd21e6-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/I/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> To reduce expenditures while improving the quality of care furnished.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2dd21e7-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><chapeau> The purchase, distribution, and use of pharmaceuticals, medical and surgical supplies, medical devices, and health care-related services by the Department, including the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc2dd21e8-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/J/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> The prices paid for, standardization of, and use by, the Department with respect to the following:</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc2dd21e9-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/J/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> Pharmaceuticals.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc2dd21ea-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/J/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> Medical and surgical supplies.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc2dd21eb-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/J/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> Medical devices.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc2dd21ec-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/J/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The use by the Department of group purchasing arrangements to purchase pharmaceuticals, medical and surgical supplies, medical devices, and health care-related services.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc2dd21ed-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/J/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> The strategy and systems used by the Department to distribute pharmaceuticals, medical and surgical supplies, medical devices, and health care-related services to Veterans Integrated Service Networks and medical facilities of the Department.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2dd21ee-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/K"><num value="K">(K)</num><content> The competency of Department leadership with respect to culture, accountability, reform readiness, leadership development, physician alignment, employee engagement, succession planning, and performance management.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2dd21ef-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/L"><num value="L">(L)</num><content> The effectiveness of the authorities and programs of the Department to educate and train health personnel pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s7302">section 7302 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2dd21f0-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/M"><num value="M">(M)</num><content> The conduct of medical and prosthetic research of the Department.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2dd21f1-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/N"><num value="N">(N)</num><content> The provision of assistance by the Department to Federal agencies and personnel involved in responding to a disaster or emergency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2dd21f2-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/a/2/O"><num value="O">(O)</num><content> Such additional matters as may be determined relevant by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2dd21f3-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Timing</inline>.—</heading><content>The private sector entity or entities carrying out an assessment pursuant to subsection (a) shall complete such assessment not later than 18 months after entering into the contract described in such paragraph.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2dd21f4-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Leveraging of Existing Data and Contracts</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>To the extent practicable, the private sector entity or entities carrying out an assessment pursuant to subsection (a) shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2dd21f5-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> make maximum use of existing data that has been compiled by the Department, compiled for the Department, or purchased by the Department, including data that has been collected for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc2dd21f6-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the performance of quadrennial market assessments under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s7330C">section 7330C of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc2dd21f7-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the quarterly publication of information on staffing and vacancies with respect to the Veterans Health Administration pursuant to section 505 of the VA MISSION Act of 2018 (<ref href="/us/pl/115/182">Public Law 115–182</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s301">38 U.S.C. 301</ref> note); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc2dd21f8-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the conduct of annual audits pursuant to section 3102 of the Johnny Isakson and David P. Roe, M.D. Veterans Health Care and Benefits Improvement Act of 2020 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/315">Public Law 116–315</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1701">38 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2dd21f9-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> maximize the use of existing contracts and other agreements of the Department for studies, analysis, data collection, or research in order to efficiently fulfill the requirements of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2dd21fa-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Private Sector Entities Described</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A private sector entity described in this subsection is a private entity that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2dd21fb-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> has experience and proven outcomes in optimizing the performance of national health care delivery systems, including the Veterans Health Administration, other federal health care systems, and systems in the private, non-profit, or public health care sector;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2dd21fc-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> specializes in implementing large-scale organizational and cultural transformations, especially with respect to health care delivery systems; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2dd21fd-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> is not currently under contract with the Department to provide direct or indirect patient care or related clinical care services or supplies under the laws administered by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2dd21fe-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program Integrator</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2dd21ff-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If the Secretary enters into contracts with more than one private sector entity under subsection (a) with respect to a single assessment under such subsection, the Secretary shall designate one such entity as the program integrator.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2dd2200-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The program integrator designated pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be responsible for coordinating the outcomes of the assessments conducted by the private sector entities pursuant to such contracts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2dd2201-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2dd2202-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2dd2203-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Not later than 60 days after completing an assessment pursuant to subsection (a), the private sector entity or entities carrying out such assessment shall submit to the Secretary and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the findings and recommendations of the private sector entity or entities with respect to such assessment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2dd2204-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Each report under subparagraph (A) with respect to an assessment shall include an identification of the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2dd2205-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/f/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> Any changes with respect to the matters included in such assessment since the date that is the later of the following:</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc2dd2206-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/f/1/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> The date on which the independent assessment under section 201 of the Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014 (<ref href="/us/pl/113/146">Public Law 113–146</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1701">38 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note) was completed.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc2dd2207-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/f/1/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> The date on which the last assessment under subsection (a) was completed.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc2dd2208-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/f/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Any recommendations regarding matters to be covered by subsequent assessments under subsection (a), including any additional matters to include for assessment or previously assessed matters to exclude.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2dd2209-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Not later than 30 days after receiving a report under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall publish such report in the Federal Register and on a publicly accessible internet website of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2dd220a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Not later than 90 days after receiving a report under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report outlining the feasibility and advisability of implementing the recommendations made by the private sector entity or entities in such report received, including an identification of the timeline, cost, and any legislative authorities necessary for such implementation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc2dd220b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1704A/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sunset</inline>.—</heading><content>The requirement to enter into contracts under subsection (a) shall terminate on <date date="2055-12-31">December 31, 2055</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc2dd220c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dU/tI/s194/a">Pub. L. 117–328, div. U, title I, § 194(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5440">136 Stat. 5440</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc2dd220d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc2dd220e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc2dd220f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Deadline for Initial Assessment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dU/tI/s194/c">Pub. L. 117–328, div. U, title I, § 194(c)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5444">136 Stat. 5444</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/328/dU/tI/s194/c">“The initial assessment under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1704A">section 1704A of title 38</ref>, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall be completed by not later than <date date="2025-12-31">December 31, 2025</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
