<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc3165a84-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1907"><num value="1907">§ 1907.</num><heading> Payment or use of dividends</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3165a85-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1907/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Until and unless the Secretary has received from the insured a request or directive in writing exercising any other dividend option allowable under the insured’s policy, any dividend accumulations and unpaid dividends shall be applied in payment of premiums becoming due on insurance subsequent to the date the dividend is payable after <date date="1952-01-01">January 1, 1952</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3165a86-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1907/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> No claim by an insured for payment in cash of a special dividend declared prior to <date date="1952-01-01">January 1, 1952</date>, shall be processed by the Secretary unless such claim was received within six years after such dividend was declared. Whenever any claim for payment of a special dividend, the processing of which is barred by this subsection, is received by the Secretary, it shall be returned to the claimant, with a copy of this subsection, and such action shall be a complete response without further communication.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3165a87-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s1907/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The Secretary, upon application in writing made by the insured for insurance under this subsection, and without proof of good health, is authorized to apply any dividend due and payable on national service life insurance after the date of such application to purchase paid up insurance. Also, the Secretary, upon application in writing made by the insured during the one-year period beginning <date date="1991-09-01">September 1, 1991</date>, and without proof of good health, is authorized to apply any national service life insurance dividend credits and deposits of such insured existing at the date of the insured’s application to purchase paid up insurance. After <date date="1992-09-01">September 1, 1992</date>, the Secretary may, from time to time, provide for further one-year periods during which insureds may purchase additional paid up insurance from existing dividend credits and deposits. Any such period for the purchase of additional paid up insurance may be allowed only if the Secretary determines in the case of any such period that it would be actuarially and administratively sound to do so. Any dividends, dividend credits, or deposits on endowment policies may be used under this subsection only to purchase additional paid up endowment insurance which matures concurrently with the basic policy. Any dividends, dividend credits, or deposits on policies (other than endowment policies) may be used under this section only to purchase additional paid up whole life insurance. The paid up insurance granted under this subsection shall be in addition to any insurance otherwise authorized under this title, or under prior provisions of law. The paid up insurance granted under this subsection shall be issued on the same terms and conditions as are contained in the standard policies of national service life insurance except (1) the premium rates for such insurance and all cash and loan values thereon shall be based on such table of mortality and rate of interest per annum as may be prescribed by the Secretary; (2) the total disability income provision authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1915">section 1915 of this title</ref> may not be added to insurance issued under this section; and (3) the insurance shall include such other changes in terms and conditions as the Secretary determines to be reasonable and practicable.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc3165a88-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">(<ref href="/us/pl/85/857">Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1149">72 Stat. 1149</ref>, § 707; <ref href="/us/pl/91/291/s9">Pub. L. 91–291, § 9</ref>, <date date="1970-06-25">June 25, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/331">84 Stat. 331</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/188/s2">Pub. L. 92–188, § 2</ref>, <date date="1971-12-15">Dec. 15, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/645">85 Stat. 645</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/295/s4/22">Pub. L. 97–295, § 4(22)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1306">96 Stat. 1306</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/576/tVII/s701/23">Pub. L. 99–576, title VII, § 701(23)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-28">Oct. 28, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3292">100 Stat. 3292</ref>; renumbered § 1907 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/83">Pub. L. 102–83</ref>, §§ 4(a)(2)(A)(iii)(I), (C)(i), (b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/403-406">105 Stat. 403–406</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/86/tII/s203">Pub. L. 102–86, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1991-08-14">Aug. 14, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/416">105 Stat. 416</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc3165a89-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc3165a8a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc3165a8b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—<ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/a">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s707">section 707 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s4/a/2/A/iii/I">Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(a)(2)(A)(iii)(I)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” for “Veterans’ Administration”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s4/a/2/C/i">Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(a)(2)(C)(i)</ref>, substituted “by the Secretary” for “in the Veterans’ Administration” in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s4/a/2/A/iii/I">Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(a)(2)(A)(iii)(I)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” for “Veterans’ Administration” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/86">Pub. L. 102–86</ref> amended subsec. (c) of this section as in effect before the redesignations made by <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5</ref>, by substituting “during the one-year period beginning <date date="1991-09-01">September 1, 1991</date>” for “before <date date="1973-02-01">February 1, 1973</date>” and inserting after second sentence “After <date date="1992-09-01">September 1, 1992</date>, the Secretary may, from time to time, provide for further one-year periods during which insureds may purchase additional paid up insurance from existing dividend credits and deposits. Any such period for the purchase of additional paid up insurance may be allowed only if the Secretary determines in the case of any such period that it would be actuarially and administratively sound to do so.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/c/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “1915” for “715” in cl. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s4/b/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, (2)(E), substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsecs. (a), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/576">Pub. L. 99–576</ref> substituted “the insured’s” for “his”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/295">Pub. L. 97–295</ref> substituted “before <date date="1973-02-01">February 1, 1973</date>” for “within six calendar months after the effective date of this subsection”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1971—<ref href="/us/pl/92/188/s2/3">Pub. L. 92–188, § 2(3)</ref>, substituted “Payment or use of dividends” for “Dividends to pay premiums” as section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/92/188/s2/1">Pub. L. 92–188, § 2(1)</ref>, substituted “or directive in writing exercising any other dividend option allowable under his policy” for “in writing for payment in cash”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/92/188/s2/2">Pub. L. 92–188, § 2(2)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—<ref href="/us/pl/91/291">Pub. L. 91–291</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc3165a8c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3165a8d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1971 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/92/188/s4">Pub. L. 92–188, § 4</ref>, <date date="1971-12-15">Dec. 15, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/645">85 Stat. 645</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/92/188/s4">“The amendments made by this Act [amending this section and sections 703 and 741 [now 1903 and 1941] of this title] shall take effect on a date established by the Administrator but in no event later than the first day of the first calendar month which begins more than six calendar months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1971-12-15">Dec. 15, 1971</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3165a8e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1970 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/291">Pub. L. 91–291</ref> effective <date date="1970-06-25">June 25, 1970</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/291/s14/a">section 14(a) of Pub. L. 91–291</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1317">section 1317 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
