<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc33ef124-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306"><num value="2306">§ 2306.</num><heading> Headstones, markers, and burial receptacles</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef125-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall furnish, when requested, appropriate Government headstones or markers at the expense of the United States for the unmarked graves of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef126-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any individual buried in a national cemetery or in a post cemetery.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef127-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any individual eligible for burial in a national cemetery (but not buried there), except for those persons or classes of persons enumerated in section 2402(a)(4), (5), and (6) of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef128-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Soldiers of the Union and Confederate Armies of the Civil War.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef129-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Any individual described in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s2402/a/5">section 2402(a)(5) of this title</ref> who is buried in a veterans’ cemetery owned by a State or a veterans’ cemetery owned by a tribal organization or on land owned by or held in trust for a tribal organization.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef12a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Any individual who at the time of death was entitled to retired pay under chapter 1223 of title 10 or would have been entitled to retired pay under that chapter but for the fact that the person was under 60 years of age.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef12b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef12c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall furnish, when requested, an appropriate memorial headstone or marker for the purpose of commemorating an eligible individual whose remains are unavailable. Such a headstone or marker shall be furnished for placement in a national cemetery area reserved for that purpose under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s2403">section 2403 of this title</ref>, a veterans’ cemetery owned by a State, a veterans’ cemetery of a tribal organization or on land owned by or held in trust for a tribal organization, or, in the case of a veteran, in a State, local, or private cemetery.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef12d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> For purposes of paragraph (1), an eligible individual is any of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef12e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A veteran.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef12f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> An individual who dies on or after <date date="1998-11-11">November 11, 1998</date>, who is the spouse or surviving spouse of a veteran, or the spouse of a member of the Armed Forces serving on active duty under conditions other than dishonorable, as shown by a statement from a general court-martial convening authority, at the time of the spouse’s death if such death occurs before <date date="2032-09-30">September 30, 2032</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef130-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> An individual who dies on or after <date date="1998-11-11">November 11, 1998</date>, who is an eligible dependent child of a veteran, or the eligible dependent child of a member of the Armed Forces serving on active duty under conditions other than dishonorable, as shown by a statement from a general court-martial convening authority, at the time of the child’s death if such death occurs before <date date="2032-09-30">September 30, 2032</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef131-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> For purposes of paragraph (1), the remains of an individual shall be considered to be unavailable if the individual’s remains—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef132-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> have not been recovered or identified;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef133-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> were buried at sea, whether by the individual’s own choice or otherwise;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef134-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> were donated to science; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef135-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/b/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> were cremated and the ashes scattered without interment of any portion of the ashes.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef136-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this subsection:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef137-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The term “veteran” includes an individual who dies in the active military, naval, air, or space service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef138-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The term “surviving spouse” includes a surviving spouse who had a subsequent remarriage.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef139-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this section, the term “eligible dependent child” means a child—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef13a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/b/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> who is under 21 years of age, or under 23 years of age if pursuing a course of instruction at an approved educational institution; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef13b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/b/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> who is unmarried and became permanently physically or mentally disabled and incapable of self-support before reaching 21 years of age, or before reaching 23 years of age if pursuing a course of instruction at an approved educational institution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef13c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> A headstone or marker furnished under subsection (a), (b), or (d) of this section may be of any material, including but not limited to marble, granite, bronze, or slate, requested by the person entitled to request such headstone or marker if the material requested is determined by the Secretary (1) to be cost effective, and (2) in a case in which the headstone or marker is to be placed in a national cemetery, to be aesthetically compatible with the area of the cemetery in which it is to be placed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef13d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef13e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall furnish, when requested, an appropriate Government headstone or marker at the expense of the United States for the grave of an individual described in paragraph (2) or (5) of subsection (a) who is buried in a private cemetery, notwithstanding that the grave is marked by a headstone or marker furnished at private expense. Such a headstone or marker may be furnished only if the individual making the request for the Government headstone or marker certifies to the Secretary that the headstone or marker will be placed on the grave for which the headstone or marker is requested, or, if placement on the grave is impossible or impracticable, as close as possible to the grave within the grounds of the cemetery in which the grave is located.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef13f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any headstone or marker furnished under this subsection shall be delivered by the Secretary directly to the cemetery where the grave is located or to a receiving agent for delivery to the cemetery.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef140-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The headstone or marker furnished under this subsection shall be the headstone or marker selected by the individual making the request from among all the headstones and markers made available by the Government for selection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef141-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef142-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/d/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In lieu of furnishing a headstone or marker under this subsection to a deceased individual described in subparagraph (B), the Secretary may furnish, upon request, a medallion or other device of a design determined by the Secretary to signify the deceased individual’s status as a veteran, to be attached to a headstone or marker furnished at private expense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef143-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/d/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> A deceased individual described in this subsection is an individual who—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef144-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/d/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> served in the Armed Forces on or after <date date="1917-04-06">April 6, 1917</date>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef145-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/d/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> is eligible for a headstone or marker furnished under paragraph (1) (or would be so eligible but for the date of the death of the individual).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef146-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef147-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/d/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In carrying out this subsection with respect to a deceased individual described in subparagraph (C), the Secretary shall furnish, upon request, a headstone or marker under paragraph (1) or a medallion under paragraph (4) that signifies the deceased’s status as a medal of honor recipient.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef148-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/d/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> If the Secretary furnished a headstone, marker, or medallion under paragraph (1) or (4) for a deceased individual described in subparagraph (C) that does not signify the deceased’s status as a medal of honor recipient, the Secretary shall, upon request, replace such headstone, marker, or medallion with a headstone, marker, or medallion, as the case may be, that so signifies the deceased’s status as a medal of honor recipient.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef149-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/d/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> A deceased individual described in this subparagraph is a deceased individual who—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef14a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/d/5/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> is eligible for a headstone or marker furnished under paragraph (1) or a medallion furnished under paragraph (4) (except that subparagraph (B)(i) of such paragraph shall not apply) (or would be so eligible for such headstone, marker, or medallion but for the date of the death of the individual); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef14b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/d/5/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> was awarded the medal of honor under section 7271, 8291, or 9271 of title 10 or <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s2732">section 2732 of title 14</ref> (including posthumously).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef14c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/d/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> In this paragraph, the term “medal of honor recipient” means an individual who is awarded the medal of honor under section 7271, 8291, or 9271 of title 10 or <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s2732">section 2732 of title 14</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef14d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef14e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef14f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may provide an outer burial receptacle for each new grave in an open cemetery under the control of the National Cemetery Administration, or in a cemetery that is the subject of a grant to a State or a tribal organization under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s2408">section 2408 of this title</ref>, in which remains are interred in a casket.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef150-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary of the Army may provide an outer burial receptacle for such a grave in the Arlington National Cemetery.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef151-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Secretary of the Interior may provide an outer burial receptacle for each such a grave in an open national cemetery administered by the National Park Service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef152-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef153-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The use of outer burial receptacles in a cemetery under the control of the National Cemetery Administration or in a cemetery that is the subject of a grant to a State or a tribal organization under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s2408">section 2408 of this title</ref> shall be in accordance with regulations or procedures approved by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef154-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The use of outer burial receptacles in Arlington National Cemetery shall be in accordance with regulations or procedures approved by the Secretary of the Army.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef155-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The use of outer burial receptacles in a national cemetery administered by the National Park Service shall be in accordance with regulations or procedures approved by the Secretary of the Interior.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef156-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Regulations or procedures under paragraph (2) may specify that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef157-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an outer burial receptacle other than a grave liner be provided in lieu of a grave liner at the election of the survivors of the interred veteran; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef158-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> if an outer burial receptacle other than a grave liner is provided in lieu of a grave liner upon an election of such survivors, such survivors be required—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc33ef159-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/e/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to pay the amount by which the cost of the outer burial receptacle exceeds the cost of the grave liner that would otherwise have been provided in the absence of the election; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc33ef15a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/e/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to pay the amount of the administrative costs incurred by the Secretary (or the Secretary of the Army with respect to Arlington National Cemetery or the Secretary of the Interior with respect to a national cemetery administered by the National Park Service) in providing the outer burial receptacle in lieu of such grave liner.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef15b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Regulations or procedures under paragraph (2) may provide for the use of a voucher system, or other system of reimbursement approved by the Secretary (or the Secretary of the Army with respect to Arlington National Cemetery or the Secretary of the Interior with respect to a national cemetery administered by the National Park Service), for payment for outer burial receptacles other than grave liners provided under such regulations or procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef15c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef15d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary may furnish a casket or urn, of such quality as the Secretary considers appropriate for a dignified burial, for burial of a deceased veteran in a covered cemetery in any case in which the Secretary—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef15e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is unable to identify the veteran’s next of kin, if any; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef15f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> determines that sufficient resources for the furnishing of a casket or urn for such burial are not otherwise available.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef160-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The term “covered cemetery” means any of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef161-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A national cemetery.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef162-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A veterans’ cemetery of a State for which the Department has provided a grant under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s2408">section 2408 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef163-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/f/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> A veterans’ cemetery of a tribal organization or on land owned by or held in trust for a tribal organization for which the Department has provided a grant under subsection (f) of such section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef164-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef165-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> When the Secretary has furnished a headstone or marker under subsection (a) for the unmarked grave of an individual, the Secretary shall, if feasible, add a memorial inscription to that headstone or marker rather than furnishing a separate headstone or marker under that subsection for the surviving spouse or eligible dependent child of such individual.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef166-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> When the Secretary has furnished a memorial headstone or marker under subsection (b) for purposes of commemorating a veteran or an individual who died in the active military, naval, air, or space service, the Secretary shall, if feasible, add a memorial inscription to that headstone or marker rather than furnishing a separate memorial headstone or marker under that subsection for the surviving spouse or eligible dependent child of such individual.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef167-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef168-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In lieu of furnishing a headstone or marker under this section for a deceased individual described in paragraph (3), the Secretary shall furnish, upon request and at the expense of the United States—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef169-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an urn made of any material to signify the individual’s status as a veteran, in which the remains of such individual may be placed at private expense; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef16a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a commemorative plaque signifying the individual’s status as a veteran.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef16b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> If the Secretary furnishes an urn or commemorative plaque for an individual under paragraph (1), the Secretary may not provide for such individual—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef16c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a headstone or marker under this section; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef16d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any burial benefit under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s2402">section 2402 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc33ef16e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> A deceased individual described in this paragraph is an individual—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef16f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/h/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> who served in the Armed Forces on or after <date date="1917-04-06">April 6, 1917</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc33ef170-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/h/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> who is eligible for a headstone or marker furnished under subsection (d) (or would be so eligible but for the date of the death of the individual); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3413a61-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/h/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> whose remains were cremated and not interred in a national cemetery, a State veterans’ cemetery, a tribal cemetery, a county cemetery, or a private cemetery.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3413a62-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/h/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3413a63-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/h/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Any urn or commemorative plaque furnished under this subsection shall be the personal property of the next of kin or such other individual as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3413a64-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/h/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Federal Government shall not be liable for any damage to an urn or commemorative plaque furnished under this subsection that occurs after the date on which the urn or commemorative plaque is so furnished.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3413a65-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/h/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The Secretary shall prescribe regulations to carry out this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3413a66-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3413a67-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A headstone or marker may not be furnished under subsection (a) for the unmarked grave of a person described in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s2411/b">section 2411(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3413a68-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A memorial headstone or marker may not be furnished under subsection (b) for the purpose of commemorating a person described in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s2411/b">section 2411(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3413a69-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A headstone or marker may not be furnished under subsection (d) for the grave of a person described in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s2411/b">section 2411(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3413a6a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/i/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> A casket or urn may not be furnished under subsection (f) for burial of a person described in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s2411/b">section 2411(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3413a6b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3413a6c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In addition to any other authority under this section, in the case of an individual whose grave is not in a covered cemetery (as that term is defined in subsection (f)(2)) and for whom the Secretary has furnished a headstone or marker under subsection (a) or (d), the Secretary, if feasible and upon request, may replace the headstone or marker to add an inscription for the surviving spouse or eligible dependent child of such individual following the death of the surviving spouse or eligible dependent child.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3413a6d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If the spouse or eligible dependent child of an individual referred to in paragraph (1) predeceases the individual, the Secretary may, if feasible and upon request, include an inscription for the spouse or dependent child on the headstone or marker furnished for the individual under subsection (a) or (d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3413a6e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s2306/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content> In this section, the term “tribal organization” has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3765">section 3765 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc3413a6f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/93/43/s5/a/2">Pub. L. 93–43, § 5(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1973-06-18">June 18, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/80">87 Stat. 80</ref>, § 906; amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/476/tII/s203/a">Pub. L. 95–476, title II, § 203(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-18">Oct. 18, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1505">92 Stat. 1505</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/479/tIII/s303/b">Pub. L. 95–479, title III, § 303(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-18">Oct. 18, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1565">92 Stat. 1565</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/385/tV/s502">Pub. L. 96–385, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="1980-10-07">Oct. 7, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1534">94 Stat. 1534</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/66/tVI/s603/a">Pub. L. 97–66, title VI, § 603(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-10-17">Oct. 17, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1034">95 Stat. 1034</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/322/tIII/s344/a">Pub. L. 100–322, title III, § 344(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1988-05-20">May 20, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/540">102 Stat. 540</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/237/tIII/s313/b/1">Pub. L. 101–237, title III, § 313(b)(1)</ref>, (3), title V, §§ 501, 504(a), <date date="1989-12-18">Dec. 18, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2077">103 Stat. 2077</ref>, 2093, 2094; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tVIII/s8041/a">Pub. L. 101–508, title VIII, § 8041(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-349">104 Stat. 1388–349</ref>; renumbered § 2306 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/a">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/406">105 Stat. 406</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/547/s11/b">Pub. L. 102–547, § 11(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3644">106 Stat. 3644</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/275/tII/s213/a">Pub. L. 104–275, title II, § 213(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3331">110 Stat. 3331</ref>, 3332; <ref href="/us/pl/105/368/tIV">Pub. L. 105–368, title IV</ref>, §§ 401(a), (b), 403(c)(2), <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3334">112 Stat. 3334</ref>, 3335, 3338; <ref href="/us/pl/107/103/tV/s502/a">Pub. L. 107–103, title V, § 502(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/994">115 Stat. 994</ref>, 995; <ref href="/us/pl/107/330/tII/s201/c">Pub. L. 107–330, title II, § 201(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-06">Dec. 6, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2823">116 Stat. 2823</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/444/s2/f">Pub. L. 109–444, § 2(f)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-21">Dec. 21, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3305">120 Stat. 3305</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/tIV">Pub. L. 109–461, title IV</ref>, §§ 401(a), (b), 402, title X, § 1006(b), <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3429">120 Stat. 3429</ref>, 3468; <ref href="/us/pl/110/157/tII">Pub. L. 110–157, title II</ref>, §§ 201, 203(a), <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1832">121 Stat. 1832</ref>, 1833; <ref href="/us/pl/110/389/tVIII/s810/a">Pub. L. 110–389, title VIII, § 810(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4190">122 Stat. 4190</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/275/tV/s502/d/3">Pub. L. 111–275, title V, § 502(d)(3)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-13">Oct. 13, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2883">124 Stat. 2883</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/260/tI/s101/a">Pub. L. 112–260, title I, § 101(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-10">Jan. 10, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2418">126 Stat. 2418</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/273/s2">Pub. L. 114–273, § 2</ref>, <date date="2016-12-14">Dec. 14, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1400">130 Stat. 1400</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/315/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 114–315, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1550">130 Stat. 1550</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/136/s1">Pub. L. 115–136, § 1</ref>, <date date="2018-03-16">Mar. 16, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/343">132 Stat. 343</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/184/s2">Pub. L. 115–184, § 2</ref>, <date date="2018-06-15">June 15, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1483">132 Stat. 1483</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tVIII/s809/n/2">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(n)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1843">132 Stat. 1843</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/407/tII">Pub. L. 115–407, title II</ref>, §§ 201, 202(a), <date date="2018-12-31">Dec. 31, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5372">132 Stat. 5372</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tIX/s926/a/38">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 926(a)(38)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3830">134 Stat. 3830</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/315/tII">Pub. L. 116–315, title II</ref>, §§ 2203(a), 2204(a), 2207(a), <date date="2021-01-05">Jan. 5, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4985">134 Stat. 4985</ref>, 4986, 4988; <ref href="/us/pl/118/83/dB/tIII/s311">Pub. L. 118–83, div. B, title III, § 311</ref>, <date date="2024-09-26">Sept. 26, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1540">138 Stat. 1540</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/134/s2">Pub. L. 118–134, § 2</ref>, <date date="2024-11-25">Nov. 25, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1646">138 Stat. 1646</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/271/s2">Pub. L. 118–271, § 2</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2991">138 Stat. 2991</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc3413a70-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc3413a71-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc3413a72-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (b)(2)(B), (C). <ref href="/us/pl/118/271">Pub. L. 118–271</ref> substituted “<date date="2032-09-30">September 30, 2032</date>” for “<date date="2025-09-30">September 30, 2025</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (b)(2)(B), (C). <ref href="/us/pl/118/83">Pub. L. 118–83</ref> substituted “<date date="2025-09-30">September 30, 2025</date>” for “<date date="2024-10-01">October 1, 2024</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5)(C)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/118/134/s2/a/1">Pub. L. 118–134, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, (3), redesignated cl. (ii) as (i) and struck out former cl. (i) which read as follows: “served in the Armed Forces on or after <date date="1917-04-06">April 6, 1917</date>;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5)(C)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/118/134/s2/a/3">Pub. L. 118–134, § 2(a)(3)</ref>, (b), redesignated cl. (iii) as (ii) and substituted “section 2732” for “section 491”. Former cl. (ii) redesignated (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/118/134/s2/a/2">Pub. L. 118–134, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “(except that subparagraph (B)(i) of such paragraph shall not apply)” after “paragraph (4)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5)(C)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/118/134/s2/a/3">Pub. L. 118–134, § 2(a)(3)</ref>, redesignated cl. (iii) as (ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/118/134/s2/b">Pub. L. 118–134, § 2(b)</ref>, substituted “section 2732” for “section 491”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (b)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> substituted “air, or space service” for “or air service”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/116/315/s2203/a/1/A">Pub. L. 116–315, § 2203(a)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “may” for “shall” and inserted “, or in a cemetery that is the subject of a grant to a State or a tribal organization under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s2408">section 2408 of this title</ref>,” after “National Cemetery Administration”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/116/315/s2203/a/1/B">Pub. L. 116–315, § 2203(a)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “may” for “shall”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/116/315/s2203/a/2">Pub. L. 116–315, § 2203(a)(2)</ref>, added par. (2) and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows: “The use of outer burial receptacles in a cemetery under the control of the National Cemetery Administration, in the Arlington National Cemetery, or in a national cemetery administered by the National Park Service shall be in accordance with regulations or procedures approved by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Secretary of the Army, or the Secretary of the Interior, respectively.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> substituted “air, or space service” for “or air service”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/116/315/s2207/a/2">Pub. L. 116–315, § 2207(a)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (h). Former subsec. (h) redesignated (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (i), (j). <ref href="/us/pl/116/315/s2207/a/1">Pub. L. 116–315, § 2207(a)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (h) and (i) as (i) and (j), respectively. Former subsec. (j) redesignated (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/315/s2204/a">Pub. L. 116–315, § 2204(a)</ref>, added subsec. (i) and redesignated former subsec. (i) as (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/116/315/s2207/a/1">Pub. L. 116–315, § 2207(a)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (j) as (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/115/407/s201/1">Pub. L. 115–407, § 201(1)</ref>, inserted “or a veterans’ cemetery owned by a tribal organization or on land owned by or held in trust for a tribal organization” after “State”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/115/407/s201/2">Pub. L. 115–407, § 201(2)</ref>, inserted “, a veterans’ cemetery of a tribal organization or on land owned by or held in trust for a tribal organization” after “owned by a State”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/115/407/s202/a/1">Pub. L. 115–407, § 202(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “, or the spouse of a member of the Armed Forces serving on active duty under conditions other than dishonorable, as shown by a statement from a general court-martial convening authority, at the time of the spouse’s death if such death occurs before <date date="2024-10-01">October 1, 2024</date>” after “veteran”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/115/136/s1/1">Pub. L. 115–136, § 1(1)</ref>, substituted “An individual who dies on or after <date date="1998-11-11">November 11, 1998</date>, who is the” for “The”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/115/407/s202/a/2">Pub. L. 115–407, § 202(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “, or the eligible dependent child of a member of the Armed Forces serving on active duty under conditions other than dishonorable, as shown by a statement from a general court-martial convening authority, at the time of the child’s death if such death occurs before <date date="2024-10-01">October 1, 2024</date>” after “veteran”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/115/136/s1/2">Pub. L. 115–136, § 1(2)</ref>, substituted “An individual who dies on or after <date date="1998-11-11">November 11, 1998</date>, who is an” for “An”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5)(C)(iii), (D). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232">Pub. L. 115–232</ref> substituted “section 7271, 8291, or 9271 of title 10” for “section 3741, 6241, or 8741 of title 10”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/115/184/s2/1">Pub. L. 115–184, § 2(1)</ref>, designated first sentence as subpar. (A) and second sentence as subpar. (B) and added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/184/s2/2">Pub. L. 115–184, § 2(2)</ref>, substituted “, in the Arlington National Cemetery, or in a national cemetery administered by the National Park Service” for “or in the Arlington National Cemetery” and “, the Secretary of the Army, or the Secretary of the Interior” for “or Secretary of the Army”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/115/184/s2/3">Pub. L. 115–184, § 2(3)</ref>, substituted “or the Secretary of the Army with respect to Arlington National Cemetery or the Secretary of the Interior with respect to a national cemetery administered by the National Park Service” for “or, with respect to Arlington National Cemetery, the Secretary of the Army”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/115/184/s2/4">Pub. L. 115–184, § 2(4)</ref>, substituted “or the Secretary of the Army with respect to Arlington National Cemetery or the Secretary of the Interior with respect to a national cemetery administered by the National Park Service” for “or, with respect to Arlington National Cemetery, the Secretary of the Army”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/115/407/s201/3">Pub. L. 115–407, § 201(3)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), redesignated former pars. (1) and (2) as subpars. (A) and (B), respectively, of par. (1), substituted “a covered cemetery” for “a national cemetery or in a veterans cemetery of a State or tribal organization for which the Department has provided a grant under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s2408">section 2408 of this title</ref>” in introductory provisions of par. (1), and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/115/407/s201/4">Pub. L. 115–407, § 201(4)</ref>, added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (d)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/114/315/s301/1">Pub. L. 114–315, § 301(1)</ref>, added par. (4) and struck out former par. (4) which read as follows: “In lieu of furnishing a headstone or marker under this subsection, the Secretary may furnish, upon request, a medallion or other device of a design determined by the Secretary to signify the deceased’s status as a veteran, to be attached to a headstone or marker furnished at private expense.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/114/315/s301/2">Pub. L. 114–315, § 301(2)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/114/273/s2/1">Pub. L. 114–273, § 2(1)</ref> substituted “for burial of a deceased veteran in a national cemetery or in a veterans cemetery of a State or tribal organization for which the Department has provided a grant under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s2408">section 2408 of this title</ref>” for “for burial in a national cemetery of a deceased veteran” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/114/273/s2/2">Pub. L. 114–273, § 2(2)</ref>, substituted “such burial” for “the burial of the veteran in a national cemetery”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsecs. (f) to (h). <ref href="/us/pl/112/260/s101/a/1">Pub. L. 112–260, § 101(a)(1)</ref>, (2), added subsec. (f) and redesignated former subsecs. (f) and (g) as (g) and (h), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/112/260/s101/a/3">Pub. L. 112–260, § 101(a)(3)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/275/s502/d/3/A">Pub. L. 111–275, § 502(d)(3)(A)</ref>, substituted “section 2402(a)(4)” for “section 2402(4)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/111/275/s502/d/3/B">Pub. L. 111–275, § 502(d)(3)(B)</ref>, substituted “section 2402(a)(5)” for “section 2402(5)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (b)(4)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/110/389">Pub. L. 110–389</ref> substituted “a surviving spouse who had a subsequent remarriage” for “an unremarried surviving spouse whose subsequent remarriage was terminated by death or divorce”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Subsec. (d)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/110/157/s203/a">Pub. L. 110–157, § 203(a)</ref>, redesignated pars. (4) and (5) as (3) and (4), respectively, and struck out former par. (3) which read as follows: “The authority to furnish a marker under this subsection expires on <date date="2007-12-31">December 31, 2007</date>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/110/157/s203/a/2">Pub. L. 110–157, § 203(a)(2)</ref>, redesignated par. (5) as (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/157/s201">Pub. L. 110–157, § 201</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (b)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s401/a/1">Pub. L. 109–461, § 401(a)(1)</ref>, added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s401/a/2">Pub. L. 109–461, § 401(a)(2)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s402/b/1/A/ii">Pub. L. 109–461, § 402(b)(1)(A)(ii)</ref>, (c), in second sentence, inserted “headstone or” before “marker” in four places and “, or, if placement on the grave is impossible or impracticable, as close as possible to the grave within the grounds of the cemetery in which the grave is located” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s402/b/1/A/i">Pub. L. 109–461, § 402(b)(1)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “Government headstone or marker” for “Government marker” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s402/b/1/B">Pub. L. 109–461, § 402(b)(1)(B)</ref>, (d), inserted “headstone or” before “marker” and “or to a receiving agent for delivery to the cemetery” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s1006/b">Pub. L. 109–461, § 1006(b)</ref>, provided that as of the enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/109/461">Pub. L. 109–461</ref>, the amendments made by <ref href="/us/pl/109/444">Pub. L. 109–444</ref> were deemed for all purposes not to have taken effect and that <ref href="/us/pl/109/444">Pub. L. 109–444</ref> ceased to be in effect. See Amendment notes below and <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s1006/b">section 1006(b) of Pub. L. 109–461</ref>, set out as a Coordination of Provisions With <ref href="/us/pl/109/444">Pub. L. 109–444</ref> note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s402/a">Pub. L. 109–461, § 402(a)</ref>, substituted “<date date="2007-12-31">December 31, 2007</date>” for “<date date="2006-12-31">December 31, 2006</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/444">Pub. L. 109–444</ref>, which substituted “<date date="2007-12-31">December 31, 2007</date>” for “<date date="2006-12-31">December 31, 2006</date>”, was terminated by <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s1006/b">Pub. L. 109–461, § 1006(b)</ref>. See Amendment notes above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s402/f">Pub. L. 109–461, § 402(f)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s402/e">Pub. L. 109–461, § 402(e)</ref>, struck out par. (4) which read as follows: “Not later than <date date="2006-02-01">February 1, 2006</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report on the use of the authority under this subsection. The report shall include the following:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) The rate of use of the benefit under this subsection, shown by fiscal year.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) An assessment as to the extent to which markers furnished under this subsection are being delivered to cemeteries and placed on grave sites consistent with the provisions of this subsection.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) The Secretary’s recommendation for extension or repeal of the expiration date specified in paragraph (3).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s401/b">Pub. L. 109–461, § 401(b)</ref>, inserted “or eligible dependent child” after “surviving spouse” in pars. (1) and (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s402/b/2">Pub. L. 109–461, § 402(b)(2)</ref>, inserted “headstone or” before “marker”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/107/330">Pub. L. 107–330</ref> added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/107/103/s502/c">Pub. L. 107–103, § 502(c)</ref>, substituted “chapter 1223” for “chapter 67”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/107/103/s502/b">Pub. L. 107–103, § 502(b)</ref>, substituted “subsection (a), (b), or (d)” for “subsection (a) or (b)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d) to (f). <ref href="/us/pl/107/103/s502/a">Pub. L. 107–103, § 502(a)</ref>, added subsec. (d) and redesignated former subsecs. (d) and (e) as (e) and (f), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/105/368/s401/a">Pub. L. 105–368, § 401(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (b) read as follows: “The Secretary shall furnish, when requested, an appropriate memorial headstone or marker for the purpose of commemorating any veteran—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) whose remains have not been recovered or identified,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) whose remains were buried at sea, whether by the veteran’s own choice or otherwise,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(3) whose remains were donated to science, or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(4) whose remains were cremated and the ashes scattered without interment of any portion of the ashes,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">for placement by the applicant in a national cemetery area reserved for such purpose under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s2403">section 2403 of this title</ref> or in a State, local, or private cemetery.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1), (2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/368/s403/c/2">Pub. L. 105–368, § 403(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “under the control of the National Cemetery Administration” for “within the National Cemetery System”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/105/368/s401/b">Pub. L. 105–368, § 401(b)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—<ref href="/us/pl/104/275/s213/b/1">Pub. L. 104–275, § 213(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “burial receptacles” for “grave liners” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/275/s213/a/1">Pub. L. 104–275, § 213(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “an outer burial receptacle” for “a grave liner” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/275/s213/a/2">Pub. L. 104–275, § 213(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “outer burial receptacles” for “grave liners” and “regulations or procedures” for “specifications and procedures”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/104/275/s213/a/3">Pub. L. 104–275, § 213(a)(3)</ref>, added pars. (3) and (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/102/547">Pub. L. 102–547</ref> added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—<ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/a">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s906">section 906 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/c/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “2402(4)” for “1002(4)” in par. (2) and “2402(5)” for “1002(5)” in par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/c/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “2403” for “1003” in concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> redesignated subsec. (e) as (d) and struck out former subsec. (d) which read as follows: “In lieu of furnishing a headstone or marker under subsection (a)(2) or (b) of this section, the Secretary, in the Secretary’s discretion, having due regard for the circumstances in each case, may reimburse the person entitled to request such headstone or marker for the cost of acquiring a non-Government headstone or marker for placement in any cemetery other than a national cemetery in connection with the burial or memorialization of the deceased individual. The cost referred to in the preceding sentence is the cost actually incurred by or on behalf of such person or the cost prepaid by the deceased individual, as the case may be. Reimbursement under this subsection may be made only upon the request of the person entitled to request the headstone or marker and may not be made in an amount in excess of the average actual cost, as determined by the Secretary, of headstones and markers furnished under subsections (a) and (b) of this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsecs. (a) to (c). <ref href="/us/pl/101/237/s313/b/1">Pub. L. 101–237, § 313(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/237/s501">Pub. L. 101–237, § 501</ref>, substituted “cost of acquiring” for “actual costs incurred by or on behalf of such person in acquiring” in first sentence, inserted after first sentence “The cost referred to in the preceding sentence is the cost actually incurred by or on behalf of such person or the cost prepaid by the deceased individual, as the case may be.”, and substituted “this subsection” for “the preceding sentence” in last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/237/s313/b/1">Pub. L. 101–237, § 313(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” and “Secretary’s” for “Administrator” and “Administrator’s”, respectively, wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/237/s504/a">Pub. L. 101–237, § 504(a)</ref>, inserted first sentence and struck out former first sentence which read as follows: “The Secretary may provide a grave liner for any grave in a cemetery within the National Cemetery System in which remains are interred in a casket.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/237/s313/b/1">Pub. L. 101–237, § 313(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Secretary may provide” for “Administrator may provide”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/237/s313/b/3">Pub. L. 101–237, § 313(b)(3)</ref>, substituted “Secretary of Veterans Affairs or Secretary of the Army” for “Administrator or the Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/322/s344/b/1">Pub. L. 100–322, § 344(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Headstones, markers, and grave liners” for “Headstones and markers” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/100/322/s344/a">Pub. L. 100–322, § 344(a)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/97/66">Pub. L. 97–66</ref> inserted provisions relating to veterans whose remains were donated to science or whose remains were cremated and the ashes scattered without interment of any portion of the ashes.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/96/385">Pub. L. 96–385</ref> added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/479">Pub. L. 95–479</ref> struck out “dying in the service, and” after “to commemorate any veteran”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/476">Pub. L. 95–476</ref> added subsecs. (c) and (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc3413a73-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3413a74-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/315/tII/s2203/b">Pub. L. 116–315, title II, § 2203(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-05">Jan. 5, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4986">134 Stat. 4986</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/315/tII/s2203/b">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall take effect on the date that is two years after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-01-05">Jan. 5, 2021</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/116/315/tII/s2204/b">Pub. L. 116–315, title II, § 2204(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-05">Jan. 5, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4986">134 Stat. 4986</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/315/tII/s2204/b">“Subsection (i) of <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s2306">section 2306 of title 38</ref>, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall apply with respect to an individual who dies on or after <date date="2019-10-01">October 1, 2019</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/116/315/tII/s2207/b">Pub. L. 116–315, title II, § 2207(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-05">Jan. 5, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4988">134 Stat. 4988</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/315/tII/s2207/b">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall take on [sic] effect on the date that is two years after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-01-05">Jan. 5, 2021</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3413a75-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2018 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/115/232">Pub. L. 115–232</ref> effective <date date="2019-02-01">Feb. 1, 2019</date>, with provision for the coordination of amendments and special rule for certain redesignations, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s800">section 800 of Pub. L. 115–232</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3413a76-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2013 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/260/tI/s101/b">Pub. L. 112–260, title I, § 101(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-10">Jan. 10, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2418">126 Stat. 2418</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/260/tI/s101/b">“Subsections (f) and (h)(4) of <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s2306">section 2306 of title 38</ref>, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall take effect on the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2013-01-10">Jan. 10, 2013</date>] and shall apply with respect to deaths occurring on or after the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3413a77-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/275">Pub. L. 111–275</ref> applicable with respect to the death, on or after <date date="2010-10-13">Oct. 13, 2010</date>, of the parent of a person described in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s2402/a/9/B">section 2402(a)(9)(B) of this title</ref>, who dies on or after <date date="2001-10-07">October 7, 2001</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/275/s502/e">section 502(e) of Pub. L. 111–275</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s107">section 107 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3413a78-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/389/tVIII/s810/b">Pub. L. 110–389, title VIII, § 810(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4190">122 Stat. 4190</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/389/tVIII/s810/b">“The amendment made by this section [amending this section] shall apply to deaths occurring on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3413a79-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2006 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/157/tII/s203/b">Pub. L. 110–157, title II, § 203(b)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1833">121 Stat. 1833</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/157/tII/s203/b">“Notwithstanding subsection (d) of section 502 of the Veterans Education and Benefits Expansion Act of 2001 (<ref href="/us/pl/107/103">Public Law 107–103</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/115/995">115 Stat. 995</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s2306">38 U.S.C. 2306</ref> note) or any other provision of law, the amendments made by that section and by subsections (a), (b), (c), (d), and (f) of section 402 of the Veterans Benefits, Health Care, and Information Technology Act of 2006 (<ref href="/us/pl/109/461">Public Law 109–461</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/120/3429">120 Stat. 3429</ref>) [amending this section] shall take effect as of <date date="1990-11-01">November 1, 1990</date>, and shall apply with respect to headstones and markers for the graves of individuals dying on or after that date.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/109/461/tIV/s401/c">Pub. L. 109–461, title IV, § 401(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3429">120 Stat. 3429</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/461/tIV/s401/c">“The amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to individuals dying after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3413a7a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2002 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/330">Pub. L. 107–330</ref> applicable with respect to deaths occurring on or after <date date="2002-12-06">Dec. 6, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/330/s201/d">section 201(d) of Pub. L. 107–330</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s112">section 112 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3413a7b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2001 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/103/s502">section 502 of Pub. L. 107–103</ref> effective <date date="1990-11-01">Nov. 1, 1990</date>, and applicable with respect to headstones and markers for the graves of individuals dying on or after that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/157/s203/b">section 203(b) of Pub. L. 110–157</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2006 Amendment note above.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/107/103/tV/s502/d">Pub. L. 107–103, title V, § 502(d)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/995">115 Stat. 995</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/107/330/tII/s203/a">Pub. L. 107–330, title II, § 203(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-06">Dec. 6, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2824">116 Stat. 2824</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/330/tII/s203/a">“The amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to markers for the graves of individuals dying on or after <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>[<ref href="/us/pl/107/330/tII/s203/b">Pub. L. 107–330, title II, § 203(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-06">Dec. 6, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2824">116 Stat. 2824</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/330/tII/s203/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending <ref href="/us/pl/107/103/s502/d">section 502(d) of Pub. L. 107–103</ref>, set out above] shall take effect as if included in the enactment of such section 502.”</quotedContent>
]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3413a7c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/368/tIV/s401/d">Pub. L. 105–368, title IV, § 401(d)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3335">112 Stat. 3335</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/368/tIV/s401/d">“The amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) [amending this section] shall apply to deaths occurring after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3413a7d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tVIII/s8041/b">Pub. L. 101–508, title VIII, § 8041(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-349">104 Stat. 1388–349</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/508/tVIII/s8041/b">“This section [amending this section] shall apply to deaths occurring on or after <date date="1990-11-01">November 1, 1990</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3413a7e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1989 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/237/tV/s504/b">Pub. L. 101–237, title V, § 504(b)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-18">Dec. 18, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2094">103 Stat. 2094</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/237/tV/s504/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to interments that occur after <date date="1990-01-01">January 1, 1990</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3413a7f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/66">Pub. L. 97–66</ref> applicable with respect to veterans dying before, on, or after <date date="1981-10-17">Oct. 17, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/66/s701/b/6">section 701(b)(6) of Pub. L. 97–66</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1114">section 1114 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3413a80-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/385">Pub. L. 96–385</ref> applicable only with respect to individuals who die after <date date="1980-09-30">Sept. 30, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/385/s601/c">section 601(c) of Pub. L. 96–385</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1114">section 1114 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3413a81-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/479">Pub. L. 95–479</ref> effective <date date="1978-10-01">Oct. 1, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/479/s401/a">section 401(a) of Pub. L. 95–479</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1114">section 1114 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/476">Pub. L. 95–476</ref> effective <date date="1978-10-18">Oct. 18, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/476/s205/a">section 205(a) of Pub. L. 95–476</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s2303">section 2303 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idc3413a82-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/43/s10/c">Pub. L. 93–43, § 10(c)</ref>, <date date="1973-06-18">June 18, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/88">87 Stat. 88</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/43/s10/c">“Clause (2) of section 5(a) [enacting this section and section 907 [now 2307] of this title] and sections 6 [enacting provisions set out a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s2404">section 2404 of this title</ref>] and 7 [repealing sections 271 to 276, 278 to 279d, 281 to 282, 286 to 290, and 296 of Title 24, Hospitals and Asylums, and enacting provisions set out as notes under sections 271 to 276 of Title 24] of this Act shall take effect <date date="1973-09-01">September 1, 1973</date>, or on such earlier date as the President may prescribe and publish in the Federal Register.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc3413a83-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Continuation of Authority</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/92/s162">Pub. L. 110–92, § 162</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/110/149/s2">Pub. L. 110–149, § 2</ref>, <date date="2007-12-21">Dec. 21, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1819">121 Stat. 1819</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/149/s2">“Notwithstanding section 106 [<ref href="/us/stat/121/990">121 Stat. 990</ref>], the authority provided by <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s2306/d/3">section 2306(d)(3) of title 38</ref>, United States Code, shall continue in effect through <date date="2008-09-30">September 30, 2008</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
