<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc34f934d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3014A"><num value="3014A">§ 3014A.</num><heading> Accelerated payment of basic educational assistance for education leading to employment in high technology occupation in high technology industry</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc34f934e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3014A/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> An individual described in subsection (b) who is entitled to basic educational assistance under this subchapter may elect to receive an accelerated payment of the basic educational assistance allowance otherwise payable to the individual under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3015">section 3015 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc34f934f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3014A/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> An individual described in this subsection is an individual who is—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc34f9350-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3014A/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> enrolled in an approved program of education that leads to employment in a high technology occupation in a high technology industry (as determined pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc34f9351-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3014A/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> charged tuition and fees for the program of education that, when divided by the number of months (and fractions thereof) in the enrollment period, exceeds the amount equal to 200 percent of the monthly rate of basic educational assistance allowance otherwise payable to the individual under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3015">section 3015 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc34f9352-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3014A/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc34f9353-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3014A/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The amount of the accelerated payment of basic educational assistance made to an individual making an election under subsection (a) for a program of education shall be the lesser of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc34f9354-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3014A/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the amount equal to 60 percent of the established charges for the program of education; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc34f9355-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3014A/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the aggregate amount of basic educational assistance to which the individual remains entitled under this chapter at the time of the payment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc34f9356-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3014A/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> In this subsection, the term “established charges”, in the case of a program of education, means the actual charges (as determined pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary) for tuition and fees which similarly circumstanced nonveterans enrolled in the program of education would be required to pay. Established charges shall be determined on the following basis:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc34f9357-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3014A/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In the case of an individual enrolled in a program of education offered on a term, quarter, or semester basis, the tuition and fees charged the individual for the term, quarter, or semester.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc34f9358-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3014A/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In the case of an individual enrolled in a program of education not offered on a term, quarter, or semester basis, the tuition and fees charged the individual for the entire program of education.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc34f9359-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3014A/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The educational institution providing the program of education for which an accelerated payment of basic educational assistance allowance is elected by an individual under subsection (a) shall certify to the Secretary the amount of the established charges for the program of education.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc34f935a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3014A/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><chapeau> An accelerated payment of basic educational assistance made to an individual under this section for a program of education shall be made not later than the last day of the month immediately following the month in which the Secretary receives a certification from the educational institution regarding—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc34f935b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3014A/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the individual’s enrollment in and pursuit of the program of education; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc34f935c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3014A/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the amount of the established charges for the program of education.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc34f935d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3014A/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc34f935e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3014A/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), for each accelerated payment of basic educational assistance made to an individual under this section, the individual’s entitlement to basic educational assistance under this chapter shall be charged the number of months (and any fraction thereof) determined by dividing the amount of the accelerated payment by the full-time monthly rate of basic educational assistance allowance otherwise payable to the individual under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3015">section 3015 of this title</ref> as of the beginning date of the enrollment period for the program of education for which the accelerated payment is made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc34f935f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3014A/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If the monthly rate of basic educational assistance allowance otherwise payable to an individual under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3015">section 3015 of this title</ref> increases during the enrollment period of a program of education for which an accelerated payment of basic educational assistance is made under this section, the charge to the individual’s entitlement to basic educational assistance under this chapter shall be determined by prorating the entitlement chargeable, in the matter provided for under paragraph (1), for the periods covered by the initial rate and increased rate, respectively, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc34f9360-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3014A/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> The Secretary may not make an accelerated payment under this section for a program of education to an individual who has received an advance payment under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3680/d">section 3680(d) of this title</ref> for the same enrollment period.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc34f9361-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3014A/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> The Secretary shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section. The regulations shall include requirements, conditions, and methods for the request, issuance, delivery, certification of receipt and use, and recovery of overpayment of an accelerated payment under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc34f9362-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/107/103/tI/s104/a/1">Pub. L. 107–103, title I, § 104(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/980">115 Stat. 980</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/107/330/tIII/s308/b/1">Pub. L. 107–330, title III, § 308(b)(1)</ref>, (2)(A), <date date="2002-12-06">Dec. 6, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2827">116 Stat. 2827</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc34f9363-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc34f9364-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc34f9365-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—<ref href="/us/pl/107/330/s308/b/2/A">Pub. L. 107–330, § 308(b)(2)(A)</ref>, amended section catchline generally. Prior to amendment, catchline read as follows: “Accelerated payment of basic educational assistance for education leading to employment in high technology industry”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/330/s308/b/1">Pub. L. 107–330, § 308(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “employment in a high technology occupation in a high technology industry” for “employment in a high technology industry”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc34f9366-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idc34f9367-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/103/tI/s104/c">Pub. L. 107–103, title I, § 104(c)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/982">115 Stat. 982</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/103/tI/s104/c">“The amendments made by this section [enacting this section and amending <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3680">section 3680 of this title</ref>] shall take effect <date date="2002-10-01">October 1, 2002</date>, and shall apply with respect to enrollments in courses or programs of education or training beginning on or after that date.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
