<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc3544e47-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020"><num value="3020">§ 3020.</num><heading> Authority to transfer unused education benefits to family members for career service members</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e48-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to the provisions of this section, the Secretary of Defense may authorize the Secretary concerned, to promote recruitment and retention of members of the Armed Forces, to permit an individual described in subsection (b) who is entitled to basic educational assistance under this subchapter to elect to transfer to one or more of the dependents specified in subsection (c) the unused portion of entitlement to such assistance, subject to the limitation under subsection (d).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e49-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible Individuals</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An individual referred to in subsection (a) is any member of the Armed Forces—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3544e4a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> who, while serving on active duty or as a member of the Selected Reserve at the time of the approval by the Secretary concerned of the member’s request to transfer entitlement to basic educational assistance under this section, has completed six years of service in the Armed Forces and enters into an agreement to serve at least four more years as a member of the Armed Forces; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3544e4b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> as determined in regulations pursuant to subsection (k).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e4c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible Dependents</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An individual approved to transfer an entitlement to basic educational assistance under this section may transfer the individual’s entitlement as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3544e4d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> To the individual’s spouse.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3544e4e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> To one or more of the individual’s children.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3544e4f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> To a combination of the individuals referred to in paragraphs (1) and (2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e50-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Months of Transfer</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e51-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An individual approved to transfer an entitlement to basic educational assistance under this section may transfer any unused entitlement to one or more of the dependents specified in subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e52-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The total number of months of entitlement transferred by an individual under this section may not exceed 36 months. The Secretary of Defense may prescribe regulations that would limit the months of entitlement that may be transferred under this section to no less than 18 months.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e53-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Designation of Transferee</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An individual transferring an entitlement to basic educational assistance under this section shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3544e54-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> designate the dependent or dependents to whom such entitlement is being transferred;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3544e55-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> designate the number of months of such entitlement to be transferred to each such dependent; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3544e56-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> specify the period for which the transfer shall be effective for each dependent designated under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e57-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Time for Transfer; Revocation and Modification</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e58-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Subject to the time limitation for use of entitlement under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3031">section 3031 of this title</ref>, an individual approved to transfer entitlement to basic educational assistance under this section may transfer such entitlement at any time after the approval of the individual’s request to transfer such entitlement only while the individual is a member of the Armed Forces when the transfer is executed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e59-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e5a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> An individual transferring entitlement under this section may modify or revoke at any time the transfer of any unused portion of the entitlement so transferred as long as the individual is serving on active duty or as a member of the Selected Reserve.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e5b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The modification or revocation of the transfer of entitlement under this paragraph shall be made by the submittal of written notice of the action to both the Secretary concerned and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e5c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Entitlement transferred under this section may not be treated as marital property, or the asset of a marital estate, subject to division in a divorce or other civil proceeding.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e5d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Commencement of Use</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A dependent to whom entitlement to basic educational assistance is transferred under this section may not commence the use of the transferred entitlement until—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3544e5e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> in the case of entitlement transferred to a spouse, the completion by the individual making the transfer of six years of service in the Armed Forces; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3544e5f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> in the case of entitlement transferred to a child, both—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3544e60-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/g/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the completion by the individual making the transfer of 10 years of service in the Armed Forces; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3544e61-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/g/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> either—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc3544e62-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/g/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the completion by the child of the requirements of a secondary school diploma (or equivalency certificate); or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc3544e63-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/g/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the attainment by the child of 18 years of age.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e64-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional Administrative Matters</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e65-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The use of any entitlement to basic educational assistance transferred under this section shall be charged against the entitlement of the individual making the transfer at the rate of one month for each month of transferred entitlement that is used.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e66-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Except as provided under subsection (e)(2) and subject to paragraphs (5) and (6), a dependent to whom entitlement is transferred under this section is entitled to basic educational assistance under this subchapter in the same manner as the individual from whom the entitlement was transferred.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e67-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e68-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/h/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Subject to subparagraph (B), the monthly rate of educational assistance payable to a dependent to whom entitlement is transferred under this section shall be the monthly amount payable under sections 3015 and 3022 of this title to the individual making the transfer.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e69-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/h/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The monthly rate of assistance payable to a dependent under subparagraph (A) shall be subject to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3032">section 3032 of this title</ref>, except that the provisions of subsection (a)(1) of that section shall not apply even if the individual making the transfer to the dependent under this section is on active duty during all or any part of enrollment period of the dependent in which such entitlement is used.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e6a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/h/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The death of an individual transferring an entitlement under this section shall not affect the use of the entitlement by the dependent to whom the entitlement is transferred.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e6b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/h/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3031">section 3031 of this title</ref>, a child to whom entitlement is transferred under this section may use the benefit without regard to the 10-year delimiting date, but may not use any entitlement so transferred after attaining the age of 26 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e6c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/h/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The administrative provisions of this chapter (including the provisions set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3034/a/1">section 3034(a)(1) of this title</ref>) shall apply to the use of entitlement transferred under this section, except that the dependent to whom the entitlement is transferred shall be treated as the eligible veteran for purposes of such provisions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e6d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/h/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The purposes for which a dependent to whom entitlement is transferred under this section may use such entitlement shall include the pursuit and completion of the requirements of a secondary school diploma (or equivalency certificate).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e6e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Overpayment</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e6f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In the event of an overpayment of basic educational assistance with respect to a dependent to whom entitlement is transferred under this section, the dependent and the individual making the transfer shall be jointly and severally liable to the United States for the amount of the overpayment for purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3685">section 3685 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e70-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (3), if an individual transferring entitlement under this section fails to complete the service agreed to by the individual under subsection (b)(3) in accordance with the terms of the agreement of the individual under that subsection, the amount of any transferred entitlement under this section that is used by a dependent of the individual as of the date of such failure shall be treated as an overpayment of basic educational assistance under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e71-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Paragraph (2) shall not apply in the case of an individual who fails to complete service agreed to by the individual—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3544e72-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/i/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> by reason of the death of the individual; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3544e73-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/i/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> for a reason referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3011/a/1/A/ii/I">section 3011(a)(1)(A)(ii)(I) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e74-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Approvals of Transfer Subject to Availability of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary concerned may approve transfers of entitlement to basic educational assistance under this section in a fiscal year only to the extent that appropriations for military personnel are available in that fiscal year for purposes of making deposits in the Department of Defense Education Benefits Fund under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2006">section 2006 of title 10</ref> in that fiscal year to cover the present value of future benefits payable from the Fund for the Department of Defense portion of payments of basic educational assistance attributable to increased usage of benefits as a result of such transfers of entitlement in that fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e75-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall prescribe regulations for purposes of this section. Such regulations shall specify—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3544e76-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/k/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the manner of authorizing the military departments to offer transfer of entitlements under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3544e77-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/k/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the eligibility criteria in accordance with subsection (b);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3544e78-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/k/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the limitations on the amount of entitlement eligible to be transferred; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3544e79-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/k/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the manner and effect of an election to modify or revoke a transfer of entitlement under subsection (f)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3544e7a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/l"><num value="l">(l)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secretary Concerned Defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s101/25">section 101(25) of this title</ref>, in this section, the term “Secretary concerned” means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3544e7b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/l/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Secretary of the Army with respect to matters concerning the Army;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3544e7c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/l/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the Secretary of the Navy with respect to matters concerning the Navy or the Marine Corps;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3544e7d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/l/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the Secretary of the Air Force with respect to matters concerning the Air Force or the Space Force; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3544e7e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3020/l/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the Secretary of Defense with respect to matters concerning the Coast Guard, or the Secretary of Homeland Security when it is not operating as a service in the Navy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc3544e7f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tVI/s654/a/1">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title VI, § 654(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1153">115 Stat. 1153</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/107/296/tXVII/s1704/d">Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(d)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2315">116 Stat. 2315</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tVI/s643/a">Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title VI, § 643(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2577">116 Stat. 2577</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/252/tV/s5006/a">Pub. L. 110–252, title V, § 5006(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-06-30">June 30, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/2380">122 Stat. 2380</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/dA/tX/s1063/b">Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1063(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1586">125 Stat. 1586</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tIX/s926/f">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 926(f)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3831">134 Stat. 3831</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc3544e80-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc3544e81-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idc3544e82-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 3020 was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s5120">section 5120 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc3544e83-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (<i>l</i>)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> inserted “or the Space Force” before semicolon.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsecs. (<i>l</i>), (m). <ref href="/us/pl/112/81">Pub. L. 112–81</ref> redesignated subsec. (m) as (<i>l</i>) and struck out former subsec. (<i>l</i>) which required the Secretary of Defense to submit an annual report on approved transfers of entitlement to basic educational assistance.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—<ref href="/us/pl/110/252/s5006/a/1">Pub. L. 110–252, § 5006(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Authority to transfer unused education benefits to family members for career service members” for “Transfer of entitlement to basic educational assistance: members of the Armed Forces with critical military skills” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (a), (b). <ref href="/us/pl/110/252/s5006/a/1">Pub. L. 110–252, § 5006(a)(1)</ref>, added subsecs. (a) and (b) and struck out former subsecs. (a) and (b) which provided for transfers of entitlement to basic educational assistance from eligible members of the Armed Forces to certain dependents and described eligibility criteria for such members, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/110/252/s5006/a/2">Pub. L. 110–252, § 5006(a)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (d) and struck out former subsec. (d). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The total number of months of entitlement transferred by an individual under this section may not exceed 18 months.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/110/252/s5006/a/3">Pub. L. 110–252, § 5006(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “only while” for “without regard to whether”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/110/252/s5006/a/4">Pub. L. 110–252, § 5006(a)(4)</ref>, inserted “as long as the individual is serving on active duty or as a member of the Selected Reserve” after “so transferred”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/110/252/s5006/a/5">Pub. L. 110–252, § 5006(a)(5)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/110/252/s5006/a/6">Pub. L. 110–252, § 5006(a)(6)</ref>, inserted “may use the benefit without regard to the 10-year delimiting date, but” after “under this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/110/252/s5006/a/7">Pub. L. 110–252, § 5006(a)(7)</ref>, added subsec. (k) and struck out former subsec. (k). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations for purposes of this section. Such regulations shall specify the manner and effect of an election to modify or revoke a transfer of entitlement under subsection (f)(2) and shall specify the manner of the applicability of the administrative provisions referred to in subsection (h)(5) to a dependent to whom entitlement is transferred under this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (h)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s643/a/1">Pub. L. 107–314, § 643(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “paragraphs (5) and (6)” for “paragraphs (4) and (5)” and struck out “and at the same rate” after “in the same manner”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(3) to (7). <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s643/a/2">Pub. L. 107–314, § 643(a)(2)</ref>, (3), added par. (3) and redesignated former pars. (3) to (6) as (4) to (7), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref> substituted “of Homeland Security” for “of Transportation”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc3544e84-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3544e85-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2002 Amendments</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tVI/s643/c/1">Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title VI, § 643(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2578">116 Stat. 2578</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tVI/s643/c/1">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect as if included in the enactment of <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3020">section 3020 of title 38</ref>, United States Code, by section 654(a)(1) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2002 (<ref href="/us/pl/107/107">Public Law 107–107</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/115/1153">115 Stat. 1153</ref>).”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref> effective on the date of transfer of the Coast Guard to the Department of Homeland Security, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/296/s1704/g">section 1704(g) of Pub. L. 107–296</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101">section 101 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc3544e86-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plan for Implementation</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tVI/s654/c">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title VI, § 654(c)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1157">115 Stat. 1157</ref>, required the Secretary of Defense, not later than <date date="2002-06-30">June 30, 2002</date>, to submit to Congress a report describing the manner in which the Secretaries of the military departments and the Secretary of Transportation propose to exercise the authority granted by this section, including the regulations prescribed under subsec. (k) of this section for purposes of the exercise of the authority.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
