<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc3603477-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231"><num value="3231">§ 3231.</num><heading> Entitlement; loan eligibility</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3603478-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3603479-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Subject to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3695">section 3695 of this title</ref> limiting the aggregate period for which any person may receive assistance under two or more programs of educational or vocational assistance administered by the Department of Veterans Affairs, a participant shall be entitled to a maximum of 36 monthly benefit payments (or their equivalent in the event of part-time benefits).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc360347a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (5)(E) of this subsection and in subsection (e) of this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3233">section 3233 of this title</ref> and subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3241">section 3241 of this title</ref>, the amount of the monthly payment to which any eligible veteran is entitled shall be ascertained by (A) adding all contributions made to the fund by the eligible veteran, (B) multiplying the sum by 3, (C) adding all contributions made to the fund for such veteran by the Secretary of Defense, and (D) dividing the sum by the lesser of 36 or the number of months in which contributions were made by such veteran.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc360347b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Payment of benefits under this chapter may be made only for periods of time during which an eligible veteran is actually enrolled in and pursuing an approved program of education and, except as provided in paragraph (4), only after an eligible veteran has been discharged or released from active duty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc360347c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Payment of benefits under this chapter may be made after a participant has completed his or her first obligated period of active duty (which began after <date date="1976-12-31">December 31, 1976</date>), or 6 years of active duty (which began after <date date="1976-12-31">December 31, 1976</date>), whichever period is less.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc360347d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc360347e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/a/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter or chapter 36 of this title, any payment of an educational assistance allowance described in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc360347f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/a/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> shall not be charged against the entitlement of any eligible veteran under this chapter; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3603480-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/a/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> shall not be counted toward the aggregate period for which <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3695">section 3695 of this title</ref> limits an individual’s receipt of assistance.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3603481-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/a/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> The payment of an educational assistance allowance referred to in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph is any payment of a monthly benefit under this chapter to an eligible veteran for pursuit of a course or courses under this chapter if the Secretary finds that the eligible veteran—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3603482-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/a/5/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> in the case of a person not serving on active duty, had to discontinue such course pursuit as a result of being ordered to serve on active duty under section 688, 12301(a), 12301(d), 12301(g), 12302, or 12304 of title 10; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3603483-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/a/5/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in the case of a person serving on active duty, had to discontinue such course pursuit as a result of being ordered to a new duty location or assignment or to perform an increased amount of work; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3603484-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/a/5/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> failed to receive credit or training time toward completion of the individual’s approved educational, professional, or vocational objective as a result of having to discontinue, as described in clause (i) or (ii) of this subparagraph, his or her course pursuit.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3603485-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/a/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The period for which, by reason of this subsection, an educational assistance allowance is not charged against entitlement or counted toward the applicable aggregate period under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3695">section 3695 of this title</ref> shall not exceed the portion of the period of enrollment in the course or courses for which the individual failed to receive credit or with respect to which the individual lost training time, as determined under subparagraph (B)(iii) of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3603486-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/a/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The amount in the fund for each eligible veteran who received a payment of an educational assistance allowance described in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph shall be restored to the amount that would have been in the fund for the veteran if the payment had not been made. For purposes of carrying out the previous sentence, the Secretary of Defense shall deposit into the fund, on behalf of each such veteran, an amount equal to the entire amount of the payment made to the veteran.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3603487-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/a/5/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><chapeau> In the case of a veteran who discontinues pursuit of a course or courses as described in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, the formula for ascertaining the amount of the monthly payment to which the veteran is entitled in paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be implemented as if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3603488-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/a/5/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the payment made to the fund by the Secretary of Defense under subparagraph (D) of this paragraph, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3603489-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/a/5/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any payment for a course or courses described in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph that was paid out of the fund,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">had not been made or paid.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc360348a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Any enlisted member of the Armed Forces participating in the program shall be eligible to enroll in a course, courses, or program of education for the purpose of attaining a secondary school diploma (or an equivalency certificate), as authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3491/a">section 3491(a) of this title</ref>, during the last six months of such member’s first enlistment and at any time thereafter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc360348b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> When an eligible veteran is pursuing a program of education under this chapter by correspondence, such eligible veteran’s entitlement shall be charged at the rate of 1 month’s entitlement for each month of benefits paid to the eligible veteran (computed on the basis of the formula provided in subsection (a)(2) of this section).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc360348c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc360348d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection, the amount of the educational assistance benefits paid to an eligible veteran who is pursuing a program of education under this chapter while incarcerated in a Federal, State, local, or other penal institution or correctional facility for conviction of a felony may not exceed the lesser of (A) such amount as the Secretary determines, in accordance with regulations which the Secretary shall prescribe, is necessary to cover the cost of established charges for tuition and fees required of similarly circumstanced nonveterans enrolled in the same program and the cost of necessary supplies, books, and equipment, or (B) the applicable monthly benefit payment otherwise prescribed in this section or <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3233">section 3233 of this title</ref>. The amount of the educational assistance benefits payable to a veteran while so incarcerated shall be reduced to the extent that the tuition and fees of the veteran for any course are paid under any Federal program (other than a program administered by the Secretary) or under any State or local program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc360348e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not apply in the case of any veteran who is pursuing a program of education under this chapter while residing in a halfway house or participating in a work-release program in connection with such veteran’s conviction of a felony.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc360348f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3603490-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Subject to subsection (a)(1) of this section, each individual who is pursuing a program of education consisting exclusively of flight training approved as meeting the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3241/b">section 3241(b) of this title</ref> shall be paid educational assistance under this chapter in the amount equal to 60 percent of the established charges for tuition and fees which similarly circumstanced nonveterans enrolled in the same flight course are required to pay.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3603491-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> No payment may be paid under this chapter to an individual for any month during which such individual is pursuing a program of education consisting exclusively of flight training until the Secretary has received from that individual and the institution providing such training a certification of the flight training received by the individual during that month and the tuition and other fees charged for that training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3603492-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The entitlement of an eligible veteran pursuing a program of education described in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be charged at the rate of one month for each amount of educational assistance paid which is equal to the monthly benefit otherwise payable to such veteran (computed on the basis of the formula provided in subsection (a)(2) of this section).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3603493-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3231/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The number of solo flying hours for which an individual may be paid an educational assistance allowance under this subsection may not exceed the minimum number of solo flying hours required by the Federal Aviation Administration for the flight rating or certification which is the goal of the individual’s flight training.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc3603494-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/94/502/tIV/s404">Pub. L. 94–502, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="1976-10-15">Oct. 15, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2396">90 Stat. 2396</ref>, § 1631; amended <ref href="/us/pl/96/466/tIV">Pub. L. 96–466, title IV</ref>, §§ 403, 404, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2201">94 Stat. 2201</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXX">Pub. L. 97–35, title XX</ref>, §§ 2003(a)(1), 2005(a), <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/782">95 Stat. 782</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/576/tIII/s310/b/1">Pub. L. 99–576, title III, § 310(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-28">Oct. 28, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3271">100 Stat. 3271</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/689/tI">Pub. L. 100–689, title I</ref>, §§ 108(b)(2), 122, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4170">102 Stat. 4170</ref>, 4174; <ref href="/us/pl/101/237/tIV/s423/b/1">Pub. L. 101–237, title IV, § 423(b)(1)</ref>, (4)(A), <date date="1989-12-18">Dec. 18, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2092">103 Stat. 2092</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/16/s7/b">Pub. L. 102–16, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-03-22">Mar. 22, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/51">105 Stat. 51</ref>; renumbered § 3231 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/a">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/406">105 Stat. 406</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/127/s2/b">Pub. L. 102–127, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-10-10">Oct. 10, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/619">105 Stat. 619</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/568/tIII/s310/c">Pub. L. 102–568, title III, § 310(c)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4330">106 Stat. 4330</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/275/tI/s105/b">Pub. L. 104–275, title I, § 105(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3327">110 Stat. 3327</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/368/tX/s1005/b/7">Pub. L. 105–368, title X, § 1005(b)(7)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3365">112 Stat. 3365</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/103/tI/s103/a">Pub. L. 107–103, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, (d), <date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/979">115 Stat. 979</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/tX/s1002/c">Pub. L. 109–461, title X, § 1002(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3465">120 Stat. 3465</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc3603495-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc3603496-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc3603497-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/461">Pub. L. 109–461</ref> substituted “local, or other penal institution or correctional facility” for “or local penal institution”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (a)(5)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/107/103/s103/a">Pub. L. 107–103, § 103(a)</ref>, substituted “to serve on active duty under section 688, 12301(a), 12301(d), 12301(g), 12302, or 12304 of title 10;” for “, in connection with the Persian Gulf War, to serve on active duty under section 672(a), (d), or (g), 673, 673b, or 688 of title 10;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/107/103/s103/d">Pub. L. 107–103, § 103(d)</ref>, struck out “, in connection with such War,” after “being ordered”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/368">Pub. L. 105–368</ref> substituted “subsection (e)” for “subsection (f)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsecs. (d) to (f). <ref href="/us/pl/104/275">Pub. L. 104–275</ref> redesignated subsecs. (e) and (f) as (d) and (e), respectively, and struck out former subsec. (d) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(d)(1) The amount of the monthly benefit payment to an individual pursuing a cooperative program under this chapter shall be 80 percent of the monthly benefit otherwise payable to such individual (computed on the basis of the formula provided in subsection (a)(2) of this section).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2) For each month that an individual is paid a monthly benefit payment for pursuit of a cooperative program under this chapter, the individual’s entitlement under this chapter shall be charged at the rate 80 percent of a month.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/568/s310/c/1">Pub. L. 102–568, § 310(c)(1)</ref>, struck out “(other than tuition and fees charged for or attributable to solo flying hours)” after “for tuition and fees”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/102/568/s310/c/2">Pub. L. 102–568, § 310(c)(2)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—<ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/a">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1631">section 1631 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/c/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “3695” for “1795”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/127/s2/b/2">Pub. L. 102–127, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, inserted “in paragraph (5)(E) of this subsection and” after “Except as provided”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/c/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “3233” for “1633” and “3241” for “1641”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/16/s7/b/1">Pub. L. 102–16, § 7(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “subsection (f) of this section and” after “Except as provided in”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/102/127/s2/b/1">Pub. L. 102–127, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/c/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “3491(a)” for “1691(a)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/c/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “3233” for “1633”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/c/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “3241(b)” for “1641(b)” in par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/16/s7/b/2">Pub. L. 102–16, § 7(b)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/237/s423/b/1/B">Pub. L. 101–237, § 423(b)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “Department of Veterans Affairs” for “Veterans’ Administration”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/101/237/s423/b/4/A">Pub. L. 101–237, § 423(b)(4)(A)</ref>, inserted “of Defense” after “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/237/s423/b/1/A">Pub. L. 101–237, § 423(b)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/100/689/s108/b/2">Pub. L. 100–689, § 108(b)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/100/689/s122">Pub. L. 100–689, § 122</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/576">Pub. L. 99–576</ref> substituted “Except as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1633">section 1633 of this title</ref> and subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1641">section 1641 of this title</ref>, the” for “The”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2003/a/1">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2003(a)(1)</ref>, struck out applicability to a program of flight training.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2005/a">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2005(a)</ref>, struck out subsec. (d) which related to eligibility of veterans for loans authorized by subchapter III of chapter 36 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/96/466/s404">Pub. L. 96–466, § 404</ref>, inserted reference to provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1795">section 1795 of this title</ref> limiting the aggregate period for which any person may receive assistance under two or more programs of educational or vocational assistance administered by the Veterans’ Administration, and substituted reference to part-time benefits, for reference to part-time benefit payments.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/96/466/s403">Pub. L. 96–466, § 403</ref>, substituted reference to enrolling in a course, courses, or program of education for the purpose of attaining a secondary school diploma or an equivalency certificate during the last six months of such member’s first enlistment and at any time thereafter, for reference to participating in the Predischarge Education Program authorized by subchapter VI of chapter 34 of this title during the last 6 months of such member’s first enlistment.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc362a598-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc362a599-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2001 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/103">Pub. L. 107–103</ref> effective <date date="2001-09-11">Sept. 11, 2001</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/103/s103/e">section 103(e) of Pub. L. 107–103</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3013">section 3013 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc362a59a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/568">Pub. L. 102–568</ref> applicable to flight training received under this chapter, chapter 30 of this title, and chapter 106 of Title 10, Armed Forces, after <date date="1992-09-30">Sept. 30, 1992</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/568/s310/d">section 310(d) of Pub. L. 102–568</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s16131">section 16131 of Title 10</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc362a59b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1991 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/16/s7/c">Pub. L. 102–16, § 7(c)</ref>, <date date="1991-03-22">Mar. 22, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/52">105 Stat. 52</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/16/s7/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and section 1641 [now 3241] of this title] shall take effect on <date date="1991-04-01">April 1, 1991</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc362a59c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/689/s108/b/2">section 108(b)(2) of Pub. L. 100–689</ref> effective <date date="1989-01-01">Jan. 1, 1989</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/689/s108/c">section 108(c) of Pub. L. 100–689</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3002">section 3002 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc362a59d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXX/s2006">Pub. L. 97–35, title XX, § 2006</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/783">95 Stat. 783</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/35/tXX/s2006">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> Except as provided in subsection (b), the amendments made by sections 2003 [amending this section and sections 1641, 1662, 1673, 1681, 1682, and 1780 [now 3241, 3462, 3473, 3481, 3482, and 3680] of this title and repealing <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1677">section 1677 of this title</ref>] and 2005 [amending this section and sections 1686 [repealed], 1737 [repealed], and 1798 [now 3698] of this title] shall take effect on <date date="1981-10-01">October 1, 1981</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The amendments made by such sections shall not apply to any person receiving educational assistance under section 1677 [now 3477] of title 38, United States Code, as such section was in effect on <date date="1981-08-31">August 31, 1981</date>, for the pursuit of a program of education (as defined in section 1652(b) [now 3452(b)] of such title) in which such person was enrolled on that date, for as long as such person is continuously thereafter so enrolled and meets the requirements of eligibility for such assistance for the pursuit of such program under the provisions of chapters 34 and 36 of such title, as in effect on that date.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc362a59e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/466">Pub. L. 96–466</ref> effective <date date="1980-10-01">Oct. 1, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/466/s802/d/2">section 802(d)(2) of Pub. L. 96–466</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3224">section 3224 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idc362a59f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1977-01-01">Jan. 1, 1977</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/502/s406">section 406 of Pub. L. 94–502</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3201">section 3201 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
