<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc36c42d9-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452"><num value="3452">§ 3452.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this chapter and chapter 36 of this title—</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc36c42da-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc36c42db-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The term “eligible veteran” means any veteran who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc36c42dc-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> served on active duty for a period of more than 180 days, any part of which occurred after <date date="1955-01-31">January 31, 1955</date>, and before <date date="1977-01-01">January 1, 1977</date>, and was discharged or released therefrom under conditions other than dishonorable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc36c42dd-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> contracted with the Armed Forces and was enlisted in or assigned to a reserve component prior to <date date="1977-01-01">January 1, 1977</date>, and as a result of such enlistment or assignment served on active duty for a period of more than 180 days, any part of which commenced within 12 months after <date date="1977-01-01">January 1, 1977</date>, and was discharged or released from such active duty under conditions other than dishonorable; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc36c42de-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> was discharged or released from active duty, any part of which was performed after <date date="1955-01-31">January 31, 1955</date>, and before <date date="1977-01-01">January 1, 1977</date>, or following entrance into active service from an enlistment provided for under subparagraph (B), because of a service-connected disability.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc36c42df-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The requirement of discharge or release, prescribed in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1), shall be waived in the case of any individual who served more than 180 days in an active-duty status for so long as such individual continues on active duty without a break therein.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc36c42e0-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> For purposes of paragraph (1)(A) and section 3461(a), the term “active duty” does not include any period during which an individual (A) was assigned full time by the Armed Forces to a civilian institution for a course of education which was substantially the same as established courses offered to civilians, (B) served as a cadet or midshipman at one of the service academies, or (C) served under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12103/d">section 12103(d) of title 10</ref> pursuant to an enlistment in the Army National Guard or the Air National Guard or as a Reserve for service in the Army Reserve, Navy Reserve, Air Force Reserve, Marine Corps Reserve, or Coast Guard Reserve unless at some time subsequent to the completion of such period of active duty for training such individual served on active duty for a consecutive period of one year or more (not including any service as a cadet or midshipman at one of the service academies).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc36e8bd1-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The term “program of education” means any curriculum or any combination of unit courses or subjects pursued at an educational institution which is generally accepted as necessary to fulfill requirements for the attainment of a predetermined and identified educational, professional, or vocational objective. Such term also means any curriculum of unit courses or subjects pursued at an educational institution which fulfill requirements for the attainment of more than one predetermined and identified educational, professional, or vocational objective if all the objectives pursued are generally recognized as being reasonably related to a single career field. Such term also means any unit course or subject, or combination of courses or subjects, pursued by an eligible veteran at an educational institution, required by the Administrator of the Small Business Administration as a condition to obtaining financial assistance under the provisions of section 7(i)(1) of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s636/i/1">15 U.S.C. 636(i)(1)</ref>). Such term also includes licensing or certification tests, the successful completion of which demonstrates an individual’s possession of the knowledge or skill required to enter into, maintain, or advance in employment in a predetermined and identified vocation or profession, provided such tests and the licensing or credentialing organizations or entities that offer such tests are approved by the Secretary in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3689">section 3689 of this title</ref>. Such term also includes any course, or combination of courses, offered by a qualified provider of entrepreneurship courses. Such term also includes national tests for admission to institutions of higher learning or graduate schools (such as the Scholastic Aptitude Test (SAT), Law School Admission Test (LSAT), Graduate Record Exam (GRE), and Graduate Management Admission Test (GMAT)), national tests providing an opportunity for course credit at institutions of higher learning (such as the Advanced Placement (AP) exam and College-Level Examination Program (CLEP)), and national tests that evaluate prior learning and knowledge and provides <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002063">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002063"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “provide”.</note> an opportunity for course credit at an institution of higher learning.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc36e8bd2-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The term “educational institution” means any public or private elementary school, secondary school, vocational school, correspondence school, business school, junior college, teachers’ college, college, normal school, professional school, university, or scientific or technical institution, or other institution furnishing education for adults. Such term includes any entity that provides training required for completion of any State-approved alternative teacher certification program (as determined by the Secretary). Such term also includes any private entity (that meets such requirements as the Secretary may establish) that offers, either directly or under an agreement with another entity (that meets such requirements), a course or courses to fulfill requirements for the attainment of a license or certificate generally recognized as necessary to obtain, maintain, or advance in employment in a profession or vocation in a high technology occupation (as determined by the Secretary). Such term also includes any qualified provider of entrepreneurship courses.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc36e8bd3-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><chapeau> The term “dependent” means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc36e8bd4-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a child of an eligible veteran;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc36e8bd5-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a dependent parent of an eligible veteran; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc36e8bd6-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the spouse of an eligible veteran.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc36e8bd7-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><chapeau> The term “training establishment” means any of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc36e8bd8-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An establishment providing apprentice or other on-job training, including those under the supervision of a college or university or any State department of education.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc36e8bd9-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An establishment providing self-employment on-job training consisting of full-time training for a period of less than six months that is needed or accepted for purposes of obtaining licensure to engage in a self-employment occupation or required for ownership and operation of a franchise that is the objective of the training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc36e8bda-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A State board of vocational education.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc36e8bdb-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> A Federal or State apprenticeship registration agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc36e8bdc-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The sponsor of a program of apprenticeship.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc36e8bdd-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452/e/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> An agency of the Federal Government authorized to supervise such training.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc36e8bde-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> The term “institution of higher learning” means a college, university, or similar institution, including a technical or business school, offering postsecondary level academic instruction that leads to an associate or higher degree if the school is empowered by the appropriate State education authority under State law to grant an associate or higher degree. When there is no State law to authorize the granting of a degree, the school may be recognized as an institution of higher learning if it is accredited for degree programs by a recognized accrediting agency. Such term shall also include a hospital offering educational programs at the postsecond­ary level without regard to whether the hospital grants a postsecondary degree. Such term shall also include an educational institution which is not located in a State, which offers a course leading to a standard college degree, or the equivalent, and which is recognized as such by the secretary of education (or comparable official) of the country or other jurisdiction in which the institution is located.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc36e8bdf-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> The term “standard college degree” means an associate or higher degree awarded by (1) an institution of higher learning that is accredited as a collegiate institution by a recognized regional or national accrediting agency; or (2) an institution of higher learning that is a “candidate” for accreditation as that term is used by the regional or national accrediting agencies; or (3) an institution of higher learning upon completion of a course which is accredited by an agency recognized to accredit specialized degree-level programs. For the purpose of this section, the accrediting agency must be one recognized by the Secretary of Education under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3675">section 3675 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc36e8be0-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3452/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content> The term “qualified provider of entrepreneurship courses” means any small business development center described in section 21 of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s648">15 U.S.C. 648</ref>), insofar as such center offers, sponsors, or cosponsors an entrepreneurship course, as that term is defined in section 3675(c)(2).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc36e8be1-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/89/358/s2">Pub. L. 89–358, § 2</ref>, <date date="1966-03-03">Mar. 3, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/13">80 Stat. 13</ref>, § 1652; amended <ref href="/us/pl/90/77/tIII/s304/c">Pub. L. 90–77, title III, § 304(c)</ref>, <date date="1967-08-31">Aug. 31, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/186">81 Stat. 186</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/219/tII/s201">Pub. L. 91–219, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1970-03-26">Mar. 26, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/78">84 Stat. 78</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/584/s10">Pub. L. 91–584, § 10</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1577">84 Stat. 1577</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/508/tII/s201">Pub. L. 93–508, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1974-12-03">Dec. 3, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1581">88 Stat. 1581</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/502/tII">Pub. L. 94–502, title II</ref>, §§ 202, 210(1), 211(1), title IV, § 402, <date date="1976-10-15">Oct. 15, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2385">90 Stat. 2385</ref>, 2388, 2392; <ref href="/us/pl/96/466/tIII/s307/a">Pub. L. 96–466, title III, § 307(a)</ref>, title VIII, § 801(a), <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2193">94 Stat. 2193</ref>, 2216; <ref href="/us/pl/97/295/s4/38">Pub. L. 97–295, § 4(38)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1307">96 Stat. 1307</ref>; renumbered § 3452 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/a">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/406">105 Stat. 406</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/446/tVI/s603/a">Pub. L. 103–446, title VI, § 603(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4671">108 Stat. 4671</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/275/tI/s102">Pub. L. 104–275, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3326">110 Stat. 3326</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/419/tI/s122/a">Pub. L. 106–419, title I, § 122(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-01">Nov. 1, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1833">114 Stat. 1833</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/14/s8/a/4">Pub. L. 107–14, § 8(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2001-06-05">June 5, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/34">115 Stat. 34</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/103/tI/s110/a">Pub. L. 107–103, title I, § 110(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/986">115 Stat. 986</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/183/tIII/s301/a">Pub. L. 108–183, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, § 305(c)–(e), <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2658">117 Stat. 2658</ref>, 2660; <ref href="/us/pl/108/454/tI">Pub. L. 108–454, title I</ref>, §§ 106(a), 110(a), <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3602">118 Stat. 3602</ref>, 3605; <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tV/s515/e/4">Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(e)(4)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3236">119 Stat. 3236</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dA/tXVI/s1699/c/2">Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XVI, § 1699(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2092">126 Stat. 2092</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/48/tI/s108/c">Pub. L. 115–48, title I, § 108(c)</ref>, <date date="2017-08-16">Aug. 16, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/978">131 Stat. 978</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc36e8be2-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc36e8be3-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idc36e8be4-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those comprising subsecs. (a) to (d) of this section were contained in <ref href="/us/pl/85/857">Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1174">72 Stat. 1174</ref>, 1176, which was classified to former sections 1601(a)(2) and 1611(a)(1), and 1601(a)(3), (5), and (6) of this title, respectively, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/89/358/s4/a">section 4(a) of Pub. L. 89–358</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc36e8be5-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/115/48">Pub. L. 115–48</ref> substituted “, national tests providing” for “and national tests providing” and inserted before period at end “, and national tests that evaluate prior learning and knowledge and provides an opportunity for course credit at an institution of higher learning”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239">Pub. L. 112–239</ref> substituted “any small business development center described in section 21 of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s648">15 U.S.C. 648</ref>), insofar as such center offers, sponsors, or cosponsors an entrepreneurship course, as that term is defined in section 3675(c)(2).” for “any of the following entities insofar as such entity offers, sponsors, or cosponsors an entrepreneurship course (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3675/c/2">section 3675(c)(2) of this title</ref>):</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) Any small business development center described in section 21 of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s648">15 U.S.C. 648</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) The National Veterans Business Development Corporation (established under section 33 of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s657c">15 U.S.C. 657c</ref>)).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (a)(3)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/109/163">Pub. L. 109–163</ref> substituted “Navy Reserve” for “Naval Reserve”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/108/454/s106/a">Pub. L. 108–454, § 106(a)</ref>, inserted at end “Such term also includes national tests for admission to institutions of higher learning or graduate schools (such as the Scholastic Aptitude Test (SAT), Law School Admission Test (LSAT), Graduate Record Exam (GRE), and Graduate Management Admission Test (GMAT)) and national tests providing an opportunity for course credit at institutions of higher learning (such as the Advanced Placement (AP) exam and College-Level Examination Program (CLEP)).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/108/454/s110/a">Pub. L. 108–454, § 110(a)</ref>, amended par. (5) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (5) read as follows: “A joint apprenticeship committee established pursuant to the Act of <date date="1937-08-16">August 16, 1937</date>, popularly known as the ‘National Apprenticeship Act’ (<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s50">29 U.S.C. 50</ref> et seq.).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/108/183/s305/c">Pub. L. 108–183, § 305(c)</ref>, inserted at end “Such term also includes any course, or combination of courses, offered by a qualified provider of entrepreneurship courses.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/108/183/s305/d">Pub. L. 108–183, § 305(d)</ref>, inserted at end “Such term also includes any qualified provider of entrepreneurship courses.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/108/183/s301/a">Pub. L. 108–183, § 301(a)</ref>, substituted “means any of the following:” and pars. (1) to (6) for “means any establishment providing apprentice or other training on the job, including those under the supervision of a college or university or any State department of education, or any State apprenticeship agency, or any State board or vocational education, or any joint apprenticeship committee, or the Bureau of Apprenticeship and Training established pursuant to the Act of <date date="1937-08-16">August 16, 1937</date>, popularly known as the ‘National Apprenticeship Act’ (<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s50">29 U.S.C. 50</ref> et seq.), or any agency of the Federal Government authorized to supervise such training.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/108/183/s305/e">Pub. L. 108–183, § 305(e)</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/107/14/s8/a/4/A/i">Pub. L. 107–14, § 8(a)(4)(A)(i)</ref>, struck out “or” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/107/14/s8/a/4/A/ii">Pub. L. 107–14, § 8(a)(4)(A)(ii)</ref>, substituted “subparagraph (B)” for “clause (B) of this paragraph”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/107/14/s8/a/4/B">Pub. L. 107–14, § 8(a)(4)(B)</ref>, substituted “subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1)” for “paragraph (1)(A) or (B)” and “180 days” for “one hundred and eighty days”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/107/14/s8/a/4/C">Pub. L. 107–14, § 8(a)(4)(C)</ref>, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12103/d">section 12103(d) of title 10</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s511/d">section 511(d) of title 10</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/107/103">Pub. L. 107–103</ref> inserted at end “Such term also includes any private entity (that meets such requirements as the Secretary may establish) that offers, either directly or under an agreement with another entity (that meets such requirements), a course or courses to fulfill requirements for the attainment of a license or certificate generally recognized as necessary to obtain, maintain, or advance in employment in a profession or vocation in a high technology occupation (as determined by the Secretary).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/107/14/s8/a/4/D">Pub. L. 107–14, § 8(a)(4)(D)</ref>, substituted “the Act of <date date="1937-08-16">August 16, 1937</date>, popularly known as the ‘National Apprenticeship Act’ (<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s50">29 U.S.C. 50</ref> et seq.),” for “chapter 4C of title 29,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/106/419">Pub. L. 106–419</ref> inserted at end “Such term also includes licensing or certification tests, the successful completion of which demonstrates an individual’s possession of the knowledge or skill required to enter into, maintain, or advance in employment in a predetermined and identified vocation or profession, provided such tests and the licensing or credentialing organizations or entities that offer such tests are approved by the Secretary in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3689">section 3689 of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/275">Pub. L. 104–275</ref> substituted “Such” for “For the period ending on <date date="1996-09-30">September 30, 1996</date>, such”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/446">Pub. L. 103–446</ref> inserted at end “For the period ending on <date date="1996-09-30">September 30, 1996</date>, such term includes any entity that provides training required for completion of any State-approved alternative teacher certification program (as determined by the Secretary).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—<ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/a">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1652">section 1652 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/c/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “3461(a)” for “1661(a)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/c/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “3675” for “1775”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/97/295">Pub. L. 97–295</ref> substituted “section 7(i)(1) of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s636/i/1">15 U.S.C. 636(i)(1)</ref>)” for “402(a) of the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2902/a">42 U.S.C. 2902(a)</ref>)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—<ref href="/us/pl/96/466/s801/a/1">Pub. L. 96–466, § 801(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “and chapter 36 of this title” after “chapter” in introductory text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/96/466/s801/a/2">Pub. L. 96–466, § 801(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “The” for “For the purposes of this chapter and chapter 36 of this title, the”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/96/466">Pub. L. 96–466</ref>, §§ 307(a), 801(a)(2), substituted “The” for “For the purposes of this chapter and chapter 36 of this title, the” and inserted provision including within “institution of higher learning” an educational institution which is not located in a State, which offers a course leading to a standard college degree, or the equivalent, and which is recognized as such by the secretary of education (or comparable official) of the country or other jurisdiction in which the institution is located.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/96/466/s801/a/2">Pub. L. 96–466, § 801(a)(2)</ref>, (3), substituted “The” for “For the purposes of this chapter and chapter 36 of this title, the” and “Secretary of Education” for “Commissioner of Education”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/94/502/s402/1">Pub. L. 94–502, § 402(1)</ref>, restricted the definition of an eligible veteran to a veteran who commenced his active duty requirement after <date date="1955-01-31">Jan. 31, 1955</date> but before <date date="1977-01-01">Jan. 1, 1977</date>, with the exception of a veteran who enlisted or was assigned to a reserve component before <date date="1977-01-01">Jan. 1, 1977</date> and commenced his active duty requirement within 12 months following <date date="1977-01-01">Jan. 1, 1977</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/94/502">Pub. L. 94–502</ref>, §§ 211(1), 402(2), substituted “such individual” for “he” and inserted “or (B)” after “paragraph (1)(A)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/94/502/s211/1">Pub. L. 94–502, § 211(1)</ref>, substituted “spouse” for “wife”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/94/502/s210/1">Pub. L. 94–502, § 210(1)</ref>, struck out “United States Code,” after “chapter 4C of title 29,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (f), (g). <ref href="/us/pl/94/502/s202">Pub. L. 94–502, § 202</ref>, added subsecs. (f) and (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/93/508">Pub. L. 93–508</ref> substituted “Coast Guard Reserve unless at some time subsequent to the completion of such period of active duty for training such individual served on active duty for a consecutive period of one year or more (not including any service as a cadet or midshipman at one of the service academies)” for “Coast Guard Reserve”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/91/584/s10/1">Pub. L. 91–584, § 10(1)</ref>, substituted “more than one hundred eighty days” for “at least two years”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/91/584/s10/2">Pub. L. 91–584, § 10(2)</ref>, expanded the definition of “program of education” to include unit course or subject, or combination of courses or subjects, pursued by eligible veterans at an educational institution, required by the Administrator of the Small Business Administration as a condition to obtaining financial assistance under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2902/a">section 2902(a) of title 42</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/91/219/s201/a">Pub. L. 91–219, § 201(a)</ref>, provided that a program of education may include more than one predetermined and identified educational, professional, or vocational objective if all the objectives pursued are generally recognized as being reasonably related to single career field.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/91/219/s201/b">Pub. L. 91–219, § 201(b)</ref>, included within the term “educational institution” any public or private “elementary” school, and substituted “other institution furnishing education for adults”, for “any other institution if it furnishes education at the secondary school level or above”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1967—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/90/77">Pub. L. 90–77</ref> added subsec. (e).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc36e8be6-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc36e8be7-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2017 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/115/48">Pub. L. 115–48</ref> applicable to a test taken on or after <date date="2018-08-01">Aug. 1, 2018</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/48/s108/d">section 108(d) of Pub. L. 115–48</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3315">section 3315 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc36e8be8-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2003 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/183/tIII/s301/b">Pub. L. 108–183, title III, § 301(b)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2658">117 Stat. 2658</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/183/tIII/s301/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect on the date that is six months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>] and shall apply to self-employment on-job training approved and pursued on or after that date.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/108/183/tIII/s305/f">Pub. L. 108–183, title III, § 305(f)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2661">117 Stat. 2661</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/183/tIII/s305/f">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 3471 and 3675 of this title] shall apply to courses approved by State approving agencies after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2003-12-16">Dec. 16, 2003</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc36e8be9-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2001 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/103/tI/s110/b">Pub. L. 107–103, title I, § 110(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/986">115 Stat. 986</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/103/tI/s110/b">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3501">section 3501 of this title</ref>] shall apply to enrollments in courses beginning on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc36e8bea-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2000 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/419">Pub. L. 106–419</ref> effective <date date="2001-03-01">Mar. 1, 2001</date>, and applicable with respect to licensing and certification tests approved by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs on or after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/106/419/s122/d">section 122(d) of Pub. L. 106–419</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3032">section 3032 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc36e8beb-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/466/tVIII/s802/c">Pub. L. 96–466, title VIII, § 802(c)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2218">94 Stat. 2218</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/466/tVIII/s802/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by title III [see Tables for classification] shall become effective on <date date="1980-10-01">October 1, 1980</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Paragraph (2) of section 1691(a) [probably means 1691(b), now 3491(b)] of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 311(2), shall not apply to any person receiving educational assistance under chapter 34 of title 38, United States Code, on <date date="1980-10-01">October 1, 1980</date>, for the pursuit of a program of education, as defined in section 1652(b) [now 3452(b)] of such title, in which such person is enrolled on that date, for as long as such person continuously thereafter is so enrolled and meets the requirements of eligibility for such assistance for pursuit of such program.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/96/466/tVIII/s802/h">Pub. L. 96–466, title VIII, § 802(h)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2219">94 Stat. 2219</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/466/tVIII/s802/h">“Section 801 [see Tables for classification] shall become effective on <date date="1980-10-01">October 1, 1980</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc36e8bec-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by sections 202, 210(1), and 211(1) of <ref href="/us/pl/94/502">Pub. L. 94–502</ref> effective <date date="1976-10-15">Oct. 15, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/502/s703/b">section 703(b) of Pub. L. 94–502</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3693">section 3693 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/502/s402">section 402 of Pub. L. 94–502</ref> effective <date date="1977-01-01">Jan. 1, 1977</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/502/s406">section 406 of Pub. L. 94–502</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3201">section 3201 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc36e8bed-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1974 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/508/s503">Section 503 of Pub. L. 93–508</ref> provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/508/s503">“Titles II and IV of this Act [see Tables for classification] shall become effective on the date of their enactment [<date date="1974-12-03">Dec. 3, 1974</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc36e8bee-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1967 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/90/77">Pub. L. 90–77</ref> effective first day of first calendar month which begins more than ten days after <date date="1967-08-31">Aug. 31, 1967</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/77/s405">section 405 of Pub. L. 90–77</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idc36e8bef-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
