<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc375b836-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501"><num value="3501">§ 3501.</num><heading> Definitions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc375b837-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> For the purposes of this chapter and chapter 36 of this title—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc375b838-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The term “eligible person” means any of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc375b839-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> A child of a person who, as a result of qualifying service—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc375b83a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> died of a service-connected disability; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc375b83b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> has a total disability permanent in nature resulting from a service-connected disability, or who died while a disability so evaluated was in existence.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc375b83c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The surviving spouse of any person who died of a service-connected disability sustained during a period of qualifying service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc375b83d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The spouse or child of any member of the Armed Forces serving on active duty who, at the time of application for benefits under this chapter is listed, pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t37/s556">section 556 of title 37</ref> and regulations issued thereunder, by the Secretary concerned in one or more of the following categories and has been so listed for a total of more than ninety days: (i) missing in action, (ii) captured in line of duty by a hostile force, or (iii) forcibly detained or interned in line of duty by a foreign government or power.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc375b83e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc375b83f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a/1/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The spouse of any person who has a total disability permanent in nature resulting from a service-connected disability sustained during a period of qualifying service, or (ii) the surviving spouse of a veteran who died while a disability so evaluated was in existence.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc375b840-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><chapeau> The spouse or child of a person who—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc375b841-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a/1/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> at the time of the Secretary’s determination under clause (ii), is a member of the Armed Forces who is hospitalized or receiving outpatient medical care, services, or treatment;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc375b842-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a/1/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the Secretary determines has a total disability permanent in nature incurred or aggravated in the line of duty in the active military, naval, air, or space service; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc375b843-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a/1/E/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> is likely to be discharged or released from such service for such disability.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc375b844-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “child” includes individuals who are married and individuals who are above the age of twenty-three years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc375b845-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “duty with the Armed Forces” as used in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3512">section 3512 of this title</ref> means (A) active duty, (B) active duty for training for a period of six or more consecutive months, or (C) active duty for training required by <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12103/d">section 12103(d) of title 10</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc375b846-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The term “guardian” includes a fiduciary legally appointed by a court of competent jurisdiction, or any other person who has been appointed by the Secretary under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s5502">section 5502 of this title</ref> to receive payment of benefits for the use and benefit of the eligible person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc375b847-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The term “program of education” means any curriculum or any combination of unit courses or subjects pursued at an educational institution which is generally accepted as necessary to fulfill the requirements for the attainment of a predetermined and identified educational, professional, or vocational objective. Such term also includes any preparatory course described in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3002/3/B">section 3002(3)(B) of this title</ref>. Such term also includes licensing or certification tests, the successful completion of which demonstrates an individual’s possession of the knowledge or skill required to enter into, maintain, or advance in employment in a predetermined and identified vocation or profession, provided such tests and the licensing or credentialing organizations or entities that offer such tests are approved by the Secretary in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3689">section 3689 of this title</ref>. Such term also includes national tests for admission to institutions of higher learning or graduate schools (such as the Scholastic Aptitude Test (SAT), Law School Admission Test (LSAT), Graduate Record Exam (GRE), and Graduate Management Admission Test (GMAT)) and national tests providing an opportunity for course credit at institutions of higher learning (such as the Advanced Placement (AP) exam and College-Level Examination Program (CLEP)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc375b848-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The term “educational institution” means any public or private secondary school, vocational school, correspondence school, business school, junior college, teachers’ college, college, normal school, professional school, university, or scientific or technical institution, or any other institution if it furnishes education at the secondary school level or above. Such term also includes any private entity (that meets such requirements as the Secretary may establish) that offers, either directly or under an agreement with another entity (that meets such requirements), a course or courses to fulfill requirements for the attainment of a license or certificate generally recognized as necessary to obtain, maintain, or advance in employment in a profession or vocation in a high technology occupation (as determined by the Secretary).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc375b849-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The term “special restorative training” means training furnished under subchapter V of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc375b84a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> The term “total disability permanent in nature” means any disability rated total for the purposes of disability compensation which is based upon an impairment reasonably certain to continue throughout the life of the disabled person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc375b84b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> The term “training establishment” means any establishment providing apprentice or other training on the job, including those under the supervision of a college or university or any State department of education, or any State apprenticeship agency, or any State board of vocational education, or any joint apprenticeship committee, or the Bureau of Apprenticeship and Training established pursuant to the Act of <date date="1937-08-16">August 16, 1937</date>, popularly known as the “National Apprenticeship Act” (<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s50">29 U.S.C. 50</ref> et seq.), or any agency of the Federal Government authorized to supervise such training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc375b84c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> The term “institution of higher learning” means a college, university, or similar institution, including a technical or business school, offering postsecondary level academic instruction that leads to an associate or higher degree if the school is empowered by the appropriate State education authority under State law to grant an associate or higher degree. When there is no State law to authorize the granting of a degree, the school may be recognized as an institution of higher learning if it is accredited for degree programs by a recognized accrediting agency. Such term shall also include a hospital offering educational programs at the postsecondary level without regard to whether the hospital grants a postsecondary degree. Such term shall also include an educational institution which is not located in a State, which offers a course leading to a standard college degree, or the equivalent, and which is recognized by the secretary of education (or comparable official) of the country or other jurisdiction in which the institution is located.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc375b84d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> The term “standard college degree” means an associate or higher degree awarded by (A) an institution of higher learning that is accredited as a collegiate institution by a recognized regional or national accrediting agency; or (B) an institution of higher learning that is a “candidate” for accreditation as that term is used by the regional or national accrediting agencies; or (C) an institution of higher learning upon completion of a course which is accredited by an agency recognized to accredit specialized degree-level programs. For the purpose of this section, the accrediting agency must be one recognized by the Secretary of Education under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3675">section 3675 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc375b84e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/a/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> The term “qualifying service” means service in the active military, naval, air, or space service after the beginning of the Spanish-American War that did not terminate under dishonorable conditions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc375b84f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> If an eligible person has attained the person’s majority and is under no known legal disability, all references in this chapter to “parent or guardian” shall refer to the eligible person.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc375b850-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> Any provision of this chapter which requires any action to be taken by or with respect to the parent or guardian of an eligible person who has not attained such person’s majority, or who, having attained such person’s majority, is under a legal disability, shall not apply when the Secretary determines that its application would not be in the best interest of the eligible person, would result in undue delay, or would not be administratively feasible. In such a case the Secretary, where necessary to protect the interest of the eligible person, may designate some other person (who may be the eligible person) as the person by or with respect to whom the action so required should be taken.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc375b851-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3501/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> No eligible person may be afforded educational assistance under this chapter unless such person was discharged or released after each period such person was on duty with the Armed Forces under conditions other than dishonorable, or while such person is on duty with the Armed Forces.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc375b852-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">(<ref href="/us/pl/85/857">Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1193">72 Stat. 1193</ref>, § 1701; <ref href="/us/pl/86/236/s1">Pub. L. 86–236, § 1</ref>, <date date="1959-09-08">Sept. 8, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/471">73 Stat. 471</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/785">Pub. L. 86–785</ref>, §§ 1–3, <date date="1960-09-14">Sept. 14, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/1023">74 Stat. 1023</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/361/s1">Pub. L. 88–361, § 1</ref>, <date date="1964-07-07">July 7, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/297">78 Stat. 297</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/222/s3">Pub. L. 89–222, § 3</ref>, <date date="1965-09-30">Sept. 30, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/896">79 Stat. 896</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/349/s1">Pub. L. 89–349, § 1</ref>, <date date="1965-11-08">Nov. 8, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1313">79 Stat. 1313</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/358/s4/j">Pub. L. 89–358, § 4(j)</ref>, <date date="1966-03-03">Mar. 3, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/24">80 Stat. 24</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/631/s2/b">Pub. L. 90–631, § 2(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="1968-10-23">Oct. 23, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1332">82 Stat. 1332</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/24/s9/a">Pub. L. 91–24, § 9(a)</ref>, <date date="1969-06-11">June 11, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/34">83 Stat. 34</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/584/s1">Pub. L. 91–584, § 1</ref>, <date date="1970-12-24">Dec. 24, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1575">84 Stat. 1575</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/540/tIII/s309">Pub. L. 92–540, title III, § 309</ref>, <date date="1972-10-24">Oct. 24, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1083">86 Stat. 1083</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/295/tIII/s302">Pub. L. 93–295, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1974-05-31">May 31, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/184">88 Stat. 184</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/502/tIII">Pub. L. 94–502, title III</ref>, §§ 302, 310(2)–(5), <date date="1976-10-15">Oct. 15, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2389">90 Stat. 2389</ref>, 2391; <ref href="/us/pl/96/466/tIII/s327/a">Pub. L. 96–466, title III, § 327(a)</ref>, title VIII, § 801(c), <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2197">94 Stat. 2197</ref>, 2216; <ref href="/us/pl/98/160/tVII/s702/12">Pub. L. 98–160, title VII, § 702(12)</ref>, <date date="1983-11-21">Nov. 21, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1009">97 Stat. 1009</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/237/tIV/s423/b/1/A">Pub. L. 101–237, title IV, § 423(b)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-18">Dec. 18, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2092">103 Stat. 2092</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/40/tIV/s402/d/1">Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/239">105 Stat. 239</ref>; renumbered § 3501 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/a">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/406">105 Stat. 406</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tXV/s1501/e/2/C">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(e)(2)(C)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/501">110 Stat. 501</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/419/tI">Pub. L. 106–419, title I</ref>, §§ 114(a), 122(a), <date date="2000-11-01">Nov. 1, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1833">114 Stat. 1833</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/103/tI">Pub. L. 107–103, title I</ref>, §§ 108(a), 110(a), <date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/985">115 Stat. 985</ref>, 986; <ref href="/us/pl/108/454/tI/s106/a">Pub. L. 108–454, title I, § 106(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3602">118 Stat. 3602</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/444/s3/a">Pub. L. 109–444, § 3(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2006-12-21">Dec. 21, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3305">120 Stat. 3305</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/tIII/s301/a">Pub. L. 109–461, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, (b)(1), title X, § 1006(b), <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3425">120 Stat. 3425</ref>, 3468; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tIX/s926/a/44">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 926(a)(44)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3830">134 Stat. 3830</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dU/tII/s215/a">Pub. L. 117–328, div. U, title II, § 215(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5455">136 Stat. 5455</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc375b853-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I84" topic="prospectiveAmendment" id="idc375b854-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered fontsize8 smallCaps">Amendment of Subsection (a)(6)</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dU/tII/s215">Pub. L. 117–328, div. U, title II, § 215</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5455">136 Stat. 5455</ref>, provided that effective on <date date="2026-08-01">August 1, 2026</date>, subsection (a)(6) of this section is amended:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(1) by striking “secondary school,”; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(2) by striking “secondary school level” and inserting “postsecondary school level”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">See 2022 Amendment note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc375b855-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc375b856-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Apprenticeship Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(9), is <ref href="/us/act/1937-08-16/ch663">act Aug. 16, 1937, ch. 663</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/50/664">50 Stat. 664</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 4C (§ 50 et seq.) of Title 29, Labor. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s50">section 50 of Title 29</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idc375b857-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Prior sections 3501 to 3505 were renumbered sections 6101 to 6105 of this title, respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc375b858-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328">Pub. L. 117–328</ref> struck out “secondary school,” after “ private” and substituted “postsecondary school level” for “secondary school level”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (a)(1)(E)(ii), (12). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> substituted “air, or space service” for “or air service”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—<ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s1006/b">Pub. L. 109–461, § 1006(b)</ref>, provided that as of the enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/109/461">Pub. L. 109–461</ref>, the amendments made by <ref href="/us/pl/109/444">Pub. L. 109–444</ref> were deemed for all purposes not to have taken effect and that <ref href="/us/pl/109/444">Pub. L. 109–444</ref> ceased to be in effect. See Amendment notes below and <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s1006/b">section 1006(b) of Pub. L. 109–461</ref>, set out as a Coordination of Provisions With <ref href="/us/pl/109/444">Pub. L. 109–444</ref> note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s301/a/1">Pub. L. 109–461, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, (8), substituted “means any of the following:” for “means—” in introductory provisions and struck out concluding provisions, which read as follows: “arising out of active military, naval, or air service after the beginning of the Spanish-American War, but only if such service did not terminate under dishonorable conditions. The standards and criteria for determining whether or not a disability arising out of such service is service connected shall be those applicable under chapter 11 of this title.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/444/s3/a/1">Pub. L. 109–444, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, (8), which substituted “means any of the following:” for “means—” in introductory provisions and struck out concluding provisions, was terminated by <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s1006/b">Pub. L. 109–461, § 1006(b)</ref>. See Amendment notes above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s301/a/2">Pub. L. 109–461, § 301(a)(2)</ref>, (3), substituted “A child of a person who, as a result of qualifying service” for “a child of a person who” in introductory provisions substituted “; or” for a comma in cl. (i) and a period for “, or” in cl. (ii), and struck out cl. (iii) which read as follows: “at the time of application for benefits under this chapter is a member of the Armed Forces serving on active duty listed, pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t37/s556">section 556 of title 37</ref> and regulations issued thereunder, by the Secretary concerned in one or more of the following categories and has been so listed for a total of more than ninety days: (A) missing in action, (B) captured in line of duty by a hostile force, or (C) forcibly detained or interned in line of duty by a foreign government or power.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/444/s3/a/2">Pub. L. 109–444, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, (3), which substituted “A child of a person who, as a result of qualifying service” for “a child of a person who” in introductory provisions substituted “; or” for a comma in cl. (i) and a period for “, or” in cl. (ii), and struck out cl. (iii), was terminated by <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s1006/b">Pub. L. 109–461, § 1006(b)</ref>. See Amendment notes above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s301/a/2">Pub. L. 109–461, § 301(a)(2)</ref>, (4), substituted “The surviving spouse of any person who died of a service-connected disability sustained during a period of qualifying service.” for “the surviving spouse of any person who died of a service-connected disability,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/444/s3/a/2">Pub. L. 109–444, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, (4), which substituted “The surviving spouse of any person who died of a service-connected disability sustained during a period of qualifying service.” for “the surviving spouse of any person who died of a service-connected disability,”, was terminated by <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s1006/b">Pub. L. 109–461, § 1006(b)</ref>. See Amendment notes above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s301/a/2">Pub. L. 109–461, § 301(a)(2)</ref>, (5), substituted “The spouse or child” for “the spouse” and a period at end for “, or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/444/s3/a/2">Pub. L. 109–444, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, (5), which substituted “The spouse or child” for “the spouse” and a period at end for “, or”, was terminated by <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s1006/b">Pub. L. 109–461, § 1006(b)</ref>. See Amendment notes above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s301/a/2">Pub. L. 109–461, § 301(a)(2)</ref>, (6), substituted “The spouse” for “the spouse”, inserted “sustained during a period of qualifying service” before comma in cl. (i), and substituted period for comma at end of cl. (ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/444/s3/a/2">Pub. L. 109–444, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, (6), which substituted “The spouse” for “the spouse”, inserted “sustained during a period of qualifying service” before comma in cl. (i), and substituted period for comma at end of cl. (ii), was terminated by <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s1006/b">Pub. L. 109–461, § 1006(b)</ref>. See Amendment notes above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s301/a/7">Pub. L. 109–461, § 301(a)(7)</ref>, added subpar. (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/444/s3/a/7">Pub. L. 109–444, § 3(a)(7)</ref>, which added subpar. (E) identical to that added by <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s301/a/7">Pub. L. 109–461, § 301(a)(7)</ref>, was terminated by <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s1006/b">Pub. L. 109–461, § 1006(b)</ref>. See Amendment notes above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(12). <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s301/b/1">Pub. L. 109–461, § 301(b)(1)</ref>, added par. (12).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/444/s3/b/1">Pub. L. 109–444, § 3(b)(1)</ref>, which added par. (12) identical to that added by <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s301/b/1">Pub. L. 109–461, § 301(b)(1)</ref>, was terminated by <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/s1006/b">Pub. L. 109–461, § 1006(b)</ref>. See Amendment notes above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/108/454">Pub. L. 108–454</ref> inserted at end “Such term also includes national tests for admission to institutions of higher learning or graduate schools (such as the Scholastic Aptitude Test (SAT), Law School Admission Test (LSAT), Graduate Record Exam (GRE), and Graduate Management Admission Test (GMAT)) and national tests providing an opportunity for course credit at institutions of higher learning (such as the Advanced Placement (AP) exam and College-Level Examination Program (CLEP)).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (a)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/107/103/s108/a">Pub. L. 107–103, § 108(a)</ref>, inserted cl. (i) designation after “(D)” and cl. (ii) designation after “or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/107/103/s110/a">Pub. L. 107–103, § 110(a)</ref>, inserted at end “Such term also includes any private entity (that meets such requirements as the Secretary may establish) that offers, either directly or under an agreement with another entity (that meets such requirements), a course or courses to fulfill requirements for the attainment of a license or certificate generally recognized as necessary to obtain, maintain, or advance in employment in a profession or vocation in a high technology occupation (as determined by the Secretary).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/106/419/s122/a">Pub. L. 106–419, § 122(a)</ref>, inserted at end “Such term also includes licensing or certification tests, the successful completion of which demonstrates an individual’s possession of the knowledge or skill required to enter into, maintain, or advance in employment in a predetermined and identified vocation or profession, provided such tests and the licensing or credentialing organizations or entities that offer such tests are approved by the Secretary in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3689">section 3689 of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/419/s114/a">Pub. L. 106–419, § 114(a)</ref>, inserted at end “Such term also includes any preparatory course described in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3002/3/B">section 3002(3)(B) of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(3)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106">Pub. L. 104–106</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12103/d">section 12103(d) of title 10</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s511/d">section 511(d) of title 10</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—<ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/a">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a)</ref>, renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1701">section 1701 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/c/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “3512” for “1712”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/102/40">Pub. L. 102–40</ref> substituted “5502” for “3202”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s5/c/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “3675” for “1775”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsecs. (a)(4), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/101/237">Pub. L. 101–237</ref> substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (a)(1)(A)(iii), (C). <ref href="/us/pl/98/160/s702/12/A">Pub. L. 98–160, § 702(12)(A)</ref>, struck out “, United States Code,” after “title 37” and inserted a comma after “regulations issued thereunder”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/98/160/s702/12/B">Pub. L. 98–160, § 702(12)(B)</ref>, substituted “the Act of <date date="1937-08-16">August 16, 1937</date>, popularly known as the ‘National Apprenticeship Act’ (<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s50">29 U.S.C. 50</ref> et seq.)” for “chapter 4C of title 29”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/96/466/s801/c/1">Pub. L. 96–466, § 801(c)(1)</ref>, inserted “and chapter 36 of this title” after “chapter” in introductory text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/96/466/s801/c/2">Pub. L. 96–466, § 801(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “The” for “For the purposes of this chapter and chapter 36 of this title, the”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/96/466">Pub. L. 96–466</ref>, §§ 327(a), 801(c)(2), substituted “The” for “For the purposes of this chapter and chapter 36 of this title, the” and inserted provision including within the term “institution of higher learning” an educational institution which is not located in a State, which offers a course leading to a standard college degree, or the equivalent, and which is recognized as such by the secretary of education (or comparable official) of the country or other jurisdiction in which the institution is located.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/96/466/s801/c/2">Pub. L. 96–466, § 801(c)(2)</ref>, (3), substituted “The” for “For the purposes of this chapter and chapter 36 of this title, the” and “Secretary of Education” for “Commissioner of Education”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/94/502/s310/2">Pub. L. 94–502, § 310(2)</ref>, substituted “surviving spouse” for “widow” and “spouse” for “wife” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(10), (11). <ref href="/us/pl/94/502/s302">Pub. L. 94–502, § 302</ref>, added pars. (10), (11).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/94/502/s310/3">Pub. L. 94–502, § 310(3)</ref>, substituted “the person’s” for “his” and “the eligible person” for “the eligible person himself”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/94/502/s310/4">Pub. L. 94–502, § 310(4)</ref>, substituted “such person’s” for “his” and “be the eligible person” for “be the eligible person himself” in the parenthetical phrase.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/94/502/s310/5">Pub. L. 94–502, § 310(5)</ref>, substituted “such person” for “he” in three places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/93/295">Pub. L. 93–295</ref> substituted “any other person who has been appointed by the Administrator under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3202">section 3202 of this title</ref> to receive payment of benefits for the use and benefit of the eligible person” for “any person who is determined by the Administrator in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3202">section 3202 of this title</ref> to be otherwise legally vested with the care of the eligible person”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1972—Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/92/540/s309/1">Pub. L. 92–540, § 309(1)</ref>, inserted reference to correspondence school within the definition of “educational institution”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/92/540/s309/2">Pub. L. 92–540, § 309(2)</ref>, added par. (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/91/584/s1/3">Pub. L. 91–584, § 1(3)</ref>, added cl. (iii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(C), (D). <ref href="/us/pl/91/584/s1/5">Pub. L. 91–584, § 1(5)</ref>, (6), added subpar. (C) and redesignated former subpar. (C) as (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1969—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/91/24">Pub. L. 91–24</ref> substituted “the age of twenty-three years” for “the age of twenty-one years”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/90/631/s2/b">Pub. L. 90–631, § 2(b)</ref>, extended the definition of “eligible person” to include the widow of any person who died of a service-connected disability, or the wife of any person who has a total disability permanent in nature resulting from a service-connected disability, or the widow of a veteran who died while a disability so evaluated was in existence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/90/631/s2/c">Pub. L. 90–631, § 2(c)</ref>, substituted provisions requiring that any eligible person seeking educational assistance under this chapter to have been discharged or released after each period he was on duty with the armed forces under conditions other than dishonorable, or while he is on duty with the armed forces, for provisions setting forth the purposes of educational assistance programs established under this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/89/358/s4/j/3">Pub. L. 89–358, § 4(j)(3)</ref>, struck out “and prior to the end of the induction period” after “Spanish-American War”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/89/358/s4/j/1">Pub. L. 89–358, § 4(j)(1)</ref>, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s511/d">section 511(d) of title 10</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1013/c/1">section 1013(c)(1) of title 50</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(8) to (10). <ref href="/us/pl/89/358/s4/j/2">Pub. L. 89–358, § 4(j)(2)</ref>, struck out par. (8) including the Canal Zone in the term “State” (now incorporated in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s101/20">section 101(20) of this title</ref>) and par. (9) defining “induction period” and redesignated par. (10) as (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/89/358/s4/j/3">Pub. L. 89–358, § 4(j)(3)</ref>, struck out “and prior to the end of the induction period” after “Spanish-American War”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/89/349/s1/a">Pub. L. 89–349, § 1(a)</ref>, (b), generally amended par. (1) and, among other changes, substituted “after the beginning of the Spanish-American War and prior to the end of the induction period” for “during the Spanish-American War, World War I, World War II, the Korean conflict, or the induction period” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/89/222">Pub. L. 89–222</ref> substituted “such service” the second time it appears for “service during the Spanish-American War, World War I, World War II, or the Korean conflict” and struck out provisions which prescribed the applicable standards and criteria for determining whether or not a disability arising out of service during the induction period is service-connected.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/89/349/s1/c">Pub. L. 89–349, § 1(c)</ref>, struck out provisions which included the period beginning <date date="1940-09-16">Sept. 16, 1940</date>, and ending <date date="1941-12-06">Dec. 6, 1941</date>, and the period beginning <date date="1947-01-01">Jan. 1, 1947</date>, and ending <date date="1950-06-26">June 26, 1950</date>, within the term “induction period”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/89/349/s1/d">Pub. L. 89–349, § 1(d)</ref>, substituted “after the beginning of the Spanish-American War and prior to the end of the induction period” for “during the Spanish-American War, World War I, World War II, the Korean conflict, or the induction period”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1964—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/88/361/s1/a">Pub. L. 88–361, § 1(a)</ref>, included the child of a person who has a service-connected disability, or who died while such disability existed.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/88/361/s1/b">Pub. L. 88–361, § 1(b)</ref>, added par. (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/88/361/s1/c">Pub. L. 88–361, § 1(c)</ref>, inserted “disability or” before “death” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1960—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/86/785/s1">Pub. L. 86–785, § 1</ref>, substituted “the Korean conflict, or the induction period” for “or the Korean conflict”, inserted “arising out of service during the Spanish-American War, World War I, World War II, or the Korean conflict” after “whether or not a disability”, and inserted the sentence relating to the criteria for determining whether a disability arising out of service during the induction period is service connected.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/86/785/s2">Pub. L. 86–785, § 2</ref>, added par. (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/86/785/s3">Pub. L. 86–785, § 3</ref>, substituted “the Korean conflict, or the induction period” for “or the Korean conflict”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1959—Subsecs. (a)(1), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/86/236">Pub. L. 86–236</ref> inserted reference to Spanish-American War.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc375b859-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc375b85a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2022 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dU/tII/s215/b">Pub. L. 117–328, div. U, title II, § 215(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5455">136 Stat. 5455</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/328/dU/tII/s215/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect on <date date="2026-08-01">August 1, 2026</date>, and shall apply with respect to an academic period that begins on or after that date.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc375b85b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2006 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/461/tIII/s301/d">Pub. L. 109–461, title III, § 301(d)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3427">120 Stat. 3427</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/461/tIII/s301/d">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 3511, 3512, 3540, 3563, 3686, and 5113 of this title] shall apply with respect to a payment of educational assistance for a course of education pursued after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/444/s3/d">Pub. L. 109–444, § 3(d)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-21">Dec. 21, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3307">120 Stat. 3307</ref>, which provided that amendments made by <ref href="/us/pl/109/444/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 109–444</ref> would apply with respect to a payment of educational assistance for a course of education pursued after <date date="2006-12-21">Dec. 21, 2006</date>, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/tX/s1006/b">Pub. L. 109–461, title X, § 1006(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3468">120 Stat. 3468</ref>, set out as a Coordination of Provisions With <ref href="/us/pl/109/444">Pub. L. 109–444</ref> note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc375b85c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2001 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/103/s110/a">section 110(a) of Pub. L. 107–103</ref> applicable to enrollments in courses beginning on or after <date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/103/s110/b">section 110(b) of Pub. L. 107–103</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3452">section 3452 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc375b85d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2000 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/419/s122/a">section 122(a) of Pub. L. 106–419</ref> effective <date date="2001-03-01">Mar. 1, 2001</date>, and applicable with respect to licensing and certification tests approved by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs on or after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/106/419/s122/d">section 122(d) of Pub. L. 106–419</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3032">section 3032 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc375b85e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/106">Pub. L. 104–106</ref> effective as if included in the Reserve Officer Personnel Management Act, title XVI of <ref href="/us/pl/103/337">Pub. L. 103–337</ref>, as enacted on <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1501/f/3">section 1501(f)(3) of Pub. L. 104–106</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s113">section 113 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc375b85f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/466">Pub. L. 96–466</ref> effective <date date="1980-10-01">Oct. 1, 1980</date>, see section 802(c), (h) of <ref href="/us/pl/96/466">Pub. L. 96–466</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3452">section 3452 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc375b860-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/502">Pub. L. 94–502</ref> effective <date date="1976-10-15">Oct. 15, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/502/s703/b">section 703(b) of Pub. L. 94–502</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3693">section 3693 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc375b861-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1974 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/93/295">Pub. L. 93–295</ref> effective first day of second calendar month following <date date="1974-05-31">May 31, 1974</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/295/s401">section 401 of Pub. L. 93–295</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1114">section 1114 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc375b862-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1968 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/90/631">Pub. L. 90–631</ref> effective first day of second calendar month which begins after <date date="1968-10-23">Oct. 23, 1968</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/631/s6/a">section 6(a) of Pub. L. 90–631</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3500">section 3500 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc375b863-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Eligible Person</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/86/785/s5">Pub. L. 86–785, § 5</ref>, <date date="1960-09-14">Sept. 14, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/1024">74 Stat. 1024</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/87/815/s2/b">Pub. L. 87–815, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-15">Oct. 15, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/927">76 Stat. 927</ref>, which contained a savings clause which granted five years of educational training to certain children of veterans dying of disabilities incurred subsequent to the Korean War, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/91/24/s14/c">Pub. L. 91–24, § 14(c)</ref>, <date date="1969-06-11">June 11, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/35">83 Stat. 35</ref>, effective <date date="1969-06-11">June 11, 1969</date>, except as to any indebtedness which may be due the Government as the result of any benefits granted thereunder.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc3782964-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Children of Spanish-American War Veterans</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Period of eligibility for educational assistance of children of Spanish-American War Veterans, see <ref href="/us/pl/86/236/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 86–236</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3512">section 3512 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc3782965-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Eligibility Period</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Termination of eligibility period for a wife or widow, or an eligible person eight years from <date date="1972-10-24">Oct. 24, 1972</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/92/540/s604">section 604 of Pub. L. 92–540</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3512">section 3512 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The period referred to in section 1712 [now 3512] of this title as ending five years from <date date="1965-11-08">Nov. 8, 1965</date>, in the case of any individual who is an “eligible person” within the meaning of subsec. (a)(1) of this section solely by virtue of the amendment made by <ref href="/us/pl/89/349/s1">section 1 of Pub. L. 89–349</ref> to this section, and who is above the age of seventeen years and below the age of twenty-three years on <date date="1965-11-08">Nov. 8, 1965</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/89/349/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 89–349</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3512">section 3512 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
