<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc39bdde1-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3697B"><num value="3697B">§ 3697B.</num><heading> On-campus educational and vocational counseling</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39bdde2-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3697B/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall provide educational and vocational counseling services for individuals described in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3697A/b">section 3697A(b) of this title</ref> at locations on the campuses of institutions of higher learning selected by the Secretary. Such counseling services shall be provided by employees of the Department who provide such services under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3697A">section 3697A of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39bdde3-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3697B/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Selection of Locations</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39bdde4-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3697B/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> To be selected by the Secretary under this section, an institution of higher learning shall provide an appropriate space on the campus of the institution where counseling services can be provided under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39bdde5-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3697B/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In selecting locations for the provision of counseling services under this section, the Secretary shall seek to select locations where the maximum number of veterans would have access to such services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39bdde6-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3697B/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, and each year thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the counseling services provided under this section. Such report shall include, for the year covered by the report—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39bdde7-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3697B/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the average ratio of counselors providing such services to individuals who received such services at each location where such services were provided;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39bdde8-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3697B/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a description of such services provided;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39bdde9-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3697B/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the recommendations of the Secretary for improving the provision of such services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39bddea-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3697B/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> any other matters the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc39bddeb-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/115/48/tIII/s307/a">Pub. L. 115–48, title III, § 307(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-08-16">Aug. 16, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/993">131 Stat. 993</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc39bddec-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc39bdded-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc39bddee-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of the enactment of this section, referred to in subsec. (c), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/115/48">Pub. L. 115–48</ref>, which was approved <date date="2017-08-16">Aug. 16, 2017</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc39bddef-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc39bddf0-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Native VetSuccess at Tribal Colleges and Universities Pilot Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dU/tII/s211">Pub. L. 117–328, div. U, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5451">136 Stat. 5451</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/328/dU/tII/s211">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Short Title</inline>.—</heading><content>This section [enacting this note] may be cited as the ‘Native VetSuccess at Tribal Colleges and Universities Pilot Program Act’.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pilot Program.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>], the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall commence carrying out a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of expanding the VetSuccess on Campus program to additional Tribal colleges and universities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading><content>The pilot program carried out under paragraph (1) shall be known as the ‘Native VetSuccess at Tribal Colleges and Universities Pilot Program’.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Duration</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program required by subsection (b)(1) during the five-year period beginning on the date of the commencement of the pilot program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Parameters</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Under the pilot program required by subsection (b)(1) the Secretary shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> identify three regional Native VetSuccess service areas consisting of at least two participating Tribal colleges or universities that do not already have a VetSuccess program, counselor, or outreach coordinator; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> assign to each regional Native VetSuccess service area a VetSuccess on Campus counselor and a full-time Vet Center outreach coordinator, both of whom shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> be based on one or more of the participating Tribal colleges or universities in the service area; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> provide for eligible students at such participating colleges and universities with all services for which such students would be eligible under the VetSuccess on Campus program of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible Students</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of the pilot program, an eligible student is a student who is a veteran, member of the Armed Forces, or dependent of a veteran or member of the Armed Forces who is eligible for any service or benefit under the VetSuccess on Campus program of the Department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation Requirement</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In developing the pilot program required by subsection (b)(1), the Secretary shall, acting through the Veteran Readiness and Employment Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs and in coordination with the Office of Tribal Government Relations of the Department, consult with Indian Tribes, and Tribal organizations, and seek comment from the Advisory Committee on Tribal and Indian Affairs of the Department, and veterans service organizations regarding each of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The design of the pilot program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> The process for selection of the three regional Native VetSuccess service areas and participating Tribal colleges and universities, taking into consideration—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the number of eligible students enrolled in the college or university and in the regional service area;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the capacity of the colleges and universities in the regional service area to accommodate a full-time VetSuccess on Campus counselor and a full-time Vet Center outreach coordinator;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> barriers in specific regional service areas that prevent native veterans’ access to benefits and services under the laws administered by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> any other factor that the Secretary, in consultation with Indian Tribes and Tribal organizations, and after considering input from veterans service organizations and the Advisory Committee on Tribal and Indian Affairs identifies as relevant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The most effective way to provide culturally competent outreach and services to eligible students at Tribal colleges and universities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Outreach to Colleges and Universities</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall provide notice of the pilot program to all Tribal colleges and universities and encourage all Tribal colleges and universities to coordinate with each other to create regional service areas to participate in the pilot program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefings and Reports.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation briefing</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>], the Secretary shall provide the appropriate committees of Congress a briefing on—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the design, structure, and objectives of the pilot program required by subsection (b)(1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the three regional Native Vet Success service areas and the Tribal colleges and universities selected for participation in the pilot program and the reason for the selection of such service areas and such colleges and universities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than four years after the date on which the Secretary commences the pilot program under subsection (b)(1), the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the pilot program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall include each of the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> The number of eligible students provided services through the pilot program.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> The types of services that eligible students received through the pilot program.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> The graduation rate of eligible students who received services through the pilot program and graduation rate of eligible students who did not receive services through the pilot program.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> The rate of employment within one year of graduation for eligible students who received services through the pilot program.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="v">“(v)</num><content> Feedback from each Tribal college or university that participated in the pilot program, including on the regional nature of the program.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="vi">“(vi)</num><content> Analysis of the feasibility of expanding a regionally based Native VetSuccess at Tribal Colleges and Universities Program, including an explanation of the challenges of such a model due to issues with distance, communication, and coordination, and to the level of unmet services.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="vii">“(vii)</num><content> A detailed proposal regarding a long-term extension of the pilot program, including a budget, unless the Secretary determines that such an extension is not appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate committee of congress</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘appropriate committees of Congress’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Culturally competent</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘culturally competent’ means considerate of the unique values, customs, traditions, cultures, and languages of Native American veterans.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Tribal college or university</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Tribal college or university’ has the meaning given the term ‘Tribal College or University’ under section 316 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Tribal organization</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Tribal organization’ has the meaning given that term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</ref>).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
