<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc39e4f8d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C"><num value="3699C">§ 3699C.</num><heading> High technology program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4f8e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4f8f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall carry out a program under which the Secretary provides covered individuals with the opportunity to enroll in high technology programs of education that the Secretary determines provide training or skills sought by employers in a relevant field or industry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4f90-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Not more than 4,000 covered individuals may participate in the program under this section in any fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4f91-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Amount of Assistance</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4f92-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall provide, to each covered individual who pursues a high technology program of education under this section, educational assistance in amounts equal to the amounts provided under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3313/c/1">section 3313(c)(1) of this title</ref>, including, except as provided in paragraph (3), with respect to the housing stipend described in that section and in accordance with the treatment of programs that are distance learning and programs that are less than half-time.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4f93-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall provide such amounts of educational assistance to a covered individual for each of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4f94-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A high technology program of education.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4f95-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> A second such program if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc39e4f96-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/b/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the second such program begins at least 18 months after the covered individual graduates from the first such program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc39e4f97-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/b/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the covered individual uses educational assistance under chapter 33 of this title to pursue the second such program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4f98-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> No covered individual may receive a housing stipend under this subsection for any month if such individual is in receipt of a housing stipend under chapter 33 of this title for that month.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4f99-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contracts</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4f9a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> For purposes of carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall seek to enter into contracts with any number of qualified providers of high technology programs of education for the provision of such programs to covered individuals. Each such contract shall provide for the conditions under which the Secretary may terminate the contract with the provider and the procedures for providing for the graduation of students who were enrolled in a program provided by such provider in the case of such a termination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4f9b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> A contract under this subsection shall provide that the Secretary shall pay to a provider—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4f9c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> upon the enrollment of a covered individual in the program, 25 percent of the cost of the tuition and other fees for the program of education for the individual;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4f9d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> upon graduation of the individual from the program, 25 percent of such cost; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4f9e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> 50 percent of such cost upon—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc39e4f9f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> the successful employment of the covered individual for a period—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc39e4fa0-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/2/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> of 180 days in the field of study of the program; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc39e4fa1-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/2/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> that begins not later than 180 days following graduation of the covered individual from the program;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc39e4fa2-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the employment of the individual by the provider for a period of one year; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc39e4fa3-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/2/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the enrollment of the individual in a program of education to continue education in such field of study.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4fa4-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this section, a provider of a high technology program of education is qualified if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc39e4fa5-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the provider employs instructors whom the Secretary determines are experts in their respective fields in accordance with paragraph (5);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc39e4fa6-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the provider has successfully provided the high technology program for at least one year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc39e4fa7-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the provider does not charge tuition and fees to a covered individual who receives assistance under this section to pursue such program that are higher than the tuition and fees charged by such provider to another individual; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc39e4fa8-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the provider meets the approval criteria developed by the Secretary under paragraph (4).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4fa9-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4faa-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary shall prescribe criteria for approving providers of a high technology program of education under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4fab-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In developing such criteria, the Secretary may consult with State approving agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4fac-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Such criteria are not required to meet the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3672">section 3672 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4fad-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Such criteria shall include the job placement rate, in the field of study of a program of education, of covered individuals who complete such program of education.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4fae-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall determine whether instructors are experts under paragraph (3)(A) based on evidence furnished to the Secretary by the provider regarding the ability of the instructors to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc39e4faf-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> identify professions in need of new employees to hire, tailor the programs to meet market needs, and identify the employers likely to hire graduates;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc39e4fb0-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> effectively teach the skills offered to covered individuals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc39e4fb1-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> provide relevant industry experience in the fields of programs offered to incoming covered individuals; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc39e4fb2-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> demonstrate relevant industry experience in such fields of programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4fb3-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> In entering into contracts under this subsection, the Secretary shall give preference to a provider of a high technology program of education—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc39e4fb4-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> from which at least 70 percent of graduates find full-time employment in the field of study of the program during the 180-day period beginning on the date the student graduates from the program; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc39e4fb5-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/c/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> that offers tuition reimbursement for any student who graduates from such a program and does not find employment described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4fb6-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effect on Other Entitlement</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4fb7-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If a covered individual enrolled in a high technology program of education under this section has remaining entitlement to educational assistance under chapter 30, 32, 33, 34, or 35 of this title, such entitlement shall be charged at the rate of one month of such entitlement for each month of educational assistance provided under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4fb8-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If a covered individual enrolled in a high technology program of education under this section does not have remaining entitlement to educational assistance under chapter 30, 32, 33, 34, or 35 of this title, any educational assistance provided to such individual under this section shall be provided in addition to the entitlement that the individual has used.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4fb9-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary may not consider enrollment in a high technology program of education under this section to be assistance under a provision of law referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3695">section 3695 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4fba-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4fbb-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/d/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> An application for enrollment in a high technology program of education under this section shall include notice of the requirements relating to use of entitlement under paragraphs (1) and (2), including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4fbc-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/d/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> in the case of the enrollment of an individual referred to under paragraph (1), the amount of entitlement that is typically charged for such enrollment;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4fbd-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/d/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> an identification of any methods that may be available for minimizing the amount of entitlement required for such enrollment; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4fbe-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/d/4/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> an element requiring applicants to acknowledge receipt of the notice under this subparagraph.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4fbf-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/d/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> If the Secretary approves the enrollment of a covered individual in a high technology program of education under this section, the Secretary shall deliver electronically to the individual an award letter that provides notice of such approval and includes specific information describing how paragraphs (1) and (2) will be applied to the individual if the individual chooses to enroll in the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4fc0-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements for Educational Institutions</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4fc1-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall not approve the enrollment of any covered individual, not already enrolled, in any high technology programs of education under this section for any period during which the Secretary finds that more than 85 percent of the students enrolled in the program are having all or part of their tuition, fees, or other charges paid to or for them by the educational institution or by the Department of Veterans Affairs under this title or under chapter 1606 or 1607 of title 10, except with respect to tuition, fees, or other charges that are paid under a payment plan at an educational institution that the Secretary determines has a history of offering payment plans that are completed not later than 180 days after the end of the applicable term, quarter, or semester.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4fc2-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary may waive a requirement of paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines, pursuant to regulations which the Secretary shall prescribe, such waiver to be in the interest of the covered individual and the Federal Government. Not later than 30 days after the Secretary waives such a requirement, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report regarding such waiver.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4fc3-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4fc4-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4fc5-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/e/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The Secretary shall establish and maintain a process by which an educational institution may request a review of a determination that the educational institution does not meet the requirements of paragraph (1).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4fc6-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/e/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The Secretary may consult with a State approving agency regarding such process or such a review.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4fc7-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/e/3/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Not later than 180 days after the Secretary establishes or revises a process under this subparagraph, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report regarding such process.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4fc8-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> An educational institution that requests a review under subparagraph (A)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4fc9-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/e/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> shall request the review not later than 30 days after the start of the term, quarter, or semester for which the determination described in subparagraph (A) applies; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4fca-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/e/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> may include any information that the educational institution believes the Department should have taken into account when making the determination, including with respect to any mitigating circumstances.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4fcb-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Reports</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, and annually thereafter until the termination date specified in subsection (i), the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report on the operation of program <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002084">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002084"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be preceded by “the”.</note> under this section during the year covered by the report. Each such report shall include each of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4fcc-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The number of covered individuals enrolled in the program, disaggregated by type of educational institution, during the year covered by the report.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4fcd-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The number of covered individuals who completed a high technology program of education under the program during the year covered by the report.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4fce-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The average employment rate of covered individuals who completed such a program of education during such year, as of 180 days after the date of completion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4fcf-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The average length of time between the completion of such a program of education and employment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4fd0-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/f/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The total number of covered individuals who completed a program of education under the program and who, as of the date of the submission of the report, are employed in a position related to technology.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4fd1-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/f/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The average salary of a covered individual who completed a program of education under the program and who is employed in a position related to technology, in various geographic areas determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4fd2-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/f/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The average salary of all individuals employed in positions related to technology in the geographic areas determined under subparagraph (F), and the difference, if any, between such average salary and the average salary of a covered individual who completed a program of education under the program and who is employed in a position related to technology.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4fd3-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/f/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> The number of covered individuals who completed a program of education under the program and who subsequently enrolled in a second program of education under the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4fd4-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Collection of Information; Consultation</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4fd5-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall develop practices to use to collect information about covered individuals and providers of high technology programs of education.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4fd6-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> For the purpose of carrying out program <sup>1</sup> under this section, the Secretary may consult with providers of high technology programs of education and may establish an advisory group made up of representatives of such providers, private employers in the technology field, and other relevant groups or entities, as the Secretary determines necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc39e4fd7-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4fd8-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The term “covered individual” means any of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc39e4fd9-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> A veteran whom the Secretary determines—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc39e4fda-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/h/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> served an aggregate of at least 36 months on active duty in the Armed Forces (including service on active duty in entry level and skill training) and was discharged or released therefrom under conditions other than dishonorable; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc39e4fdb-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/h/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> has not attained the age of 62.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc39e4fdc-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A member of the Armed Forces that the Secretary determines will become a veteran described in subparagraph (A) fewer than 180 days after the date of such determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc39e4fdd-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The term “high technology program of education” means a program of education—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc39e4fde-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> offered by a public or private educational institution;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc39e4fdf-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if offered by an institution of higher learning, that is provided directly by such institution rather than by an entity other than such institution under a contract or other agreement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc39e4fe0-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/h/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> that does not lead to a degree;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc39e4fe1-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/h/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> that has a term of not less than six and not more than 28 weeks; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc39e4fe2-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/h/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><chapeau> that provides instruction in computer programming, computer software, media application, data processing, or information sciences.</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc39e4fe3-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s3699C/h/2/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may not provide educational assistance under this section for a high technology program of education that begins after <date date="2027-09-30">September 30, 2027</date>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc39e4fe4-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/118/210/tII/s212/a/1">Pub. L. 118–210, title II, § 212(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2025-01-02">Jan. 2, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2767">138 Stat. 2767</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc39e4fe5-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc39e4fe6-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc39e4fe7-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of enactment of this section, referred to in subsec. (f), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/118/210">Pub. L. 118–210</ref>, which was approved <date date="2025-01-02">Jan. 2, 2025</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
