<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc3c474fe-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303"><num value="4303">§ 4303.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this chapter—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c474ff-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “Attorney General” means the Attorney General of the United States or any person designated by the Attorney General to carry out a responsibility of the Attorney General under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c47500-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “benefit”, “benefit of employment”, or “rights and benefits” means the terms, conditions, or privileges of employment, including any advantage, profit, privilege, gain, status, account, or interest (including wages or salary for work performed) that accrues by reason of an employment contract or agreement or an employer policy, plan, or practice and includes rights and benefits under a pension plan, a health plan, an employee stock ownership plan, insurance coverage and awards, bonuses, severance pay, supplemental unemployment benefits, vacations, and the opportunity to select work hours or location of employment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c47501-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “employee” means any person employed by an employer. Such term includes any person who is a citizen, national, or permanent resident alien of the United States employed in a workplace in a foreign country by an employer that is an entity incorporated or otherwise organized in the United States or that is controlled by an entity organized in the United States, within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s4319/c">section 4319(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c47502-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c47503-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C), the term “employer” means any person, institution, organization, or other entity that pays salary or wages for work performed or that has control over employment opportunities, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c47504-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a person, institution, organization, or other entity to whom the employer has delegated the performance of employment-related responsibilities;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c47505-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the Federal Government;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c47506-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/4/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> a State;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c47507-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/4/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> any successor in interest to a person, institution, organization, or other entity referred to in this subparagraph; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c47508-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/4/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> a person, institution, organization, or other entity that has denied initial employment in violation of section 4311.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c47509-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In the case of a National Guard technician employed under <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s709">section 709 of title 32</ref>, the term “employer” means the adjutant general of the State in which the technician is employed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c4750a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Except as an actual employer of employees, an employee pension benefit plan described in section 3(2) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002/2">29 U.S.C. 1002(2)</ref>) shall be deemed to be an employer only with respect to the obligation to provide benefits described in section 4318.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c4750b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c4750c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/4/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> Whether the term “successor in interest” applies with respect to an entity described in subparagraph (A) for purposes of clause (iv) of such subparagraph shall be determined on a case-by-case basis using a multi-factor test that considers the following factors:</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c4750d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/4/D/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> Substantial continuity of business operations.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c4750e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/4/D/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> Use of the same or similar facilities.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c4750f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/4/D/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> Continuity of work force.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c47510-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/4/D/i/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> Similarity of jobs and working conditions.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c47511-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/4/D/i/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> Similarity of supervisory personnel.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c47512-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/4/D/i/VI"><num value="VI">(VI)</num><content> Similarity of machinery, equipment, and production methods.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c47513-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/4/D/i/VII"><num value="VII">(VII)</num><content> Similarity of products or services.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c47514-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/4/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The entity’s lack of notice or awareness of a potential or pending claim under this chapter at the time of a merger, acquisition, or other form of succession shall not be considered when applying the multi-factor test under clause (i).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c47515-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> The term “Federal executive agency”—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c47516-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> except as provided in subparagraph (B), includes—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc3c47517-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the United States Postal Service;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc3c47518-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the Postal Regulatory Commission;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc3c47519-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/5/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> any nonappropriated fund instrumentality of the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc3c4751a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/5/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> any Executive agency (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s105">section 105 of title 5</ref>); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc3c4751b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/5/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> any military department (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s102">section 102 of title 5</ref>) with respect to the civilian employees of that department; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c4751c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> does not include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc3c4751d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/5/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> an agency referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2302/a/2/C/ii">section 2302(a)(2)(C)(ii) of title 5</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc3c4751e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/5/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration with respect to members of the commissioned officer corps of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc3c4751f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/5/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the Public Health Service with respect to members of the Commissioned Corps of the Public Health Service serving on active duty, active duty for training, or inactive duty training.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c47520-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The term “Federal Government” includes any Federal executive agency, the legislative branch of the United States, and the judicial branch of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c47521-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The term “health plan” means an insurance policy or contract, medical or hospital service agreement, membership or subscription contract, or other arrangement under which health services for individuals are provided or the expenses of such services are paid.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c47522-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> The term “notice” means (with respect to subchapter II) any written or verbal notification of an obligation or intention to perform service in the uniformed services provided to an employer by the employee who will perform such service or by the uniformed service in which such service is to be performed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c47523-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> The term “qualified”, with respect to an employment position, means having the ability to perform the essential tasks of the position.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c47524-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> The term “reasonable efforts”, in the case of actions required of an employer under this chapter, means actions, including training provided by an employer, that do not place an undue hardship on the employer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c47525-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> Notwithstanding section 101, the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Labor or any person designated by such Secretary to carry out an activity under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c47526-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> The term “seniority” means longevity in employment together with any benefits of employment which accrue with, or are determined by, longevity in employment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c47527-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> The term “service in the uniformed services” means the performance of duty on a voluntary or involuntary basis in a uniformed service under competent authority and includes active duty, active duty for training, initial active duty for training, inactive duty training, full-time National Guard duty, State active duty for a period of 14 days or more, State active duty in response to a national emergency declared by the President under the National Emergencies Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1601">50 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.), State active duty in response to a major disaster declared by the President under section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</ref>), a period for which a person is absent from a position of employment for the purpose of an examination to determine the fitness of the person to perform any such duty, a period for which a System member of the National Urban Search and Rescue Response System is absent from a position of employment due to an appointment into Federal service under section 327 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, a period for which a person is absent from a position of employment due to an appointment into service in the Federal Emergency Management Agency as intermittent personnel under section 306(b)(1) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5149/b/1">42 U.S.C. 5149(b)(1)</ref>), and a period for which a person is absent from employment for the purpose of performing funeral honors duty as authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12503">section 12503 of title 10</ref> or <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s115">section 115 of title 32</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c47528-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> The term “State” means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Virgin Islands, and other territories of the United States (including the agencies and political subdivisions thereof).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c47529-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><chapeau> The term “State active duty” means training or other duty, other than inactive duty, performed by a member of the National Guard of a State—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c4752a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/15/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> not under <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s502">section 502 of title 32</ref> or under title 10;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c4752b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/15/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in service to the Governor of a State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c4752c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/15/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> for which the member is not entitled to pay from the Federal Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c4752d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/16"><num value="16">(16)</num><chapeau> The term “undue hardship”, in the case of actions taken by an employer, means actions requiring significant difficulty or expense, when considered in light of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c4752e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/16/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the nature and cost of the action needed under this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c4752f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/16/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the overall financial resources of the facility or facilities involved in the provision of the action; the number of persons employed at such facility; the effect on expenses and resources, or the impact otherwise of such action upon the operation of the facility;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c47530-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/16/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the overall financial resources of the employer; the overall size of the business of an employer with respect to the number of its employees; the number, type, and location of its facilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c47531-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/16/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the type of operation or operations of the employer, including the composition, structure, and functions of the work force of such employer; the geographic separateness, administrative, or fiscal relationship of the facility or facilities in question to the employer.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c47532-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4303/17"><num value="17">(17)</num><content> The term “uniformed services” means the Armed Forces, the Army National Guard and the Air National Guard when engaged in active duty for training, inactive duty training, or full-time National Guard duty, the Commissioned Corps of the Public Health Service, the commissioned officer corps of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, System members of the National Urban Search and Rescue Response System during a period of appointment into Federal service under section 327 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, intermittent personnel who are appointed into Federal Emergency Management Agency service under section 306(b)(1) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5149/b/1">42 U.S.C. 5149(b)(1)</ref>) or to train for such service, and any other category of persons designated by the President in time of war or national emergency.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idc3c47533-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/103/353/s2/a">Pub. L. 103–353, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3150">108 Stat. 3150</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/104/275/tIII/s311/2">Pub. L. 104–275, title III, § 311(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3334">110 Stat. 3334</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/368/tII/s212/a">Pub. L. 105–368, title II, § 212(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3331">112 Stat. 3331</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/419/tIII/s323/a">Pub. L. 106–419, title III, § 323(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-01">Nov. 1, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1855">114 Stat. 1855</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/14/s8/a/11">Pub. L. 107–14, § 8(a)(11)</ref>, (b)(2), <date date="2001-06-05">June 5, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/35">115 Stat. 35</ref>, 36; <ref href="/us/pl/109/435/tVI/s604/f">Pub. L. 109–435, title VI, § 604(f)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3242">120 Stat. 3242</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/275/tVII">Pub. L. 111–275, title VII</ref>, §§ 701(a), 702(a), <date date="2010-10-13">Oct. 13, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2887">124 Stat. 2887</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/56/tII/s251">Pub. L. 112–56, title II, § 251</ref>, <date date="2011-11-21">Nov. 21, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/729">125 Stat. 729</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/326/s2/b/2">Pub. L. 114–326, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1972">130 Stat. 1972</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/259/tII/s208">Pub. L. 116–259, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="2020-12-23">Dec. 23, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/1168">134 Stat. 1168</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/315/tVII/s7004">Pub. L. 116–315, title VII, § 7004</ref>, <date date="2021-01-05">Jan. 5, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/5058">134 Stat. 5058</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/178/s3/a">Pub. L. 117–178, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-09-29">Sept. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2110">136 Stat. 2110</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dE/tLI/s5121">Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LI, § 5121</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3210">136 Stat. 3210</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc3c47534-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc3c47535-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc3c47536-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Emergencies Act, referred to in par. (13), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/412">Pub. L. 94–412</ref>, <date date="1976-09-14">Sept. 14, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1255">90 Stat. 1255</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 34 (§ 1601 et seq.) of Title 50, War and National Defense. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1601">section 1601 of Title 50</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 327 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, referred to in pars. (13) and (17), is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5165f">section 5165f of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idc3c47537-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 4303, added <ref href="/us/pl/93/508/tIV/s404/a">Pub. L. 93–508, title IV, § 404(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-12-03">Dec. 3, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1596">88 Stat. 1596</ref>, § 2023; amended <ref href="/us/pl/97/295/s4/72">Pub. L. 97–295, § 4(72)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1310">96 Stat. 1310</ref>; renumbered § 4303 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/568/tV/s506/a">Pub. L. 102–568, title V, § 506(a)</ref>, (c)(2), <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4340">106 Stat. 4340</ref>, 4341, related to reemployment by the United States, by any territory, possession, or political subdivision thereof, or by the District of Columbia, prior to the general amendment of this chapter by <ref href="/us/pl/103/353">Pub. L. 103–353</ref>. This section, as in effect on the day before <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, continues to apply to reemployments initiated before the end of the 60-day period beginning <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/353/s8">section 8 of Pub. L. 103–353</ref>, as amended, set out as an Effective Date under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s4301">section 4301 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another prior section 4303 was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s7603">section 7603 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc3c47538-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Par. (5). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s5121/a">Pub. L. 117–263, § 5121(a)</ref>, amended par. (5) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (5) read as follows: “The term ‘Federal executive agency’ includes the United States Postal Service, the Postal Regulatory Commission, any nonappropriated fund instrumentality of the United States, any Executive agency (as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s105">section 105 of title 5</ref>) other than an agency referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2302/a/2/C/ii">section 2302(a)(2)(C)(ii) of title 5</ref>, and any military department (as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s102">section 102 of title 5</ref>) with respect to the civilian employees of that department.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (13). <ref href="/us/pl/117/178/s3/a/1">Pub. L. 117–178, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “, a period for which a person is absent from a position of employment due to an appointment into service in the Federal Emergency Management Agency as intermittent personnel under section 306(b)(1) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5149/b/1">42 U.S.C. 5149(b)(1)</ref>)” before “, and a period”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (16). <ref href="/us/pl/117/178/s3/a/2">Pub. L. 117–178, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, redesignated par. (16) defining “uniformed services” as (17).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (17). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s5121/b">Pub. L. 117–263, § 5121(b)</ref>, substituted “Commissioned Corps of the Public Health Service” for “commissioned corps of the Public Health Service”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/178/s3/a/2">Pub. L. 117–178, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, (3), redesignated par. (16) defining “uniformed services” as (17) and inserted “intermittent personnel who are appointed into Federal Emergency Management Agency service under section 306(b)(1) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5149/b/1">42 U.S.C. 5149(b)(1)</ref>) or to train for such service,” before “and any other category”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Par. (13). <ref href="/us/pl/116/315/s7004/1">Pub. L. 116–315, § 7004(1)</ref>, inserted “State active duty for a period of 14 days or more, State active duty in response to a national emergency declared by the President under the National Emergencies Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1601">50 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.), State active duty in response to a major disaster declared by the President under section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</ref>),” after “full-time National Guard duty,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Pars. (15), (16). <ref href="/us/pl/116/315/s7004/2">Pub. L. 116–315, § 7004(2)</ref>, (3), added par. (15) and redesignated former par. (15) as (16) defining “undue hardship”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Par. (16). <ref href="/us/pl/116/259">Pub. L. 116–259</ref> inserted “the commissioned officer corps of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration,” after “Public Health Service,” in par. (16) defining “uniformed services”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Par. (13). <ref href="/us/pl/114/326/s2/b/2/A">Pub. L. 114–326, § 2(b)(2)(A)</ref>, inserted “, a period for which a System member of the National Urban Search and Rescue Response System is absent from a position of employment due to an appointment into Federal service under section 327 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act” before “, and a period”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (16). <ref href="/us/pl/114/326/s2/b/2/B">Pub. L. 114–326, § 2(b)(2)(B)</ref>, inserted “System members of the National Urban Search and Rescue Response System during a period of appointment into Federal service under section 327 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act,” after “Public Health Service,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Par. (2). <ref href="/us/pl/112/56">Pub. L. 112–56</ref> inserted “the terms, conditions, or privileges of employment, including” after “means”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Par. (2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/275/s701/a">Pub. L. 111–275, § 701(a)</ref>, substituted “(including” for “(other than”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (4)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/111/275/s702/a">Pub. L. 111–275, § 702(a)</ref>, added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Par. (5). <ref href="/us/pl/109/435">Pub. L. 109–435</ref> substituted “Postal Regulatory Commission” for “Postal Rate Commission”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Par. (13). <ref href="/us/pl/107/14/s8/b/2">Pub. L. 107–14, § 8(b)(2)</ref>, made technical amendment to directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/106/419/s323/a/1">Pub. L. 106–419, § 323(a)(1)</ref>. See 2000 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/14/s8/a/11">Pub. L. 107–14, § 8(a)(11)</ref>, struck out second period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Par. (13). <ref href="/us/pl/106/419/s323/a/2">Pub. L. 106–419, § 323(a)(2)</ref>, inserted before period at end “, and a period for which a person is absent from employment for the purpose of performing funeral honors duty as authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12503">section 12503 of title 10</ref> or <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s115">section 115 of title 32</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/419/s323/a/1">Pub. L. 106–419, § 323(a)(1)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/107/14/s8/b/2">Pub. L. 107–14, § 8(b)(2)</ref>, struck out “and” after “National Guard duty,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Par. (3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/368">Pub. L. 105–368</ref> inserted at end “Such term includes any person who is a citizen, national, or permanent resident alien of the United States employed in a workplace in a foreign country by an employer that is an entity incorporated or otherwise organized in the United States or that is controlled by an entity organized in the United States, within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s4319/c">section 4319(c) of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Par. (16). <ref href="/us/pl/104/275">Pub. L. 104–275</ref> inserted “national” before “emergency”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc3c47539-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3c4753a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/275/tVII/s701/b">Pub. L. 111–275, title VII, § 701(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-13">Oct. 13, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2887">124 Stat. 2887</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/275/tVII/s701/b">
<inline>“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> any failure to comply with a provision of or any violation of chapter 43 of title 38, United States Code, that occurs before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2010-10-13">Oct. 13, 2010</date>]; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> all actions or complaints filed under such chapter 43 that are pending on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/111/275/tVII/s702/b">Pub. L. 111–275, title VII, § 702(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-13">Oct. 13, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2888">124 Stat. 2888</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/275/tVII/s702/b">
<inline>“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> any failure to comply with a provision of or any violation of chapter 43 of title 38, United States Code, that occurs before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2010-10-13">Oct. 13, 2010</date>]; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> all actions or complaints filed under such chapter 43 that are pending on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3c4753b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2001 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/14/s8/b">Pub. L. 107–14, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-06-05">June 5, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/36">115 Stat. 36</ref>, provided that the amendment made by section 8(b) is effective <date date="2000-11-01">Nov. 1, 2000</date>, and as if included in the Veterans Benefits and Health Care Improvement Act of 2000, <ref href="/us/pl/106/419">Pub. L. 106–419</ref>, as enacted.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3c4753c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2000 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/419/tIII/s323/c">Pub. L. 106–419, title III, § 323(c)</ref>, <date date="2000-11-01">Nov. 1, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1856">114 Stat. 1856</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/419/tIII/s323/c">“The amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s4316">section 4316 of this title</ref>] shall take effect 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2000-11-01">Nov. 1, 2000</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3c4753d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/368/tII/s212/c">Pub. L. 105–368, title II, § 212(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3331">112 Stat. 3331</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/368/tII/s212/c">“The amendments made by this section [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s4319">section 4319 of this title</ref> and amending this section] shall apply only with respect to causes of action arising after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3c4753e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/275">Pub. L. 104–275</ref> effective <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/275/s313">section 313 of Pub. L. 104–275</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s4301">section 4301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idc3c4753f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective with respect to reemployments initiated on or after the first day after the 60-day period beginning <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, with transition rules, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/353/s8">section 8 of Pub. L. 103–353</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s4301">section 4301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
