<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc3c6be8c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4313"><num value="4313">§ 4313.</num><heading> Reemployment positions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3c6be8d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4313/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> Subject to subsection (b) (in the case of any employee) and sections 4314 and 4315 (in the case of an employee of the Federal Government), a person entitled to reemployment under section 4312, upon completion of a period of service in the uniformed services, shall be promptly reemployed in a position of employment in accordance with the following order of priority:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c6be8e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4313/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in paragraphs (3) and (4), in the case of a person whose period of service in the uniformed services was for less than 91 days—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c6be8f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4313/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in the position of employment in which the person would have been employed if the continuous employment of such person with the employer had not been interrupted by such service, the duties of which the person is qualified to perform; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c6be90-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4313/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the position of employment in which the person was employed on the date of the commencement of the service in the uniformed services, only if the person is not qualified to perform the duties of the position referred to in subparagraph (A) after reasonable efforts by the employer to qualify the person.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c6be91-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4313/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in paragraphs (3) and (4), in the case of a person whose period of service in the uniformed services was for more than 90 days—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c6be92-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4313/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in the position of employment in which the person would have been employed if the continuous employment of such person with the employer had not been interrupted by such service, or a position of like seniority, status and pay, the duties of which the person is qualified to perform; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c6be93-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4313/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the position of employment in which the person was employed on the date of the commencement of the service in the uniformed services, or a position of like seniority, status and pay, the duties of which the person is qualified to perform, only if the person is not qualified to perform the duties of a position referred to in subparagraph (A) after reasonable efforts by the employer to qualify the person.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c6be94-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4313/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> In the case of a person who has a disability incurred in, or aggravated during, such service, and who (after reasonable efforts by the employer to accommodate the disability) is not qualified due to such disability to be employed in the position of employment in which the person would have been employed if the continuous employment of such person with the employer had not been interrupted by such service—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c6be95-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4313/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in any other position which is equivalent in seniority, status, and pay, the duties of which the person is qualified to perform or would become qualified to perform with reasonable efforts by the employer; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c6be96-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4313/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if not employed under subparagraph (A), in a position which is the nearest approximation to a position referred to in subparagraph (A) in terms of seniority, status, and pay consistent with circumstances of such person’s case.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c6be97-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4313/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> In the case of a person who (A) is not qualified to be employed in (i) the position of employment in which the person would have been employed if the continuous employment of such person with the employer had not been interrupted by such service, or (ii) in the position of employment in which such person was employed on the date of the commencement of the service in the uniformed services for any reason (other than disability incurred in, or aggravated during, service in the uniformed services), and (B) cannot become qualified with reasonable efforts by the employer, in any other position which is the nearest approximation to a position referred to first in clause (A)(i) and then in clause (A)(ii) which such person is qualified to perform, with full seniority.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3c6be98-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4313/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3c6be99-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4313/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If two or more persons are entitled to reemployment under section 4312 in the same position of employment and more than one of them has reported for such reemployment, the person who left the position first shall have the prior right to reemployment in that position.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3c6be9a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4313/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Any person entitled to reemployment under section 4312 who is not reemployed in a position of employment by reason of paragraph (1) shall be entitled to be reemployed as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c6be9b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4313/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), in any other position of employment referred to in subsection (a)(1) or (a)(2), as the case may be (in the order of priority set out in the applicable subsection), that provides a similar status and pay to a position of employment referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection, consistent with the circumstances of such person’s case, with full seniority.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c6be9c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4313/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In the case of a person who has a disability incurred in, or aggravated during, a period of service in the uniformed services that requires reasonable efforts by the employer for the person to be able to perform the duties of the position of employment, in any other position referred to in subsection (a)(3) (in the order of priority set out in that subsection) that provides a similar status and pay to a position referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection, consistent with circumstances of such person’s case, with full seniority.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc3c6be9d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/103/353/s2/a">Pub. L. 103–353, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3157">108 Stat. 3157</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/104/275/tIII/s311/5">Pub. L. 104–275, title III, § 311(5)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3335">110 Stat. 3335</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc3c6be9e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc3c6be9f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idc3c6bea0-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 4313 was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s7613">section 7613 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc3c6bea1-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/104/275">Pub. L. 104–275</ref> substituted “uniformed services” for “uniform services” in cl. (A)(ii) and “which is the nearest approximation to a position referred to first in clause (A)(i) and then in clause (A)(ii) which” for “of lesser status and pay which” in cl. (B).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc3c6bea2-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3c6bea3-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/275">Pub. L. 104–275</ref> effective <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/275/s313">section 313 of Pub. L. 104–275</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s4301">section 4301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idc3c6bea4-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective with respect to reemployments initiated on or after the first day after the 60-day period beginning <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, with transition rules, except that subsec. (a)(3) of this section applicable to reemployments initiated on or after <date date="1990-08-01">Aug. 1, 1990</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/353/s8">section 8 of Pub. L. 103–353</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s4301">section 4301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
