<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc3c6beb6-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4315"><num value="4315">§ 4315.</num><heading> Reemployment by certain Federal agencies</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3c6beb7-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4315/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The head of each agency referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2302/a/2/C/ii">section 2302(a)(2)(C)(ii) of title 5</ref> shall prescribe procedures for ensuring that the rights under this chapter apply to the employees of such agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3c6beb8-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4315/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> In prescribing procedures under subsection (a), the head of an agency referred to in that subsection shall ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that the procedures of the agency for reemploying persons who serve in the uniformed services provide for the reemployment of such persons in the agency in a manner similar to the manner of reemployment described in section 4313.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3c6beb9-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4315/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3c6beba-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4315/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The procedures prescribed under subsection (a) shall designate an official at the agency who shall determine whether or not the reemployment of a person referred to in subsection (b) by the agency is impossible or unreasonable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3c6bebb-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4315/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Upon making a determination that the reemployment by the agency of a person referred to in subsection (b) is impossible or unreasonable, the official referred to in paragraph (1) shall notify the person and the Director of the Office of Personnel Management of such determination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3c6bebc-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4315/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A determination pursuant to this subsection shall not be subject to judicial review.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3c6bebd-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4315/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The head of each agency referred to in subsection (a) shall submit to the Select Committee on Intelligence and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives on an annual basis a report on the number of persons whose reemployment with the agency was determined under this subsection to be impossible or unreasonable during the year preceding the report, including the reason for each such determination.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3c6bebe-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4315/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3c6bebf-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4315/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in this section, nothing in this section, section 4313, or section 4325 shall be construed to exempt any agency referred to in subsection (a) from compliance with any other substantive provision of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3c6bec0-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4315/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> This section may not be construed—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c6bec1-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4315/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> as prohibiting an employee of an agency referred to in subsection (a) from seeking information from the Secretary regarding assistance in seeking reemployment from the agency under this chapter, alternative employment in the Federal Government under this chapter, or information relating to the rights and obligations of employee and Federal agencies under this chapter; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c6bec2-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4315/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> as prohibiting such an agency from voluntarily cooperating with or seeking assistance in or of clarification from the Secretary or the Director of the Office of Personnel Management of any matter arising under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3c6bec3-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4315/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><chapeau> The Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall ensure the offer of employment to a person in a position in a Federal executive agency on the basis described in subsection (b) if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c6bec4-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4315/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the person was an employee of an agency referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2302/a/2/C/ii">section 2302(a)(2)(C)(ii) of title 5</ref> at the time the person entered the service from which the person seeks reemployment under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c6bec5-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4315/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the appropriate officer of the agency determines under subsection (c) that reemployment of the person by the agency is impossible or unreasonable; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c6bec6-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4315/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the person submits an application to the Director for an offer of employment under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc3c6bec7-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/103/353/s2/a">Pub. L. 103–353, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3159">108 Stat. 3159</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc3c6bec8-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc3c6bec9-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idc3c6beca-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 4315 was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s7615">section 7615 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc3c6becb-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idc3c6becc-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective with respect to reemployments initiated on or after the first day after the 60-day period beginning <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, with transition rules, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/353/s8">section 8 of Pub. L. 103–353</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s4301">section 4301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
