<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc3c6beec-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4317"><num value="4317">§ 4317.</num><heading> Health plans</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3c6beed-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4317/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3c6beee-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4317/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In any case in which a person (or the person’s dependents) has coverage under a health plan in connection with the person’s position of employment, including a group health plan (as defined in section 607(1) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974), and such person is absent from such position of employment by reason of service in the uniformed services, or such person becomes eligible for medical and dental care under chapter 55 of title 10 by reason of subsection (d) of section 1074 of that title, the plan shall provide that the person may elect to continue such coverage as provided in this subsection. The maximum period of coverage of a person and the person’s dependents under such an election shall be the lesser of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c6beef-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4317/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the 24-month period beginning on the date on which the person’s absence begins; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c6bef0-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4317/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the day after the date on which the person fails to apply for or return to a position of employment, as determined under section 4312(e).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3c6bef1-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4317/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A person who elects to continue health-plan coverage under this paragraph may be required to pay not more than 102 percent of the full premium under the plan (determined in the same manner as the applicable premium under section 4980B(f)(4) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) associated with such coverage for the employer’s other employees, except that in the case of a person who performs service in the uniformed services for less than 31 days, such person may not be required to pay more than the employee share, if any, for such coverage.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3c6bef2-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4317/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> In the case of a health plan that is a multiemployer plan, as defined in section 3(37) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, any liability under the plan for employer contributions and benefits arising under this paragraph shall be allocated—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c6bef3-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4317/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> by the plan in such manner as the plan sponsor shall provide; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3c6bef4-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4317/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> if the sponsor does not provide—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c6bef5-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4317/a/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to the last employer employing the person before the period served by the person in the uniformed services, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3c6bef6-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4317/a/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> if such last employer is no longer functional, to the plan.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3c6bef7-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4317/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3c6bef8-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4317/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), in the case of a person whose coverage under a health plan was terminated by reason of service in the uniformed services, or by reason of the person’s having become eligible for medical and dental care under chapter 55 of title 10 by reason of subsection (d) of section 1074 of that title, an exclusion or waiting period may not be imposed in connection with the reinstatement of such coverage upon reemployment under this chapter if an exclusion or waiting period would not have been imposed under a health plan had coverage of such person by such plan not been terminated as a result of such service or eligibility. This paragraph applies to the person who is reemployed and to any individual who is covered by such plan by reason of the reinstatement of the coverage of such person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3c6bef9-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4317/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Paragraph (1) shall not apply to the coverage of any illness or injury determined by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to have been incurred in, or aggravated during, performance of service in the uniformed services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3c6befa-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s4317/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In the case of a person whose coverage under a health plan is terminated by reason of the person having become eligible for medical and dental care under chapter 55 of title 10 by reason of subsection (d) of section 1074 of that title but who subsequently does not commence a period of active duty under the order to active duty that established such eligibility because the order is canceled before such active duty commences, the provisions of paragraph (1) relating to any exclusion or waiting period in connection with the reinstatement of coverage under a health plan shall apply to such person’s continued employment, upon the termination of such eligibility for medical and dental care under chapter 55 of title 10 that is incident to the cancellation of such order, in the same manner as if the person had become reemployed upon such termination of eligibility.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc3c6befb-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/103/353/s2/a">Pub. L. 103–353, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3161">108 Stat. 3161</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/104/275/tIII/s311/7">Pub. L. 104–275, title III, § 311(7)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3335">110 Stat. 3335</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/454/tII/s201/a">Pub. L. 108–454, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3605">118 Stat. 3605</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/233/tIII/s303">Pub. L. 109–233, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/406">120 Stat. 406</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc3c6befc-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc3c6befd-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc3c6befe-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 3(37) and 607(1) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), (3), are classified to sections 1002(37) and 1167(1), respectively, of Title 29, Labor.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 4980B(f)(4) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s4980B/f/4">section 4980B(f)(4) of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idc3c6beff-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 4317 was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s7617">section 7617 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc3c6bf00-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/233/s303/a">Pub. L. 109–233, § 303(a)</ref>, inserted “or such person becomes eligible for medical and dental care under chapter 55 of title 10 by reason of subsection (d) of section 1074 of that title,” after “by reason of service in the uniformed services,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/233/s303/b/1">Pub. L. 109–233, § 303(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “or by reason of the person’s having become eligible for medical and dental care under chapter 55 of title 10 by reason of subsection (d) of section 1074 of that title,” after “by reason of service in the uniformed services,” and “or eligibility” after “such service”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/109/233/s303/b/2">Pub. L. 109–233, § 303(b)(2)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/108/454">Pub. L. 108–454</ref> substituted “24-month period” for “18-month period”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/275">Pub. L. 104–275</ref> substituted “(a)(1) In” for “(a)(1)(A) Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), in”, redesignated cls. (i) and (ii) of par. (1) as subpars. (A) and (B), respectively, redesignated former subpars. (B) and (C) as pars. (2) and (3), respectively, and in par. (3), redesignated cls. (i) and (ii) as subpars. (A) and (B), respectively, and subcls. (I) and (II) as cls. (i) and (ii), respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc3c6bf01-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3c6bf02-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2004 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/454/tII/s201/b">Pub. L. 108–454, title II, § 201(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3606">118 Stat. 3606</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/454/tII/s201/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to elections made under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s4317">section 4317 of title 38</ref>, United States Code, on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2004-12-10">Dec. 10, 2004</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3c6bf03-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/275">Pub. L. 104–275</ref> effective <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/275/s313">section 313 of Pub. L. 104–275</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s4301">section 4301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idc3c6bf04-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective with respect to reemployments initiated on or after the first day after the 60-day period beginning <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, with transition rules, except that a person on active duty on <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, or a family member or personal representative of such person, may, after <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, elect to reinstate or continue a health plan provided in this section, and the health plan shall remain in effect for the remaining portion of the 18-month period that began on the date of such person’s separation from civilian employment or the period of the person’s service in the uniformed service, whichever is of lesser duration, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/353/s8">section 8 of Pub. L. 103–353</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s4301">section 4301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
