<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc284efbf-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s527"><num value="527">§ 527.</num><heading> Evaluation and data collection</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc284efc0-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s527/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Secretary, pursuant to general standards which the Secretary shall prescribe in regulations, shall measure and evaluate on a continuing basis the effect of all programs authorized under this title, in order to determine their effectiveness in achieving stated goals in general, and in achieving such goals in relation to their cost, their effect on related programs, and their structure and mechanisms for delivery of services. Such information as the Secretary may consider necessary for purposes of such evaluations shall be made available to the Secretary, upon request, by all departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the executive branch.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc28739b1-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s527/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall collect, collate, and analyze on a continuing basis full statistical data regarding participation (including the duration thereof), provision of services, categories of beneficiaries, planning and construction of facilities, acquisition of real property, proposed excessing of land, accretion and attrition of personnel, and categorized expenditures attributable thereto, under all programs carried out under this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc28739b2-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s527/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The Secretary shall make available to the public, and on a regular basis provide to the appropriate committees of the Congress, copies of all completed evaluative research studies and summaries of evaluations of program impact and effectiveness carried out, and tabulations and analyses of all data collected, under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc28739b3-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s2/a">Pub. L. 102–83, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/391">105 Stat. 391</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc28739b4-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc28739b5-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idc28739b6-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s219">section 219 of this title</ref> prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s2/a">Pub. L. 102–83, § 2(a)</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc28739b7-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc28739b8-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Analysis and Report on Treatment of Veterans for Medical Conditions Related to Toxic Exposure</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/168/tV/s502">Pub. L. 117–168, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="2022-08-10">Aug. 10, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/1786">136 Stat. 1786</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/168/tV/s502">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall analyze, on a continuous basis, all clinical data that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> is obtained by the Department of Veterans Affairs in connection with hospital care, medical services, and nursing home care furnished under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1710/a/2/F">section 1710(a)(2)(F) of title 38</ref>, United States Code; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> is likely to be scientifically useful in determining the association, if any, between the medical condition of a veteran and a toxic exposure.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-08-10">Aug. 10, 2022</date>], and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report containing the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The aggregate data compiled under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> An analysis of such data.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> A description of the types and incidences of medical conditions identified by the Department under such subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The explanation of the Secretary for the incidence of such medical conditions and other explanations for the incidence of such conditions as the Secretary considers reasonable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> The views of the Secretary on the scientific validity of drawing conclusions from the incidence of such medical conditions, as evidenced by the data compiled under subsection (a), regarding any association between such conditions and toxic exposures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Toxic Exposure Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘toxic exposure’ has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s101">section 101 of title 38</ref>, United States Code, as amended by section 102(b).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc28739b9-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Department of Veterans Affairs Public Website for Toxic Exposure Research</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/168/tV/s509">Pub. L. 117–168, title V, § 509</ref>, <date date="2022-08-10">Aug. 10, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/1791">136 Stat. 1791</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/168/tV/s509">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Website</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-08-10">Aug. 10, 2022</date>], the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish, and maintain thereafter, a publicly accessible internet website of the Department of Veterans Affairs that serves as a clearinghouse for the publication of all toxic exposure research carried out or funded by the executive branch of the Federal Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coordination</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall coordinate with—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the heads of each Federal agency carrying out or funding toxic exposure research;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the War Related Illness and Injury Study Center of the Department of Veterans Affairs, or successor center; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> any working group of the Department of Veterans Affairs or other similar entity responsible for coordinating toxic exposure research.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Toxic exposure</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘toxic exposure’ has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s101">section 101 of title 38</ref>, United States Code, as added by section 102(b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Toxic exposure research</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘toxic exposure research’ means research on the health consequences of toxic exposures experienced during service in the Armed Forces.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc28739ba-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Burn Pit Transparency</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/168/tVIII/s808">Pub. L. 117–168, title VIII, § 808</ref>, <date date="2022-08-10">Aug. 10, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/1806">136 Stat. 1806</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/168/tVIII/s808">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Report on Disability Claims.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, [<date date="2022-08-10">Aug. 10, 2022</date>] and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report detailing the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The total number of covered veterans.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The total number of claimed issues for disability compensation under chapter 11 of title 38, United States Code, approved and the total number denied by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs with respect to a covered veteran, and a breakdown of the reasons for the denials.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> A comprehensive list of the top 10 conditions from each body system for which the Secretary awarded service connection for covered veterans.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Any updates or trends with respect to the information described in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C), that the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered veteran defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this subsection, the term ‘covered veteran’ means a veteran who deployed to the Southwest Asia theater of operations any time after August 1990, or Afghanistan, Syria, Djibouti, or Uzbekistan after <date date="2001-09-19">September 19, 2001</date>, and who submits a claim for disability compensation under chapter 11 of title 38, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Information Regarding the Airborne Hazards and Open Burn Pit Registry.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall ensure that a medical professional of the Department of Veterans Affairs informs a veteran of the Airborne Hazards and Open Burn Pit Registry if the veteran presents at a medical facility of the Department for treatment that the veteran describes as being related to, or ancillary to, the exposure of the veteran to toxic airborne chemicals and fumes caused by open burn pits.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Display</inline>.—</heading><content>In making information public regarding the number of participants in the Airborne Hazards and Open Burn Pit Registry, the Secretary shall display such numbers by both State and by congressional district.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Airborne hazards and open burn pit registry</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Airborne Hazards and Open Burn Pit Registry’ means the registry established by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs under section 201 of the Dignified Burial and Other Veterans’ Benefits Improvement Act of 2012 (<ref href="/us/pl/112/260">Public Law 112–260</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s527">38 U.S.C. 527</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate congressional committees</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘appropriate congressional committees’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Open burn pit</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘open burn pit’ has the meaning given that term in section 201(c) of the Dignified Burial and Other Veterans’ Benefits Improvement Act of 2012 (<ref href="/us/pl/112/260">Public Law 112–260</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s527">38 U.S.C. 527</ref> note).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc28739bb-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Requirement for Collection and Analysis of Data on Department of Veterans Affairs Benefits and Services and Disaggregation of Such Data by Gender, Race, and Ethnicity</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/315/tV/s5401">Pub. L. 116–315, title V, § 5401</ref>, <date date="2021-01-05">Jan. 5, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/5045">134 Stat. 5045</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/315/tV/s5401">
<inline>“The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> collect and analyze data on each program of the Department of Veterans Affairs that provides a service or benefit to a veteran, including the program carried out under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1144">section 1144 of title 10</ref>, United States Code;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> disaggregate such data by gender, race, and ethnicity, when the data lends itself to such disaggregation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> publish the data collected and analyzed under paragraph (1), except for such cases in which the Secretary determines that some portions of the data would undermine the anonymity of a veteran.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc28739bc-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Addition of Burn Pit Registration and Other Information to Electronic Health Records of Members of the Armed Forces</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tVII/s720">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VII, § 720</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3697">134 Stat. 3697</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tVII/s720">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Updates to Electronic Health Records</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Beginning not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall ensure that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the electronic health record maintained by the Secretary for a member of the Armed Forces registered with the Airborne Hazards and Open Burn Pit Registry is updated with any information contained in such registry with respect to the member; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> any occupational or environmental health exposure recorded in the Defense Occupational and Environmental Health Readiness System (or any successor system) is linked to the electronic health record system of the Department of Defense to notify health professionals treating a member specified in paragraph (1) of any such exposure recorded for the member.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Airborne Hazards and Open Burn Pit Registry Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘Airborne Hazards and Open Burn Pit Registry’ means the registry established by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs under section 201 of the Dignified Burial and Other Veterans’ Benefits Improvement Act of 2012 (<ref href="/us/pl/112/260">Public Law 112–260</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s527">38 U.S.C. 527</ref> note).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc28739bd-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Health Assessments of Veterans Diagnosed With Pandemic Diseases To Determine Exposure to Open Burn Pits and Toxic Airborne Chemicals</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tVII/s735">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VII, § 735</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3703">134 Stat. 3703</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tVII/s735">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exposure to Open Burn Pits and Toxic Airborne Chemicals or Other Airborne Contaminants as Part of Health Assessments for Veterans During a Pandemic and Inclusion of Information in Registry.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Health assessments and physical examinations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall ensure that the first health assessment or physical examination furnished to a veteran under the laws administered by the Secretary after the veteran tests positive for a pathogen, such as a virus, with respect to which a public health emergency has been declared under section 319 of the Public Health Service Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s247d">42 U.S.C. 247d</ref>) includes an evaluation of whether the veteran has been—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> based or stationed at a location where an open burn pit was used; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> exposed to toxic airborne chemicals or other airborne contaminants relating to service in the Armed Forces, including an evaluation of any information recorded as part of the Airborne Hazards and Open Burn Pit Registry.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inclusion of individuals in registry</inline>.—</heading><content>If an evaluation conducted under paragraph (1) with respect to a veteran establishes that the veteran was based or stationed at a location where an open burn pit was used, or that the individual was exposed to toxic airborne chemicals or other airborne contaminants, the individual shall be enrolled in the Airborne Hazards and Open Burn Pit Registry unless the veteran elects to not enroll in such registry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to preclude eligibility of a veteran for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs by reason of the history of exposure of the veteran to an open burn pit not being recorded in an evaluation conducted under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study on Impact of Viral Pandemics on Members of Armed Forces and Veterans Who Have Experienced Toxic Exposure.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall conduct a study, through the Airborne Hazards and Burn Pits Center of Excellence (in this subsection referred to as the ‘Center’), on the health impacts of infection with a pathogen, such as a virus, with respect to which a public health emergency has been declared under section 319 of the Public Health Service Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s247d">42 U.S.C. 247d</ref>), including a coronavirus, to members of the Armed Forces and veterans who have been exposed to open burn pits and other toxic exposures for the purposes of understanding the health impacts of the pathogen and whether individuals infected with the pathogen are at increased risk of severe symptoms due to previous conditions linked to toxic exposure.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Preparation for future pandemic</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary, through the Center, shall analyze potential lessons learned through the study conducted under paragraph (1) to assist in preparing the Department of Veterans Affairs for potential future pandemics.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subsection [probably should be “section”]:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The term ‘Airborne Hazards and Open Burn Pit Registry’ means the registry established by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs under section 201 of the Dignified Burial and Other Veterans’ Benefits Improvement Act of 2012 (<ref href="/us/pl/112/260">Public Law 112–260</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s527">38 U.S.C. 527</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘coronavirus’ has the meaning given that term in section 506 of the Coronavirus Preparedness and Response Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2020 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/123">Public Law 116–123</ref> [<ref href="/us/stat/134/155">134 Stat. 155</ref>]).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The term ‘open burn pit’ has the meaning given that term in section 201(c) of the Dignified Burial and Other Veterans’ Benefits Improvement Act of 2012 (<ref href="/us/pl/112/260">Public Law 112–260</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/126/2422">126 Stat. 2422</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s527">38 U.S.C. 527</ref> note).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc28739be-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Access of Veterans to Individual Longitudinal Exposure Record</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dH/tXCI/s9105">Pub. L. 116–283, div. H, title XCI, § 9105</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4783">134 Stat. 4783</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/283/dH/tXCI/s9105">“The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall provide to a veteran read-only access to the documents of the veteran contained in the Individual Longitudinal Exposure Record in a printable format through a portal accessible through an internet website of the Department of Veterans Affairs.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc28739bf-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Access to Information in Burn Pit Registry</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tVII/s705/c">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VII, § 705(c)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1440">133 Stat. 1440</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tVII/s705/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that all medical personnel of the Department of Defense have access to the information contained in the burn pit registry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Burn pit registry defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this subsection, the term ‘burn pit registry’ means the registry established under section 201 of the Dignified Burial and Other Veterans’ Benefits Improvement Act of 2012 (<ref href="/us/pl/112/260">Public Law 112–260</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s527">38 U.S.C. 527</ref> note).”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc28739c0-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Education Campaign for Airborne Hazards and Open Burn Pit Registry</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tX/s1050">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title X, § 1050</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1962">132 Stat. 1962</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tX/s1050">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Education Campaign</inline>.—</heading><content>Beginning not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall carry out an annual education campaign to inform individuals who may be eligible to enroll in the Airborne Hazards and Open Burn Pit Registry of such eligibility. Each such campaign shall include at least one electronic method and one physical mailing method to provide such information.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Airborne Hazards and Open Burn Pit Registry Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘Airborne Hazards and Open Burn Pit Registry’ means the registry established by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs under section 201 of the Dignified Burial and Other Veterans’ Benefits Improvement Act of 2012 (<ref href="/us/pl/112/260">Public Law 112–260</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s527">38 U.S.C. 527</ref> note) [set out below].”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc28739c1-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Coordination by Veterans Health Administration of Efforts To Understand Effects of Burn Pits</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tVII/s738">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VII, § 738</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1446">131 Stat. 1446</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tVII/s738">“The Under Secretary for Health of the Department of Veterans Affairs, acting through the Office of Public Health of the Veterans Health Administration, shall coordinate efforts related to furthering understanding of burn pits, the effect of burn pits on veterans, and effective treatments relating to such effects, including with respect to research efforts and training of clinical staff on related matters.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc28739c2-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Submittal of Information to Secretary of Veterans Affairs Relating to Exposure to Airborne Hazards and Open Burn Pits</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/92/dA/tVII/s728">Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title VII, § 728</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/873">129 Stat. 873</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/92/dA/tVII/s728">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>], and periodically thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs such information in the possession of the Secretary of Defense as the Secretary of Veterans Affairs considers necessary to supplement and support—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the development of information to be included in the Airborne Hazards and Open Burn Pit Registry established by the Department of Veterans Affairs under section 201 of the Dignified Burial and Other Veterans’ Benefits Improvement Act of 2012 (<ref href="/us/pl/112/260">Public Law 112–260</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s527">38 U.S.C. 527</ref> note); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> research and development activities conducted by the Department of Veterans Affairs to explore the potential health risks of exposure by members of the Armed Forces to environmental factors in Iraq and Afghanistan, in particular the connection of such exposure to respiratory illnesses such as chronic cough, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, constrictive bronchiolitis, and pulmonary fibrosis.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inclusion of Certain Information</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall include in the information submitted to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs under subsection (a) information on any research and surveillance efforts conducted by the Department of Defense to evaluate the incidence and prevalence of respiratory illnesses among members of the Armed Forces who were exposed to open burn pits while deployed overseas.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc28739c3-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Establishment of Open Burn Pit Registry</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/260/tII/s201">Pub. L. 112–260, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2013-01-10">Jan. 10, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2422">126 Stat. 2422</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/116/315/tII/s2010/g">Pub. L. 116–315, title II, § 2010(g)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-05">Jan. 5, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4979">134 Stat. 4979</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dF/tLXVI/s6602">Pub. L. 117–81, div. F, title LXVI, § 6602</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/2438">135 Stat. 2438</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/81/dF/tLXVI/s6602">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Registry.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2013-01-10">Jan. 10, 2013</date>], the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> establish and maintain an open burn pit registry for eligible individuals who may have been exposed to toxic airborne chemicals and fumes caused by open burn pits;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> include any information in such registry that the Secretary of Veterans Affairs determines necessary to ascertain and monitor the health effects of the exposure of members of the Armed Forces to toxic airborne chemicals and fumes caused by open burn pits;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> develop a public information campaign to inform eligible individuals about the open burn pit registry, including how to register and the benefits of registering; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> periodically notify eligible individuals of significant developments in the study and treatment of conditions associated with exposure to toxic airborne chemicals and fumes caused by open burn pits.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coordination</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall coordinate with the Secretary of Defense in carrying out paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports by independent scientific organization</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall enter into an agreement with an independent scientific organization to prepare reports as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> Not later than two years after the date on which the registry under subsection (a) is established, an initial report containing the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> An assessment of the effectiveness of actions taken by the Secretaries to collect and maintain information on the health effects of exposure to toxic airborne chemicals and fumes caused by open burn pits.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> Recommendations to improve the collection and maintenance of such information.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> Using established and previously published epidemiological studies, recommendations regarding the most effective and prudent means of addressing the medical needs of eligible individuals with respect to conditions that are likely to result from exposure to open burn pits.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> Not later than five years after completing the initial report described in subparagraph (A), a follow-up report containing the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> An update to the initial report described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> An assessment of whether and to what degree the content of the registry established under subsection (a) is current and scientifically up-to-date.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submittal to congress.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Initial report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than two years after the date on which the registry under subsection (a) is established, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to Congress the initial report prepared under paragraph (1)(A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Follow-up report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than five years after submitting the report under subparagraph (A), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to Congress the follow-up report prepared under paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible individual</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘eligible individual’ means any individual who, on or after <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> was deployed in support of a contingency operation while serving in the Armed Forces; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> during such deployment, was based or stationed at a location where an open burn pit was used.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Open burn pit</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘open burn pit’ means an area of land located in Afghanistan, Iraq,, [sic] Uzbekistan, Egypt, or Syria that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> is designated by the Secretary of Defense to be used for disposing solid waste by burning in the outdoor air; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> does not contain a commercially manufactured incinerator or other equipment specifically designed and manufactured for the burning of solid waste.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc28739c4-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Persian Gulf War Veterans’ Health Status</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/585/tVII">Pub. L. 102–585, title VII</ref>, <date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4975">106 Stat. 4975</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/103/446/tI/s108">Pub. L. 103–446, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4653">108 Stat. 4653</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/368/tI">Pub. L. 105–368, title I</ref>, §§ 104, 106, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3323">112 Stat. 3323</ref>, 3325; <ref href="/us/pl/111/163/tV/s502">Pub. L. 111–163, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="2010-05-05">May 5, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1157">124 Stat. 1157</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/163/tV/s502">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="701">“SEC. 701.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This title may be cited as the ‘Persian Gulf War Veterans’ Health Status Act’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="702">“SEC. 702.</num><heading> PERSIAN GULF WAR VETERANS HEALTH REGISTRY.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Registry</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish and maintain a special record to be known as the ‘Persian Gulf War Veterans Health Registry’ (in this section referred to as the ‘Registry’).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents of Registry</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (c), the Registry shall include the following information:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> A list containing the name of each individual who served as a member of the Armed Forces in the Persian Gulf theater of operations during the Persian Gulf War and who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> applies for care or services from the Department of Veterans Affairs under chapter 17 of title 38, United States Code;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> files a claim for compensation under chapter 11 of such title on the basis of any disability which may be associated with such service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> dies and is survived by a spouse, child, or parent who files a claim for dependency and indemnity compensation under chapter 13 of such title on the basis of such service;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> requests from the Department a health examination under section 703; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> receives from the Department of Defense a health examination similar to the health examination referred to in subparagraph (D) and requests inclusion in the Registry.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> Relevant medical data relating to the health status of, and other information that the Secretary considers relevant and appropriate with respect to, each individual described in paragraph (1) who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> grants to the Secretary permission to include such information in the Registry; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> at the time the individual is listed in the Registry, is deceased.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Individuals Submitting Claims or Making Requests Before Date of Enactment</inline>.—</heading><content>If in the case of an individual described in subsection (b)(1) the application, claim, or request referred to in such subsection was submitted, filed, or made, before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>], the Secretary shall, to the extent feasible, include in the Registry such individual’s name and the data and information, if any, described in subsection (b)(2) relating to the individual.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Department of Defense Information</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall furnish to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs such information maintained by the Department of Defense as the Secretary of Veterans Affairs considers necessary to establish and maintain the Registry.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Relation to Department of Defense Registry</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall ensure that information is collected and maintained in the Registry in a manner that permits effective and efficient cross-reference between the Registry and the registry established under section 734 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Years 1992 and 1993 (<ref href="/us/pl/102/190">Public Law 102–190</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/105/1411">105 Stat. 1411</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1074">10 U.S.C. 1074</ref> note), as amended by section 704.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Ongoing Outreach to Individuals Listed in Registry</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall, from time to time, notify individuals listed in the Registry of significant developments in research on the health consequences of military service in the Persian Gulf theater of operations during the Persian Gulf War.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="703">“SEC. 703.</num><heading> HEALTH EXAMINATIONS AND COUNSELING FOR VETERANS ELIGIBLE FOR INCLUSION IN CERTAIN HEALTH-RELATED REGISTRIES.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of Veterans Affairs—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> shall, upon the request of a veteran described in subsection (b)(1), provide the veteran with a health examination (including any appropriate diagnostic tests) and consultation and counseling with respect to the results of the examination and the tests; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> may, upon the request of a veteran described in subsection (b)(2), provide the veteran with such an examination (including diagnostic tests) and such consultation and counseling.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall carry out appropriate outreach activities with respect to the provision of any health examinations (including any diagnostic tests) and consultation and counseling services under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered Veterans</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In accordance with subsection (a)(1)(A), the Secretary shall provide an examination (including diagnostic tests), consultation, and counseling under that subsection to any veteran who is eligible for listing or inclusion in the Persian Gulf War Veterans Health Registry established by section 702.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> In accordance with subsection (a)(1)(B), the Secretary may provide an examination (including diagnostic tests), consultation, and counseling under that subsection to any veteran who is eligible for listing or inclusion in any other similar health-related registry administered by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="704">“SEC. 704.</num><heading> EXPANSION OF COVERAGE OF PERSIAN GULF REGISTRY.</heading><note topic="miscellaneous" style="-uslm-lc:I21" id="idc28739c5-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<p class="indent0">“[Amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/s734">section 734 of Pub. L. 102–190</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1074">section 1074 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces.]</p></note>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="705">“SEC. 705.</num><heading> STUDY BY OFFICE OF TECHNOLOGY ASSESSMENT OF PERSIAN GULF REGISTRY AND PERSIAN GULF WAR VETERANS HEALTH REGISTRY.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Director of the Office of Technology Assessment shall, in a manner consistent with the Technology Assessment Act of 1972 (<ref href="/us/usc/t2/s472/d">2 U.S.C. 472(d)</ref> [<ref href="/us/usc/t2/s471">2 U.S.C. 471</ref> et seq.]), assess—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the potential utility of each of the Persian Gulf Registry and the Persian Gulf War Veterans Health Registry for scientific study and assessment of the intermediate and long-term health consequences of military service in the Persian Gulf theater of operations during the Persian Gulf War;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the extent to which each registry meets the requirements of the provisions of law under which the registry is established;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> the extent to which data contained in each registry—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> are maintained in a manner that ensures permanent preservation and facilitates the effective, efficient retrieval of information that is potentially relevant to the scientific study of the intermediate and long-term health consequences of military service in the Persian Gulf theater of operations during the Persian Gulf War; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> would be useful for scientific study regarding such health consequences;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the adequacy of any plans to update each of the registries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> the extent to which the Department of Defense or the Department of Veterans Affairs, as the case may be, is assembling and maintaining information on the Persian Gulf theater of operations (including information on troop locations and atmospheric and weather conditions) in a manner that facilitates the usefulness of, maintenance of, and retrieval of information from, the applicable registry; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> the adequacy and compatibility of protocols for the health examinations and counseling provided under section 703 and health examinations provided by the Department of Defense to members of the Armed Forces for the purpose of assessing the health status of members of the Armed Forces who served in the Persian Gulf theater of operations during the Persian Gulf War.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Access to Information</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense shall provide the Director with access to such records and information under the jurisdiction of each such secretary as the Director determines necessary to permit the Director to carry out the study required under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Director shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>], submit to Congress a report on the results of the assessment carried out under this section of the Persian Gulf Registry and health-examination protocols; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> not later than 15 months after such date, submit to Congress a report on the results of the assessment carried out under this section of the Persian Gulf War Veterans Health Registry.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For the purposes of this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The term ‘Persian Gulf Registry’ means the registry established under section 734 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Years 1992 and 1993 (<ref href="/us/pl/102/190">Public Law 102–190</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/105/1411">105 Stat. 1411</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1074">10 U.S.C. 1074</ref> note), as amended by section 704.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘Persian Gulf War Veterans Health Registry’ means the Persian Gulf War Veterans Health Registry established under section 702.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="706">“SEC. 706.</num><heading> AGREEMENT WITH NATIONAL ACADEMY OF SCIENCES FOR REVIEW OF HEALTH CONSEQUENCES OF SERVICE DURING THE PERSIAN GULF WAR.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Agreement</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Veterans Affairs and Secretary of Defense jointly shall seek to enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences for the Medical Follow-Up Agency (MFUA) of the Institute of Medicine of the Academy to review existing scientific, medical, and other information on the health consequences of military service in the Persian Gulf theater of operations during the Persian Gulf War.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The agreement shall require MFUA to provide members of veterans organizations and members of the scientific community (including the Director of the Office of Technology Assessment) with the opportunity to comment on the method or methods MFUA proposes to use in conducting the review.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The agreement shall permit MFUA, in conducting the review, to examine and evaluate medical records of individuals who are included in the registries referred to in section 705(d) for purposes that MFUA considers appropriate, including the purpose of identifying illnesses of those individuals.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense shall seek to enter into the agreement under this section not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1992-11-04">Nov. 4, 1992</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The agreement under this section shall require the National Academy of Sciences to submit to the committees and secretaries referred to in paragraph (2) a report on the results of the review carried out under the agreement. Such report shall contain the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> An assessment of the effectiveness of actions taken by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense to collect and maintain information that is potentially useful for assessing the health consequences of the military service referred to in subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Recommendations on means of improving the collection and maintenance of such information.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Recommendations on whether there is sound scientific basis for an epidemiological study or studies on the health consequences of such service, and if the recommendation is that there is sound scientific basis for such a study or studies, the nature of the study or studies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> The committees and secretaries referred to in paragraph (1) are the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> The Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense shall make available up to a total of $500,000 in fiscal year 1993, from funds available to the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Department of Defense in that fiscal year, to carry out the review. Any amounts provided by the two departments shall be provided in equal amounts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> If the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense enter into an agreement under subsection (a) with the National Academy of Sciences—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall make available $250,000 in each of fiscal years 1994 through 2003, from amounts available to the Department of Veterans Affairs in each such fiscal year, to the National Academy of Sciences for the general purposes of conducting epidemiological research with respect to military and veterans populations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Secretary of Defense shall make available $250,000 in each of fiscal years 1994 through 2003, from amounts available to the Department of Defense in each such fiscal year, to the National Academy of Sciences for the purposes of carrying out the research referred to in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Research Review and Development of Medical Education Curriculum</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In order to further understand the health consequences of military service in the Persian Gulf theater of operations during the Persian Gulf War and of new research findings with implications for improving the provision of care for veterans of such service, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense shall seek to enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences under which the Institute of Medicine of the Academy would—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> develop a curriculum pertaining to the care and treatment of veterans of such service who have ill-defined or undiagnosed illnesses for use in the continuing medical education of both general and specialty physicians who provide care for such veterans; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> on an ongoing basis, periodically review and provide recommendations regarding the research plans and research strategies of the Departments relating to the health consequences of military service in the Persian Gulf theater of operations during the Persian Gulf War.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Recommendations to be provided under paragraph (1)(B) include any recommendations that the Academy considers appropriate for additional scientific studies (including studies related to treatment models) to resolve areas of continuing scientific uncertainty relating to the health consequences of any aspects of such military service. In making recommendations for additional studies, the Academy shall consider the available scientific data, the value and relevance of the information that could result from such studies, and the cost and feasibility of carrying out such studies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Not later than 9 months after the Institute of Medicine provides the Secretaries the curriculum developed under paragraph (1)(A), the Secretaries shall provide for the conduct of continuing education programs using that curriculum. Those programs shall include instruction which seeks to emphasize use of appropriate protocols of diagnosis, referral, and treatment of such veterans.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="707">“SEC. 707.</num><heading> COORDINATION OF HEALTH-RELATED GOVERNMENT ACTIVITIES ON THE PERSIAN GULF WAR.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Designation of Coordinating Organization</inline>.—</heading><content>The President shall designate, and may redesignate from time to time, the head of an appropriate department or agency of the Federal Government to coordinate all activities undertaken or funded by the Executive Branch of the Federal Government on the health consequences of military service in the Persian Gulf theater of operations during the Persian Gulf War.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Public Advisory Committee</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="1999-01-01">January 1, 1999</date>, the head of the department or agency designated under subsection (a) shall establish an advisory committee consisting of members of the general public, including Persian Gulf War veterans and representatives of such veterans, to provide advice to the head of that department or agency on proposed research studies, research plans, or research strategies relating to the health consequences of military service in the Southwest Asia theater of operations during the Persian Gulf War. The department or agency head shall consult with such advisory committee on a regular basis.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Not later than <date date="2010-07-01">July 1, 2010</date>, and July 1 of each of the five following years, the head of the department or agency designated under subsection (a) shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report on—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the status and results of all such research activities undertaken by the executive branch during the previous year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> research priorities identified during that year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Not later than 120 days after submission of the epidemiological research study conducted by the Department of Veterans Affairs entitled ‘VA National Survey of Persian Gulf Veterans—Phase III’, the head of the department or agency designated under subsection (a) shall submit to the congressional committees specified in paragraph (1) a report on the findings under that study and any other pertinent medical literature.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> With respect to any findings of that study and any other pertinent medical literature which identify scientific evidence of a greater relative risk of illness or illnesses in family members of veterans who served in the Persian Gulf War theater of operations than in family members of veterans who did not so serve, the head of the department or agency designated under subsection (a) shall seek to ensure that appropriate research studies are designed to follow up on such findings.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Public Availability of Research Findings</inline>.—</heading><content>The head of the department or agency designated under subsection (a) shall ensure that the findings of all research conducted by or for the executive branch relating to the health consequences of military service in the Persian Gulf theater of operations during the Persian Gulf War (including information pertinent to improving provision of care for veterans of such service) are made available to the public through peer-reviewed medical journals, the World Wide Web, and other appropriate media.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Outreach</inline>.—</heading><content>The head of the department or agency designated under subsection (a) shall ensure that the appropriate departments consult and coordinate in carrying out an ongoing program to provide information to those who served in the Southwest Asia theater of operations during the Persian Gulf War relating to: (1) the health risks, if any, resulting from any risk factors associated with such service; and (2) any services or benefits available with respect to such health risks.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="708">“SEC. 708.</num><heading> DEFINITION.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“For the purposes of this title, the term ‘Persian Gulf War’ has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s101/33">section 101(33) of title 38</ref>, United States Code.”</p>
</content>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc28739c6-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Services for Homeless Veterans</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/405/tI/s107">Pub. L. 102–405, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1992-10-09">Oct. 9, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1976">106 Stat. 1976</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/103/446/tX/s1002">Pub. L. 103–446, title X, § 1002</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4679">108 Stat. 4679</ref>, required Secretary of Veterans’ Affairs and directors of each medical center or benefits office to assess needs of homeless veterans and programs which have been developed to assist homeless veterans, and to replicate programs which have successfully rehabilitated homeless veterans, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/105/114/tII/s202/c/2">Pub. L. 105–114, title II, § 202(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-21">Nov. 21, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2287">111 Stat. 2287</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
