<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc3d5165e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5303"><num value="5303">§ 5303.</num><heading> Certain bars to benefits</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3d5165f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5303/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The discharge or dismissal by reason of the sentence of a general court-martial of any person from the Armed Forces, or the discharge of any such person on the ground that such person was a conscientious objector who refused to perform military duty or refused to wear the uniform or otherwise to comply with lawful orders of competent military authority, or as a deserter, or on the basis of an absence without authority from active duty for a continuous period of at least one hundred and eighty days if such person was discharged under conditions other than honorable unless such person demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that there are compelling circumstances to warrant such prolonged unauthorized absence, or of an officer by the acceptance of such officer’s resignation for the good of the service, or (except as provided in subsection (c)) the discharge of any individual during a period of hostilities as an alien, shall bar all rights of such person under laws administered by the Secretary based upon the period of service from which discharged or dismissed, notwithstanding any action subsequent to the date of such discharge by a board established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1553">section 1553 of title 10</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3d51660-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5303/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Notwithstanding subsection (a), if it is established to the satisfaction of the Secretary that, at the time of the commission of an offense leading to a person’s court-martial, discharge, or resignation, that person was insane, such person shall not be precluded from benefits under laws administered by the Secretary based upon the period of service from which such person was separated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3d51661-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5303/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> Subsection (a) shall not apply to any alien whose service was honest and faithful, and who was not discharged on the individual’s own application or solicitation as an alien. No individual shall be considered as having been discharged on the individual’s own application or solicitation as an alien in the absence of affirmative evidence establishing that the individual was so discharged.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3d51662-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5303/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><chapeau> This section shall not apply to the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3d51663-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5303/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any war-risk insurance, Government (converted) or National Service Life Insurance policy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3d51664-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5303/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Benefits under section 2011, 2012, 2013, 2044, or 2061 of this title (except for benefits for individuals discharged or dismissed from the Armed Forces by reason of the sentence of a general court-martial).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3d51665-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5303/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3d51666-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5303/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, (A) no benefits under laws administered by the Secretary shall be provided, as a result of a change in or new issuance of a discharge under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1553">section 1553 of title 10</ref>, except upon a case-by-case review by the board of review concerned, subject to review by the Secretary concerned, under such section, of all the evidence and factors in each case under published uniform standards (which shall be historically consistent with criteria for determining honorable service and shall not include any criterion for automatically granting or denying such change or issuance) and procedures generally applicable to all persons administratively discharged or released from active military, naval, air, or space service under other than honorable conditions; and (B) any such person shall be afforded an opportunity to apply for such review under such section 1553 for a period of time terminating not less than one year after the date on which such uniform standards and procedures are promulgated and published.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3d51667-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5303/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of law—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3d51668-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5303/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> no person discharged or released from active military, naval, air, or space service under other than honorable conditions who has been awarded a general or honorable discharge under revised standards for the review of discharges, (i) as implemented by the President’s directive of <date date="1977-01-19">January 19, 1977</date>, initiating further action with respect to the President’s Proclamation 4313 of <date date="1974-09-16">September 16, 1974</date>, (ii) as implemented on or after <date date="1977-04-05">April 5, 1977</date>, under the Department of Defense’s special discharge review program, or (iii) as implemented subsequent to <date date="1977-04-05">April 5, 1977</date>, and not made applicable to all persons administratively discharged or released from active military, naval, air, or space service under other than honorable conditions, shall be entitled to benefits under laws administered by the Secretary except upon a determination, based on a case-by-case review, under standards (meeting the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection) applied by the board of review concerned under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1553">section 1553 of title 10</ref>, subject to review by the Secretary concerned, that such person would be awarded an upgraded discharge under such standards; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3d51669-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5303/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such determination shall be made by such board (i) on an expedited basis after notification by the Department to the Secretary concerned that such person has received, is in receipt of, or has applied for such benefits or after a written request is made by such person or such determination, (ii) on its own initiative before <date date="1978-10-09">October 9, 1978</date>, in any case where a general or honorable discharge has been awarded before <date date="1977-10-09">October 9, 1977</date>, under revised standards referred to in clause (A)(i), (ii), or (iii) of this paragraph, or (iii) on its own initiative at the time a general or honorable discharge is so awarded in any case where a general or honorable discharge is awarded after <date date="1977-10-08">October 8, 1977</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">If such board makes a preliminary determination that such person would not have been awarded an upgraded discharge under standards meeting the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection, such person shall be entitled to an appearance before the board, as provided for in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1553/c">section 1553(c) of title 10</ref>, prior to a final determination on such question and shall be given written notice by the board of such preliminary determination and of the right to such appearance. The Secretary shall, as soon as administratively feasible, notify the appropriate board of review of the receipt of benefits under laws administered by the Secretary, or of the application for such benefits, by any person awarded an upgraded discharge under revised standards referred to in clause (A)(i), (ii), or (iii) of this paragraph with respect to whom a favorable determination has not been made under this paragraph.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc3d7876a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">(<ref href="/us/pl/85/857">Pub. L. 85–857</ref>, <date date="1958-09-02">Sept. 2, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1230">72 Stat. 1230</ref>, § 3103; <ref href="/us/pl/86/113">Pub. L. 86–113</ref>, <date date="1959-07-28">July 28, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/262">73 Stat. 262</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/126/s1/a">Pub. L. 95–126, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-10-08">Oct. 8, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1106">91 Stat. 1106</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/295/s4/75">Pub. L. 97–295, § 4(75)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1310">96 Stat. 1310</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/576/tVII/s701/70">Pub. L. 99–576, title VII, § 701(70)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-28">Oct. 28, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3296">100 Stat. 3296</ref>; renumbered § 5303, <ref href="/us/pl/102/40/tIV/s402/b/1">Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/238">105 Stat. 238</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s4/a/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, (3), (4), (b)(1), (2)(E), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/403-405">105 Stat. 403–405</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/315/tVII/s702">Pub. L. 114–315, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1585">130 Stat. 1585</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tIX/s926/a/55">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 926(a)(55)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3830">134 Stat. 3830</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc3d7876b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc3d7876c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc3d7876d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">President’s Proclamation 4313 of <date date="1974-09-16">September 16, 1974</date>, referred to in subsec. (e)(2)(A), is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3811">section 3811 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc3d7876e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> substituted “air, or space service” for “or air service” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/114/315">Pub. L. 114–315</ref> substituted “not apply to the following:” and pars. (1) and (2) for “not apply to any war-risk insurance, Government (converted) or National Service Life Insurance policy.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—<ref href="/us/pl/102/40">Pub. L. 102–40</ref> renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3103">section 3103 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (a), (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s4/b/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, (2)(E), substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s4/a/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “administered by the Secretary” for “administered by the Veterans’ Administration”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s4/a/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “administered by the Secretary” for “administered by the Veterans’ Administration”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s4/b/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, (2)(E), substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator” in last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s4/a/3">Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(a)(3)</ref>, (4), substituted “Department” for “Veterans’ Administration” in subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s4/a/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “administered by the Secretary” for “administered by the Veterans’ Administration” in subpar. (A) and last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/576/s701/70/A">Pub. L. 99–576, § 701(70)(A)</ref>, substituted “such person” for “he” after “on the ground that” and “such officer’s” for “his” before “resignation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/576/s701/70/B">Pub. L. 99–576, § 701(70)(B)</ref>, substituted “a person’s” for “his”, “that person” for “any person”, and “such person” for “he” before “was separated”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/576/s701/70/C">Pub. L. 99–576, § 701(70)(C)</ref>, substituted “the individual’s” for “his” in two places, and “the individual” for “he”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/576/s701/70/D">Pub. L. 99–576, § 701(70)(D)</ref>, substituted “the” for “his or her” before “right to such appearance” at end of second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (e)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/97/295">Pub. L. 97–295</ref> substituted “before <date date="1978-10-09">October 9, 1978</date>,” for “within one year after the date of enactment of this paragraph”, “before <date date="1977-10-09">October 9, 1977</date>,” for “on or prior to the date of enactment of this paragraph”, and “<date date="1977-10-08">October 8, 1977</date>” for “such enactment date”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/126/s1/a/1">Pub. L. 95–126, § 1(a)(1)</ref>, inserted provisions barring a person in the Armed Forces from being a recipient of benefits when discharged on the basis of an absence without authority from active duty for a continuous period of at least one hundred and eighty days if such person was discharged under conditions other than honorable unless such person demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Administrator that there are compelling circumstances to warrant such prolonged unauthorized absence and barred benefits notwithstanding any action subsequent to the date of such discharge by a board established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1553">section 1553 of Title 10</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/95/126/s1/a/2">Pub. L. 95–126, § 1(a)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1959—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/86/113">Pub. L. 86–113</ref> required affirmative evidence to establish that alien was discharged on his own application or solicitation.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc3d7876f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc3d78770-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1977 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/126/s5">Pub. L. 95–126, § 5</ref>, <date date="1977-10-08">Oct. 8, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1108">91 Stat. 1108</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/126/s5">
<inline>“This Act [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s101">section 101 of this title</ref> and enacting provisions set out below] shall become effective on the date of its enactment [<date date="1977-10-08">Oct. 8, 1977</date>], except that—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> section 2 [set out below] shall become effective on <date date="1977-10-01">October 1, 1977</date>, or on such enactment date, whichever is later; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> the amendments made by section 1(a) [amending this section] shall apply retroactively to deny benefits under laws administered by the Veterans’ Administration, except that, notwithstanding any other provision of law—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> with respect to any person who, on such enactment date [<date date="1977-10-08">Oct. 8, 1977</date>] is receiving benefits under laws administered by the Veterans’ Administration, (i) such benefits shall not be terminated under paragraph (2) of section 3103(e) [now 5303(e)] of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 1(a)(2) of this Act, until (I) the day on which a final determination not favorable to the person concerned is made on an expedited basis under paragraph (2) of such section 3103(e) [now 5303(e)], (II) the day following the expiration of ninety days after a preliminary determination not favorable to such person is made under such paragraph, or (III) the day following the expiration of one hundred and eighty days after such enactment date, whichever day is the earliest, and (ii) the United States shall not make any claim to recover the value of any benefits provided to such person prior to such earliest day;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> with respect to any person awarded a general or honorable discharge under revised standards for the review of discharges referred to in clause (A) (i), (ii), or (iii) of such paragraph who has been provided any such benefits prior to such enactment date [<date date="1977-10-08">Oct. 8, 1977</date>], the United States shall not make any claim to recover the value of any benefits so provided; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the amendments made by clause (1) of section 1(a) [amending this section] shall apply (i) retroactively only to persons awarded general or honorable discharges under such revised standards and to persons who, prior to the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1977-10-08">Oct. 8, 1977</date>], had not attained general eligibility for such benefits by virtue of (I) a change in or new issuance of a discharge under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1553">section 1553 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, or (II) any other provision of law, and (ii) prospectively (on and after such enactment date) to all other persons.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc3d78771-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Expedited Determinations After Information and Notification to Persons Awarded General or Honorable Discharges; Procedures for Application to Title 10 § 1552 Board and to Secretary of Veterans Affairs</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/126/s1/b">Pub. L. 95–126, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1977-10-08">Oct. 8, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1107">91 Stat. 1107</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/527/s10/1">Pub. L. 100–527, § 10(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1988-10-25">Oct. 25, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2640">102 Stat. 2640</ref>, 2641; <ref href="/us/pl/102/40/tIV/s402/d/2">Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/239">105 Stat. 239</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/40/tIV/s402/d/2">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall fully inform each person awarded a general or honorable discharge under revised standards for the review of discharges referred to in section 5303(e)(2)(A)(i), (ii), or (iii) [formerly 3103(e)(2)(A)(i), (ii), or (iii)] of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)(2) of this section, of his or her right to obtain an expedited determination under section 5303(e)(2)(B)(i) [formerly 3103(e)(2)(B)(i)] of such title and of the implications of the provisions of this Act [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s101/18">section 101(18) of this title</ref> and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section] for each such person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Defense shall inform each person who applies to a board of review under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1553">section 1553 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, and who appears to have been discharged under circumstances which might constitute a bar to benefits under section 5303(a) [formerly 3103(a)] of title 38, United States Code, (A) that such person might possibly be administratively found to be entitled to benefits under laws administered by the Department of Veterans Affairs only through the action of a board for the correction of military records under section 1552 of such title 10 or the action of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs under section 5303 [formerly 3103] of such title 38, and (B) of the procedures for making application to such section 1552 board for such purpose and to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for such purpose (including the right to proceed concurrently under such sections 5303 [formerly 3103], 1552, and 1553).”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc3d78772-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Health Care and Benefits for Disability During Active Service in Line of Duty, Except When Barred Under Subsec. (a) or by Bad Conduct Discharge</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/126/s2">Pub. L. 95–126, § 2</ref>, <date date="1977-10-08">Oct. 8, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1107">91 Stat. 1107</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/527/s10/1">Pub. L. 100–527, § 10(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-25">Oct. 25, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2640">102 Stat. 2640</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/40/tIV/s402/d/2">Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/239">105 Stat. 239</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/40/tIV/s402/d/2">“Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall provide the type of health care and related benefits authorized to be provided under chapter 17 of title 38, United States Code, for any disability incurred or aggravated during active military, naval, or air service in line of duty by a person other than a person barred from receiving benefits by section 5303(a) [formerly 3103(a)] of such title, but shall not provide such health care and related benefits pursuant to this section for any disability incurred or aggravated during a period of service from which such person was discharged by reason of a bad conduct discharge.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc3d78773-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations Respecting Standards and Procedures for Determination of Separation From Active Service Under Conditions Other Than Dishonorable Free of Unique or Special Advantages or Special Distinctions Between Veterans</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/126/s4">Pub. L. 95–126, § 4</ref>, <date date="1977-10-08">Oct. 8, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1108">91 Stat. 1108</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/527/s10/1">Pub. L. 100–527, § 10(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1988-10-25">Oct. 25, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2640">102 Stat. 2640</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/40/tIV/s402/d/2">Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/239">105 Stat. 239</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/40/tIV/s402/d/2">“In promulgating, or making any revisions of or amendments to, regulations governing the standards and procedures by which the Department of Veterans Affairs determines whether a person was discharged or released from active military, naval, or air service under conditions other than dishonorable, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall, in keeping with the spirit and intent of this Act [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s101/18">section 101(18) of this title</ref> and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section], not promulgate any such regulations or revise or amend any such regulations for the purpose of, or having the effect of, (1) providing any unique or special advantage to veterans awarded general or honorable discharges under revised standards for the review of discharges described in section 5303(e)(2)(A)(i), (ii), or (iii) [formerly 3103(e)(2)(A)(i), (ii), or (iii)] of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 1(a)(2) of this Act, or (2) otherwise making any special distinction between such veterans and other veterans.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
