<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc3e0fe22-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723"><num value="5723">§ 5723.</num><heading> Responsibilities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3e0fe23-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secretary of Veterans Affairs</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In accordance with the provisions of subchapter III of chapter 35 of title 44, the Secretary is responsible for the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe24-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Ensuring that the Department adopts a Department-wide information security program and otherwise complies with the provisions of subchapter III of chapter 35 of title 44 and other related information security requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe25-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Ensuring that information security protections are commensurate with the risk and magnitude of the potential harm to Department information and information systems resulting from unauthorized access, use, disclosure, disruption, modification, or destruction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe26-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Ensuring that information security management processes are integrated with Department strategic and operational planning processes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe27-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Ensuring that the Under Secretaries, Assistant Secretaries, and other key officials of the Department provide adequate security for the information and information systems under their control.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe28-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Ensuring enforcement and compliance with the requirements imposed on the Department under the provisions of subchapter III of chapter 35 of title 44.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe29-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Ensuring that the Department has trained program and staff office personnel sufficient to assist in complying with all the provisions of subchapter III of chapter 35 of title 44 and other related information security requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe2a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Ensuring that the Assistant Secretary for Information and Technology, in coordination with the Under Secretaries, Assistant Secretaries, and other key officials of the Department report to Congress, the Office of Management and Budget, and other entities as required by law and Executive Branch direction on the effectiveness of the Department information security program, including remedial actions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe2b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> Notifying officials other than officials of the Department of data breaches when required under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe2c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> Ensuring that the Assistant Secretary for Information and Technology has the authority and control necessary to develop, approve, implement, integrate, and oversee the policies, procedures, processes, activities, and systems of the Department relating to subchapter III of chapter 35 of title 44, including the management of all related mission applications, information resources, personnel, and infrastructure.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe2d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> Submitting to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives, the Committee on Government Reform of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, not later than March 1 each year, a report on the compliance of the Department with subchapter III of chapter 35 of title 44, with the information in such report displayed in the aggregate and separately for each Administration, office, and facility of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe2e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/a/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> Taking appropriate action to ensure that the budget for any fiscal year, as submitted by the President to Congress under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105">section 1105 of title 31</ref>, sets forth separately the amounts required in the budget for such fiscal year for compliance by the Department with Federal law and regulations governing information security, including this subchapter and subchapter III of chapter 35 of title 44.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe2f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/a/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> Providing notice to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Inspector General of the Department, and such other Federal agencies as the Secretary considers appropriate of a presumptive data breach of which notice is provided the Secretary under subsection (b)(16) if, in the opinion of the Assistant Secretary for Information and Technology, the breach involves the information of twenty or more individuals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3e0fe30-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assistant Secretary for Information and Technology</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Assistant Secretary for Information and Technology, as the Chief Information Officer of the Department, is responsible for the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe31-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Establishing, maintaining, and monitoring Department-wide information security policies, procedures, control techniques, training, and inspection requirements as elements of the Department information security program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe32-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Issuing policies and handbooks to provide direction for implementing the elements of the information security program to all Department organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe33-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Approving all policies and procedures that are related to information security for those areas of responsibility that are currently under the management and the oversight of other Department organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe34-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Ordering and enforcing Department-wide compliance with and execution of any information security policy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe35-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Establishing minimum mandatory technical, operational, and management information security control requirements for each Department system, consistent with risk, the processes identified in standards of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and the responsibilities of the Assistant Secretary to operate and maintain all Department systems currently creating, processing, collecting, or disseminating data on behalf of Department information owners.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe36-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Establishing standards for access to Department information systems by organizations and individual employees, and to deny access as appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe37-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Directing that any incidents of failure to comply with established information security policies be immediately reported to the Assistant Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe38-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> Reporting any compliance failure or policy violation directly to the appropriate Under Secretary, Assistant Secretary, or other key official of the Department for appropriate administrative or disciplinary action.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe39-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> Reporting any compliance failure or policy violation directly to the appropriate Under Secretary, Assistant Secretary, or other key official of the Department along with taking action to correct the failure or violation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe3a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> Requiring any key official of the Department who is so notified to report to the Assistant Secretary with respect to an action to be taken in response to any compliance failure or policy violation reported by the Assistant Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe3b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/b/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> Ensuring that the Chief Information Officers and Information Security Officers of the Department comply with all cyber security directives and mandates, and ensuring that these staff members have all necessary authority and means to direct full compliance with such directives and mandates relating to the acquisition, operation, maintenance, or use of information technology resources from all facility staff.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe3c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/b/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> Establishing the VA National Rules of Behavior for appropriate use and protection of the information which is used to support Department missions and functions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe3d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/b/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> Establishing and providing supervision over an effective incident reporting system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe3e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/b/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> Submitting to the Secretary, at least once every quarter, a report on any deficiency in the compliance with subchapter III of chapter 35 of title 44 of the Department or any Administration, office, or facility of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe3f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/b/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content> Reporting immediately to the Secretary on any significant deficiency in the compliance described by paragraph (14).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe40-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/b/16"><num value="16">(16)</num><content> Providing immediate notice to the Secretary of any presumptive data breach.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3e0fe41-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Associate Deputy Assistant Secretary for Cyber and Information Security</inline>.—</heading><content>In accordance with the provisions of subchapter III of chapter 35 of title 44, the Associate Deputy Assistant Secretary for Cyber and Information Security, as the Senior Information Security Officer of the Department, is responsible for carrying out the responsibilities of the Assistant Secretary for Information and Technology under the provisions of subchapter III of chapter 35 of title 44, as set forth in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3e0fe42-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Department Information Owners</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In accordance with the criteria of the Centralized IT Management System, Department information owners are responsible for the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe43-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Providing assistance to the Assistant Secretary for Information and Technology regarding the security requirements and appropriate level of security controls for the information system or systems where sensitive personal information is currently created, collected, processed, disseminated, or subject to disposal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe44-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Determining who has access to the system or systems containing sensitive personal information, including types of privileges and access rights.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe45-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Ensuring the VA National Rules of Behavior is signed on an annual basis and enforced by all system users to ensure appropriate use and protection of the information which is used to support Department missions and functions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe46-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Assisting the Assistant Secretary for Information and Technology in the identification and assessment of the common security controls for systems where their information resides.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe47-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Providing assistance to Administration and staff office personnel involved in the development of new systems regarding the appropriate level of security controls for their information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3e0fe48-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other Key Officials</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In accordance with the provisions of subchapter III of chapter 35 of title 44, the Under Secretaries, Assistant Secretaries, and other key officials of the Department are responsible for the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe49-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Implementing the policies, procedures, practices, and other countermeasures identified in the Department information security program that comprise activities that are under their day-to-day operational control or supervision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe4a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Periodically testing and evaluating information security controls that comprise activities that are under their day-to-day operational control or supervision to ensure effective implementation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe4b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Providing a plan of action and milestones to the Assistant Secretary for Information and Technology on at least a quarterly basis detailing the status of actions being taken to correct any security compliance failure or policy violation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe4c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Complying with the provisions of subchapter III of chapter 35 of title 44 and other related information security laws and requirements in accordance with orders of the Assistant Secretary for Information and Technology to execute the appropriate security controls commensurate to responding to a security bulletin of the Security Operations Center of the Department, with such orders to supersede and take priority over all operational tasks and assignments and be complied with immediately.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe4d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> Ensuring that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3e0fe4e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/e/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> all employees within their organizations take immediate action to comply with orders from the Assistant Secretary for Information and Technology to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc3e0fe4f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/e/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> mitigate the impact of any potential security vulnerability;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc3e0fe50-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/e/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> respond to a security incident; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc3e0fe51-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/e/5/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> implement the provisions of a bulletin or alert of the Security Operations Center; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc3e0fe52-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/e/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> organizational managers have all necessary authority and means to direct full compliance with such orders from the Assistant Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe53-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/e/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Ensuring the VA National Rules of Behavior is signed and enforced by all system users to ensure appropriate use and protection of the information which is used to support Department missions and functions on an annual basis.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3e0fe54-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Users of Department Information and Information Systems</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Users of Department information and information systems are responsible for the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe55-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Complying with all Department information security program policies, procedures, and practices.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe56-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Attending security awareness training on at least an annual basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe57-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Reporting all security incidents immediately to the Information Security Officer of the system or facility and to their immediate supervisor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe58-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Complying with orders from the Assistant Secretary for Information and Technology directing specific activities when a security incident occurs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe59-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/f/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Signing an acknowledgment that they have read, understand, and agree to abide by the VA National Rules of Behavior on an annual basis.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc3e0fe5a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inspector General of Department of Veterans Affairs</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In accordance with the provisions of subchapter III of chapter 35 of title 44, the Inspector General of the Department is responsible for the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe5b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Conducting an annual audit of the Department information security program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe5c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Submitting an independent annual report to the Office of Management and Budget on the status of the Department information security program, based on the results of the annual audit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc3e0fe5d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s5723/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Conducting investigations of complaints and referrals of violations as considered appropriate by the Inspector General.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc3e0fe5e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/tIX/s902/a">Pub. L. 109–461, title IX, § 902(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3451">120 Stat. 3451</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/111/275/tX/s1001/m/1">Pub. L. 111–275, title X, § 1001(m)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-13">Oct. 13, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2897">124 Stat. 2897</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc3e0fe5f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc3e0fe60-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc3e0fe61-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (g)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/275">Pub. L. 111–275</ref> inserted “the” before “Department”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc3e0fe62-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idc3e0fe63-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Government Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Tenth Congress, <date date="2007-01-05">Jan. 5, 2007</date>. Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Reform of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Sixteenth Congress, <date date="2019-01-09">Jan. 9, 2019</date>. Committee on Oversight and Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Accountability of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Eighteenth Congress, <date date="2023-01-09">Jan. 9, 2023</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
