<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc290d656-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714"><num value="714">§ 714.</num><heading> Employees: removal, demotion, or suspension based on performance or misconduct</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d657-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d658-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary may remove, demote, or suspend a covered individual who is an employee of the Department if the Secretary determines the performance or misconduct of the covered individual warrants such removal, demotion, or suspension.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d659-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> If the Secretary so removes, demotes, or suspends such a covered individual, the Secretary may—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc290d65a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> remove the covered individual from the civil service (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2101">section 2101 of title 5</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc290d65b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> demote the covered individual by means of a reduction in grade for which the covered individual is qualified, that the Secretary determines is appropriate, and that reduces the annual rate of pay of the covered individual; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc290d65c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> suspend the covered individual.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d65d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pay of Certain Demoted Individuals</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d65e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any covered individual subject to a demotion under subsection (a)(2) shall, beginning on the date of such demotion, receive the annual rate of pay applicable to such grade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d65f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d660-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A covered individual so demoted may not be placed on administrative leave during the period during which an appeal (if any) under this section is ongoing, and may only receive pay if the covered individual reports for duty or is approved to use accrued unused annual, sick, family medical, military, or court leave.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d661-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> If a covered individual so demoted does not report for duty or receive approval to use accrued unused leave, such covered individual shall not receive pay or other benefits pursuant to subsection (d)(5).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d662-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Procedure</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d663-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d664-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The aggregate period for notice, response, and final decision in a removal, demotion, or suspension under this section may not exceed 15 business days.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d665-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The period for the response of a covered individual to a notice of a proposed removal, demotion, or suspension under this section shall be 7 business days.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d666-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Paragraph (3) of subsection (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7513">section 7513 of title 5</ref> shall apply with respect to a removal, demotion, or suspension under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d667-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/c/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The procedures in this subsection shall supersede any collective bargaining agreement to the extent that such agreement is inconsistent with such procedures.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d668-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall issue a final decision with respect to a removal, demotion, or suspension under this section not later than 15 business days after the Secretary provides notice, including a file containing all the evidence in support of the proposed action, to the covered individual of the removal, demotion, or suspension. The decision shall be in writing and shall include the specific reasons therefor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d669-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The procedures under chapter 43 of title 5 shall not apply to a removal, demotion, or suspension under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d66a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d66b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Subject to subparagraph (B) and subsection (d), any removal or demotion under this section, and any suspension of more than 14 days under this section, may be appealed to the Merit Systems Protection Board, which shall refer such appeal to an administrative judge pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7701/b/1">section 7701(b)(1) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d66c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> An appeal under subparagraph (A) of a removal, demotion, or suspension may only be made if such appeal is made not later than 10 business days after the date of such removal, demotion, or suspension.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d66d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Expedited Review</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d66e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Upon receipt of an appeal under subsection (c)(4)(A), the administrative judge shall expedite any such appeal under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7701/b/1">section 7701(b)(1) of title 5</ref> and, in any such case, shall issue a final and complete decision not later than 180 days after the date of the appeal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d66f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d670-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7701/c/1/B">section 7701(c)(1)(B) of title 5</ref>, the administrative judge shall uphold the decision of the Secretary to remove, demote, or suspend an employee under subsection (a) if the decision is supported by substantial evidence.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d671-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Notwithstanding title 5 or any other provision of law, if the decision of the Secretary is supported by substantial evidence, the administrative judge shall not mitigate the penalty prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d672-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d673-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The decision of the administrative judge under paragraph (1) may be appealed to the Merit Systems Protection Board.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d674-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7701/c/1/B">section 7701(c)(1)(B) of title 5</ref>, the Merit Systems Protection Board shall uphold the decision of the Secretary to remove, demote, or suspend an employee under subsection (a) if the decision is supported by substantial evidence.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d675-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/d/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Notwithstanding title 5 or any other provision of law, if the decision of the Secretary is supported by substantial evidence, the Merit Systems Protection Board shall not mitigate the penalty prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d676-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> In any case in which the administrative judge cannot issue a decision in accordance with the 180-day requirement under paragraph (1), the Merit Systems Protection Board shall, not later than 14 business days after the expiration of the 180-day period, submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report that explains the reasons why a decision was not issued in accordance with such requirement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d677-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d678-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/d/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A decision of the Merit Systems Protection Board under paragraph (3) may be appealed to the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7703">section 7703 of title 5</ref> or to any court of appeals of competent jurisdiction pursuant to subsection (b)(1)(B) of such section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d679-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/d/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any decision by such Court shall be in compliance with <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s7462/f/2">section 7462(f)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d67a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The Merit Systems Protection Board may not stay any removal or demotion under this section, except as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1214/b">section 1214(b) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d67b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/d/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> During the period beginning on the date on which a covered individual appeals a removal from the civil service under subsection (c) and ending on the date that the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit issues a final decision on such appeal, such covered individual may not receive any pay, awards, bonuses, incentives, allowances, differentials, student loan repayments, special payments, or benefits related to the employment of the individual by the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d67c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/d/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall provide to the Merit Systems Protection Board such information and assistance as may be necessary to ensure an appeal under this subsection is expedited.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d67d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/d/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> If an employee prevails on appeal under this section, the employee shall be entitled to backpay (as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5596">section 5596 of title 5</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d67e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/d/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> If an employee who is subject to a collective bargaining agreement chooses to grieve an action taken under this section through a grievance procedure provided under the collective bargaining agreement, the timelines and procedures set forth in subsection (c) and this subsection shall apply.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d67f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Whistleblower Protection</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d680-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In the case of a covered individual seeking corrective action (or on behalf of whom corrective action is sought) from the Office of Special Counsel based on an alleged prohibited personnel practice described in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2302/b">section 2302(b) of title 5</ref>, the Secretary may not remove, demote, or suspend such covered individual under subsection (a) without the approval of the Special Counsel under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1214/f">section 1214(f) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d681-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> In the case of a covered individual who has made a whistleblower disclosure to the Assistant Secretary for Accountability and Whistleblower Protection, the Secretary may not remove, demote, or suspend such covered individual under subsection (a) until—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc290d682-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in the case in which the Assistant Secretary determines to refer the whistleblower disclosure under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s323/c/1/D">section 323(c)(1)(D) of this title</ref> to an office or other investigative entity, a final decision with respect to the whistleblower disclosure has been made by such office or other investigative entity; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc290d683-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case in which the Assistant Secretary determines not to refer the whistleblower disclosure under such section, the Assistant Secretary makes such determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d684-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination of Investigations by Office of Special Counsel</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d685-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Special Counsel (established by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1211">section 1211 of title 5</ref>) may terminate an investigation of a prohibited personnel practice alleged by an employee or former employee of the Department after the Special Counsel provides to the employee or former employee a written statement of the reasons for the termination of the investigation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d686-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Such statement may not be admissible as evidence in any judicial or administrative proceeding without the consent of such employee or former employee.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d687-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Vacancies</inline>.—</heading><content>In the case of a covered individual who is removed or demoted under subsection (a), to the maximum extent feasible, the Secretary shall fill the vacancy arising as a result of such removal or demotion.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc290d688-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc290d689-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The term “covered individual” means an individual occupying a position at the Department, but does not include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc290d68a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an individual occupying a senior executive position (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s713/d">section 713(d) of this title</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc290d68b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> an individual appointed pursuant to sections 7306, 7401(1), 7401(4), or 7405 of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc290d68c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/h/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> an individual who has not completed a probationary or trial period; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc290d68d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/h/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> a political appointee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc290d68e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “suspend” means the placing of an employee, for disciplinary reasons, in a temporary status without duties and pay for a period in excess of 14 days.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc290d68f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “grade” has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7511/a">section 7511(a) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc290d690-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/h/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The term “misconduct” includes neglect of duty, malfeasance, or failure to accept a directed reassignment or to accompany a position in a transfer of function.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc290d691-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/h/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> The term “political appointee” means an individual who is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc290d692-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/h/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> employed in a position described under sections 5312 through 5316 of title 5 (relating to the Executive Schedule);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc290d693-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/h/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a limited term appointee, limited emergency appointee, or noncareer appointee in the Senior Executive Service, as defined under paragraphs (5), (6), and (7), respectively, of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3132/a">section 3132(a) of title 5</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc290d694-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/h/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> employed in a position of a confidential or policy-determining character under schedule C of subpart C of part 213 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations, or successor regulation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc290d695-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s714/h/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The term “whistleblower disclosure” has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s323/g">section 323(g) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc290d696-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/115/41/tII/s202/a">Pub. L. 115–41, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-06-23">June 23, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/869">131 Stat. 869</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/116/61/s6/1">Pub. L. 116–61, § 6(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-09-30">Sept. 30, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1116">133 Stat. 1116</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc290d697-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc290d698-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idc290d699-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 714 was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1914">section 1914 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc290d69a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (e)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/116/61">Pub. L. 116–61</ref> substituted “to refer” for “to the refer”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
