<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc410bfd6-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455"><num value="7455">§ 7455.</num><heading> Increases in rates of basic pay</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc410bfd7-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc410bfd8-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Subject to subsections (b), (c), and (d), when the Secretary determines it to be necessary in order to obtain or retain the services of persons described in paragraph (2), the Secretary may increase the minimum, intermediate, or maximum rates of basic pay authorized under applicable statutes and regulations. Any increase in such rates of basic pay—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc410bfd9-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> may be made on a nationwide basis, local basis, or other geographic basis; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc410bfda-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> may be made—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc410bfdb-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/a/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> for one or more of the grades listed in the schedules in subsection (b)(1) of section 7404 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002117">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002117"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc410bfdc-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/a/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> for one or more of the health personnel fields within such grades; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc410bfdd-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/a/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> for one or more of the grades of the General Schedule under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5332">section 5332 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc410bfde-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Paragraph (1) applies to the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc410bfdf-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Individuals employed in positions listed in paragraphs (1) and (3) of <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s7401">section 7401 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc410bfe0-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Health-care personnel who—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc410bfe1-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/a/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> are employed in the Administration (other than administrative, clerical, and physical plant maintenance and protective services employees);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc410bfe2-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/a/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> are paid under the General Schedule pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5332">section 5332 of title 5</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc410bfe3-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/a/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> are determined by the Secretary to be providing either direct patient-care services or services incident to direct patient-care services; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc410bfe4-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/a/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> would not otherwise be available to provide medical care and treatment for veterans.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc410bfe5-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Employees who are Department police officers providing services under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s902">section 902 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc410bfe6-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> Increases in rates of basic pay may be made under subsection (a) only in order—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc410bfe7-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to provide pay in an amount competitive with, but not exceeding, the amount of the same type of pay paid to the same category of personnel at non-Federal facilities in the same labor market;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc410bfe8-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to achieve adequate staffing at particular facilities; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc410bfe9-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to recruit personnel with specialized skills, especially those with skills which are especially difficult or demanding.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc410bfea-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc410bfeb-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Subject to paragraph (2), the amount of any increase under subsection (a) in the minimum rate for any grade may not (except in the case of nurse anesthetists, licensed practical nurses, licensed vocational nurses, nursing positions otherwise covered by title 5, pharmacists, and licensed physical therapists) exceed the maximum rate of basic pay (excluding any locality-based comparability payment under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5304">section 5304 of title 5</ref> or similar provision of law) for the grade or level by more than 50 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc410bfec-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> No rate may be established under this section in excess of the rate of basic pay payable for level II of the Executive Schedule.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc410bfed-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc410bfee-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5304">section 5304 of title 5</ref> or any other provision of law, but subject to the limitation under paragraph (2), pursuant to an increase under subsection (a), the Secretary may pay a special rate or an adjusted rate of basic pay in excess of the rate of basic pay payable for level IV of the Executive Schedule.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc410bfef-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> If an employee is in receipt of a special rate of pay under subparagraph (A) in excess of the rate of basic pay payable for level IV of the Executive Schedule with an established special rate supplement of greater value than a supplement based on the applicable locality-based comparability payment percentage under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5304">section 5304 of title 5</ref>, but a pay adjustment would cause such established special rate supplement to be of lesser value, the special rate supplement shall be converted to a supplement based on the applicable locality-based comparability percentage unless the Secretary determines that some other action is appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc410bff0-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc410bff1-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In the exercise of the authority provided in subsection (a) with respect to personnel described in subparagraph (B) or (C) of paragraph (2) of that subsection to increase the rates of basic pay for any category of personnel not appointed under subchapter I, the Secretary shall, not less than 45 days before the effective date of a proposed increase, notify the President of the Secretary’s intention to provide such an increase.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc410bff2-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Such a proposed increase shall not take effect if, before the effective date of the proposed increase, the President disapproves such increase and provides the appropriate committees of the Congress with a written statement of the President’s reasons for such disapproval.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc410bff3-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7455/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If, before that effective date, the President approves such increase, the Secretary may advance the effective date to any date not earlier than the date of the President’s approval.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc410bff4-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/102/40/tIV/s401/b/4">Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 401(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/234">105 Stat. 234</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s2/c/7">Pub. L. 102–83, § 2(c)(7)</ref>, <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/402">105 Stat. 402</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/405/tII/s201">Pub. L. 102–405, title II, § 201</ref>, title III, § 302(c)(1), <date date="1992-10-09">Oct. 9, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1983">106 Stat. 1983</ref>, 1984; <ref href="/us/pl/106/419/tII/s203">Pub. L. 106–419, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2000-11-01">Nov. 1, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1841">114 Stat. 1841</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/163/tVI/s601">Pub. L. 111–163, title VI, § 601</ref>(<i>l</i>), <date date="2010-05-05">May 5, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1172">124 Stat. 1172</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/168/tIX/s904/a">Pub. L. 117–168, title IX, § 904(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-08-10">Aug. 10, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/1811">136 Stat. 1811</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc410bff5-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc410bff6-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc410bff7-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t38/s7404/b">Section 7404(b) of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (a)(1)(B)(i), was amended by <ref href="/us/pl/108/445/s3/a/1">Pub. L. 108–445, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-03">Dec. 3, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/2636">118 Stat. 2636</ref>. As so amended, section 7404(b) no longer contains paragraphs. Schedules appear under section 7404(b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Level II of the Executive Schedule, referred to in subsec. (c)(2), is set out in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5313">section 5313 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Level IV of the Executive Schedule, referred to in subsec. (c)(3), is set out in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5315">section 5315 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idc410bff8-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s4107/g">section 4107(g) of this title</ref> prior to the repeal of that section as part of the complete revision of chapter 73 of this title by <ref href="/us/pl/102/40">Pub. L. 102–40</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc410bff9-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/168/s904/a/1">Pub. L. 117–168, § 904(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “50 percent” for “30 percent”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/117/168/s904/a/2">Pub. L. 117–168, § 904(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “level II” for “level IV”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/117/168/s904/a/3">Pub. L. 117–168, § 904(a)(3)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/111/163">Pub. L. 111–163</ref> amended subsec. (c) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (c) read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(c)(1) The amount of any increase under subsection (a) in the maximum rate for any grade may not (except in the case of nurse anesthetists, pharmacists, and licensed physical therapists) exceed by two times the amount by which the maximum for such grade (under applicable provisions of law other than this subsection) exceeds the minimum for such grade (under applicable provisions of law other than this subsection), and the maximum rate as so increased may not exceed the rate paid for individuals serving as Assistant Under Secretary for Health.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2) Whenever the amount of an increase under subsection (a) results in a rate of basic pay for a position being equal to or greater than the amount that is 94 percent of the maximum amount permitted under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall promptly notify the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives of the increase and the amount thereof.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/106/419">Pub. L. 106–419</ref> inserted “, pharmacists,” after “anesthetists”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/405/s302/c/1">Pub. L. 102–405, § 302(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “Under Secretary for Health” for “Chief Medical Director” in par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/405/s201">Pub. L. 102–405, § 201</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted “by two times” after first reference to “exceed”, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (a)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83">Pub. L. 102–83</ref> substituted “902” for “218”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idc410bffa-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idc410bffb-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 12797. Review of Increases in Rates of Basic Pay for Certain Employees of Department of Veterans Affairs and Other Agencies</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 12797, <date date="1992-04-03">Apr. 3, 1992</date>, 57 F.R. 11671, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 7455(d)(2)–(3) of title 38, United States Code, in order to establish procedures for review of proposed increases in the rates of basic pay of certain employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs and of other agencies, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. The Director of the Office of Personnel Management is designated to exercise the authority vested in the President by section 7455(d)(2)–(3) of title 38, United States Code, to review and approve or disapprove the increases in rates of basic pay proposed by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and to provide the appropriate committees of the Congress with a written statement of the reasons for any such disapproval.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. In exercising this authority, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall assure that any increases in basic pay proposed by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs are in the best interest of the Federal Government, do not exceed the amounts authorized by section 7455, and are made only to:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(1) Provide pay in an amount competitive with, but not exceeding, the amount of the same type of pay paid to the same category of health-care personnel at non-Federal health-care facilities in the same labor market;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) Achieve adequate staffing at particular facilities; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(3) Recruit personnel with specialized skills, especially those with skills which are especially difficult or demanding.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall provide to the Director of the Office of Personnel Management such information as the Director may request in order to carry out the responsibilities delegated by this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 4. The Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall provide the Secretary of Veterans Affairs with a copy of any written statement provided to the appropriate committees of the Congress that sets forth the reasons for disapproval of any proposed increase in rates of basic pay under this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 5. In the case of any other law authorizing another agency to use the authority provided by <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s7455">section 7455 of title 38</ref>, United States Code, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall exercise the same authority in the same manner as provided for with respect to section 7455 under sections 1 through 4 of this order, and the head of such other agency shall provide information requested by the Director as provided for in section 3 of this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 6. Executive Order No. 12438 of <date date="1983-08-23">August 23, 1983</date>, is revoked.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 7. This order shall be effective upon publication in the Federal Register.</p>
<signature>
<name>George Bush.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
