<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc4157b29-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7632"><num value="7632">§ 7632.</num><heading> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than March 1 of each year, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the Educational Assistance Program. Each such report shall include the following information:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc4157b2a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7632/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The number of students receiving educational assistance under the Educational Assistance Program, showing the numbers of students receiving assistance under the Scholarship Program, the Tuition Reimbursement Program, the Employee Incentive Scholarship Program, the Education Debt Reduction Program, the Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program, and the Readjustment Counseling Service Scholarship Program separately, and the number of students (if any) enrolled in each type of health profession training under each program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc4157b2b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7632/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The education institutions (if any) providing such training to students in each program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc4157b2c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7632/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The number of applications filed under each program, by health profession category, during the school year beginning in such year and the total number of such applications so filed for all years in which the Educational Assistance Program (or predecessor program) has been in existence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc4157b2d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7632/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The average amounts of educational assistance provided per participant in the Scholarship Program, per participant in the Tuition Reimbursement Program, per participant in the Employee Incentive Scholarship Program, per participant in the Education Debt Reduction Program, per participant in the Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program, and per participant in the Readjustment Counseling Service Scholarship Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc4157b2e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7632/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The amount of tuition and other expenses paid, by health profession category, in the aggregate and at each educational institution for the school year beginning in such year and for prior school years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc4157b2f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7632/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The number of scholarships accepted, by health profession category, during the school year beginning in such year and the number, by health profession category, which were offered and not accepted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc4157b30-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s7632/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The number of participants who complete a course or course of training in each program each year and for all years that such program (or predecessor program) has been in existence.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idc4157b31-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/100/322/tII/s216/b">Pub. L. 100–322, title II, § 216(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-05-20">May 20, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/528">102 Stat. 528</ref>, § 4332; renumbered § 7632, <ref href="/us/pl/102/40/tIV/s402/b/1">Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/238">105 Stat. 238</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s4/b/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, (2)(E), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/404">105 Stat. 404</ref>, 405; <ref href="/us/pl/105/368/tVIII/s805/5">Pub. L. 105–368, title VIII, § 805(5)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3359">112 Stat. 3359</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/182/tIII/s303/b/1/E">Pub. L. 115–182, title III, § 303(b)(1)(E)</ref>, <date date="2018-06-06">June 6, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1467">132 Stat. 1467</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/171/tV/s502/b/1/E">Pub. L. 116–171, title V, § 502(b)(1)(E)</ref>, <date date="2020-10-17">Oct. 17, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/818">134 Stat. 818</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc4157b32-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc4157b33-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc4157b34-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Par. (1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/171/s502/b/1/E/i">Pub. L. 116–171, § 502(b)(1)(E)(i)</ref>, substituted “the Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program, and the Readjustment Counseling Service Scholarship Program” for “and the Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (4). <ref href="/us/pl/116/171/s502/b/1/E/ii">Pub. L. 116–171, § 502(b)(1)(E)(ii)</ref>, substituted “per participant in the Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program, and per participant in the Readjustment Counseling Service Scholarship Program” for “and per participant in the Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Par. (1). <ref href="/us/pl/115/182/s303/b/1/E/i">Pub. L. 115–182, § 303(b)(1)(E)(i)</ref>, substituted “the Education Debt Reduction Program, and the Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program” for “and the Education Debt Reduction Program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (4). <ref href="/us/pl/115/182/s303/b/1/E/ii">Pub. L. 115–182, § 303(b)(1)(E)(ii)</ref>, substituted “per participant in the Education Debt Reduction Program, and per participant in the Specialty Education Loan Repayment Program” for “and per participant in the Education Debt Reduction Program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Par. (1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/368/s805/5/A">Pub. L. 105–368, § 805(5)(A)</ref>, substituted “, the Tuition Reimbursement Program, the Employee Incentive Scholarship Program, and the Education Debt Reduction Program” for “and the Tuition Reimbursement Program” and inserted “(if any)” after “number of students”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/368/s805/5/B">Pub. L. 105–368, § 805(5)(B)</ref>, inserted “(if any)” after “education institutions”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (4). <ref href="/us/pl/105/368/s805/5/C">Pub. L. 105–368, § 805(5)(C)</ref>, substituted “, per participant” for “and per participant” and inserted “, per participant in the Employee Incentive Scholarship Program, and per participant in the Education Debt Reduction Program” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—<ref href="/us/pl/102/40">Pub. L. 102–40</ref> renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s4332">section 4332 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/83">Pub. L. 102–83</ref> substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator” in introductory provisions.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc4157b35-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc4157b36-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, of reporting provisions in this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, and page 145 of House Document No. 103–7.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
