<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc41f17cf-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104"><num value="8104">§ 8104.</num><heading> Congressional approval of certain medical facility acquisitions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f17d0-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f17d1-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The purpose of this subsection is to enable Congress to ensure the equitable distribution of medical facilities throughout the United States, taking into consideration the comparative urgency of the need for the services to be provided in the case of each particular facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f17d2-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f17d3-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> No funds may be appropriated for any fiscal year, and the Secretary may not obligate or expend funds (other than for advance planning and design), for any major medical facility project unless funds for that project have been specifically authorized by law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f17d4-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> No funds may be appropriated for any fiscal year, and the Secretary may not obligate or expend funds (other than for advance planning and design), for any major medical facility lease unless the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives each adopt a resolution approving the lease.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f17d5-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this subsection:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f17d6-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The term “major medical facility project” means a project for the construction, alteration, or acquisition of a medical facility involving a total expenditure of more than the amount specified in paragraph (4), but such term does not include an acquisition by exchange, nonrecurring maintenance projects of the Department, or the construction, alteration, or acquisition of a shared Federal medical facility for which the Department’s estimated share of the project costs does not exceed the amount specified in paragraph (4).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f17d7-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> The term “major medical facility lease”—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc41f17d8-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/a/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> means a lease for space for use as a new medical facility approved through the General Services Administration under <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s3307/a">section 3307(a) of title 40</ref> at an average annual rent equal to or greater than the appropriate dollar threshold described in such section, which shall be subject to annual adjustment in accordance with section 3307(h) of such title; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc41f17d9-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/a/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> does not include a lease for space for use as a shared Federal medical facility for which the Department’s estimated share of the lease costs does not exceed such dollar threshold.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f17da-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f17db-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The amount specified in this paragraph is $30,000,000, as adjusted pursuant to this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f17dc-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f17dd-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/a/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> The Secretary may annually adjust the amount specified in this paragraph to reflect a percentage increase, if any, in construction costs during the prior calendar year, as determined by—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f17de-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/a/4/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the relevant composite construction and lease cost indices pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s3307/h">section 3307(h) of title 40</ref>, or any similar successor index developed by the Administrator of the General Services Administration; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f17df-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/a/4/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the Producer Price Index for New Health Care Building Construction published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor, or any similar successor index developed by the Secretary of Labor.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f17e0-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/a/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> If there is no percentage increase in construction costs determined as described in clause (i) for a calendar year, the Secretary may not adjust the amount specified in subparagraph (A) for that year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f17e1-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/a/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> If the Secretary adjusts the amount specified in this paragraph, the Secretary shall publish a notice of such adjustment in the Federal Register.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f17e2-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/a/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Not later than 30 days before adjusting the amount specified in this paragraph, the Secretary shall notify the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f17e3-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/a/4/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> The Secretary shall determine a logical schedule for adjustments under this paragraph to take effect so that the amounts for and types of construction projects requested by the Department in the budget of the President under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105/a">section 1105(a) of title 31</ref> are consistent with the threshold for construction projects as so adjusted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f17e4-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f17e5-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Whenever the President or the Secretary submit <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002119">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002119"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “submits”.</note> to Congress a request for the funding of a major medical facility project (as defined in subsection (a)(3)(A)), the Secretary shall submit to each committee, on the same day, a prospectus of the proposed medical facility. Any such prospectus shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f17e6-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> A detailed estimate of the total costs of the medical facility to be constructed, altered, or otherwise acquired under this subchapter, including a description of the location of such facility and, in the case of a prospectus proposing the construction of a new or replacement medical facility, a detailed report of the consideration that was given to acquiring an existing facility by lease or purchase and to the sharing of health-care resources with the Department of Defense under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s8111">section 8111 of this title</ref>. Such detailed estimate shall include an identification of each of the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc41f17e7-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Total construction costs.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc41f17e8-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Activation costs.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc41f17e9-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Special purpose alterations (lump-sum payment) costs.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc41f17ea-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/1/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> Number of personnel.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc41f17eb-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/1/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> Total costs of ancillary services, equipment, and all other items.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f17ec-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Demographic data applicable to such facility, including information on projected changes in the population of veterans to be served by the facility over a five-year period, a ten-year period, and a twenty-year period.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f17ed-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Current and projected workload and utilization data regarding the facility, including information on projected changes in workload and utilization over a five-year period, a ten-year period, and a twenty-year period.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f17ee-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Projected operating costs of the facility, including both recurring and non-recurring costs (including and identifying both recurring and non-recurring costs (including activation costs and total costs of ancillary services, equipment and all other items)) over a five-year period, a ten-year period, and a twenty-year period.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f17ef-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> The priority score assigned to the project under the Department’s prioritization methodology and, if the project is being proposed for funding before a project with a higher score, a specific explanation of the factors other than the priority score that were considered and the basis on which the project is proposed for funding ahead of projects with higher priority scores.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f17f0-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><chapeau> In the case of a prospectus proposing the construction of a new or replacement medical facility, each of the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc41f17f1-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/1/F/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> A detailed estimate of the total costs (including total construction costs, activation costs, special purpose alterations (lump-sum payment) costs, number of personnel and total costs of ancillary services, equipment and all other items) for each alternative to construction of the facility that was considered.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc41f17f2-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/1/F/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> A comparison of total costs to total benefits for each such alternative.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc41f17f3-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/1/F/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> An explanation of why the preferred alternative is the most effective means to achieve the stated project goals and the most cost-effective alternative.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f17f4-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Whenever the President or the Secretary submit <sup>1</sup> to Congress a request for the funding of a major medical facility lease (as defined in subsection (a)(3)(B)), the Secretary shall submit to each committee, on the same day, a prospectus of the proposed medical facility. Any such prospectus shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f17f5-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A description of the facility to be leased.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f17f6-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> An estimate of the cost to the Federal Government of the facility to be leased.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f17f7-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> An estimate of the energy performance of the proposed lease space, to include a description of anticipated utilization of renewable energy, energy efficient and climate resilient elements, and related matters.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f17f8-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Current and projected workload and utilization data regarding the facility to be leased, including information on projected changes in workload and utilization over a five-year period, a ten-year period, and a twenty-year period.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f17f9-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><chapeau> A detailed analysis of how the lease is expected to comply with Office of Management and Budget Circular A–11 and <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1341">section 1341 of title 31</ref> (commonly referred to as the “Anti-Deficiency Act”). Any such analysis shall include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc41f17fa-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/2/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> an analysis of the classification of the lease as a “lease purchase”, a “capital lease”, or an “operating lease” as those terms are defined in Office of Management and Budget Circular A–11;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc41f17fb-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/2/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> an analysis of the obligation of budgetary resources associated with the lease; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc41f17fc-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/b/2/E/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> an analysis of the methodology used in determining the asset cost, fair market value, and cancellation costs of the lease.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f17fd-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f17fe-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not less than 30 days before obligating funds for a major medical facility project approved by a law described in subsection (a)(2) of this section in an amount that would cause the total amount obligated for that project to exceed the amount specified in the law for that project (or would add to total obligations exceeding such specified amount) by more than 10 percent, the Secretary shall provide the committees with notice of the Secretary’s intention to do so and the reasons for the specified amount being exceeded.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f17ff-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f1800-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> enter into a contract or agreement with an appropriate non-department Federal entity with the ability to conduct forensic audits on medical facility projects for the conduct of an external forensic audit of the expenditures relating to any major medical facility or super construction project for which the total expenditures exceed the amount requested in the initial budget request for the project submitted to Congress under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105">section 1105 of title 31</ref> by more than 25 percent; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f1801-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> enter into a contract or agreement with an appropriate non-department Federal entity with the ability to conduct forensic audits on medical facility projects for the conduct of an external audit of the medical center construction project in Aurora, Colorado.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f1802-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f1803-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), in any case in which the Secretary proposes that funds be used for a purpose other than the purpose for which such funds were appropriated, the Secretary shall promptly notify each committee, in writing, of the particulars involved and the reasons why such funds were not used for the purpose for which appropriated.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f1804-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f1805-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In any fiscal year, unobligated amounts in the Construction, Major Projects account that are a direct result of bid savings from a major construction project may only be obligated for major construction projects authorized for that fiscal year or a previous fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f1806-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Whenever the Secretary obligates amounts for a major construction project under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives notice of the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f1807-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/d/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The major construction project that is the source of the bid savings.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f1808-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/d/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> If the major construction project that is the source of the bid savings is not complete—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc41f1809-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/d/2/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the amount already obligated by the Department or available in the project reserve for such project;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc41f180a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/d/2/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the percentage of such project that has been completed; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc41f180b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/d/2/B/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the amount available to the Department to complete such project.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f180c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/d/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> The other major construction project for which the bid savings amounts are being obligated.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f180d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/d/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> The bid savings amounts being obligated for such other major construction project.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f180e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> The Secretary may not obligate an amount under subparagraph (A) to expand the purpose of a major construction project except pursuant to a provision of law enacted after the date on which the Secretary submits to the committees described in subparagraph (B) notice of the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f180f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/d/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The major construction project that is the source of the bid savings.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f1810-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/d/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The major construction project for which the Secretary intends to expand the purpose.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f1811-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/d/2/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> A description of such expansion of purpose.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f1812-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/d/2/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> The amounts the Secretary intends to obligate to expand the purpose.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f1813-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> The Secretary may accept gifts or donations for any of the purposes of this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f1814-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><chapeau> The Secretary may not obligate funds in an amount in excess of $500,000 from the Advance Planning Fund of the Department toward design or development of a major medical facility project (as defined in subsection (a)(3)(A)) until—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f1815-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Secretary submits to the committees a report on the proposed obligation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f1816-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a period of 30 days has passed after the date on which the report is received by the committees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f1817-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> The limitation in subsection (f) does not apply to a project for which funds have been authorized by law in accordance with subsection (a)(2).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f1818-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f1819-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Not less than 30 days before entering into a major medical facility lease, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f181a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> notice of the Secretary’s intention to enter into the lease;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f181b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a detailed summary of the proposed lease;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f181c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/h/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a description and analysis of any differences between the prospectus submitted pursuant to subsection (b) and the proposed lease; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f181d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/h/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> a scoring analysis demonstrating that the proposed lease fully complies with Office of Management and Budget Circular A–11.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f181e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Each committee described in paragraph (1) shall ensure that any information submitted to the committee under such paragraph is treated by the committee with the same level of confidentiality as is required by law of the Secretary and subject to the same statutory penalties for unauthorized disclosure or use as the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f181f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Not more than 30 days after entering into a major medical facility lease, the Secretary shall submit to each committee described in paragraph (1) a report on any material differences between the lease that was entered into and the proposed lease described under such paragraph, including how the lease that was entered into changes the previously submitted scoring analysis described in subparagraph (D) of such paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f1820-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f1821-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding subsection (a)(2)(B), the Secretary may carry out interim leasing actions as the Secretary considers necessary for the following leases:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f1822-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/i/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Major medical facility leases (as defined in subsection (a)(3)(B)) approved pursuant to this section and for which a prospectus for a replacement lease has been submitted to Congress pursuant to subsection (b)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc41f1823-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/i/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Replacement leases that do not require approval under this section and for which a prospectus has been submitted to Congress pursuant to subsection (b)(2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f1824-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In this subsection, the term “interim leasing actions” has the meaning given that term by the Administrator of the General Services Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc41f1825-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8104/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content> The Secretary may obligate and expend funds to exercise a purchase option included in any major medical facility lease (as defined in subsection (a)(3)(B)).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc41f1826-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/96/22/tIII/s301/a">Pub. L. 96–22, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1979-06-13">June 13, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/56">93 Stat. 56</ref>, § 5004; amended <ref href="/us/pl/99/166/tIII">Pub. L. 99–166, title III</ref>, §§ 301, 303, <date date="1985-12-03">Dec. 3, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/954">99 Stat. 954</ref>, 955; <ref href="/us/pl/99/576/tII/s221/b">Pub. L. 99–576, title II, § 221(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-28">Oct. 28, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3259">100 Stat. 3259</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/322/tIV/s422">Pub. L. 100–322, title IV, § 422</ref>, <date date="1988-05-20">May 20, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/553">102 Stat. 553</ref>; renumbered § 8104 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/40/tIV/s402/b/1">Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, (d)(1), <date date="1991-05-07">May 7, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/238">105 Stat. 238</ref>, 239; <ref href="/us/pl/102/83/s4/b/1">Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, (2)(E), <date date="1991-08-06">Aug. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/404">105 Stat. 404</ref>, 405; <ref href="/us/pl/102/405/tIII/s301/a">Pub. L. 102–405, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-09">Oct. 9, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1984">106 Stat. 1984</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/79/s3/a">Pub. L. 103–79, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-08-13">Aug. 13, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/771">107 Stat. 771</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/262/tII">Pub. L. 104–262, title II</ref>, §§ 205(a), 206(a), (c), <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3189">110 Stat. 3189</ref>, 3190; <ref href="/us/pl/105/368/tVII/s704">Pub. L. 105–368, title VII, § 704</ref>, <date date="1998-11-11">Nov. 11, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3350">112 Stat. 3350</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/170/tII/s201">Pub. L. 108–170, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2003-12-06">Dec. 6, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2047">117 Stat. 2047</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/422/tIV/s416">Pub. L. 108–422, title IV, § 416</ref>, <date date="2004-11-30">Nov. 30, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/2393">118 Stat. 2393</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/tVIII/s812">Pub. L. 109–461, title VIII, § 812</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3447">120 Stat. 3447</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/387/tVII/s705">Pub. L. 110–387, title VII, § 705</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4138">122 Stat. 4138</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/275/tIX/s905">Pub. L. 111–275, title IX, § 905</ref>, <date date="2010-10-13">Oct. 13, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2895">124 Stat. 2895</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/37">Pub. L. 112–37</ref>, §§ 6, 7, <date date="2011-10-05">Oct. 5, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/394">125 Stat. 394</ref>, 396; <ref href="/us/pl/113/146/tVI/s602/c">Pub. L. 113–146, title VI, § 602(c)</ref>, <date date="2014-08-07">Aug. 7, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1794">128 Stat. 1794</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/315/tVIII/s801/b">Pub. L. 114–315, title VIII, § 801(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1590">130 Stat. 1590</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/182/tV/s503/b">Pub. L. 115–182, title V, § 503(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-06-06">June 6, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1476">132 Stat. 1476</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/61/s6/9">Pub. L. 116–61, § 6(9)</ref>, <date date="2019-09-30">Sept. 30, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1117">133 Stat. 1117</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/168/tVII/s703/a">Pub. L. 117–168, title VII, § 703(a)</ref>–(e), <date date="2022-08-10">Aug. 10, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/1797">136 Stat. 1797</ref>, 1798; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dE/tLI/s5124/b">Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LI, § 5124(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3211">136 Stat. 3211</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dE/tL/s5001">Pub. L. 118–31, div. E, title L, § 5001</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/930">137 Stat. 930</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc41f1827-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc41f1828-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc41f1829-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2023—Subsec. (a)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s5001/1">Pub. L. 118–31, § 5001(1)</ref>, substituted “the amount specified in paragraph (4)” for “$20,000,000” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s5001/2">Pub. L. 118–31, § 5001(2)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/117/168/s703/a">Pub. L. 117–168, § 703(a)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A), struck out “or any major medical facility lease” after “major medical facility project” and “or lease” after “for that project”, and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/117/168/s703/b">Pub. L. 117–168, § 703(b)</ref>, amended subpar. (B) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (B) read as follows: “The term ‘major medical facility lease’ means a lease for space for use as a new medical facility at an average annual rent of more than $1,000,000.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s5124/b">Pub. L. 117–263, § 5124(b)</ref>, amended <ref href="/us/pl/117/168/s703/c/5">Pub. L. 117–168, § 703(c)(5)</ref>. See below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/168/s703/c/5">Pub. L. 117–168, § 703(c)(5)</ref>, (8), as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s5124/b">Pub. L. 117–263, § 5124(b)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), substituted “to Congress” for “to the Congress” and struck out “or a major medical facility lease (as defined in subsection (a)(3)(B))” after “subsection (a)(3)(A))” in introductory provisions, and added par. (2). Former pars. (1) and (2) redesignated subpars. (A) and (B), respectively, of par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/117/168/s703/c/2">Pub. L. 117–168, § 703(c)(2)</ref>, (4), (6), redesignated subsec. (b)(1) and its subpars. (A) to (E) as subsec. (b)(1)(A) and cls. (i) to (v), respectively, and struck out “leased,” after “altered,” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B) to (D). <ref href="/us/pl/117/168/s703/c/4">Pub. L. 117–168, § 703(c)(4)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (b)(2) to (4) as subsec. (b)(1)(B) to (D), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/117/168/s703/c/4">Pub. L. 117–168, § 703(c)(4)</ref>, (7), redesignated subsec. (b)(5) as subsec. (b)(1)(E) and struck out “or lease” after “project” wherever appearing and “or leases” after “projects”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/117/168/s703/c/3">Pub. L. 117–168, § 703(c)(3)</ref>, (4), redesignated subsec. (b)(6) and its subpars. (A) to (C) as subsec. (b)(1)(F) and cls. (i) to (iii), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/117/168/s703/c/1">Pub. L. 117–168, § 703(c)(1)</ref>, struck out par. (7) which required detailed analyses of proposed funding for major medical facility leases.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/117/168/s703/d">Pub. L. 117–168, § 703(d)</ref>, added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/117/168/s703/e">Pub. L. 117–168, § 703(e)</ref>, added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/61">Pub. L. 116–61</ref> added par. (3) and struck out former par. (3) which read as follows: “For purposes of this subsection, the term ‘major medical facility project’ means a project for the construction, alteration, or acquisition of a medical facility involving a total expenditure of more than $20,000,000, but such term does not include an acquisition by exchange, nonrecurring maintenance projects of the Department, or the construction, alteration, or acquisition of a shared Federal medical facility for which the Department’s estimated share of the project costs does not exceed $20,000,000.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/115/182">Pub. L. 115–182</ref>, which directed the general amendment of par. (3) of section 8104(a), without specifying the Code title to be amended, was executed by amending par. (3) of subsec. (a) of this section, to reflect the probable intent of Congress. Prior to amendment, par. (3) read as follows: “For the purpose of this subsection:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) The term ‘major medical facility project’ means a project for the construction, alteration, or acquisition of a medical facility involving a total expenditure of more than $10,000,000, but such term does not include an acquisition by exchange.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) The term ‘major medical facility lease’ means a lease for space for use as a new medical facility at an average annual rental of more than $1,000,000.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/114/315/s801/b">Pub. L. 114–315, § 801(b)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(B)(ii) to (iv). <ref href="/us/pl/114/315/s801/c">Pub. L. 114–315, § 801(c)</ref>, added cl. (ii), redesignated former cls. (ii) and (iii) as (iii) and (iv), respectively, and in cls. (iii) and (iv) substituted “bid savings amounts” for “amounts”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (b)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/113/146/s602/c/1">Pub. L. 113–146, § 602(c)(1)</ref>, added par. (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/113/146/s602/c/2">Pub. L. 113–146, § 602(c)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/112/37/s6/1/A">Pub. L. 112–37, § 6(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “detailed estimate of the total costs” for “detailed description” and “a detailed report of the consideration” for “a description of the consideration” and inserted at end “Such detailed estimate shall include an identification of each of the following:” and subpars. (A) to (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/112/37/s6/1/B">Pub. L. 112–37, § 6(1)(B)</ref>, (C), struck out par. (2), redesignated par. (4) as (2), and substituted “a five-year period, a ten-year period, and a twenty-year period” for “a five-year period and a ten-year period”. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “An estimate of the cost to the United States of the construction, alteration, lease, or other acquisition of such facility (including site costs, if applicable).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/112/37/s6/1/B">Pub. L. 112–37, § 6(1)(B)</ref>, (D), struck out par. (3), redesignated par. (5) as (3), and inserted before period at end “, including information on projected changes in workload and utilization over a five-year period, a ten-year period, and a twenty-year period”. Prior to amendment, par. (3) read as follows: “An estimate of the cost to the United States of the equipment required for the operation of such facility.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/112/37/s6/1/B">Pub. L. 112–37, § 6(1)(B)</ref>, (E), redesignated par. (6) as (4), substituted “Projected” for “Current and projected”, and inserted before period at end “(including and identifying both recurring and non-recurring costs (including activation costs and total costs of ancillary services, equipment and all other items)) over a five-year period, a ten-year period, and a twenty-year period”. Former par. (4) redesignated (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/112/37/s6/1/B">Pub. L. 112–37, § 6(1)(B)</ref>, redesignated par. (7) as (5). Former par. (5) redesignated (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/112/37/s6/1/B">Pub. L. 112–37, § 6(1)(B)</ref>, (F), redesignated par. (8) as (6), substituted “each of the following:” for “a description of each alternative to construction of the facility that was considered.”, and added subpars. (A) to (C). Former par. (6) redesignated (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(7),(8). <ref href="/us/pl/112/37/s6/1/B">Pub. L. 112–37, § 6(1)(B)</ref>, redesignated pars. (7) and (8) as (5) and (6), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/112/37/s6/2/A">Pub. L. 112–37, § 6(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “major construction project” for “major medical facility project” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/112/37/s6/2/B/i">Pub. L. 112–37, § 6(2)(B)(i)</ref>, substituted “major construction projects” for “major medical facility projects”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/112/37/s6/2/B/ii">Pub. L. 112–37, § 6(2)(B)(ii)</ref>, substituted “major construction project” for “major medical facility” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/112/37/s7">Pub. L. 112–37, § 7</ref>, added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/111/275">Pub. L. 111–275</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1), substituted “Except as provided in paragraph (2), in any case” for “In any case”, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (a)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/110/387">Pub. L. 110–387</ref> substituted “$1,000,000” for “$600,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (a)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/461">Pub. L. 109–461</ref> substituted “$10,000,000” for “$7,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/108/422">Pub. L. 108–422</ref> added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (a)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/108/170">Pub. L. 108–170</ref> substituted “$7,000,000” for “$4,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/105/368">Pub. L. 105–368</ref> substituted “$600,000” for “$300,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/104/262/s206/a">Pub. L. 104–262, § 206(a)</ref>, substituted “$4,000,000” for “$3,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/104/262/s205/a/1">Pub. L. 104–262, § 205(a)(1)</ref>, inserted introductory provisions and struck out former introductory provisions which read as follows: “In the event that the President or the Secretary proposes to the Congress the funding of any construction, alteration, lease, or other acquisition to which subsection (a) of this section is applicable, the Secretary shall submit to each committee, on the same day, a prospectus of the proposed medical facility. Such prospectus shall include—”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1) to (3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/262/s205/a/2">Pub. L. 104–262, § 205(a)(2)</ref>–(4), substituted “A detailed” for “a detailed” and “title.” for “title;” in par. (1), “An estimate” for “an estimate” and “applicable).” for “applicable); and” in par. (2), and “An estimate” for “an estimate” in par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4) to (8). <ref href="/us/pl/104/262/s205/a/5">Pub. L. 104–262, § 205(a)(5)</ref>, added pars. (4) to (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/104/262/s206/c">Pub. L. 104–262, § 206(c)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (a)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/103/79">Pub. L. 103–79</ref> substituted “$3,000,000” for “$2,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/405/s301/a/1">Pub. L. 102–405, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “It shall not be in order in the Senate or in the House of Representatives to consider a bill, resolution, or amendment which would make an appropriation for any fiscal year which may be expended for a major medical facility project or a major medical facility lease unless—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) such bill, resolution, or amendment specifies the amount to be appropriated for that project or lease,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) the project or lease has been approved in a resolution adopted by the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of that House, and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) the amount to be appropriated for that project or lease is no more than the amount specified in that resolution for that project or lease for that fiscal year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/102/405/s301/a/2">Pub. L. 102–405, § 301(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “new” after “as a” and substituted “$300,000” for “$500,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/405/s301/a/3">Pub. L. 102–405, § 301(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “law” for “resolution” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—<ref href="/us/pl/102/40/s402/b/1">Pub. L. 102–40, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s5004">section 5004 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83">Pub. L. 102–83</ref> substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator” in two places in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/40/s402/d/1">Pub. L. 102–40, § 402(d)(1)</ref>, substituted “8111” for “5011”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83">Pub. L. 102–83</ref> substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator” and “Secretary’s” for “Administrator’s”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/102/83">Pub. L. 102–83</ref> substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/322/s422/a">Pub. L. 100–322, § 422(a)</ref>, amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “After the adoption by the committees during a fiscal year of resolutions with identical texts approving major medical facility projects, it shall not be in order in the House of Representatives or in the Senate to consider a bill, resolution, or amendment making an appropriation for that fiscal year or for the next fiscal year which may be expended for a major medical facility project—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) if the project for which the appropriation is proposed to be made is not approved in those resolutions; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) in the event that the project is approved in the resolutions, if either—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(i) the bill, resolution, or amendment making the appropriation does not specify—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3">“(I) the medical facility project for which the appropriation is proposed to be made; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3">“(II) the amount proposed to be appropriated for the project; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(ii) the amount proposed to be appropriated for the project (when added to any amount previously appropriated for the project) exceeds the amount approved for the project.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/100/322/s422/b">Pub. L. 100–322, § 422(b)</ref>, added par. (3) and struck out former pars. (3) and (4) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(3) No appropriation may be made for the lease of any space for use as a medical facility at an average annual rental of more than $500,000 unless each committee has first adopted a resolution approving such lease and setting forth the estimated cost thereof.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(4) For the purpose of this subsection, the term ‘major medical facility project’ means a project for the construction, alteration, or acquisition of a medical facility involving a total expenditure of more than $2,000,000. Such term does not include an acquisition by exchange.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/100/322/s422/c">Pub. L. 100–322, § 422(c)</ref>, amended subsec. (c) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (c) read as follows: “The estimated cost of any construction, alteration, lease, or other acquisition that is approved under this section, as set forth in the pertinent resolutions described in subsection (a) of this section, may be increased by the Administrator in the contract for such construction, alteration, lease, or other acquisition by an amount equal to the percentage increase, if any, as determined by the Administrator, in construction, alteration, lease, or other acquisition costs, as the case may be, from the date of such approval to the date of contract, but in no event may the amount of such increase exceed 10 per centum of such estimated cost.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d) to (f). <ref href="/us/pl/100/322/s422/d">Pub. L. 100–322, § 422(d)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (e) and (f) as (d) and (e), respectively, and struck out former subsec. (d) which read as follows: “In the case of any medical facility approved for construction, alteration, lease, or other acquisition by each committee under subsection (a) of this section for which funds have not been appropriated within one year after the date of such approval, either such committee may by resolution rescind its approval at any time thereafter before such funds are appropriated.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/576">Pub. L. 99–576</ref> inserted “and to the sharing of health-care resources with the Department of Defense under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s5011">section 5011 of this title</ref>” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/166/s301">Pub. L. 99–166, § 301</ref>, amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) read as follows: “In order to ensure the equitable distribution of medical facilities throughout the United States, taking into consideration the comparative urgency of the need for the services to be provided in the case of each particular facility—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) no appropriation may be made for the construction, alteration, or acquisition (not including exchanges) of any medical facility which involves a total expenditure of more than $2,000,000 unless each committee has first adopted a resolution approving such construction, alteration, or acquisition and setting forth the estimated cost thereof; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) no appropriation may be made for the lease of any space for use as a medical facility at an average annual rental of more than $500,000 unless each committee has first adopted a resolution approving such lease and setting forth the estimated cost thereof.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/166/s303">Pub. L. 99–166, § 303</ref>, inserted “and, in the case of a prospectus proposing the construction of a new or replacement medical facility, a description of the consideration that was given to acquiring an existing facility by lease or purchase” after “such facility”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc41f182a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc41f182b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2022 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Pub. L. 117–263</ref> effective as if included in the enactment of the Honoring our PACT Act of 2022 (<ref href="/us/pl/117/168">Public Law 117–168</ref>), see <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s524/d">section 524(d) of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1120">section 1120 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/117/168/tVII/s703/f">Pub. L. 117–168, title VII, § 703(f)</ref>, <date date="2022-08-10">Aug. 10, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/1799">136 Stat. 1799</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/168/tVII/s703/f">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply with respect to any lease that has not been specifically authorized by law on or before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-08-10">Aug. 10, 2022</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc41f182c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/262/tII/s205/b">Pub. L. 104–262, title II, § 205(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3190">110 Stat. 3190</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/262/tII/s205/b">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to any prospectus submitted by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc41f182d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/262/tII/s206/b/2">Pub. L. 104–262, title II, § 206(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3190">110 Stat. 3190</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/262/tII/s206/b/2">“The amendments made by subsection (a) of such section [meaning <ref href="/us/pl/102/405/s301/a">section 301(a) of Pub. L. 102–405</ref>, amending this section] shall apply with respect to any major medical facility project or any major medical facility lease of the Department of Veterans Affairs, regardless of when funds are first appropriated for that project or lease, except that in the case of a project for which funds were first appropriated before <date date="1992-10-09">October 9, 1992</date>, such amendments shall not apply with respect to amounts appropriated for that project for a fiscal year before fiscal year 1998.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/405/tIII/s301/b">Pub. L. 102–405, title III, § 301(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-09">Oct. 9, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1984">106 Stat. 1984</ref>, provided that the amendments made by <ref href="/us/pl/102/405/s301/a">section 301(a) of Pub. L. 102–405</ref>, amending this section, were not applicable with respect to any project for which funds were appropriated before <date date="1992-10-09">Oct. 9, 1992</date>, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/104/262/tII/s206/b/1">Pub. L. 104–262, title II, § 206(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3190">110 Stat. 3190</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idc41f182e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1979-10-01">Oct. 1, 1979</date>, but not applicable with respect to the acquisition, construction, or alteration of any medical facilities if the acquisition, construction, or alteration (not including exchange) was approved by the President before <date date="1979-10-01">Oct. 1, 1979</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/22/s302">section 302 of Pub. L. 96–22</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s8101">section 8101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc41f182f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Budgetary Treatment of Department of Veterans Affairs Major Medical Facilities Leases</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/146/tVI/s602">Pub. L. 113–146, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="2014-08-07">Aug. 7, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1794">128 Stat. 1794</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/146/tVI/s602">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Congress finds the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Title 31, United States Code, requires the Department of Veterans Affairs to record the full cost of its contractual obligation against funds available at the time a contract is executed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Office of Management and Budget Circular A–11 provides guidance to agencies in meeting the statutory requirements under title 31, United States Code, with respect to leases.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> For operating leases, Office of Management and Budget Circular A–11 requires the Department of Veterans Affairs to record up-front budget authority in an ‘amount equal to total payments under the full term of the lease or [an] amount sufficient to cover first year lease payments plus cancellation costs’.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement for Obligation of Full Cost.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Subject to the availability of appropriations provided in advance, in exercising the authority of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into leases provided in this Act, the Secretary shall record, pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1501">section 1501 of title 31</ref>, United States Code, as the full cost of the contractual obligation at the time a contract is executed either—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> an amount equal to total payments under the full term of the lease; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> if the lease specifies payments to be made in the event the lease is terminated before its full term, an amount sufficient to cover the first year lease payments plus the specified cancellation costs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Self-insuring authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The requirements of paragraph (1) may be satisfied through the use of the self-insuring authority identified in title 40, United States Code, consistent with Office of Management and Budget Circular A–11.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transparency.—</inline></heading><note topic="miscellaneous" id="idc41f1830-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<p><inline class="small-caps">[Amended subsecs. (b)(7) and (h) of this section.]</inline></p></note>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this section, or the amendments made by this section, shall be construed to in any way relieve the Department of Veterans Affairs from any statutory or regulatory obligations or requirements existing prior to the enactment of this section and such amendments.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
