<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc42d482f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127"><num value="8127">§ 8127.</num><heading> Small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans: contracting goals and preferences</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4830-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contracting Goals</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4831-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In order to increase contracting opportunities for small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans and small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans with service-connected disabilities, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d4832-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> establish a goal for each fiscal year for participation in Department contracts (including subcontracts) by small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans who are not veterans with service-connected disabilities in accordance with paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d4833-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> establish a goal for each fiscal year for participation in Department contracts (including subcontracts) by small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans with service-connected disabilities in accordance with paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4834-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The goal for a fiscal year for participation under paragraph (1)(A) shall be determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4835-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The goal for a fiscal year for participation under paragraph (1)(B) shall be not less than the Government-wide goal for that fiscal year for participation by small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans with service-connected disabilities under section 15(g)(1) of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s644/g/1">15 U.S.C. 644(g)(1)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4836-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Secretary shall establish a review mechanism to ensure that, in the case of a subcontract of a Department contract that is counted for purposes of meeting a goal established pursuant to this section, the subcontract was actually awarded to a business concern that may be counted for purposes of meeting that goal.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4837-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Noncompetitive Procedures for Certain Small Contracts</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subsection (d)(2), for purposes of meeting the goals under subsection (a), and in accordance with this section, in entering into a contract with a small business concern owned and controlled by veterans or a small business concern owned and controlled by veterans with service-connected disabilities for an amount less than the simplified acquisition threshold (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s134">section 134 of title 41</ref>), a contracting officer of the Department may use procedures other than competitive procedures.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4838-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sole Source Contracts for Contracts Above Simplified Acquisition Threshold</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (d)(2), for purposes of meeting the goals under subsection (a), and in accordance with this section, a contracting officer of the Department may award a contract to a small business concern owned and controlled by veterans or a small business concern owned and controlled by veterans with service-connected disabilities using procedures other than competitive procedures if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d4839-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> such concern is determined to be a responsible source with respect to performance of such contract opportunity;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d483a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the anticipated award price of the contract (including options) will exceed the simplified acquisition threshold (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s134">section 134 of title 41</ref>) but will not exceed $5,000,000; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d483b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> in the estimation of the contracting officer, the contract award can be made at a fair and reasonable price that offers best value to the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d483c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Restricted Competition</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d483d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2) and in subsections (b) and (c), for purposes of meeting the goals under subsection (a), and in accordance with this section, a contracting officer of the Department shall award contracts on the basis of competition restricted to small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans or small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans with service-connected disabilities if the contracting officer has a reasonable expectation that two or more small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans or small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans with service-connected disabilities will submit offers and that the award can be made at a fair and reasonable price that offers best value to the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d483e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d483f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1) and except as provided by subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, with respect to the procurement of a covered product or service, a contracting officer of the Department shall procure such product or service from a source designated under chapter 85 of title 41, and in accordance with the regulations prescribed under such chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4840-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4841-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/d/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> Subject to clause (ii), subparagraph (A) shall not apply in the case of a covered product or service for which a contract was—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d4842-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/d/2/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> awarded under paragraph (1) after <date date="2006-12-22">December 22, 2006</date>; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d4843-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/d/2/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Department of Veterans Affairs Contracting Preference Consistency Act of 2020.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4844-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/d/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> Clause (i) shall cease to apply to a covered product or service described in such clause upon a determination of the Secretary that when the current contract for the covered product or service is terminated or expires there is no reasonable expectation that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d4845-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/d/2/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> two or more small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans will submit offers as described in paragraph (1); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d4846-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/d/2/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the award can be made at a fair and reasonable price that offers best value to the United States.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4847-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> In this paragraph, the term “covered product or service” means—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d4848-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/d/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> a product or service that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc42d4849-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/d/2/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> is included on the procurement list under <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s8503/a">section 8503(a) of title 41</ref>; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc42d484a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/d/2/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> was included on such procurement list on or before <date date="2006-12-22">December 22, 2006</date>; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d484b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/d/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> a product or service that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc42d484c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/d/2/C/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> is a replacement for a product or service described under clause (i);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc42d484d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/d/2/C/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> is essentially the same and meeting the same requirement as the product or service being replaced; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc42d484e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/d/2/C/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> a contracting officer determines meets the quality standards and delivery schedule of the Department.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d484f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligibility of Small Business Concerns</inline>.—</heading><content>A small business concern may be awarded a contract under this section only if the small business concern and the veteran owner of the small business concern are listed in the database of veteran-owned businesses maintained by the Administrator under section 36 of the Small Business Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" status="transferred" id="idc42d4850-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/f"><num value="f">[(f)</num><content> Transferred. <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tVIII/s862/b/2">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VIII, § 862(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3778">134 Stat. 3778</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4851-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Enforcement Penalties for Misrepresentation</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4852-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any business concern that is determined by the Secretary to have willfully and intentionally misrepresented the status of that concern as a small business concern owned and controlled by veterans or as a small business concern owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans for purposes of this subsection shall be debarred from contracting with the Department for a period of not less than five years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4853-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In the case of a debarment under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall commence debarment action against the business concern by not later than 30 days after determining that the concern willfully and intentionally misrepresented the status of the concern as described in paragraph (1) and shall complete debarment actions against such concern by not later than 90 days after such determination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4854-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The debarment of a business concern under paragraph (1) includes the debarment of all principals in the business concern for a period of not less than five years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4855-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Priority for Contracting Preferences</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Preferences for awarding contracts to small business concerns shall be applied in the following order of priority:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d4856-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Contracts awarded pursuant to subsection (b), (c), or (d) to small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans with service-connected disabilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d4857-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Contracts awarded pursuant to subsection (b), (c), or (d) to small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans that are not covered by paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d4858-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Contracts awarded pursuant to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc42d4859-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/h/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> section 8(a) of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s637/a">15 U.S.C. 637(a)</ref>); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc42d485a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/h/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> section 31 of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s657a">15 U.S.C. 657a</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d485b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/h/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Contracts awarded pursuant to any other small business contracting preference.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d485c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability of Requirements to Contracts</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d485d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If after <date date="2008-12-31">December 31, 2008</date>, the Secretary enters into a contract, memorandum of understanding, agreement, or other arrangement with any governmental entity to acquire goods or services, the Secretary shall include in such contract, memorandum, agreement, or other arrangement a requirement that the entity will comply, to the maximum extent feasible, with the provisions of this section in acquiring such goods or services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d485e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to supersede or otherwise affect the authorities provided under the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s631">15 U.S.C. 631</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d485f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Reports</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than December 31 each year, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on small business contracting during the fiscal year ending in such year. Each report shall include, for the fiscal year covered by such report, the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d4860-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The percentage of the total amount of all contracts awarded by the Department during that fiscal year that were awarded to small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d4861-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The percentage of the total amount of all such contracts awarded to small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans with service-connected disabilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d4862-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/j/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The percentage of the total amount of all contracts awarded by each Administration of the Department during that fiscal year that were awarded to small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d4863-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/j/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The percentage of the total amount of all contracts awarded by each such Administration during that fiscal year that were awarded to small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans with service-connected disabilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4864-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Transfer for Certification Costs</inline>.—</heading><content>For each fiscal year, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall reimburse the Administrator in an amount necessary to cover any cost incurred by the Administrator for certifying small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans that do not qualify as small business concerns owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans for the Secretary for purposes of this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s8128">section 8128 of this title</ref>. The Administrator is authorized to accept such reimbursement. The amount of any such reimbursement shall be determined jointly by the Secretary and the Administrator and shall be provided from fees collected by the Secretary under multiple-award schedule contracts. Any disagreement about the amount shall be resolved by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4865-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/l"><num value="l">(l)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitations on Subcontracting</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4866-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/l/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4867-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/l/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The requirements applicable to a covered small business concern under section 46 of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s657s">15 U.S.C. 657s</ref>) shall apply with respect to a small business concern owned and controlled by veterans that is awarded a contract under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4868-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/l/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> For purposes of applying the requirements of section 46 of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s657s">15 U.S.C. 657s</ref>) pursuant to subparagraph (A), the term “similarly situated entity” used in such section 46 includes a subcontractor for a small business concern owned and controlled by veterans described in such subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4869-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/l/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Secretary may award a contract under this section only after the Secretary obtains from the offeror a certification that the offeror will comply with the requirements described in paragraph (1)(A) if awarded the contract. Such certification shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d486a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/l/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> specify the exact performance requirements applicable under such paragraph; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d486b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/l/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> explicitly acknowledge that the certification is subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1001">section 1001 of title 18</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d486c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/l/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d486d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/l/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Director of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization for the Department, established pursuant to section 15(k) of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s644/k">15 U.S.C. 644(k)</ref>), and the Chief Acquisition Officer of the Department, established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s1702">section 1702 of title 41</ref>, shall jointly implement a process using the systems described in section 16(g)(2) of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s645/g/2">15 U.S.C. 645(g)(2)</ref>), or any other relevant systems available, to monitor compliance with this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d486e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/l/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Director of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization and the Chief Acquisition Officer shall jointly refer any violations or suspected violations of this subsection to the Inspector General of the Department.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d486f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/l/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> If the Secretary determines, in consultation with the Inspector General of the Department, that a small business concern that is awarded a contract under this section did not act in good faith with respect to the requirements described in paragraph (1)(A), the small business concern shall be subject to any or all of the following consequences—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d4870-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/l/3/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> referral to the Debarment and Suspension Committee of the Department;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d4871-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/l/3/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a fine under section 16(g)(1) of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s645/g/1">15 U.S.C. 645(g)(1)</ref>); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d4872-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/l/3/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> prosecution for violating <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1001">section 1001 of title 18</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4873-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/l/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> Not later than November 30 for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2025, the Inspector General shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report for the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year during which the report is submitted that includes, for the fiscal year covered by the report—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d4874-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/l/3/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the number of referred violations and suspected violations received under subparagraph (B); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d4875-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/l/3/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the disposition of such referred violations, including the number of small business concerns suspended or debarred from Federal contracting or referred to the Attorney General for prosecution.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idc42d4876-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/m"><num value="m">(m)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d4877-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/m/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Small Business Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d4878-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/m/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “small business concern” has the meaning given that term under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s632">15 U.S.C. 632</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d4879-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/m/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “small business concern owned and controlled by veterans” has the meaning given that term under section 3(q)(3) of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s632/q/3">15 U.S.C. 632(q)(3)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc42d487a-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87" identifier="/us/usc/t38/s8127/m/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The term “small business concern owned and controlled by veterans with service-connected disabilities” has the meaning given the term “small business concern owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans” under section 3(q)(2) of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s632/q/2">15 U.S.C. 632(q)(2)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc42d487b-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/109/461/tV/s502/a/1">Pub. L. 109–461, title V, § 502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3431">120 Stat. 3431</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/110/389/tVIII/s806">Pub. L. 110–389, title VIII, § 806</ref>, <date date="2008-10-10">Oct. 10, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4189">122 Stat. 4189</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/275/tI/s104/b/1">Pub. L. 111–275, title I, § 104(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-13">Oct. 13, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2867">124 Stat. 2867</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s5/j/7">Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(j)(7)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3850">124 Stat. 3850</ref>; Pub. L. 112—154, title VII, § 706, <date date="2012-08-06">Aug. 6, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1206">126 Stat. 1206</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/315/tV/s501/a">Pub. L. 114–315, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1566">130 Stat. 1566</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tXVIII/s1832/b">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XVIII, § 1832(b)</ref>, (d), (f)(1), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2659">130 Stat. 2659</ref>, 2660; <ref href="/us/pl/116/155/s2/a">Pub. L. 116–155, § 2(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2020-08-08">Aug. 8, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/698">134 Stat. 698</ref>, 699; <ref href="/us/pl/116/183/s2/a">Pub. L. 116–183, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2020-10-30">Oct. 30, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/895">134 Stat. 895</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tVIII/s862/b/1">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VIII, § 862(b)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3776">134 Stat. 3776</ref>, 3778; <ref href="/us/pl/116/315/tVII/s7009">Pub. L. 116–315, title VII, § 7009</ref>, <date date="2021-01-05">Jan. 5, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/5061">134 Stat. 5061</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc42d487c-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc42d487d-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc42d487e-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of the enactment of the Department of Veterans Affairs Contracting Preference Consistency Act of 2020, referred to in subsec. (d)(2)(B)(i)(II), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/116/155">Pub. L. 116–155</ref>, which was approved <date date="2020-08-08">Aug. 8, 2020</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Small Business Act, referred to in subsecs. (e) and (i)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/85/536/s2">Pub. L. 85–536, § 2</ref>(1 et seq.), <date date="1958-07-18">July 18, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/384">72 Stat. 384</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 14A (§ 631 et seq.) of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. Section 36 of the Act is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s657f">section 657f of Title 15</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s631">section 631 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc42d487f-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/b/1/A">Pub. L. 116–283, § 862(b)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “the Administrator under section 36 of the Small Business Act” for “the Secretary under subsection (f)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/b/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 862(b)(2)</ref>, transferred subsec. (f) of this section to section 36(f) of the Small Business Act, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s657f">section 657f of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/b/1/B/i">Pub. L. 116–283, § 862(b)(1)(B)(i)</ref>, substituted “the Administrator” for “the Secretary” wherever appearing except in the last place it appears in par. (2)(A).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/b/1/B/ii">Pub. L. 116–283, § 862(b)(1)(B)(ii)</ref>, substituted “small business concerns owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans” for “small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans with service-connected disabilities”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/b/1/B/iii/I">Pub. L. 116–283, § 862(b)(1)(B)(iii)(I)</ref>, inserted “, United States Code,” after “title 5” and substituted “to obtain from the Secretary of Veterans Affairs” for “to access”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2)(B), (C). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/b/1/B/iii/II">Pub. L. 116–283, § 862(b)(1)(B)(iii)(II)</ref>, added subpars. (B) and (C) and struck out former subpar. (B) which read as follows: “If the Secretary receives an application for inclusion in the database from an individual whose status as a veteran cannot be verified because the Secretary does not maintain information with respect to the veteran status of the individual, the Secretary may not include the small business concern owned and controlled by the individual in the database maintained by the Secretary until the Secretary receives such information as may be necessary to verify that the individual is a veteran.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/b/1/B/iv">Pub. L. 116–283, § 862(b)(1)(B)(iv)</ref>, substituted “a veteran described in paragraph (1)” for “such veterans”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/b/1/B/vii">Pub. L. 116–283, § 862(b)(1)(B)(vii)</ref>, substituted “The Administrator” for “The Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/b/1/B/v">Pub. L. 116–283, § 862(b)(1)(B)(v)</ref>, (vi), redesignated par. (5) as (4) and struck out former par. (4), which required verification of veteran ownership or control.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/b/1/B/vi">Pub. L. 116–283, § 862(b)(1)(B)(vi)</ref>, redesignated par. (6) as (5). Former par. (5) redesignated (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/b/1/B/vi">Pub. L. 116–283, § 862(b)(1)(B)(vi)</ref>, redesignated par. (8) as (6). Former par. (6) redesignated (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(6)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/b/1/B/viii/I">Pub. L. 116–283, § 862(b)(1)(B)(viii)(I)</ref>, substituted “certify the status of the concern as a small business concern owned and controlled by veterans (under section 36A) or a small business concern owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans (under subsection (g) of this section)” for “verify the status of the concern as a small business concern or the ownership or control of the concern”, “certification” for “verification”, and “the Administration (as established under section 5(i))” for “the Small Business Administration (as established under section 5(i) of the Small Business Act)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(6)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/b/1/B/viii/II/aa">Pub. L. 116–283, § 862(b)(1)(B)(viii)(II)(aa)</ref>, substituted “small business concern owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans” for “small business concern owned and controlled by veterans with service-connected disabilities” and struck out “of the Small Business Administration” after “Hearings and Appeals”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(6)(B)(ii)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/b/1/B/viii/II/bb/AA">Pub. L. 116–283, § 862(b)(1)(B)(viii)(II)(bb)(AA)</ref>, amended subcl. (I) generally. Prior to amendment, subcl. (I) read as follows: “the Secretary; or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(6)(B)(ii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/b/1/B/viii/II/bb/BB">Pub. L. 116–283, § 862(b)(1)(B)(viii)(II)(bb)(BB)</ref>, substituted “the applicable contracting officer” for “the contracting officer of the Department”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(6)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/b/1/B/viii/III">Pub. L. 116–283, § 862(b)(1)(B)(viii)(III)</ref>, struck out subpar. (C) which read as follows: “For each fiscal year, the Secretary shall reimburse the Administrator of the Small Business Administration in an amount necessary to cover any cost incurred by the Office of Hearings and Appeals of the Small Business Administration for actions taken by the Office under this paragraph. The Administrator is authorized to accept such reimbursement. The amount of any such reimbursement shall be determined jointly by the Secretary and the Administrator and shall be provided from fees collected by the Secretary under multiple-award schedule contracts. Any disagreement about the amount shall be resolved by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/b/1/B/v">Pub. L. 116–283, § 862(b)(1)(B)(v)</ref>, struck out par. (7) which read as follows: “The Secretary may not issue regulations related to the status of a concern as a small business concern and the ownership and control of such small business concern.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/b/1/B/vi">Pub. L. 116–283, § 862(b)(1)(B)(vi)</ref>, redesignated par. (8) as (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/b/1/D">Pub. L. 116–283, § 862(b)(1)(D)</ref>, added subsec. (k). Former subsec. (k) redesignated (<i>l</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/116/315">Pub. L. 116–315</ref> substituted “or any other” for “and any other”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/b/1/C">Pub. L. 116–283, § 862(b)(1)(C)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (k) as (<i>l</i>). Former subsec. (<i>l</i>) redesignated (m).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/b/1/E">Pub. L. 116–283, § 862(b)(1)(E)</ref>, added par. (1) and redesignated former pars. (1) to (3) as (2) to (4), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/b/1/C">Pub. L. 116–283, § 862(b)(1)(C)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (<i>l</i>) as (m).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsecs. (b), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/116/155/s2/b">Pub. L. 116–155, § 2(b)</ref>, substituted “Except as provided in subsection (d)(2), for purposes” for “For purposes”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/116/155/s2/a">Pub. L. 116–155, § 2(a)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted “in paragraph (2) and” before “in subsections (b) and (c)”, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (k), (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/116/183">Pub. L. 116–183</ref> added subsec. (k) and redesignated former subsec. (k) as (<i>l</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1832/b/2/A">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1832(b)(2)(A)</ref>, inserted “or a small business concern owned and controlled by veterans with service-connected disabilities” after “a small business concern owned and controlled by veterans”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1832/b/2/B">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1832(b)(2)(B)</ref>, inserted “or a small business concern owned and controlled by veterans with service-connected disabilities” after “a small business concern owned and controlled by veterans” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1832/b/2/C">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1832(b)(2)(C)</ref>, inserted “or small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans with service-connected disabilities” after “small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1832/b/2/D">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1832(b)(2)(D)</ref>, inserted “, small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans with service-connected disabilities,” after “small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1832/d/1">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1832(d)(1)</ref>, substituted “verified, using regulations issued by the Administrator of the Small Business Administration with respect to the status of the concern as a small business concern and the ownership and control of such concern,” for “verified” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1832/d/2">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1832(d)(2)</ref>, added par. (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1832/f/1">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1832(f)(1)</ref>, added par. (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1832/b/1/A">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1832(b)(1)(A)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (i) as (h) and struck out former subsec. (h) which related to treatment of businesses after death of veteran-owner.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/114/315/s501/a/2">Pub. L. 114–315, § 501(a)(2)</ref>, amended subpar. (C) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (C) read as follows: “The date that is ten years after the date of the veteran’s death.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/114/315/s501/a/1">Pub. L. 114–315, § 501(a)(1)</ref>, substituted period at end for “rated as 100 percent disabling or who dies as a result of a service-connected disability.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (i), (j). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1832/b/1/A">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1832(b)(1)(A)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (j) and (k) as (i) and (j), respectively. Former subsec. (i) redesignated (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1832/b/1/A">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1832(b)(1)(A)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (<i>l</i>) as (k). Former subsec. (k) redesignated (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1832/b/1/B/i">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1832(b)(1)(B)(i)</ref>, amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “The term ‘small business concern owned and controlled by veterans’ means a small business concern—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A)(i) not less than 51 percent of which is owned by one or more veterans or, in the case of a publicly owned business, not less than 51 percent of the stock of which is owned by one or more veterans; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) the management and daily business operations of which are controlled by one or more veterans; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) not less than 51 percent of which is owned by one or more veterans with service-connected disabilities that are permanent and total who are unable to manage the daily business operations of such concern or, in the case of a publicly owned business, not less than 51 percent of the stock of which is owned by one or more such veterans.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1832/b/1/B/ii">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1832(b)(1)(B)(ii)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1832/b/1/A">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1832(b)(1)(A)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (<i>l</i>) as (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2012—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/112/154">Pub. L. 112–154</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted “willfully and intentionally” before “misrepresented”, substituted “a period of not less than five years” for “a reasonable period of time, as determined by the Secretary”, and added pars. (2) and (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsecs. (b), (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/350">Pub. L. 111–350</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s134">section 134 of title 41</ref>” for “section 4 of the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s403">41 U.S.C. 403</ref>)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/275/s104/b/1/A">Pub. L. 111–275, § 104(b)(1)(A)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A), inserted at end of subpar. (A) “Application for inclusion in the database shall constitute permission under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552a">section 552a of title 5</ref> (commonly referred to as the Privacy Act) for the Secretary to access such personal information maintained by the Secretary as may be necessary to verify the information contained in the application.”, and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/111/275/s104/b/1/B">Pub. L. 111–275, § 104(b)(1)(B)</ref>, added par. (4) and struck out former par. (4) which read as follows: “In maintaining the database, the Secretary shall carry out at least the following two verification functions:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) Verification that each small business concern listed in the database is owned and controlled by veterans.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) In the case of a veteran who indicates a service-connected disability, verification of the service-disabled status of such veteran.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsecs. (j) to (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/110/389">Pub. L. 110–389</ref> added subsec. (j) and redesignated former subsecs. (j) and (k) as (k) and (<i>l</i>), respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc42d4880-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc42d4881-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tVIII/s862/b/1">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VIII, § 862(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3776">134 Stat. 3776</ref>, provided that the amendment made by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/b">section 862(b) of Pub. L. 116–283</ref> shall take effect on the transfer date, which is 2 years after <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s862/a">section 862(a) of Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s657f">section 657f of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc42d4882-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2020 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/183/s2/b">Pub. L. 116–183, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2020-10-30">Oct. 30, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/896">134 Stat. 896</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/183/s2/b">“Subsection (k) of <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s8127">section 8127 of title 38</ref>, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall apply with respect to a contract entered into after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2020-10-30">Oct. 30, 2020</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/116/155/s2/c">Pub. L. 116–155, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="2020-08-08">Aug. 8, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/699">134 Stat. 699</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/155/s2/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall apply with respect to a contract entered into on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2020-08-08">Aug. 8, 2020</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc42d4883-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2016 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 1832(b), (d) of <ref href="/us/pl/114/328">Pub. L. 114–328</ref> effective on the date on which the Administrator of the Small Business Administration and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs jointly issue implementing regulations [regulations effective <date date="2018-10-01">Oct. 1, 2018</date>], see <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1832/e">section 1832(e) of Pub. L. 114–328</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s632">section 632 of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tXVIII/s1832/f/2">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XVIII, § 1832(f)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2661">130 Stat. 2661</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tXVIII/s1832/f/2">“Paragraph (8) of subsection (f) of title 38, United States Code, as added by paragraph (1), shall apply with respect to a verification decision made by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/114/315/tV/s501/b">Pub. L. 114–315, title V, § 501(b)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1566">130 Stat. 1566</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/315/tV/s501/b">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>] and shall apply with respect to contracts awarded on or after such date.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idc42d4884-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/461/tV/s502/d">Pub. L. 109–461, title V, § 502(d)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3435">120 Stat. 3435</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/461/tV/s502/d">“This section [enacting this section and provisions set out as a note below] and the amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idc42d4885-47c4-11f1-bf59-9680b1269b87"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Transition Provisions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/275/tI/s104/b/2">Pub. L. 111–275, title I, § 104(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-13">Oct. 13, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2868">124 Stat. 2868</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/275/tI/s104/b/2">
<inline>“In the case of a small business concern included in the database as of the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2010-10-13">Oct. 13, 2010</date>] for which, as of such date, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs has not verified the status of such concern in accordance with paragraph (4) of subsection (f) of <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s8127">section 8127 of title 38</ref>, United States Code, as amended by paragraph (1), not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall notify the person who owns and controls the concern that—</inline>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Secretary is required to verify the status of the concern in accordance with such paragraph, as so amended;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> verification of such status shall require that the person who owns and controls the concern apply for inclusion in the database in accordance with such subsection, as so amended;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> application for inclusion in the database shall constitute permission under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552a">section 552a of title 5</ref>, United States Code (commonly referred to as the Privacy Act), for the Secretary to access such personal information maintained by the Secretary as may be necessary to verify the information contained in the application; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> the person who owns and controls the concern must submit to the Secretary all information required by the Secretary under this paragraph within 90 days of receiving the Secretary’s notice of such requirement or the concern shall be removed from the database.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/109/461/tV/s502/b">Pub. L. 109–461, title V, § 502(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3435">120 Stat. 3435</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/461/tV/s502/b">“A small business concern that is listed in any small business database maintained by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2006-12-22">Dec. 22, 2006</date>] shall be presumed to be eligible for inclusion in the database under subsection (f) of <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s8127">section 8127 of title 38</ref>, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), during the period beginning on the effective date of that section [see Effective Date note above] and ending one year after such effective date. Such a small business concern may be removed from the database during that period if it is found not to be a small business concern owned and controlled by veterans (as defined in subsection (k) of such section).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
