<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id522d625a-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s102"><num value="102">§ 102.</num><heading> Michigan</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Michigan is divided into two judicial districts to be known as the Eastern and Western Districts of Michigan.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I81" class="centered">Eastern District</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">(a) The Eastern District comprises two divisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Southern Division comprises the counties of Genesee, Jackson, Lapeer, Lenawee, Livingston, Macomb, Monroe, Oakland, Saint Clair, Sanilac, Shiawassee, Washtenaw, and Wayne.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southern Division shall be held at Ann Arbor, Detroit, Flint, and Port Huron.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Northern Division comprises the counties of Alcona, Alpena, Arenac, Bay, Cheboygan, Clare, Crawford, Gladwin, Gratiot, Huron, Iosco, Isabella, Midland, Montmorency, Ogemaw, Oscoda, Otsego, Presque Isle, Roscommon, Saginaw, and Tuscola.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northern Division shall be held at Bay City.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I81" class="centered">Western District</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">(b) The Western District comprises two divisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Southern Division comprises the counties of Allegan, Antrim, Barry, Benzie, Berrien, Branch, Calhoun, Cass, Charlevoix, Clinton, Eaton, Emmet, Grand Traverse, Hillsdale, Ingham, Ionia, Kalamazoo, Kalkaska, Kent, Lake, Leelanau, Manistee, Mason, Mecosta, Missaukee, Montcalm, Muskegon, Newaygo, Oceana, Osceola, Ottawa, Saint Joseph, Van Buren, and Wexford.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southern Division shall be held at Grand Rapids, Kalamazoo, Lansing, and Traverse City.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Northern Division comprises the counties of Alger, Baraga, Chippewa, Delta, Dickinson, Gogebic, Houghton, Iron, Keweenaw, Luce, Mackinac, Marquette, Menominee, Ontonagon, and Schoolcraft.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northern Division shall be held at Marquette and Sault Sainte Marie.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id522d625b-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646">June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/882">62 Stat. 882</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1954-02-10/ch6">Feb. 10, 1954, ch. 6</ref> § 2(b)(8), <ref href="/us/stat/68/11">68 Stat. 11</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/36/s3/d">Pub. L. 87–36, § 3(d)</ref>, <date date="1961-05-19">May 19, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/83">75 Stat. 83</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/627">Pub. L. 88–627</ref>, <date date="1964-10-06">Oct. 6, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/1003">78 Stat. 1003</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/272/s11">Pub. L. 91–272, § 11</ref>, <date date="1970-06-02">June 2, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/298">84 Stat. 298</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id522d625c-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id522d625d-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed., § 168 (<ref href="/us/act/1911-03-03/ch231/s88">Mar. 3, 1911, ch. 231, § 88</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/36/1114">36 Stat. 1114</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1912-07-09/ch222">July 9, 1912, ch. 222</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/37/190">37 Stat. 190</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1930-03-31/ch101">Mar. 31, 1930, ch. 101</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/138">46 Stat. 138</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s168">section 168 of title 28</ref>, U.S.C., 1940 ed., relating to venue, were omitted as covered by section 1391 et seq. of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A provision for a special or adjourned term at Bay City for the hearing of admiralty cases, beginning in February of each year, was omitted. Adequate provision is made for such terms by <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s141">section 141 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Words “and mileage on service of process in said northern division shall be computed from Bay City,” at the end of the section, were omitted as covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s553">section 553 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions relating to appointment and residence of deputy clerks and deputy marshals and maintenance of offices by such deputies were omitted as covered by sections 541 [see 561], 542 [see 561], and 751 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Changes in arrangement and phraseology were made.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id522d625e-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id522d625f-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/91/272">Pub. L. 91–272</ref> provided for holding court at Traverse City.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1964—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/88/627">Pub. L. 88–627</ref> transferred counties of Genesee and Shiawassee from Northern Division to Southern Division, added Ann Arbor and Flint as places of court for Southern Division, and struck out Flint as a place for holding court.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1961—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/87/36">Pub. L. 87–36</ref> provided for holding court at Lansing instead of Mason.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1954—Subsec. (a)(1). Act <date date="1954-02-10">Feb. 10, 1954</date>, § 2(b)(8)(a), struck out counties of Branch, Calhoun, Clinton, Hillsdale, and Ingham, with respect to Southern Division of Eastern District.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). Act <date date="1954-02-10">Feb. 10, 1954</date>, § 2(b)(8)(b), substituted “Flint” for “Port Huron”, as a place for holding court.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). Act <date date="1954-02-10">Feb. 10, 1954</date>, § 2(b)(8)(c), inserted a reference to counties of Branch, Calhoun, Clinton, Hillsdale, and Ingham, with respect to composition of Southern Division of the Western District, and provided for holding court at Kalamazoo and Mason.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
