<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id522fd2b5-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s115"><num value="115">§ 115.</num><heading> Ohio</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Ohio is divided into two judicial districts to be known as the Northern and Southern Districts of Ohio.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I81" class="centered">Northern District</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">(a) The Northern District comprises two divisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Eastern Division comprises the counties of Ashland, Ashtabula, Carroll, Columbiana, Crawford, Cuyahoga, Geauga, Holmes, Lake, Lorain, Mahoning, Medina, Portage, Richland, Stark, Summit, Trumbull, Tuscarawas, and Wayne.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern Division shall be held at Cleveland, Youngstown, and Akron.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Western Division comprises the counties of Allen, Auglaize, Defiance, Erie, Fulton, Hancock, Hardin, Henry, Huron, Lucas, Marion, Mercer, Ottawa, Paulding, Putnam, Sandusky, Seneca, Van Wert, Williams, Woods, and Wyandot.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western Division shall be held at Lima and Toledo.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I81" class="centered">Southern District</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">(b) The Southern District comprises two divisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Western Division comprises the counties of Adams, Brown, Butler, Champaign, Clark, Clermont, Clinton, Darke, Greene, Hamilton, Highland, Lawrence, Miami, Montgomery, Preble, Scioto, Shelby, and Warren.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western Division shall be held at Cincinnati and Dayton.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Eastern Division comprises the counties of Athens, Belmont, Coshocton, Delaware, Fairfield, Fayette, Franklin, Gallia, Guernsey, Harrison, Hocking, Jackson, Jefferson, Knox, Licking, Logan, Madison, Meigs, Monroe, Morgan, Morrow, Muskingum, Noble, Perry, Pickaway, Pike, Ross, Union, Vinton, and Washington.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern Division shall be held at Columbus <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002004">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002004"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma.</note> St. Clairsville, and Steubenville.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id522fd2b6-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646">June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/887">62 Stat. 887</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1954-02-10/ch6/s2/b/9">Feb. 10, 1954, ch. 6, § 2(b)(9)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/11">68 Stat. 11</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/273/dC/tI/s11021">Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title I, § 11021</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1829">116 Stat. 1829</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id522fd2b7-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id522fd2b8-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed., § 181 (<ref href="/us/act/1911-03-03/ch231/s100">Mar. 3, 1911, ch. 231, § 100</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/36/1121">36 Stat. 1121</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1915-03-04/ch159">Mar. 4, 1915, ch. 159</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/1187">38 Stat. 1187</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1923-02-14/ch78">Feb. 14, 1923, ch. 78</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/1246">42 Stat. 1246</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Other provisions of said <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s181">section 181 of title 28</ref>, U.S.C., 1940 ed., are incorporated in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1865">section 1865 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions relating to the place of institution or trial of prosecutions and civil actions and transfer thereof were omitted. Such provisions, as to civil cases, are covered by section 1391 et seq. of this title, and as to criminal cases, are rendered unnecessary because of inherent power of the court and Rules 18–20 of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure relating to venue.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The provision respecting court accommodations at Lima was omitted as covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s142">section 142 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Changes were made in arrangement and phraseology.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id522fd2b9-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id522fd2ba-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/107/273">Pub. L. 107–273</ref>, which directed amendment of par. (2) by inserting “St. Clairsville,” after “Columbus,”, was executed by making the insertion after “Columbus”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1954—Subsec. (a)(1). Act <date date="1954-02-10">Feb. 10, 1954</date>, provided for holding court at Akron.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
