<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id529b18de-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1291"><num value="1291">§ 1291.</num><heading> Final decisions of district courts</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The courts of appeals (other than the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit) shall have jurisdiction of appeals from all final decisions of the district courts of the United States, the United States District Court for the District of the Canal Zone, the District Court of Guam, and the District Court of the Virgin Islands, except where a direct review may be had in the Supreme Court. The jurisdiction of the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit shall be limited to the jurisdiction described in sections 1292(c) and (d) and 1295 of this title.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id529b18df-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646">June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/929">62 Stat. 929</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1951-10-31/ch655/s48">Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 655, § 48</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/65/726">65 Stat. 726</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/508/s12/e">Pub. L. 85–508, § 12(e)</ref>, <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/348">72 Stat. 348</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/164/tI/s124">Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 124</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/36">96 Stat. 36</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id529b18e0-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id529b18e1-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed., §§ 225(a), 933(a)(1), and <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1356">section 1356 of title 48</ref>, U.S.C., 1940 ed., Territories and Insular Possessions, and sections 61 and 62 of title 7 of the Canal Zone Code (<ref href="/us/act/1911-03-03/ch231/s128">Mar. 3, 1911, ch. 231, § 128</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/36/1133">36 Stat. 1133</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1912-08-24/ch390/s9">Aug. 24, 1912, ch. 390, § 9</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/37/566">37 Stat. 566</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1915-01-28/ch22/s2">Jan. 28, 1915, ch. 22, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/804">38 Stat. 804</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1925-02-07/ch150">Feb. 7, 1925, ch. 150</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/43/813">43 Stat. 813</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1922-09-21/ch370/s3">Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 370, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/1006">42 Stat. 1006</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1925-02-13/ch229/s1">Feb. 13, 1925, ch. 229, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/43/936">43 Stat. 936</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1928-01-31/ch14/s1">Jan. 31, 1928, ch. 14, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/45/54">45 Stat. 54</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1932-05-17/ch190">May 17, 1932, ch. 190</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/47/158">47 Stat. 158</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1933-02-16/ch91/s3">Feb. 16, 1933, ch. 91, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/47/817">47 Stat. 817</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-05-31/ch160">May 31, 1935, ch. 160</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/313">49 Stat. 313</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1938-06-20/ch526">June 20, 1938, ch. 526</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/779">52 Stat. 779</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-02/ch753/s412/a/1">Aug. 2, 1946, ch. 753, § 412(a)(1)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/844">60 Stat. 844</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section rephrases and simplifies paragraphs “First”, “Second”, and “Third” of <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s225/a">section 225(a) of title 28</ref>, U.S.C., 1940 ed., which referred to each Territory and Possession separately, and to sections 61 and 62 of the Canal Zone Code, section 933(a)(1) of said title relating to jurisdiction of appeals in tort claims cases, and the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1356">section 1356 of title 48</ref>, U.S.C., 1940 ed., relating to jurisdiction of appeals from final judgments of the district court for the Canal Zone.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The district courts for the districts of Hawaii and Puerto Rico are embraced in the term “district courts of the United States.” (See definitive <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s451">section 451 of this title</ref>.)</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Paragraph “Fourth” of <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s225/a">section 225(a) of title 28</ref>, U.S.C., 1940 ed., is incorporated in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1293">section 1293 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Words “Fifth. In the United States Court for China, in all cases” in said section 225(a) were omitted. (See reviser’s note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s411">section 411 of this title</ref>.)</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Venue provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1356">section 1356 of title 48</ref>, U.S.C., 1940 ed., are incorporated in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1295">section 1295 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t7/s61">Section 61 of title 7</ref> of the Canal Zone Code is also incorporated in sections 1291 and 1295 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In addition to the jurisdiction conferred by this chapter, the courts of appeals also have appellate jurisdiction in proceedings under Title 11, Bankruptcy, and jurisdiction to review:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(1) Orders of the Secretary of the Treasury denying an application for, suspending, revoking, or annulling a basic permit under chapter 8 of title 27;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) Orders of the Interstate Commerce Commission, the Federal Communications Commission, the Civil Aeronautics Board, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Federal Trade Commission, based on violations of the antitrust laws or unfair or deceptive acts, methods, or practices in commerce;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(3) Orders of the Secretary of the Army under sections 504, 505 and 516 of title 33, U.S.C., 1940 ed., Navigation and Navigable Waters;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(4) Orders of the Civil Aeronautics Board under chapter 9 of title 49, except orders as to foreign air carriers which are subject to the President’s approval;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(5) Orders under chapter 1 of title 7, refusing to designate boards of trade as contract markets or suspending or revoking such designations, or excluding persons from trading in contract markets;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(6) Orders of the Federal Power Commission under chapter 12 of title 16;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(7) Orders of the Federal Security Administrator under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s371/e">section 371(e) of title 21</ref>, in a case of actual controversy as to the validity of any such order, by any person adversely affected thereby;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(8) Orders of the Federal Power Commission under chapter 15B of title 15;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(9) Final orders of the National Labor Relations Board;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(10) Cease and desist orders under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s193">section 193 of title 7</ref>;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(11) Orders of the Securities and Exchange Commission;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(12) Orders to cease and desist from violating <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1599">section 1599 of title 7</ref>;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(13) Wage orders of the Administrator of the Wage and Hour Division of the Department of Labor under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s208">section 208 of title 29</ref>;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(14) Orders under sections 81r and 1641 of title 19, U.S.C., 1940 ed., Customs Duties.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The courts of appeals also have jurisdiction to enforce:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(1) Orders of the Interstate Commerce Commission, the Federal Communications Commission, the Civil Aeronautics Board, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and the Federal Trade Commission, based on violations of the antitrust laws or unfair or deceptive acts, methods, or practices in commerce;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) Final orders of the National Labor Relations Board;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(3) Orders to cease and desist from violating <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1599">section 1599 of title 7</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia also has jurisdiction to review orders of the Post Office Department under <ref href="/us/usc/t39/s576">section 576 of title 39</ref> relating to discriminations in sending second-class publications by freight; Maritime Commission orders denying transfer to foreign registry of vessels under subsidy contract; sugar allotment orders; decisions of the Federal Communications Commission granting or refusing applications for construction permits for radio stations, or for radio station licenses, or for renewal or modification of radio station licenses, or suspending any radio operator’s license.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Changes were made in phraseology.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id529b18e2-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id529b18e3-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—<ref href="/us/pl/97/164/s124">Pub. L. 97–164, § 124</ref>, inserted “(other than the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit)” after “The court of appeals” and inserted provision that the jurisdiction of the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit shall be limited to the jurisdiction described in sections 1292(c) and (d) and 1295 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—<ref href="/us/pl/85/508">Pub. L. 85–508</ref> struck out provisions which gave courts of appeals jurisdiction of appeals from District Court for Territory of Alaska. See <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s81A">section 81A of this title</ref> which establishes a United States District Court for the State of Alaska.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1951—Act <date date="1951-10-31">Oct. 31, 1951</date>, inserted reference to District Court of Guam.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id529b18e4-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id529b18e5-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/164">Pub. L. 97–164</ref> effective <date date="1982-10-01">Oct. 1, 1982</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/164/s402">section 402 of Pub. L. 97–164</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s171">section 171 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id529b18e6-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1958 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/85/508">Pub. L. 85–508</ref> effective <date date="1959-01-03">Jan. 3, 1959</date>, on admission of Alaska into the Union pursuant to Proc. No. 3269, <date date="1959-01-03">Jan. 3, 1959</date>, 24 F.R. 81, 73 Stat. c.16 as required by sections 1 and 8(c) of <ref href="/us/pl/85/508">Pub. L. 85–508</ref>, see notes set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s81A">section 81A of this title</ref> and preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s21">section 21 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id529b18e7-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of United States District Court for the District of the Canal Zone</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination of the United States District Court for the District of the Canal Zone at end of the “transition period”, being the 30-month period beginning <date date="1979-10-01">Oct. 1, 1979</date>, and ending midnight <date date="1982-03-31">Mar. 31, 1982</date>, see Paragraph 5 of Article XI of the Panama Canal Treaty of 1977 and sections 2101 and 2201 to 2203 of <ref href="/us/pl/96/70/tII">Pub. L. 96–70, title II</ref>, <date date="1979-09-27">Sept. 27, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/493">93 Stat. 493</ref>, formerly classified to sections 3831 and 3841 to 3843, respectively, of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
