<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id52a4b4c8-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1367"><num value="1367">§ 1367.</num><heading> Supplemental jurisdiction</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52a4b4c9-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1367/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c) or as expressly provided otherwise by Federal statute, in any civil action of which the district courts have original jurisdiction, the district courts shall have supplemental jurisdiction over all other claims that are so related to claims in the action within such original jurisdiction that they form part of the same case or controversy under Article III of the United States Constitution. Such supplemental jurisdiction shall include claims that involve the joinder or intervention of additional parties.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52a4b4ca-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1367/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> In any civil action of which the district courts have original jurisdiction founded solely on <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1332">section 1332 of this title</ref>, the district courts shall not have supplemental jurisdiction under subsection (a) over claims by plaintiffs against persons made parties under Rule 14, 19, 20, or 24 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure, or over claims by persons proposed to be joined as plaintiffs under Rule 19 of such rules, or seeking to intervene as plaintiffs under Rule 24 of such rules, when exercising supplemental jurisdiction over such claims would be inconsistent with the jurisdictional requirements of section 1332.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52a4b4cb-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1367/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><chapeau> The district courts may decline to exercise supplemental jurisdiction over a claim under subsection (a) if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id52a4b4cc-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1367/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the claim raises a novel or complex issue of State law,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id52a4b4cd-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1367/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the claim substantially predominates over the claim or claims over which the district court has original jurisdiction,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id52a4b4ce-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1367/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the district court has dismissed all claims over which it has original jurisdiction, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id52a4b4cf-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1367/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> in exceptional circumstances, there are other compelling reasons for declining jurisdiction.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52a4b4d0-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1367/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> The period of limitations for any claim asserted under subsection (a), and for any other claim in the same action that is voluntarily dismissed at the same time as or after the dismissal of the claim under subsection (a), shall be tolled while the claim is pending and for a period of 30 days after it is dismissed unless State law provides for a longer tolling period.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52a4b4d1-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1367/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> As used in this section, the term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id52a4b4d2-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/101/650/tIII/s310/a">Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 310(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5113">104 Stat. 5113</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id52a4b4d3-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id52a4b4d4-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id52a4b4d5-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Rules of Civil Procedure, referred to in subsec. (b), are set out in the Appendix to this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id52a4b4d6-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id52a4b4d7-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/650/tIII/s310/c">Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 310(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5114">104 Stat. 5114</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/650/tIII/s310/c">“The amendments made by this section [enacting this section] shall apply to civil actions commenced on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
