<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id52abe14f-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1447"><num value="1447">§ 1447.</num><heading> Procedure after removal generally</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52abe150-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1447/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> In any case removed from a State court, the district court may issue all necessary orders and process to bring before it all proper parties whether served by process issued by the State court or otherwise.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52abe151-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1447/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> It may require the removing party to file with its clerk copies of all records and proceedings in such State court or may cause the same to be brought before it by writ of certiorari issued to such State court.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52abe152-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1447/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> A motion to remand the case on the basis of any defect other than lack of subject matter jurisdiction must be made within 30 days after the filing of the notice of removal under section 1446(a). If at any time before final judgment it appears that the district court lacks subject matter jurisdiction, the case shall be remanded. An order remanding the case may require payment of just costs and any actual expenses, including attorney fees, incurred as a result of the removal. A certified copy of the order of remand shall be mailed by the clerk to the clerk of the State court. The State court may thereupon proceed with such case.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52abe153-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1447/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> An order remanding a case to the State court from which it was removed is not reviewable on appeal or otherwise, except that an order remanding a case to the State court from which it was removed pursuant to section 1442 or 1443 of this title shall be reviewable by appeal or otherwise.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52abe154-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1447/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> If after removal the plaintiff seeks to join additional defendants whose joinder would destroy subject matter jurisdiction, the court may deny joinder, or permit joinder and remand the action to the State court.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id52abe155-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646">June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/939">62 Stat. 939</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-05-24/ch139/s84">May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 84</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/102">63 Stat. 102</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/352/tIX/s901">Pub. L. 88–352, title IX, § 901</ref>, <date date="1964-07-02">July 2, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/266">78 Stat. 266</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/702/tX/s1016/c">Pub. L. 100–702, title X, § 1016(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4670">102 Stat. 4670</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/198/s10/b">Pub. L. 102–198, § 10(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-09">Dec. 9, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1626">105 Stat. 1626</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/219/s1">Pub. L. 104–219, § 1</ref>, <date date="1996-10-01">Oct. 1, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3022">110 Stat. 3022</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/51/s2/d">Pub. L. 112–51, § 2(d)</ref>, <date date="2011-11-09">Nov. 9, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/546">125 Stat. 546</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id52abe156-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id52abe157-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I71" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id52abe158-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered">1948 <inline class="small-caps">Act</inline></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed., §§ 71, 72, 74, 76, 80, 81 and 83 (<ref href="/us/act/1911-03-03/ch231">Mar. 3, 1911, ch. 231</ref>, §§ 28, 29, 31, 33, 37 and 38, <ref href="/us/stat/36/1094-1098">36 Stat. 1094–1098</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1914-01-20/ch11">Jan. 20, 1914, ch. 11</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/278">39 Stat. 278</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1916-08-23/ch399">Aug. 23, 1916, ch. 399</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/532">39 Stat. 532</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1920-04-16/ch146">Apr. 16, 1920, ch. 146</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/41/554">41 Stat. 554</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1928-01-31/ch14/s1">Jan. 31, 1928, ch. 14, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/45/54">45 Stat. 54</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section consolidates procedural provisions of sections 71, 72, 74, 76, 80, 81 and 83 of title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed., with important changes in substance and phraseology.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (a) is derived from sections 72, 76, 81 and 83 of title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed. The remaining provisions of said section 83 are the basis of <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1448">section 1448 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (b) is derived from sections 72, 74, 76 and 83 of title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed., which have been rewritten to provide the utmost simplicity and flexibility of procedure in bringing the State court record to the district court.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[<i>Editorial Note.—</i>Subsecs. (c), (d) and (e) as originally revised and incorporated in this section read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(c) It may order the pleadings recast and the parties realigned according to their real interest.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(d) If any party fails to comply with its lawful orders, the district court may enter such further orders and judgments as justice requires.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(e) If at any time before final judgment it appears that the case was removed improvidently and without jurisdiction, the district court shall remand the case. A certified copy of the order of remand shall be mailed by its clerk to the clerk of the State court. The State court may thereupon proceed with such case.”]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsections (c) and (d) are substituted for unnecessary and inconsistent procedural provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (e) [now subsec. (c)] is derived from sections 71 and 80 of title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed. Such subsection is rewritten to eliminate the cumbersome procedure of remand. Under this chapter as revised, the petition for removal under section 1446 of this chapter will be filed in the Federal court in the first instance and the right of removal determined in that court before the petition is granted.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The provisions in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s80">section 80 of title 28</ref>, U.S.C., 1940 ed., relating to actions commenced in district courts, as distinguished from actions removed thereto, are incorporated in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1359">section 1359 of this title</ref>. Other provisions of said section 80 appear in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1919">section 1919 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I71" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id52abe159-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered">1949 <inline class="small-caps">Act</inline></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section strikes out subsections (c) and (d) of <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1447">section 1447 of title 28</ref>, U.S.C., as covered by the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure, and adds a new subsection to such section 1447 to remove any doubt that the former law as to the finality of an order of remand to a State court is continued. This section also amends renumbered subsection (c) to remove any doubt that the former law authorizing the district court upon remand to order payment of costs is continued.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id52abe15a-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id52abe15b-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/112/51">Pub. L. 112–51</ref> inserted “1442 or” before “1443”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/219">Pub. L. 104–219</ref> substituted “any defect other than lack of subject matter jurisdiction” for “any defect in removal procedure” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/198">Pub. L. 102–198</ref> substituted “removing party” for “petitioner”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/100/702/s1016/c/1">Pub. L. 100–702, § 1016(c)(1)</ref>, amended subsec. (c) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (c) read as follows: “If at any time before final judgment it appears that the case was removed improvidently and without jurisdiction, the district court shall remand the case, and may order the payment of just costs. A certified copy of the order of remand shall be mailed by its clerk to the clerk of the State court. The State court may thereupon proceed with such case.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/100/702/s1016/c/2">Pub. L. 100–702, § 1016(c)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1964—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/88/352">Pub. L. 88–352</ref>, inserted exception provision.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1949—Subsec. (c). Act <date date="1949-05-24">May 24, 1949</date>, § 84(a), struck out former subsecs. (c) and (d), renumbered former subsec. (e) to be subsec. (c) and inserted at end of first sentence of new subsec. (c) “and may order the payment of just costs”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). Act <date date="1949-05-24">May 24, 1949</date>, § 84(b), added subsec. (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id52abe15c-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id52abe15d-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Exception to Subsection (d)</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1947-08-04/ch458/s3/c">Act Aug. 4, 1947, ch. 458, § 3(c)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/732">61 Stat. 732</ref>, provides in part that the United States shall have the right to appeal from any order of remand entered in any case removed to a United States district court pursuant to the provisions of <ref href="/us/act/1926-04-12/ch115">act Apr. 12, 1926, ch. 115</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/239">44 Stat. 239</ref>. These acts referred to herein relate to restrictions on land of the Five Civilized Tribes of Oklahoma and are set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s355">section 355 of Title 25</ref>, Indians.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
