<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id52abe1bd-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1491"><num value="1491">§ 1491.</num><heading> Claims against United States generally; actions involving Tennessee Valley Authority</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52abe1be-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1491/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52abe1bf-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1491/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The United States Court of Federal Claims shall have jurisdiction to render judgment upon any claim against the United States founded either upon the Constitution, or any Act of Congress or any regulation of an executive department, or upon any express or implied contract with the United States, or for liquidated or unliquidated damages in cases not sounding in tort. For the purpose of this paragraph, an express or implied contract with the Army and Air Force Exchange Service, Navy Exchanges, Marine Corps Exchanges, Coast Guard Exchanges, or Exchange Councils of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration shall be considered an express or implied contract with the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52abe1c0-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1491/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> To provide an entire remedy and to complete the relief afforded by the judgment, the court may, as an incident of and collateral to any such judgment, issue orders directing restoration to office or position, placement in appropriate duty or retirement status, and correction of applicable records, and such orders may be issued to any appropriate official of the United States. In any case within its jurisdiction, the court shall have the power to remand appropriate matters to any administrative or executive body or official with such direction as it may deem proper and just. The Court of Federal Claims shall have jurisdiction to render judgment upon any claim by or against, or dispute with, a contractor arising under <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s7104/b/1">section 7104(b)(1) of title 41</ref>, including a dispute concerning termination of a contract, rights in tangible or intangible property, compliance with cost accounting standards, and other nonmonetary disputes on which a decision of the contracting officer has been issued under section 6 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002073">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002073"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of that Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52abe1c1-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1491/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52abe1c2-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1491/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Both the Unites <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002074">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002074"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “United”.</note> States Court of Federal Claims and the district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction to render judgment on an action by an interested party objecting to a solicitation by a Federal agency for bids or proposals for a proposed contract or to a proposed award or the award of a contract or any alleged violation of statute or regulation in connection with a procurement or a proposed procurement. Both the United States Court of Federal Claims and the district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction to entertain such an action without regard to whether suit is instituted before or after the contract is awarded.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52abe1c3-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1491/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> To afford relief in such an action, the courts may award any relief that the court considers proper, including declaratory and injunctive relief except that any monetary relief shall be limited to bid preparation and proposal costs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52abe1c4-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1491/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In exercising jurisdiction under this subsection, the courts shall give due regard to the interests of national defense and national security and the need for expeditious resolution of the action.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52abe1c5-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1491/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> In any action under this subsection, the courts shall review the agency’s decision pursuant to the standards set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s706">section 706 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52abe1c6-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1491/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> If an interested party who is a member of the private sector commences an action described in paragraph (1) with respect to a public-private competition conducted under Office of Management and Budget Circular A–76 regarding the performance of an activity or function of a Federal agency, or a decision to convert a function performed by Federal employees to private sector performance without a competition under Office of Management and Budget Circular A–76, then an interested party described in <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3551/2/B">section 3551(2)(B) of title 31</ref> shall be entitled to intervene in that action.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52abe1c7-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1491/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Jurisdiction over any action described in paragraph (1) arising out of a maritime contract, or a solicitation for a proposed maritime contract, shall be governed by this section and shall not be subject to the jurisdiction of the district courts of the United States under the Suits in Admiralty Act (chapter 309 of title 46) or the Public Vessels Act (chapter 311 of title 46).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52abe1c8-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1491/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> Nothing herein shall be construed to give the United States Court of Federal Claims jurisdiction of any civil action within the exclusive jurisdiction of the Court of International Trade, or of any action against, or founded on conduct of, the Tennessee Valley Authority, or to amend or modify the provisions of the Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933 with respect to actions by or against the Authority.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id52abe1c9-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646">June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/940">62 Stat. 940</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1953-07-28/ch253/s7">July 28, 1953, ch. 253, § 7</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/226">67 Stat. 226</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1954-09-03/ch1263/s44/a">Sept. 3, 1954, ch. 1263, § 44(a)</ref>, (b), <ref href="/us/stat/68/1241">68 Stat. 1241</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/350/s1/b">Pub. L. 91–350, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1970-07-23">July 23, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/449">84 Stat. 449</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/415/s1">Pub. L. 92–415, § 1</ref>, <date date="1972-08-29">Aug. 29, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/652">86 Stat. 652</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/563/s14/i">Pub. L. 95–563, § 14(i)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2391">92 Stat. 2391</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/417/tV/s509">Pub. L. 96–417, title V, § 509</ref>, <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1743">94 Stat. 1743</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/164/tI/s133/a">Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 133(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/39">96 Stat. 39</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/572/tIX">Pub. L. 102–572, title IX</ref>, §§ 902(a), 907(b)(1), <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4516">106 Stat. 4516</ref>, 4519; <ref href="/us/pl/104/320/s12/a">Pub. L. 104–320, § 12(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3874">110 Stat. 3874</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/161/dD/tVII/s739/c/2">Pub. L. 110–161, div. D, title VII, § 739(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/2031">121 Stat. 2031</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/181/dA/tIII/s326/c">Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title III, § 326(c)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/63">122 Stat. 63</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/417">Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title X, § 1061(d), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4613">122 Stat. 4613</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s5/g/7">Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(g)(7)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3848">124 Stat. 3848</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/dA/tVIII/s861/a">Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VIII, § 861(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1521">125 Stat. 1521</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id52abe1ca-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id52abe1cb-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed., § 250(1) (<ref href="/us/act/1911-03-03/ch231">Mar. 3, 1911, ch. 231</ref>; § 145, <ref href="/us/stat/36/1136">36 Stat. 1136</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">District courts are given concurrent jurisdiction of certain claims against the United States under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1346">section 1346 of this title</ref>. (See also reviser’s note under that section and <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1621">section 1621 of this title</ref> relating to jurisdiction of the Tax Court.)</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The proviso in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s250/1">section 250(1) of title 28</ref>, U.S.C., 1940 ed., relating to claims growing out of the Civil War, commonly known as “war claims,” and other claims which had been reported adversely before <date date="1887-03-03">March 3, 1887</date> by any court, department, or commission authorized to determine them, were omitted as obsolete.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The exception in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s250/1">section 250(1) of title 28</ref>, U.S.C., 1940 ed., as to pension claims appears in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1501">section 1501 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Words “in respect of which claims the party would be entitled to redress against the United States either in a court of law, equity, or admiralty, if the United States were suable” were omitted as unnecessary since the Court of Claims manifestly, under this section will determine whether a petition against the United States states a cause of action. In any event, the Court of Claims has no admiralty jurisdiction, but the Suits in Admiralty Act, sections 741–752 of title 46, U.S.C., 1940 ed., Shipping, vests exclusive jurisdiction over suits in admiralty against the United States in the district courts. <i>Sanday &amp; Co. v. U.S</i>., 1932, 76 Ct.Cl. 370.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For additional provisions respecting jurisdiction of the court of claims in war contract settlement cases see <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s114b">section 114b of Title 41</ref>, U.S.C., 1940 ed., Public Contracts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Changes were made in phraseology.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id52abe1cc-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id52abe1cd-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 6 of the Contract Disputes Act of 1978, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), was classified to section 605 of former Title 41, Public Contracts, and was repealed and restated as subsecs. (a) to (c)(1) and (d) to (h) of <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s7103">section 7103 of Title 41</ref>, Public Contracts, by <ref href="/us/pl/111/350">Pub. L. 111–350</ref>, §§ 3, 7(b), <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3677">124 Stat. 3677</ref>, 3855.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/act/1933-05-18/ch32">act May 18, 1933, ch. 32</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/58">48 Stat. 58</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 12A (§ 831 et seq.) of Title 16, Conservation. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s831">section 831 of Title 16</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id52abe1ce-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/350">Pub. L. 111–350</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s7104/b/1">section 7104(b)(1) of title 41</ref>” for “section 10(a)(1) of the Contract Disputes Act of 1978”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/112/81">Pub. L. 112–81</ref> added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/110/417">Pub. L. 110–417</ref> struck out par. (5), as added by <ref href="/us/pl/110/161">Pub. L. 110–161</ref>, which read as follows: “If a private sector interested party commences an action described in paragraph (1) in the case of a public-private competition conducted under Office of Management and Budget Circular A–76 regarding performance of an activity or function of a Federal agency, or a decision to convert a function performed by Federal employees to private sector performance without a competition under Office of Management and Budget Circular A–76, then an official or person described in <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3551/2/B">section 3551(2)(B) of title 31</ref> shall be entitled to intervene in that action.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/181">Pub. L. 110–181</ref> added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/110/161">Pub. L. 110–161</ref> added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/320/s12/a/2">Pub. L. 104–320, § 12(a)(2)</ref>, struck out par. (3) which read as follows: “To afford complete relief on any contract claim brought before the contract is awarded, the court shall have exclusive jurisdiction to grant declaratory judgments and such equitable and extraordinary relief as it deems proper, including but not limited to injunctive relief. In exercising this jurisdiction, the court shall give due regard to the interests of national defense and national security.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/320/s12/a/1">Pub. L. 104–320, § 12(a)(1)</ref>, (3), added subsec. (b) and redesignated former subsec. (b) as (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/572/s902/a/1">Pub. L. 102–572, § 902(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “United States Court of Federal Claims” for “United States Claims Court”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/572/s907/b/1">Pub. L. 102–572, § 907(b)(1)</ref>, inserted before period at end “, including a dispute concerning termination of a contract, rights in tangible or intangible property, compliance with cost accounting standards, and other nonmonetary disputes on which a decision of the contracting officer has been issued under section 6 of that Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/572/s902/a/2">Pub. L. 102–572, § 902(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “Court of Federal Claims” for “Claims Court”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/572/s902/a/1">Pub. L. 102–572, § 902(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “United States Court of Federal Claims” for “United States Claims Court”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/97/164">Pub. L. 97–164</ref> designated first two sentences of existing first undesignated paragraph as subsec. (a)(1) and substituted “United States Claims Court” for “Court of Claims”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/97/164">Pub. L. 97–164</ref> designated third, fourth, and fifth sentences of existing first un­designated paragraph as par. (2) and substituted “The Claims Court” for “The Court of Claims” and “arising under section 10(a)(1) of the Contract Disputes Act of 1978” for “arising under the Contract Disputes Act of 1978”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/97/164">Pub. L. 97–164</ref> added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/97/164">Pub. L. 97–164</ref> designated existing second undesignated paragraph as subsec. (b) and substituted “United States Claims Court” for “Court of Claims”, “conduct of, the Tennessee Valley Authority, or” for “actions of, the Tennessee Valley Authority, nor”, “Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933” for “Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933, as amended,”, and “actions by or against the Authority” for “suits by or against the Authority”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—<ref href="/us/pl/96/417">Pub. L. 96–417</ref> substituted “Court of Claims of any civil action within the exclusive jurisdiction of the Court of International Trade, or of any action” for “in suits” in second par.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—<ref href="/us/pl/95/563">Pub. L. 95–563</ref> provided that the Court of Claims would have jurisdiction to render judgment upon any claim by or against, or dispute with, a contractor arising under the Contract Disputes Act of 1978.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1972—<ref href="/us/pl/92/415">Pub. L. 92–415</ref> inserted provisions authorizing the court to issue orders directing restoration to office or position, placement in appropriate duty or retirement status and correction of applicable records and to issue such orders to any United States official and to remand appropriate matters to administrative and executive bodies with proper directions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—<ref href="/us/pl/91/350">Pub. L. 91–350</ref> specified that the term “express or implied contracts with the United States” includes express or implied contracts with the Army and Air Force Exchange Service, Navy Exchanges, Marine Corps Exchanges, Coast Guard Exchanges, or Exchange Councils of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1954—Act <date date="1954-09-03">Sept. 3, 1954</date>, inserted “; actions involving Tennessee Valley Authority” in section catchline and altered the form of first par. to spell out the general jurisdiction of the Court in paragraph form rather than as clauses of the par.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1953—Act <date date="1953-07-28">July 28, 1953</date>, substituted “United States Court of Claims” for “Court of Claims” near beginning of section, and inserted last par.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id52abe1cf-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id52abe1d0-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2011 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/81/dA/tVIII/s861/b">Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VIII, § 861(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1521">125 Stat. 1521</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/81/dA/tVIII/s861/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to any cause of action filed on or after the first day of the first month beginning more than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id52abe1d1-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/181/dA/tIII/s326/d">Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title III, § 326(d)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/63">122 Stat. 63</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/181/dA/tIII/s326/d">
<inline>“Subparagraph (B) of <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3551/2">section 3551(2) of title 31</ref>, United States Code (as added by subsection (a)), and paragraph (5) of <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1491/b">section 1491(b) of title 28</ref>, United States Code (as added by subsection (c)), shall apply to—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> a protest or civil action that challenges final selection of the source of performance of an activity or function of a Federal agency that is made pursuant to a study initiated under Office of Management and Budget Circular A–76 on or after <date date="2004-01-01">January 1, 2004</date>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> any other protest or civil action that relates to a public-private competition initiated under Office of Management and Budget Circular A–76, or to a decision to convert a function performed by Federal employees to private sector performance without a competition under Office of Management and Budget Circular A–76, on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>].”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id52abe1d2-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2007 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Paragraph (5) of subsec. (b) of this section applicable to protests and civil actions that challenge final selections of sources of performance of an activity or function of a Federal agency that are made pursuant to studies initiated under Office of Management and Budget Circular A–76 on or after <date date="2004-01-01">Jan. 1, 2004</date>; and to any other protests and civil actions that relate to public-private competitions initiated under Office of Management and Budget Circular A–76, or a decision to convert a function performed by Federal employees to private sector performance without a competition under Office of Management and Budget Circular A–76, on or after <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/161/s739/c/3">section 739(c)(3) of Pub. L. 110–161</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s501">section 501 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/110/161">Pub. L. 110–161</ref> applicable with respect to fiscal year 2008 and each succeeding fiscal year, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/161/s739/e">section 739(e) of Pub. L. 110–161</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s501">section 501 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id52abe1d3-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/320/s12/b">Pub. L. 104–320, § 12(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3875">110 Stat. 3875</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/320/s12/b">“This section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3556">section 3556 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3556">section 3556 of Title 31</ref>] and the amendments made by this section shall take effect on <date date="1996-12-31">December 31, 1996</date> and shall apply to all actions filed on or after that date.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id52abe1d4-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/572/s902/a">section 902(a) of Pub. L. 102–572</ref> effective <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/572/s911">section 911 of Pub. L. 102–572</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s171">section 171 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/102/572/tIX/s907/b/2">Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 907(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4519">106 Stat. 4519</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/572/tIX/s907/b/2">
<inline>“The amendment made by paragraph (1) [amending this section] shall be effective with respect to all actions filed before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>], except for those actions which, before such date of enactment, have been the subject of—</inline>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a final judgment of the United States Claims Court, if the time for appeal of that judgment has expired without an appeal having been filed, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a final judgment of the Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id52abe1d5-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/164">Pub. L. 97–164</ref> effective <date date="1982-10-01">Oct. 1, 1982</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/164/s402">section 402 of Pub. L. 97–164</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s171">section 171 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id52abe1d6-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/417">Pub. L. 96–417</ref> effective <date date="1980-11-01">Nov. 1, 1980</date>, and applicable with respect to civil actions pending on or commenced on or after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/417/s701/a">section 701(a) of Pub. L. 96–417</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s251">section 251 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id52abe1d7-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/563">Pub. L. 95–563</ref> effective with respect to contracts entered into 120 days after <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, and, at the election of the contractor, with respect to any claim pending at such time before the contracting officer or initiated thereafter, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/563/s16">section 16 of Pub. L. 95–563</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2391">92 Stat. 2391</ref>, formerly set out as an Effective Date note under section 601 of former Title 41, Public Contracts.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id52abe1d8-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1972 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/92/415/s2">Pub. L. 92–415, § 2</ref>, <date date="1972-08-29">Aug. 29, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/652">86 Stat. 652</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/92/415/s2">“This Act [amending this section] shall be applicable to all judicial proceedings pending on or instituted after the date of its enactment [<date date="1972-08-29">Aug. 29, 1972</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id52abe1d9-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1970 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/350">Pub. L. 91–350</ref> applicable to claims and civil actions dismissed before or pending on <date date="1970-07-23">July 23, 1970</date>, if the claim or civil action was based upon a transaction, omission, or breach that occurred not more than six years prior to <date date="1970-07-23">July 23, 1970</date>, notwithstanding a determination or judgment made prior to <date date="1970-07-23">July 23, 1970</date>, that the United States district courts or the United States Court of Claims did not have jurisdiction to entertain a suit on an express or implied contract with a nonappropriated fund instrumentality of the United States, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/350/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 91–350</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1346">section 1346 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="savings" id="id52abe1da-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Savings Provision</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/320/s12/e">Pub. L. 104–320, § 12(e)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3875">110 Stat. 3875</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/320/s12/e">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Orders</inline>.—</heading><content>A termination under subsection (d) [set out below] shall not terminate the effectiveness of orders that have been issued by a court in connection with an action within the jurisdiction of that court on or before <date date="2000-12-31">December 31, 2000</date>. Such orders shall continue in effect according to their terms until modified, terminated, superseded, set aside, or revoked by a court of competent jurisdiction or by operation of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Proceedings and applications</inline>.—</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a termination under subsection (d) shall not affect the jurisdiction of a court of the United States to continue with any proceeding that is pending before the court on <date date="2000-12-31">December 31, 2000</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Orders may be issued in any such proceeding, appeals may be taken therefrom, and payments may be made pursuant to such orders, as if such termination had not occurred. An order issued in any such proceeding shall continue in effect until modified, terminated, superseded, set aside, or revoked by a court of competent jurisdiction or by operation of law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Nothing in this paragraph prohibits the discontinuance or modification of any such proceeding under the same terms and conditions and to the same extent that proceeding could have been discontinued or modified absent such termination.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id52abe1db-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Sunset Provision</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/320/s12/d">Pub. L. 104–320, § 12(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3875">110 Stat. 3875</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/320/s12/d">“The jurisdiction of the district courts of the United States over the actions described in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1491/b/1">section 1491(b)(1) of title 28</ref>, United States Code (as amended by subsection (a) of this section) shall terminate on <date date="2001-01-01">January 1, 2001</date> unless extended by Congress. The savings provisions in subsection (e) [set out above] shall apply if the bid protest jurisdiction of the district courts of the United States terminates under this subsection.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id52abe1dc-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id52abe1dd-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study on Concurrent Jurisdiction</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/320/s12/c">Pub. L. 104–320, § 12(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3875">110 Stat. 3875</ref>, required that, no earlier than 2 years after <date date="1996-12-31">Dec. 31, 1996</date>, the General Accounting Office was to undertake a study regarding the concurrent jurisdiction of the district courts of the United States and the Court of Federal Claims over bid protests to determine whether concurrent jurisdiction was necessary, which study was to be completed no later than <date date="1999-12-31">Dec. 31, 1999</date>, and was to specifically consider the effect of any proposed change on the ability of small businesses to challenge violations of Federal procurement law.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
