<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id52b55688-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1608"><num value="1608">§ 1608.</num><heading> Service; time to answer; default</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52b55689-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1608/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> Service in the courts of the United States and of the States shall be made upon a foreign state or political subdivision of a foreign state:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id52b5568a-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1608/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> by delivery of a copy of the summons and complaint in accordance with any special arrangement for service between the plaintiff and the foreign state or political subdivision; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id52b5568b-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1608/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> if no special arrangement exists, by delivery of a copy of the summons and complaint in accordance with an applicable international convention on service of judicial documents; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id52b5568c-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1608/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> if service cannot be made under paragraphs (1) or (2), by sending a copy of the summons and complaint and a notice of suit, together with a translation of each into the official language of the foreign state, by any form of mail requiring a signed receipt, to be addressed and dispatched by the clerk of the court to the head of the ministry of foreign affairs of the foreign state concerned, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id52b5568d-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1608/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> if service cannot be made within 30 days under paragraph (3), by sending two copies of the summons and complaint and a notice of suit, together with a translation of each into the official language of the foreign state, by any form of mail requiring a signed receipt, to be addressed and dispatched by the clerk of the court to the Secretary of State in Washington, District of Columbia, to the attention of the Director of Special Consular Services—and the Secretary shall transmit one copy of the papers through diplomatic channels to the foreign state and shall send to the clerk of the court a certified copy of the diplomatic note indicating when the papers were transmitted.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">As used in this subsection, a “notice of suit” shall mean a notice addressed to a foreign state and in a form prescribed by the Secretary of State by regulation.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52b5568e-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1608/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> Service in the courts of the United States and of the States shall be made upon an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id52b5568f-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1608/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> by delivery of a copy of the summons and complaint in accordance with any special arrangement for service between the plaintiff and the agency or instrumentality; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id52b55690-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1608/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> if no special arrangement exists, by delivery of a copy of the summons and complaint either to an officer, a managing or general agent, or to any other agent authorized by appointment or by law to receive service of process in the United States; or in accordance with an applicable international convention on service of judicial documents; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id52b55691-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1608/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> if service cannot be made under paragraphs (1) or (2), and if reasonably calculated to give actual notice, by delivery of a copy of the summons and complaint, together with a translation of each into the official language of the foreign state—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id52b55692-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1608/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> as directed by an authority of the foreign state or political subdivision in response to a letter rogatory or request or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id52b55693-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1608/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> by any form of mail requiring a signed receipt, to be addressed and dispatched by the clerk of the court to the agency or instrumentality to be served, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id52b55694-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1608/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> as directed by order of the court consistent with the law of the place where service is to be made.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52b55695-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1608/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><chapeau> Service shall be deemed to have been made—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id52b55696-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1608/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> in the case of service under subsection (a)(4), as of the date of transmittal indicated in the certified copy of the diplomatic note; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id52b55697-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1608/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> in any other case under this section, as of the date of receipt indicated in the certification, signed and returned postal receipt, or other proof of service applicable to the method of service employed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52b55698-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1608/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> In any action brought in a court of the United States or of a State, a foreign state, a political subdivision thereof, or an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state shall serve an answer or other responsive pleading to the complaint within sixty days after service has been made under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52b55699-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s1608/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> No judgment by default shall be entered by a court of the United States or of a State against a foreign state, a political subdivision thereof, or an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state, unless the claimant establishes his claim or right to relief by evidence satisfactory to the court. A copy of any such default judgment shall be sent to the foreign state or political subdivision in the manner prescribed for service in this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id52b5569a-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/94/583/s4/a">Pub. L. 94–583, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2894">90 Stat. 2894</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id52b5569b-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id52b5569c-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id52b5569d-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 90 days after <date date="1976-10-21">Oct. 21, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/583/s8">section 8 of Pub. L. 94–583</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1602">section 1602 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
