<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id52c86a51-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s2001"><num value="2001">§ 2001.</num><heading> Sale of realty generally</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52c86a52-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s2001/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Any realty or interest therein sold under any order or decree of any court of the United States shall be sold as a whole or in separate parcels at public sale at the courthouse of the county, parish, or city in which the greater part of the property is located, or upon the premises or some parcel thereof located therein, as the court directs. Such sale shall be upon such terms and conditions as the court directs.<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Property in the possession of a receiver or receivers appointed by one or more district courts shall be sold at public sale in the district wherein any such receiver was first appointed, at the courthouse of the county, parish, or city situated therein in which the greater part of the property in such district is located, or on the premises or some parcel thereof located in such county, parish, or city, as such court directs, unless the court orders the sale of the property or one or more parcels thereof in one or more ancillary districts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52c86a53-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s2001/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> After a hearing, of which notice to all interested parties shall be given by publication or otherwise as the court directs, the court may order the sale of such realty or interest or any part thereof at private sale for cash or other consideration and upon such terms and conditions as the court approves, if it finds that the best interests of the estate will be conserved thereby. Before confirmation of any private sale, the court shall appoint three disinterested persons to appraise such property or different groups of three appraisers each to appraise properties of different classes or situated in different localities. No private sale shall be confirmed at a price less than two-thirds of the appraised value. Before confirmation of any private sale, the terms thereof shall be published in such newspaper or newspapers of general circulation as the court directs at least ten days before confirmation. The private sale shall not be confirmed if a bona fide offer is made, under conditions prescribed by the court, which guarantees at least a 10 per centum increase over the price offered in the private sale.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52c86a54-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s2001/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> This section shall not apply to sales and proceedings under Title 11 or by receivers or conservators of banks appointed by the Comptroller of the Currency.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id52c86a55-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646">June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/958">62 Stat. 958</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-05-24/ch139/s99">May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 99</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/104">63 Stat. 104</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id52c86a56-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id52c86a57-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I71" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id52c86a58-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered">1948 <inline class="small-caps">Act</inline></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed., § 847 (<ref href="/us/act/1893-03-03/ch225/s1">Mar. 3, 1893, ch. 225, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/27/751">27 Stat. 751</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-19/ch662">June 19, 1934, ch. 662</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1119">48 Stat. 1119</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-04-24/ch77/s1">Apr. 24, 1935, ch. 77, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/159">49 Stat. 159</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-06-19/ch276">June 19, 1935, ch. 276</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/390">49 Stat. 390</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A provision making the section applicable to pending proceedings was deleted as obsolete.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The term “court of the United States” is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s451">section 451 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Changes were made in phraseology.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I71" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id52c86a59-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered">1949 <inline class="small-caps">Act</inline></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section corrects a typographical error in subsection (a) of <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2001">section 2001 of title 28</ref>, U.S.C.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id52c86a5a-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id52c86a5b-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1949—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1949-05-24">May 24, 1949</date>, corrected spelling of “ancillary” in second par.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
