<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id52e0376e-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s2411"><num value="2411">§ 2411.</num><heading> Interest</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In any judgment of any court rendered (whether against the United States, a collector or deputy collector of internal revenue, a former collector or deputy collector, or the personal representative in case of death) for any overpayment in respect of any internal-revenue tax, interest shall be allowed at the overpayment rate established under section 6621 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 upon the amount of the overpayment, from the date of the payment or collection thereof to a date preceding the date of the refund check by not more than thirty days, such date to be determined by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue. The Commissioner is authorized to tender by check payment of any such judgment, with interest as herein provided, at any time after such judgment becomes final, whether or not a claim for such payment has been duly filed, and such tender shall stop the running of interest, whether or not such refund check is accepted by the judgment creditor.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id52e0376f-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646">June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/973">62 Stat. 973</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-05-24/ch139/s120">May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 120</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/106">63 Stat. 106</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/625/s7/a/2">Pub. L. 93–625, § 7(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2115">88 Stat. 2115</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/164/tIII/s302/b">Pub. L. 97–164, title III, § 302(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/56">96 Stat. 56</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, title XV, § 1511(c)(18), <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>, 2746.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id52e03770-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id52e03771-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I71" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id52e03772-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered">1948 <inline class="small-caps">Act</inline></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed., §§ 765, 931(a), 932, <ref href="/us/act/1877-03-03/ch359/s10">Mar. 3, 1877, ch. 359, § 10</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/24/507">24 Stat. 507</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1925-02-13/ch229/s8">Feb. 13, 1925, ch. 229, § 8</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/43/940">43 Stat. 940</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1928-01-31/ch14/s1">Jan. 31, 1928, ch. 14, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/45/54">45 Stat. 54</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-02/ch753">Aug. 2, 1946, ch. 753</ref>, §§ 410(a), 411, <ref href="/us/stat/60/843">60 Stat. 843</ref>, 844).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section consolidates section 765 with provisions of sections 931(a) and 932, all of title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed., relating to interest on judgments, the latter two sections being applicable to judgments in tort claims cases. For other provisions of said sections 931(a) and 932, see Distribution Table. Said section 932 made the provisions of said section 765 applicable to such judgments, therefore the provisions of said section 931(a) that “the United States shall not be liable for interest prior to judgment” was omitted as covered by the language of said section 765 providing that interest shall be computed from the date of the judgment.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s765">section 765 of title 28</ref>, U.S.C., 1940 ed., that when the findings of fact and the law applicable thereto have been filed in any case as provided in “section 763” [764] of title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed., and the judgment or decree is adverse to the Government, it shall be the duty of the district attorney to transmit to the Attorney General of the United States certified copies of all the papers filed in the cause, with a transcript of the testimony taken, the written findings of the court, and his written opinion as to the same, that, whereupon, the Attorney General shall determine and direct whether an appeal shall be taken or not, and that, when so directed, the district attorney shall cause an appeal to be perfected in accordance with the terms of the statutes and rules of practice governing the same were omitted as unnecessary and covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s507">section 507 of this title</ref> which provides for supervision of United States attorneys by the Attorney General.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Words of <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s765">section 765 of title 28</ref>, U.S.C., 1940 ed., “Until the time when an appropriation is made for the payment of the judgment or decree” were omitted and words “up to, but not exceeding, thirty days after the date of approval of any appropriation act providing for payment of the judgment” were substituted. Substituted words clarify meaning and are in accord with congressional procedure in annual deficiency appropriation acts for payment of judgments against the United States. The substituted words will obviate necessity of repeating such provisions in appropriation acts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Changes were made in phraseology.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I71" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id52e03773-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered">1949 <inline class="small-caps">Act</inline></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section amends <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2411">section 2411 of title 28</ref>, U.S.C., by restoring the provisions of section 177 of the former Judicial Code for the payment of interest on tax refunds.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id52e03774-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id52e03775-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 6621 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, referred to in text, is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6621">section 6621 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id52e03776-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—<ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1511/c/18">Pub. L. 99–514, § 1511(c)(18)</ref>, substituted “the overpayment rate established under section 6621” for “an annual rate established under section 6621”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, substituted “Internal Revenue Code of 1986” for “Internal Revenue Code of 1954”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—<ref href="/us/pl/97/164">Pub. L. 97–164</ref> struck out “(a)” before “In any judgment” and struck out subsec. (b) which provided that, except as otherwise provided in subsection (a) of this section, on all final judgments rendered against the United States in actions instituted under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1346">section 1346 of this title</ref>, interest was to be computed at the rate of 4 per centum per annum from the date of the judgment up to, but not exceeding, thirty days after the date of approval of any appropriation Act providing for payment of the judgment.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/93/625">Pub. L. 93–625</ref> substituted “an annual rate established under section 6621 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954” for “the rate of 6 per centum per annum”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1949—Act <date date="1949-05-24">May 24, 1949</date>, restored provisions relating to payment of interest on tax refunds.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id52e03777-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id52e03778-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> applicable for purposes of determining interest for periods after <date date="1986-12-31">Dec. 31, 1986</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1511/d">section 1511(d) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s6621">section 6621 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id52e03779-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/164">Pub. L. 97–164</ref> effective <date date="1982-10-01">Oct. 1, 1982</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/164/s402">section 402 of Pub. L. 97–164</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s171">section 171 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
