<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5255f96b-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s451"><num value="451">§ 451.</num><heading> Definitions</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this title:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The term “court of the United States” includes the Supreme Court of the United States, courts of appeals, district courts constituted by chapter 5 of this title, including the Court of International Trade and any court created by Act of Congress the judges of which are entitled to hold office during good behavior.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The terms “district court” and “district court of the United States” mean the courts constituted by chapter 5 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The term “judge of the United States” includes judges of the courts of appeals, district courts, Court of International Trade and any court created by Act of Congress, the judges of which are entitled to hold office during good behavior.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The term “justice of the United States” includes the Chief Justice of the United States and the associate justices of the Supreme Court.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The terms “district” and “judicial district” means the districts enumerated in Chapter 5 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The term “department” means one of the executive departments enumerated in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1">section 1 of Title 5</ref>, unless the context shows that such term was intended to describe the executive, legislative, or judicial branches of the government.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The term “agency” includes any department, independent establishment, commission, administration, authority, board or bureau of the United States or any corporation in which the United States has a proprietary interest, unless the context shows that such term was intended to be used in a more limited sense.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id5255f96c-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646">June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/907">62 Stat. 907</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/3/s10">Pub. L. 86–3, § 10</ref>, <date date="1959-03-18">Mar. 18, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/9">73 Stat. 9</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/571/s3">Pub. L. 89–571, § 3</ref>, <date date="1966-09-12">Sept. 12, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/764">80 Stat. 764</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/598/tII/s213">Pub. L. 95–598, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2661">92 Stat. 2661</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/417/tV/s501/10">Pub. L. 96–417, title V, § 501(10)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-10">Oct. 10, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1742">94 Stat. 1742</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/164/tI/s114">Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/29">96 Stat. 29</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5255f96d-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5255f96e-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revisions Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section was inserted to make possible a greater simplification in consolidation of the provisions incorporated in this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The definitions of agency and department conform with such definitions in section 6 of revised title 18, U.S.C. (H.R. 3190, 80th Cong.).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5255f96f-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Senate Revision Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Those provisions of this section which related to the Tax Court were eliminated by Senate amendment. See 80th Congress Senate Report No. 1559.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5255f970-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id5255f971-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1">Section 1 of Title 5</ref>, referred to in text, is section 1 of former Title 5, Executive Departments and Government Officers and Employees, the provisions of which are covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s101">section 101 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id5255f972-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—<ref href="/us/pl/97/164">Pub. L. 97–164</ref> struck out references to the Court of Claims and to the Court of Customs and Patent Appeals in the definitions of “court of the United States” and “judge of the United States”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—<ref href="/us/pl/96/417">Pub. L. 96–417</ref> redesignated the Customs Court as the Court of International Trade.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—<ref href="/us/pl/95/598">Pub. L. 95–598</ref> directed the amendment of section by inserting references to bankruptcy courts and bankruptcy judges, which amendment did not become effective pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/95/598/s402/b">section 402(b) of Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, as amended, set out as an Effective Date note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t11/s101">section 101 of Title 11</ref>, Bankruptcy.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—<ref href="/us/pl/89/571">Pub. L. 89–571</ref> removed the United States District Court for the District of Puerto Rico from the definition of “court of the United States”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1959—<ref href="/us/pl/86/3">Pub. L. 86–3</ref> substituted “including the United States District for the District of Puerto Rico” for “including the district courts of the United States for the districts of Hawaii and Puerto Rico” in provisions defining “court of the United States”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5255f973-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5255f974-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/164">Pub. L. 97–164</ref> effective <date date="1982-10-01">Oct. 1, 1982</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/164/s402">section 402 of Pub. L. 97–164</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s171">section 171 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5255f975-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/417">Pub. L. 96–417</ref> effective <date date="1980-11-01">Nov. 1, 1980</date>, and applicable with respect to civil actions pending on or commenced on or after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/417/s701/a">section 701(a) of Pub. L. 96–417</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s251">section 251 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id5255f976-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1959 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/86/3/s10">Pub. L. 86–3, § 10</ref>, <date date="1959-03-18">Mar. 18, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/9">73 Stat. 9</ref>, provided that the amendment made by <ref href="/us/pl/86/3/s10">section 10 of Pub. L. 86–3</ref> shall be effective on admission of the State of Hawaii into the Union. Admission of Hawaii into the Union was accomplished <date date="1959-08-21">Aug. 21, 1959</date>, on issuance of Proc. No. 3309, <date date="1959-08-21">Aug. 21, 1959</date>, 25 F.R. 6868, 73 Stat. c74, as required by sections 1 and 7(c) of <ref href="/us/pl/86/3">Pub. L. 86–3</ref>, <date date="1959-03-18">Mar. 18, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/4">73 Stat. 4</ref>, set out as notes preceding 491 of Title 48, Territories and Insular Possessions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I74" class="centered smallCaps">“Circuit Court of Appeals;” “Senior Circuit Judge,” Etc. Defined</p>
<p><ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646/s32">Act June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 32</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/991">62 Stat. 991</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/act/1949-05-24/ch139/s127">act May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 127</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/107">63 Stat. 107</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/act/1949-05-24/ch139/s127">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> All laws of the United States in force on <date date="1948-09-01">September 1, 1948</date>, in which reference is made to a ‘circuit court of appeals’; ‘senior circuit judge’; ‘senior district judge’; ‘presiding judge’; ‘chief justice’, except when reference to the Chief Justice of the United States is intended; or ‘justice’, except when used with respect to a justice of the Supreme Court of the United States in his capacity as such or as a circuit justice, are hereby amended by substituting ‘court of appeals’ for ‘circuit court of appeals’; ‘chief judge of the circuit’ for ‘senior circuit judge’; ‘chief judge of the district court’ for ‘senior district judge’; ‘chief judge’ for ‘presiding judge’; ‘chief judge’ for ‘chief justice’, except when reference to the Chief Justice of the United States is intended; and ‘judge’ for ‘justice’, except when the latter term is used with respect to a justice of the Supreme Court of the United States in his capacity as such or as a circuit justice.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> All laws of the United States in force on <date date="1948-09-01">September 1, 1948</date>, in which reference is made to the Supreme Court of the District of Columbia or to the District Court of the United States for the District of Columbia are amended by substituting ‘United States District Court for the District of Columbia’ for such designations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> All laws of the United States in force on <date date="1948-09-01">September 1, 1948</date>, in which reference is made to the ‘Conference of Senior Circuit Judges,’ or to the ‘Judicial Conference of Senior Circuit Judges’ are amended by substituting ‘Judicial Conference of the United States’ for such designations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><content> This section shall not be construed to amend historical references to courts or judicial offices which have no present or future application to such courts or offices.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5255f977-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Judges of the United States</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646/s2/a">Act June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 2(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/985">62 Stat. 985</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/act/1954-09-03/ch1263/s51/a">act Sept. 3, 1954, ch. 1263, § 51(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/1245">68 Stat. 1245</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1954-09-03/ch1263/s51/a">“The Chief Justices of the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia, the District Court of the United States for the District of Columbia, and the Court of Claims [now United States Court of Federal Claims], and the presiding judge of the Court of Customs and Patent Appeals [now United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit], in office on the effective date of this Act shall be the chief judges of their respective courts. The Chief Justice of the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia and the Associate Justices thereof, the Chief Justice of the District Court of the United States for the District of Columbia (formerly named the Supreme Court of the District of Columbia) and the Associate Justices thereof, the Chief Justice of the Court of Claims [now United States Court of Federal Claims], and the presiding judge of the Court of Customs and Patent Appeals [now United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit], in office on the effective date of this Act, shall be judges of the United States within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s451">Section 451 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure, of the United States Code, set out in Section 1 of this Act. The Chief Justice of the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia and the Associate Justices thereof, in office on the effective date of this Act, shall be circuit judges of the District of Columbia Circuit and vested with all the rights, powers, and duties thereof, and the said Chief Justice of the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia shall be Chief Judge of said Circuit. The Chief Justice of the District Court of the United States for the District of Columbia (formerly named the Supreme Court of the District of Columbia) and the Associate Justices thereof, in office on the effective date of this Act, shall be district judges for the District of Columbia and vested with all the rights, powers, and duties thereof.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1954-09-03/ch1263/s51/b">Act Sept. 3, 1954, ch. 1263, § 51(b)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/1246">68 Stat. 1246</ref>, provided that this amendment should take effect as of <date date="1948-09-01">Sept. 1, 1948</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
