<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5264508e-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s520"><num value="520">§ 520.</num><heading> Transmission of petitions in United States Court of Federal Claims or in United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit; statement furnished by departments</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5264508f-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s520/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> In suits against the United States in the United States Court of Federal Claims or in the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit founded on a contract, agreement, or transaction with an executive department or military department, or a bureau, officer, or agent thereof, or when the matter or thing on which the claim is based has been passed on and decided by an executive department, military department, bureau, or officer authorized to adjust it, the Attorney General shall send to the department, bureau, or officer a printed copy of the petition filed by the claimant, with a request that the department, bureau, or officer furnish to the Attorney General all facts, circumstances, and evidence concerning the claim in the possession or knowledge of the department, bureau, or officer.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id52645090-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s520/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Within a reasonable time after receipt of the request from the Attorney General, the executive department, military department, bureau, or officer shall furnish the Attorney General with a written statement of all facts, information, and proofs. The statement shall contain a reference to or description of all official documents and papers, if any, as may furnish proof of facts referred to in it, or may be necessary and proper for the defense of the United States against the claim, mentioning the department, office, or place where the same is kept or may be secured. If the claim has been passed on and decided by the department, bureau, or officer, the statement shall briefly state the reasons and principles on which the decision was based. When the decision was founded on an Act of Congress it shall be cited specifically, and if any previous interpretation or construction has been given to the Act, section, or clause by the department, bureau, or officer, it shall be set forth briefly in the statement and a copy of the opinion filed, if any, attached to it. When a decision in the case has been based on a regulation of a department or when a regulation has, in the opinion of the department, bureau, or officer sending the statement, any bearing on the claim, it shall be distinctly quoted at length in the statement. When more than one case or class of cases is pending, the defense of which rests on the same facts, circumstances, and proofs, the department, bureau, or officer may certify and send one statement and it shall be held to apply to all cases as if made out, certified, and sent in each case respectively.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id52645091-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s4/c">Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/614">80 Stat. 614</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/97/164/tI/s118/a">Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 118(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-04-02">Apr. 2, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/32">96 Stat. 32</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/572/tIX/s902/b/1">Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4516">106 Stat. 4516</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id52645092-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<note topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id52645093-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<html:table class="HNR" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc: c3,L2,tp7,xs42,xls54,r50,tp7,xs42,xls54,r50; " id="id52645094-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="width:46pt ; max-width:46pt;" />
<html:col style="width:58pt ; max-width:58pt;" />
<html:col style="min-width: 102pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style=""><html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Historical and Revision Notes</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="width:46.0pt ; max-width:46.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Derivation</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:58.0pt ; max-width:58.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>U.S. Code</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="min-width: 102.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-bottom:0em;"><html:i>Revised Statutes and</html:i></html:p><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-top:0em;"><html:i>Statutes at Large</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span> </html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:a href="/us/usc/t5/s91">5 U.S.C. 91</html:a>.</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">R.S. § 188.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The section is reorganized and restated for clarity.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (a), the word “concerning” is substituted for “touching”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (b), the words “without delay” are omitted as unnecessary in view of the requirement that the statement be furnished “Within a reasonable time”. The word “briefly” is substituted for “succinctly”. The words “in suit” are omitted as unnecessary.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The words “executive department” are substituted for “department” because “department” as used in R.S. § 188 meant “executive department”. (See R.S. § 159.) The words “military department” are inserted to preserve the application of the source law. Before enactment of the National Security Act Amendments of 1949 (<ref href="/us/stat/63/578">63 Stat. 578</ref>), the Department of the Army, the Department of the Navy, and the Department of the Air Force were Executive departments. The National Security Act Amendments of 1949 established the Department of Defense as an Executive Department including the Department of the Army, the Department of the Navy, and the Department of the Air Force as military departments, not as Executive departments. However, the source law for this section, which was in effect in 1949, remained applicable to the Secretaries of the military departments by virtue of section 12(g) of the National Security Act Amendments of 1949 (<ref href="/us/stat/63/591">63 Stat. 591</ref>), which is set out in the reviser’s note for <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s301">section 301 of title 5</ref>, United States Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id52645095-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id52645096-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—<ref href="/us/pl/102/572">Pub. L. 102–572</ref> substituted “United States Court of Federal Claims” for “United States Claims Court” in section catchline and subsec. (a).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—<ref href="/us/pl/97/164/s118/a/2">Pub. L. 97–164, § 118(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “United States Claims Court or in United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit” for “Court of Claims” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/164/s118/a/1">Pub. L. 97–164, § 118(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “United States Claims Court or in the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit” for “Court of Claims”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id52645097-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id52645098-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/572">Pub. L. 102–572</ref> effective <date date="1992-10-29">Oct. 29, 1992</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/572/s911">section 911 of Pub. L. 102–572</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s171">section 171 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id52645099-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/164">Pub. L. 97–164</ref> effective <date date="1982-10-01">Oct. 1, 1982</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/164/s402">section 402 of Pub. L. 97–164</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s171">section 171 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
