<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id526b7ce6-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s532"><num value="532">§ 532.</num><heading> Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Attorney General may appoint a Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation. The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation is the head of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id526b7ce7-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s4/c">Pub. L. 89–554, § 4(c)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/616">80 Stat. 616</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id526b7ce8-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id526b7ce9-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The section is supplied for convenience and clarification and is based on section 3 of Executive Order No. 6166 of <date date="1933-06-10">June 10, 1933</date>, which provided for the transfer of the functions of the Bureau of Investigation together with the investigative functions of the Bureau of Prohibition to a “Division of Investigation in the Department of Justice, at the head of which shall be a Director of Investigation”. The Division of Investigation was first designated as the “Federal Bureau of Investigation” by the <ref href="/us/act/1935-03-22/ch39/tII">Act of Mar. 22, 1935, ch. 39, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/77">49 Stat. 77</ref>, and has been so designated in statutes since that date. The title of “Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation” was recognized by statute in the <ref href="/us/act/1936-06-05/ch529">Act of June 5, 1936, ch. 529</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1484">49 Stat. 1484</ref>, and has been used in statutes since that date.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id526b7cea-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id526b7ceb-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Notification of Material Changes to Policies or Procedures Governing Terrorist Watchlist and Transnational Organized Crime Watchlist</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dF/tLXV/s6522">Pub. L. 119–60, div. F, title LXV, § 6522</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1631">139 Stat. 1631</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dF/tLXV/s6522">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notification of Material Changes.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notification required</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees notice of any material change to a policy or procedure relating to the terrorist watchlist or the transnational organized crime watchlist, including any change to the policy or procedure for adding or removing a person from either watchlist. Each notification under this subsection shall include a summary of the material changes to such policy or procedure.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Timing of notification</inline>.—</heading><content>Each notification required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted not later than 30 days after the date on which a material change described in paragraph (1) takes effect.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requests by Appropriate Committees</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 30 days after receiving a request from an appropriate congressional committee, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall submit to such committee all guidance in effect as of the date of the request that applies to or governs the use of the terrorist watchlist or the transnational organized crime watchlist.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate congressional committees</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘appropriate congressional committees’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the congressional intelligence committees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the Committees on the Judiciary of the Senate and the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Terrorist watchlist</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘terrorist watchlist’ means the Terrorist Screening Dataset or any successor or similar watchlist.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transnational organized crime watchlist</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘transnational organized crime watchlist’ means the watchlist maintained under the Transnational Organized Crime Actor Detection Program or any successor or similar watchlist.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definition of “congressional intelligence committees” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6522">section 6522 of Pub. L. 119–60</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6002">section 6002 of Pub. L. 119–60</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id526b7cec-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Review of Information Relating to Actions by Foreign Governments To Assist Persons Evading Justice</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dF/tLXVII/s6715">Pub. L. 119–60, div. F, title LXVII, § 6715</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1650">139 Stat. 1650</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dF/tLXVII/s6715">“Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>], the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall, in coordination with the Director of National Intelligence, complete a review for declassification of any information in the possession of the Federal Bureau of Investigation collected on or after <date date="2020-01-01">January 1, 2020</date>, relating to whether any foreign government official has assisted or facilitated any citizen or national of their country in departing the United States while the citizen or national was under investigation or awaiting trial or sentencing for a criminal offense committed in the United States to determine what information, if any, can be appropriately declassified and made available to the public. Upon completion of the review, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall make such information, if any, available to the public in a manner consistent with provisions of Federal law related to privacy.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id526dc6dd-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Limitation on Procurement by Federal Bureau of Investigation of People’s Republic of China Products and Services</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dX/tIV/s414">Pub. L. 117–103, div. X, title IV, § 414</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/977">136 Stat. 977</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/103/dX/tIV/s414">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Security Assessment</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation may not procure a People’s Republic of China product or service unless, before such procurement—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the Federal Bureau of Investigation conducts a security assessment of such product or service, including with respect to any physical, counterintelligence, or cyber vulnerabilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> there is included in the process of conducting such security assessment a formal mechanism through which input shall be submitted by the Counterintelligence Division and Cyber Division of the Federal Bureau of Investigation regarding such security assessment, including with respect to any such vulnerabilities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the Director (or a designee of the Director) approves a recommendation, based on the results of such security assessment, to procure such product or service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Director (or a designee of the Director, as applicable) approves a recommendation pursuant to subsection (a)(3), the Director shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees the recommendation and a copy of the security assessment upon which the recommendation was based.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate congressional committees</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘appropriate congressional committees’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the congressional intelligence committees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Subcommittees on Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies of the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">People’s republic of china product or service</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘People’s Republic of China product or service’ means an information or communication technology product manufactured in China, Hong Kong, or Macau, or a product or service provided by an entity that is fully or partially owned or controlled by, or otherwise connected to, the government of China.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definition of “congressional intelligence committees” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dX/s414">section 414 of div. X of Pub. L. 117–103</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dX/s2">section 2 of div. X of Pub. L. 117–103</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">section 3003 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id526dc6de-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Counterintelligence Units at Non-Intelligence Community Federal Departments and Agencies</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dX/tIV/s415">Pub. L. 117–103, div. X, title IV, § 415</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/978">136 Stat. 978</ref>, which related to the establishment of counterintelligence units at non-intelligence community Federal departments and agencies, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dG/tIII/s7318/b">Pub. L. 118–31, div. G, title III, § 7318(b)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/1033">137 Stat. 1033</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id526dc6df-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Findings</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/24/s1">Pub. L. 112–24, § 1</ref>, <date date="2011-07-26">July 26, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/238">125 Stat. 238</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/24/s1">
<inline>“Congress finds that—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> on <date date="2011-05-12">May 12, 2011</date>, the President requested that Congress extend the term of Robert S. Mueller III as Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation by 2 years, citing the critical need for continuity and stability at the Federal Bureau of Investigation in the face of ongoing threats to the United States and leadership transitions at the Federal agencies charged with protecting national security;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> in light of the <date date="2011-05-01">May 1, 2011</date>, successful operation against Osama bin Laden, the continuing threat to national security, and the approaching 10th anniversary of the attacks of <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>, the President’s request for a limited, 1-time exception to the term limit of the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, in these exceptional circumstances, is appropriate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> this Act [amending provisions set out as a note under this section] is intended to provide a 1-time exception to the 10-year statutory limit on the term of the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation in light of the President’s request and existing exceptional circumstances, and is not intended to create a precedent.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id526dc6e0-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Improvement of Intelligence Capabilities; Directorate of Intelligence; Intelligence Career Service</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tII">Pub. L. 108–458, title II</ref>, §§ 2001–2003, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3700">118 Stat. 3700</ref>, 3702, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/111/259/tVIII/s806/b/1">Pub. L. 111–259, title VIII, § 806(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-07">Oct. 7, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2748">124 Stat. 2748</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/113/dM/tVII/s701/b">Pub. L. 114–113, div. M, title VII, § 701(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/2929">129 Stat. 2929</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/113/dM/tVII/s701/b">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="2001">“SEC. 2001.</num><heading> IMPROVEMENT OF INTELLIGENCE CAPABILITIES OF THE FEDERAL BUREAU OF INVESTIGATION.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The National Commission on Terrorist Attacks Upon the United States in its final report stated that, under Director Robert Mueller, the Federal Bureau of Investigation has made significant progress in improving its intelligence capabilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> In the report, the members of the Commission also urged that the Federal Bureau of Investigation fully institutionalize the shift of the Bureau to a preventive counterterrorism posture.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Improvement of Intelligence Capabilities</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall continue efforts to improve the intelligence capabilities of the Federal Bureau of Investigation and to develop and maintain within the Bureau a national intelligence workforce.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">National Intelligence Workforce</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In developing and maintaining a national intelligence workforce under subsection (b), the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall develop and maintain a specialized and integrated national intelligence workforce consisting of agents, analysts, linguists, and surveillance specialists who are recruited, trained, and rewarded in a manner which ensures the existence within the Federal Bureau of Investigation of an institutional culture with substantial expertise in, and commitment to, the intelligence mission of the Bureau.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Each agent employed by the Bureau after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>] shall receive basic training in both criminal justice matters and national intelligence matters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Each agent employed by the Bureau after the date of the enactment of this Act shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be given the opportunity to undergo, during such agent’s early service with the Bureau, meaningful assignments in criminal justice matters and in national intelligence matters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><chapeau> The Director shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> establish career positions in national intelligence matters for agents, analysts, and related personnel of the Bureau; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> in furtherance of the requirement under subparagraph (A) and to the maximum extent practicable, afford agents, analysts, and related personnel of the Bureau the opportunity to work in the career specialty selected by such agents, analysts, and related personnel over their entire career with the Bureau.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> The Director shall carry out a program to enhance the capacity of the Bureau to recruit and retain individuals with backgrounds in intelligence, international relations, language, technology, and other skills relevant to the intelligence mission of the Bureau.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> The Director shall, to the maximum extent practicable, afford the analysts of the Bureau training and career opportunities commensurate with the training and career opportunities afforded analysts in other elements of the intelligence community.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> Commencing as soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, each direct supervisor of a Field Intelligence Group, and each Bureau Operational Manager at the Section Chief and Assistant Special Agent in Charge (ASAC) level and above, shall be a certified intelligence officer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> The Director shall, to the maximum extent practicable, ensure that the successful discharge of advanced training courses, and of one or more assignments to another element of the intelligence community, is a precondition to advancement to higher level intelligence assignments within the Bureau.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Field Office Matters</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In improving the intelligence capabilities of the Federal Bureau of Investigation under subsection (b), the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall ensure that each Field Intelligence Group reports directly to a field office senior manager responsible for intelligence matters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Director shall provide for such expansion of the secure facilities in the field offices of the Bureau as is necessary to ensure the discharge by the field offices of the intelligence mission of the Bureau.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The Director shall require that each Field Intelligence Group manager ensures the integration of analysts, agents, linguists, and surveillance personnel in the field.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Discharge of Improvements</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall carry out subsections (b) through (d) through the head of the Directorate of Intelligence of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall carry out subsections (b) through (d) under the joint guidance of the Attorney General and the Director of National Intelligence in a manner consistent with applicable law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Budget Matters</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall establish a budget structure of the Federal Bureau of Investigation to reflect the four principal missions of the Bureau as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Intelligence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Counterterrorism and counterintelligence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Criminal Enterprises/Federal Crimes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Criminal justice services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>], the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall submit to Congress a report on the progress made as of the date of such report in carrying out the requirements of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Director shall include in each annual program review of the Federal Bureau of Investigation that is submitted to Congress a report on the progress made by each field office of the Bureau during the period covered by such review in addressing Bureau and national program priorities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 12 months thereafter, the Director shall submit to Congress a report on the progress of the Bureau in implementing information-sharing principles.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="2002">“SEC. 2002.</num><heading> DIRECTORATE OF INTELLIGENCE OF THE FEDERAL BUREAU OF INVESTIGATION.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Directorate of Intelligence of Federal Bureau of Investigation</inline>.—</heading><content>The element of the Federal Bureau of Investigation known as of the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>] as the Office of Intelligence is hereby redesignated as the Directorate of Intelligence of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Head of Directorate</inline>.—</heading><content>The head of the Directorate of Intelligence shall be the Executive Assistant Director for Intelligence of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Directorate of Intelligence shall be responsible for the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Supervision of all national intelligence programs, projects, and activities of the Bureau.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The discharge by the Bureau of the requirements in section 105B of the National Security Act of 1947 ([former] <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s403–5b">50 U.S.C. 403–5b</ref>) [now <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3040">50 U.S.C. 3040</ref>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The oversight of Bureau field intelligence operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Coordinating human source development and management by the Bureau.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Coordinating collection by the Bureau against nationally-determined intelligence requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> Strategic analysis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> Intelligence program and budget management.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> The intelligence workforce.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> Any other responsibilities specified by the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation or specified by law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Staff</inline>.—</heading><content>The Directorate of Intelligence shall consist of such staff as the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation considers appropriate for the activities of the Directorate.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="2003">“SEC. 2003.</num><heading> FEDERAL BUREAU OF INVESTIGATION INTELLIGENCE CAREER SERVICE.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Federal Bureau of Investigation Intelligence Career Service</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> in consultation with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> establish positions for intelligence analysts, and prescribe standards and procedures for establishing and classifying such positions, without regard to chapter 51 of title 5, United States Code; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> fix the rate of basic pay for such positions, without regard to subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, United States Code, if the rate of pay is not greater than the rate of basic pay payable for level IV of the Executive Schedule [<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5315">5 U.S.C. 5315</ref>];</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> appoint individuals to such positions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> establish a performance management system for such individuals with at least one level of performance above a retention standard.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reporting Requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>Not less than 60 days before the date of the implementation of authorities authorized under this section, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall submit an operating plan describing the Director’s intended use of the authorities under this section to the appropriate committees of Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2005-12-31">December 31, 2005</date>, and annually thereafter for 4 years, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall submit an annual report of the use of the permanent authorities provided under this section during the preceding fiscal year to the appropriate committees of Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate Committees of Congress Defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term ‘appropriate committees of Congress[’] means’ [sic]—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the Committees on Appropriations, Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, and the Judiciary and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Committees on Appropriations, Government Reform [now Committee on Oversight and Accountability], and the Judiciary and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id526dc6e1-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Webster Commission Implementation Report</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/273/dC/tI/s11023">Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title I, § 11023</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1830">116 Stat. 1830</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/273/dC/tI/s11023">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation Plan</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>], the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall submit to the appropriate Committees of Congress a plan for implementation of the recommendations of the Commission for Review of FBI Security Programs, dated <date date="2002-03-31">March 31, 2002</date>, including the costs of such implementation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Reports</inline>.—</heading><content>On the date that is 1 year after the submission of the plan described in subsection (a), and for 2 years thereafter, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall submit to the appropriate Committees of Congress a report on the implementation of such plan.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate Committees of Congress</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this section, the term ‘appropriate Committees of Congress’ means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the Committees on the Judiciary of the Senate and the House of Representatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id526dc6e2-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Employment of Translators by the Federal Bureau of Investigation</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/56/tII/s205">Pub. L. 107–56, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="2001-10-26">Oct. 26, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/281">115 Stat. 281</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/56/tII/s205">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation is authorized to expedite the employment of personnel as translators to support counterterrorism investigations and operations without regard to applicable Federal personnel requirements and limitations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Security Requirements</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall establish such security requirements as are necessary for the personnel employed as translators under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Attorney General shall report to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate on—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the number of translators employed by the FBI and other components of the Department of Justice;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> any legal or practical impediments to using translators employed by other Federal, State, or local agencies, on a full, part-time, or shared basis; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the needs of the FBI for specific translation services in certain languages, and recommendations for meeting those needs.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id526dc6e3-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">FBI Critical Skills Scholarship Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/183/tV/s501">Pub. L. 102–183, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1991-12-04">Dec. 4, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1268">105 Stat. 1268</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/183/tV/s501">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall conduct a study relative to the establishment of an undergraduate training program with respect to employees of the Federal Bureau of Investigation that is similar in purpose, conditions, content, and administration to undergraduate training programs administered by the Central Intelligence Agency (under section 8 of the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s403j">50 U.S.C. 403j</ref>) [now <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3510">50 U.S.C. 3510</ref>]), the National Security Agency (under section 16 of the National Security Agency Act of 1959 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s402">50 U.S.C. 402</ref> (note)) [now <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3614">50 U.S.C. 3614</ref>][)], and the Defense Intelligence Agency (under section 1608 [now 1623] of title 10, United States Code).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading><content>Any program proposed under subsection (a) may be implemented only after the Department of Justice and the Office of Management and Budget review and approve the implementation of such program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Availability of Funds</inline>.—</heading><content>Any payment made by the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation to carry out any program proposed to be established under subsection (a) may be made in any fiscal year only to the extent that appropriated funds are available for that purpose.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id526dc6e4-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Confirmation and Compensation of Director; Term of Service</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/90/351/tVI/s1101">Pub. L. 90–351, title VI, § 1101</ref>, <date date="1968-06-19">June 19, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/236">82 Stat. 236</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/94/503/tII/s203">Pub. L. 94–503, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1976-10-15">Oct. 15, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2427">90 Stat. 2427</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/24/s2">Pub. L. 112–24, § 2</ref>, <date date="2011-07-26">July 26, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/238">125 Stat. 238</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/24/s2">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> Effective as of the day following the date on which the present incumbent in the office of Director ceases to serve as such, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and shall receive compensation at the rate prescribed for level II of the Federal Executive Salary Schedule [<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5313">section 5313 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> Effective with respect to any individual appointment by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, after <date date="1973-06-01">June 1, 1973</date>, the term of service of the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall be ten years. A Director may not serve more than one ten-year term. The provisions of subsections (a) through (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8335">section 8335 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, shall apply to any individual appointed under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Effective on the date of enactment of this subsection [<date date="2011-07-26">July 26, 2011</date>], a new term of service for the office of Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall be created, which shall begin on or after <date date="2011-08-03">August 3, 2011</date>, and continue until <date date="2013-09-04">September 4, 2013</date>. Notwithstanding the second sentence of subsection (b) of this section, the incumbent Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation on the date of enactment of this subsection shall be eligible to be appointed to the new term of service provided for by this subsection, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and only for that new term of service. Nothing in this subsection shall prevent the President, by and with the advice of the Senate, from appointing an individual, other than the incumbent Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, to a 10-year term of service subject to the provisions of subsection (b) after the date of enactment of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The individual who is the incumbent in the office of the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation on the date of enactment of this subsection may not serve as Director after <date date="2013-09-04">September 4, 2013</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> With regard to the individual who is the incumbent in the office of the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation on the date of enactment of this subsection, the second sentence of subsection (b) shall not apply.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
