<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id522636af-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s81"><num value="81">§ 81.</num><heading> Alabama</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Alabama is divided into three judicial districts to be known as the Northern, Middle, and Southern Districts of Alabama.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I81" class="centered">Northern District</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">(a) The Northern District comprises five divisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Northwestern Division comprises the counties of Colbert, Franklin, Lauderdale, and Lawrence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northwestern Division shall be held at Florence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Northeastern Division comprises the counties of Cullman, Jackson, Limestone, Madison, Marshall, and Morgan.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northeastern Division shall be held at Huntsville.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The Southern Division comprises the counties of Blount, Jefferson, and Shelby.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southern Division shall be held at Birmingham.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(4) The Eastern Division comprises the counties of Calhoun, Cherokee, Clay, Cleburne, DeKalb, Etowah, Saint Clair, and Talladega.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern Division shall be held at Anniston.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(5) The Western Division comprises the counties of Bibb, Fayette, Greene, Lamar, Marion, Pickens, Sumter, Tuscaloosa, Walker, and Winston.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western Division shall be held at Tuscaloosa.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I81" class="centered">Middle District</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">(b) The Middle District comprises three divisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Northern Division comprises the counties of Autauga, Barbour, Bullock, Butler, Chilton, Coosa, Covington, Crenshaw, Elmore, Lowndes, Montgomery, and Pike.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northern Division shall be held at Montgomery.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Southern Division comprises the counties of Coffee, Dale, Geneva, Henry, and Houston.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southern Division shall be held at Dothan.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(3) The Eastern Division comprises the counties of Chambers, Lee, Macon, Randolph, Russell, and Tallapoosa.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern Division shall be held at Opelika.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I81" class="centered">Southern District</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">(c) The Southern District comprises two divisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(1) The Northern Division comprises the counties of Dallas, Hale, Marengo, Perry, and Wilcox.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Northern Division shall be held at Selma.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">(2) The Southern Division comprises the counties of Baldwin, Choctaw, Clarke, Conecuh, Escambia, Mobile, Monroe, and Washington.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Southern Division shall be held at Mobile.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id522636b0-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646">June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/873">62 Stat. 873</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/36/s3/a">Pub. L. 87–36, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1961-05-19">May 19, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/83">75 Stat. 83</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/179/s1">Pub. L. 118–179, § 1</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2613">138 Stat. 2613</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id522636b1-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id522636b2-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed. § 142 (<ref href="/us/act/1911-03-03/ch231/s70">Mar. 3, 1911, ch. 231, § 70</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/36/1105">36 Stat. 1105</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1913-02-28/ch89">Feb. 28, 1913, ch. 89</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/37/698">37 Stat. 698</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1922-06-27/ch247">June 27, 1922, ch. 247</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/42/667">42 Stat. 667</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions relating to the places for the maintenance of the clerks’ offices were omitted as covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s751">section 751 of this title</ref>, providing that deputy clerks may be designated to reside and maintain offices at such places for holding court as the judge may determine.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions that the offices of the court shall be kept open at all times were omitted as covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s452">section 452 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A provision requiring the district judge for the northern district to reside at Birmingham was omitted as incongruous with <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s134">section 134 of this title</ref>, requiring every district judge to reside within the district for which he is appointed. Likewise the provision of <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s142">section 142 of title 28</ref>, U.S.C., 1940 ed., requiring the court to remain in session at Birmingham at least 6 months in each calendar year was omitted as unnecessary and not in harmony with provisions respecting other districts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The provisions for furnishing rooms and accommodations at Florence, Gadsden, Jasper and Opelika were omitted as obsolete upon advice of the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts that Federal accommodations are now available in each of these places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Changes in arrangement and phraseology were made.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id522636b3-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id522636b4-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/118/179/s1/1">Pub. L. 118–179, § 1(1)</ref>, substituted “five” for “seven” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/118/179/s1/2">Pub. L. 118–179, § 1(2)</ref>, substituted “Lauderdale, and Lawrence” for “and Lauderdale”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/118/179/s1/3">Pub. L. 118–179, § 1(3)</ref>, struck out Lawrence and added Marshall to the counties comprising the Northeastern Division of the Northern District and struck out “and Decatur” after “Huntsville”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/118/179/s1/4">Pub. L. 118–179, § 1(4)</ref>, substituted “Cherokee, Clay, Cleburne, DeKalb, Etowah, Saint Clair,” for “Clay, Cleburne,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/118/179/s1/5">Pub. L. 118–179, § 1(5)</ref>, substituted “Fayette, Greene, Lamar, Marion, Pickens, Sumter, Tuscaloosa, Walker, and Winston” for “Greene, Pickens, Sumter, and Tuscaloosa”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/118/179/s1/6">Pub. L. 118–179, § 1(6)</ref>, struck out par. (6) which read as follows: “The Middle Division comprises the counties of Cherokee, De Kalb, Etowah, Marshall, and Saint Clair.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4">  “Court for the Middle Division shall be held at Gadsden.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/118/179/s1/7">Pub. L. 118–179, § 1(7)</ref>, struck out par. (7) which read as follows: “The Jasper Division comprises the counties of Fayette, Lamar, Marion, Walker, and Winston.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4">  “Court for the Jasper Division shall be held at Jasper.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1961—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/87/36">Pub. L. 87–36</ref> provided for holding court at Decatur.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
