<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id522636b5-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s81A"><num value="81A">§ 81A.</num><heading> Alaska</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Alaska constitutes one judicial district.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court shall be held at Anchorage, Fairbanks, Juneau, Ketchikan, and Nome.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id522636b6-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/85/508/s12/b">Pub. L. 85–508, § 12(b)</ref>, <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/348">72 Stat. 348</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/86/70/s23/b">Pub. L. 86–70, § 23(b)</ref>, <date date="1959-06-25">June 25, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/147">73 Stat. 147</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id522636b7-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id522636b8-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id522636b9-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1959—<ref href="/us/pl/86/70">Pub. L. 86–70</ref> inserted “Ketchikan,”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id522636ba-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id522636bb-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1959 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/85/508/s12">Section 12 of Pub. L. 85–508</ref> provided in part that this section, and the amendments to sections 133, 333, 373, 376, 460, 610, 753, 1252, 1291, 1292, 1294, 1346, 1963, 2072, 2201 and 2410 of this title, <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s341b">section 341b of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees, and sections 3241, 3401, 3771 and 3772 of Title 18, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, are effective on the admission of Alaska into the Union. Admission as a State was accomplished <date date="1959-01-03">Jan. 3, 1959</date> upon issuance of Proc. No. 3269, <date date="1959-01-03">Jan. 3, 1959</date>, 24 F.R. 81, 73 Stat. c16, as required by sections 1 and 8(c) of <ref href="/us/pl/85/508">Pub. L. 85–508</ref>. See notes set out preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s21">section 21 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id522636bc-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Continuation of Suits</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/85/508/s13">Pub. L. 85–508, § 13</ref>, <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/349">72 Stat. 349</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/85/508/s13">
<inline>“No writ, action, indictment, cause, or proceeding pending in the District Court for the Territory of Alaska on the date when said Territory shall become a State, and no case pending in an appellate court upon appeal from the District Court for the Territory of Alaska at the time said Territory shall become a State, shall abate by the admission of the State of Alaska into the Union, but the same shall be transferred and proceeded with as hereinafter provided.</inline>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“All civil causes of action and all criminal offenses which shall have arisen or been committed prior to the admission of said State, but as to which no suit, action, or prosecution shall be pending at the date of such admission, shall be subject to prosecution in the appropriate State courts or in the United States District Court for the District of Alaska in like manner, to the same extent, and with like right of appellate review, as if said State had been created and said courts had been established prior to the accrual of said causes of action or the commission of such offenses; and such of said criminal offenses as shall have been committed against the laws of the Territory shall be tried and punished by the appropriate courts of said State, and such as shall have been committed against the laws of the United States shall be tried and punished in the United States District Court for the District of Alaska.”</p>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id522636bd-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Appeals</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/85/508/s14">Pub. L. 85–508, § 14</ref>, <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/349">72 Stat. 349</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/85/508/s14">“All appeals taken from the District Court for the Territory of Alaska to the Supreme Court of the United States or the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit, previous to the admission of Alaska as a State, shall be prosecuted to final determination as though this Act had not been passed. All cases in which final judgement has been rendered in such district court, and in which appeals might be had except for the admission of such State, may still be sued out, taken, and prosecuted to the Supreme Court of the United States or the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit under the provisions of then existing law, and there held and determined in like manner; and in either case, the Supreme Court of the United States, or the United States Court of Appeals, in the event of reversal, shall remand the said cause to either the State supreme court or other final appellate court of said State, or the United States district court for said district, as the case may require: <i>Provided</i>, That the time allowed by existing law for appeals from the district court for said Territory shall not be enlarged thereby.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id522636be-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Cases</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/85/508/s15">Pub. L. 85–508, § 15</ref>, <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/349">72 Stat. 349</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/85/508/s15">“All causes pending or determined in the District Court for the Territory of Alaska at the time of the admission of Alaska as a State which are of such nature as to be within the jurisdiction of a district court of the United States shall be transferred to the United States District Court for the District of Alaska for final disposition and enforcement in the same manner as is now provided by law with reference to the judgments and decrees in existing United States district courts. All other causes pending or determined in the District Court for the Territory of Alaska at the time of the admission of Alaska as a State shall be transferred to the appropriate State court of Alaska. All final judgments and decrees rendered upon such transferred cases in the United States District Court for the District of Alaska may be reviewed by the Supreme Court of the United States or by the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit in the same manner as is now provided by law with reference to the judgments and decrees in existing United States district courts.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id522636bf-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Succession of Courts</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/85/508/s16">Pub. L. 85–508, § 16</ref>, <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/350">72 Stat. 350</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/85/508/s16">“Jurisdiction of all cases pending or determined in the District Court for the Territory of Alaska not transferred to the United States District Court for the District of Alaska shall devolve upon and be exercised by the courts of original jurisdiction created by said State, which shall be deemed to be the successor of the District Court for the Territory of Alaska with respect to cases not so transferred and, as such, shall take and retain custody of all records, dockets, journals, and files of such court pertaining to such cases. The files and papers in all cases so transferred to the United States district court, together with a transcript of all book entries to complete the record in such particular cases so transferred, shall be in like manner transferred to said district court.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id522636c0-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pending Cases</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/85/508/s17">Pub. L. 85–508, § 17</ref>, <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/350">72 Stat. 350</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/85/508/s17">“All cases pending in the District Court for the Territory of Alaska at the time said Territory becomes a State not transferred to the United States District Court for the District of Alaska shall be proceeded with and determined by the courts created by said State with the right to prosecute appeals to the appellate courts created by said State, and also with the same right to prosecute appeals or writs of certiorari from the final determination in said causes made by the court of last resort created by such State to the Supreme Court of the United States, as now provided by law for appeals and writs of certiorari from the court of last resort of a State to the Supreme Court of the United States.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id522636c1-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Jurisdiction of District Court for the Territory of Alaska</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/85/508/s18">Pub. L. 85–508, § 18</ref>, <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/350">72 Stat. 350</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/85/508/s18">“The provisions of the preceding sections with respect to the termination of the jurisdiction of the District Court for the Territory of Alaska, the continuation of suits, the succession of courts, and the satisfaction of rights of litigants in suits before such courts, shall not be effective until three years after the effective date of this Act [see <ref href="/us/pl/85/508/s8/b">section 8(b) of Pub. L. 85–508</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s21">section 21 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions], unless the President, by Executive order, shall sooner proclaim that the United States District Court for the District of Alaska, established in accordance with the provisions of this Act, is prepared to assume the functions imposed upon it. During such period of three years or until such Executive order is issued, the United States District Court for the Territory of Alaska shall continue to function as heretofore. The tenure of the judges, the United States attorneys, marshals, and other officers of the United States District Court for the Territory of Alaska shall terminate at such time as that court shall cease to function as provided in this section.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id522636c2-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Schedule of Fees, Mileage, or Other Compensation</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/86/70/s23/c">Pub. L. 86–70, § 23(c)</ref>, <date date="1959-06-25">June 25, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/147">73 Stat. 147</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/86/70/s23/c">“Such authority as has been exercised by the Attorney General heretofore, with regard to the Federal court system in Alaska, pursuant to <ref href="/us/act/1900-06-06/s30">section 30 of the Act of June 6, 1900</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t48/s25">48 U.S.C. 25</ref>) shall continue to be exercised by him after the court created by <ref href="/us/act/1958-07-07/s12/b">section 12(b) of the Act of July 7, 1958</ref> (<ref href="/us/stat/72/339">72 Stat. 339</ref>, 348) [this section], providing for the admission of the State of Alaska into the Union, is established.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id522636c3-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id522636c4-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 10867. Assumption of Functions by United States District Court for District of Alaska</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 10867, <date date="1960-02-20">Feb. 20, 1960</date>, 25 F.R. 1584, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">WHEREAS the act of <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/339">72 Stat. 339</ref> [set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s21">section 21 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions], relating to the admission of the State of Alaska into the Union, provides that the United States District Court for the Territory of Alaska shall continue to function as theretofore for a period of three years after the effective date of that act, unless the President, by Executive order, shall sooner proclaim that the United States District Court for the District of Alaska, established in accordance with the provisions of that act, is prepared to assume the functions imposed upon it; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">WHEREAS that act further provides that its provisions relating to the termination of the jurisdiction of the District Court for the Territory of Alaska, the continuation of suits, the succession of courts, and the satisfaction of the rights of litigants in suits before such courts shall not be effective until the expiration of the above-mentioned three-year period or until such Executive order is issued; and that the tenure of the judges, the United States Attorneys, Marshals, and other officers of the United States District Court for the Territory of Alaska shall terminate at such time as that court shall cease to function; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">WHEREAS, I have appointed, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and commissioned the Honorable Walter N. Hodge to be United States District Judge for the District of Alaska, and he has taken his oath of office; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">WHEREAS Judge Hodge has appointed an acting United States Attorney, an acting United States Marshal, and other court officers; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">WHEREAS the United States District Court for the District of Alaska is now prepared to assume the functions imposed upon it:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">NOW, THEREFORE, by virtue of the authority vested in me by section 18 of the said act of <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date> [set out above], I hereby proclaim that the United States District Court for the District of Alaska is prepared to assume the functions imposed upon it. Accordingly, the jurisdiction of the District Court for the Territory of Alaska and the tenure of the judges, the United States Attorneys, Marshals, and other officers of that court are now terminated.</p>
<signature>
<name>Dwight D. Eisenhower.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
