<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id522b1842-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s97"><num value="97">§ 97.</num><heading> Kentucky</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Kentucky is divided into two judicial districts to be known as the Eastern and Western Districts of Kentucky.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I81" class="centered">Eastern District</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">(a) The Eastern District comprises the counties of Anderson, Bath, Bell, Boone, Bourbon, Boyd, Boyle, Bracken, Breathitt, Campbell, Carroll, Carter, Clark, Clay, Elliott, Estill, Fayette, Fleming, Floyd, Franklin, Gallatin, Garrard, Grant, Greenup, Harlan, Harrison, Henry, Jackson, Jessamine, Johnson, Kenton, Knott, Knox, Laurel, Lawrence, Lee, Leslie, Letcher, Lewis, Lincoln, McCreary, Madison, Magoffin, Martin, Mason, Menifee, Mercer, Montgomery, Morgan, Nicholas, Owen, Owsley, Pendleton, Perry, Pike, Powell, Pulaski, Robertson, Rockcastle, Rowan, Scott, Shelby, Trimble, Wayne, Whitley, Wolfe, and Woodford.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern District shall be held at Ashland, Catlettsburg, Covington, Frankfort, Jackson, Lexington, London, Pikeville, and Richmond.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I81" class="centered">Western District</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">(b) The Western District comprises the counties of Adair, Allen, Ballard, Barren, Breckenridge, Bullitt, Butler, Caldwell, Calloway, Carlisle, Casey, Christian, Clinton, Crittenden, Cumberland, Daviess, Edmonson, Fulton, Graves, Grayson, Green, Hancock, Hardin, Hart, Henderson, Hickman, Hopkins, Jefferson, Larue, Livingston, Logan, Lyon, McCracken, McLean, Marion, Marshall, Meade, Metcalfe, Monroe, Muhlenberg, Nelson, Ohio, Oldham, Russell, Simpson, Spencer, Taylor, Todd, Trigg, Union, Warren, Washington, and Webster.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western District shall be held at Bowling Green, Louisville, Owensboro, and Paducah.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id522b1843-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646">June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/880">62 Stat. 880</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/408/s2/a">Pub. L. 95–408, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-02">Oct. 2, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/883">92 Stat. 883</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id522b1844-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id522b1845-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed., § 158 (<ref href="/us/act/1911-03-03/ch231/s83">Mar. 3, 1911, ch. 231, § 83</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/36/1112">36 Stat. 1112</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1920-01-29/ch57">Jan. 29, 1920, ch. 57</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/41/400">41 Stat. 400</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1936-06-22/ch707">June 22, 1936, ch. 707</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1822">49 Stat. 1822</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Last paragraph of <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s158">section 158 of title 28</ref>, U.S.C., 1940 ed., relating to process, was omitted as covered by Rule 4 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions relating to maintenance of clerk’s offices were omitted as covered by sections 452 and 751 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions for furnishing rooms and accommodations at Lexington and Pikeville were omitted as obsolete on advice of the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts that Federal accommodations are now available in each of those places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Words “with the waters thereof,” after the list of counties in each district, were omitted as unnecessary and inconsistent with other sections of this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">McCreary County of the Eastern District was formed from parts of the counties of Pulaski, Wayne, and Whitley since the latest amendment of the Judicial Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Changes in arrangement and phraseology were made.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id522b1846-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id522b1847-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/408">Pub. L. 95–408</ref> provided for holding court at Ashland.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id522b1848-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id522b1849-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment; Savings Provision</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/408">Pub. L. 95–408</ref> effective 180 days after <date date="1978-10-02">Oct. 2, 1978</date>, with such amendment not to affect the composition or preclude the service of any grand or petit juror summoned, empaneled, or actually serving in any judicial district on the effective date of this Act, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/408/s5">section 5 of Pub. L. 95–408</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s89">section 89 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
