<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id522b184a-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s98"><num value="98">§ 98.</num><heading> Louisiana</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Louisiana is divided into three judicial districts to be known as the Eastern, Middle, and Western Districts of Louisiana.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I81" class="centered">Eastern District</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">(a) The Eastern District comprises the parishes of Assumption, Jefferson, Lafourche, Orleans, Plaquemines, Saint Bernard, Saint Charles, Saint James, Saint John the Baptist, Saint Tammany, Tangipahoa, Terrebonne, and Washington.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Eastern District shall be held at New Orleans, and Houma.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I81" class="centered">Middle District</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">(b) The Middle District comprises the parishes of Ascension, East Baton Rouge, East Feliciana, Iberville, Livingston, Pointe Coupee, Saint Helena, West Baton Rouge, and West Feliciana.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Middle District shall be held at Baton Rouge.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I81" class="centered">Western District</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">(c) The Western District comprises the parishes of Acadia, Allen, Avoyelles, Beauregard, Bienville, Bossier, Caddo, Calcasieu, Caldwell, Cameron, Catahoula, Claiborne, Concordia, Jefferson Davis, De Soto, East Carroll, Evangeline, Franklin, Grant, Iberia, Jackson, Lafayette, La Salle, Lincoln, Madison, Morehouse, Natchitoches, Ouachita, Rapides, Red River, Richland, Sabine, Saint Landry, Saint Martin, Saint Mary, Tensas, Union, Vermilion, Vernon, Webster, West Carroll, and Winn.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I56" class="indent4 firstIndent-2">Court for the Western District shall be held at Alexandria, Lafayette, Lake Charles, Monroe, Opelousas, and Shreveport.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id522b184b-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646">June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/881">62 Stat. 881</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/36/s4">Pub. L. 87–36, § 4</ref>, <date date="1961-05-19">May 19, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/83">75 Stat. 83</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/208/s3/a">Pub. L. 92–208, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/741">85 Stat. 741</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/408/s3/a">Pub. L. 95–408, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-02">Oct. 2, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/883">92 Stat. 883</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/353/tII/s203/b">Pub. L. 98–353, title II, § 203(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-10">July 10, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/350">98 Stat. 350</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id522b184c-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="id522b184d-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed., § 159 (<ref href="/us/act/1911-03-03/ch231/s84">Mar. 3, 1911, ch. 231, § 84</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/36/1113">36 Stat. 1113</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions relating to the maintenance of offices by the clerks were omitted as covered by sections 452 and 751 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The parishes of Allen, Beauregard, and Jefferson Davis of the Lake Charles Division of the Western District were formed out of part of Calcasieu Parish since the enactment of the Judicial Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Changes in arrangement and phraseology were made.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id522b184e-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id522b184f-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/353">Pub. L. 98–353</ref> inserted “, and Houma” after “New Orleans”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/408">Pub. L. 95–408</ref> struck out par. (1) to (6) designations which had divided the parishes of Western District into six divisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1971—<ref href="/us/pl/92/208">Pub. L. 92–208</ref> created a Middle District consisting of the nine parishes formerly making up Baton Rouge Division of Eastern District and designated as the entire Eastern District the thirteen parishes formerly making up New Orleans Division of Eastern District.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1961—<ref href="/us/pl/87/36">Pub. L. 87–36</ref> struck out from enumeration in subsec. (a)(1) the parishes of Iberia and Saint Mary, in subsec. (b)(1) Lafayette, Saint Martin and Vermilion, and in subsec. (b)(5) Acadia, and created sixth division of subsec. (b), consisting of such parishes.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id522b1850-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id522b1851-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment; Savings Provision</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/408">Pub. L. 95–408</ref> effective 180 days after <date date="1978-10-02">Oct. 2, 1978</date>, with such amendment not to affect the composition or preclude the service of any grand or petit juror summoned, empaneled, or actually serving in any judicial district on the effective date of this Act, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/408/s5">section 5 of Pub. L. 95–408</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s89">section 89 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id522b1852-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1971 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/92/208/s3/f">Pub. L. 92–208, § 3(f)</ref>, <date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/742">85 Stat. 742</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/92/208/s3/f">“The provisions of this section [amending this section and sections 133 and 134 of this title and enacting provisions set out below] shall become effective one hundred and twenty days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id522b1853-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">District Judge, United States Attorney, and United States Marshal for Middle District; Designation; Tenure; Appointment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/92/208/s3/b">Pub. L. 92–208, § 3(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/742">85 Stat. 742</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/92/208/s3/b">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The district judge for the Eastern District of Louisiana holding office on the day immediately prior to the effective date of this section [see Effective Date of 1971 Amendment Note above], and whose official station on such date is Baton Rouge, shall, on and after such date, be the district judge for the Middle District of Louisiana. All other district judges for the Eastern District of Louisiana holding office on the day immediately prior to the effective date of this section shall be district judges for the Eastern District of Louisiana as constituted by this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Nothing in this section shall in any manner affect the tenure of office of the United States attorney and the United States marshal for the Eastern District of Louisiana who are in office on the effective date of this section, and who shall be during the remainder of their present terms of office the United States attorney and marshal for the Eastern District of Louisiana as constituted by this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The President shall appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, a United States attorney and marshal for the Middle District of Louisiana.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
