<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5298ce53-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995"><num value="995">§ 995.</num><heading> Powers of the Commission</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id5298ce54-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> The Commission, by vote of a majority of the members present and voting, shall have the power to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5298ce55-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> establish general policies and promulgate such rules and regulations for the Commission as are necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5298ce56-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> appoint and fix the salary and duties of the Staff Director of the Sentencing Commission, who shall serve at the discretion of the Commission and who shall be compensated at a rate not to exceed the highest rate now or hereafter prescribed for Level 6 of the Senior Executive Service Schedule (<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5382">5 U.S.C. 5382</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5298ce57-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> deny, revise, or ratify any request for regular, supplemental, or deficiency appropriations prior to any submission of such request to the Office of Management and Budget by the Chair;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5298ce58-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> procure for the Commission temporary and intermittent services to the same extent as is authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3109/b">section 3109(b) of title 5</ref>, United States Code;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5298ce59-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> utilize, with their consent, the services, equipment, personnel, information, and facilities of other Federal, State, local, and private agencies and instrumentalities with or without reimbursement therefor;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5298ce5a-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> without regard to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3324">31 U.S.C. 3324</ref>, enter into and perform such contracts, leases, cooperative agreements, and other transactions as may be necessary in the conduct of the functions of the Commission, with any public agency, or with any person, firm, association, corporation, educational institution, or non-profit organization;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5298ce5b-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> accept and employ, in carrying out the provisions of this title, voluntary and uncompensated services, notwithstanding the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1342">31 U.S.C. 1342</ref>, however, individuals providing such services shall not be considered Federal employees except for purposes of chapter 81 of title 5, United States Code, with respect to job-incurred disability and title 28, United States Code, with respect to tort claims;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5298ce5c-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> request such information, data, and reports from any Federal agency or judicial officer as the Commission may from time to time require and as may be produced consistent with other law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5298ce5d-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> monitor the performance of probation officers with regard to sentencing recommendations, including application of the Sentencing Commission guidelines and policy statements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5298ce5e-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> issue instructions to probation officers concerning the application of Commission guidelines and policy statements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5298ce5f-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> arrange with the head of any other Federal agency for the performance by such agency of any function of the Commission, with or without reimbursement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5298ce60-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><chapeau> establish a research and development program within the Commission for the purpose of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5298ce61-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/12/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> serving as a clearinghouse and information center for the collection, preparation, and dissemination of information on Federal sentencing practices; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id5298ce62-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/12/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> assisting and serving in a consulting capacity to Federal courts, departments, and agencies in the development, maintenance, and coordination of sound sentencing practices;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5298ce63-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> collect systematically the data obtained from studies, research, and the empirical experience of public and private agencies concerning the sentencing process;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5298ce64-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> publish data concerning the sentencing process;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5298ce65-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content> collect systematically and disseminate information concerning sentences actually imposed, and the relationship of such sentences to the factors set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s3553/a">section 3553(a) of title 18</ref>, United States Code;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5298ce66-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/16"><num value="16">(16)</num><content> collect systematically and disseminate information regarding effectiveness of sentences imposed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5298ce67-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/17"><num value="17">(17)</num><content> devise and conduct, in various geographical locations, seminars and workshops providing continuing studies for persons engaged in the sentencing field;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5298ce68-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/18"><num value="18">(18)</num><content> devise and conduct periodic training programs of instruction in sentencing techniques for judicial and probation personnel and other persons connected with the sentencing process;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id529b1859-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/19"><num value="19">(19)</num><content> study the feasibility of developing guidelines for the disposition of juvenile delinquents;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id529b185a-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/20"><num value="20">(20)</num><content> make recommendations to Congress concerning modification or enactment of statutes relating to sentencing, penal, and correctional matters that the Commission finds to be necessary and advisable to carry out an effective, humane and rational sentencing policy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id529b185b-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/21"><num value="21">(21)</num><content> hold hearings and call witnesses that might assist the Commission in the exercise of its powers or duties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id529b185c-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/22"><num value="22">(22)</num><content> perform such other functions as are required to permit Federal courts to meet their responsibilities under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s3553/a">section 3553(a) of title 18</ref>, United States Code, and to permit others involved in the Federal criminal justice system to meet their related responsibilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id529b185d-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/23"><num value="23">(23)</num><content> retain private attorneys to provide legal advice to the Commission in the conduct of its work, or to appear for or represent the Commission in any case in which the Commission is authorized by law to represent itself, or in which the Commission is representing itself with the consent of the Department of Justice; and the Commission may in its discretion pay reasonable attorney’s fees to private attorneys employed by it out of its appropriated funds. When serving as officers or employees of the United States, such private attorneys shall be considered special government employees as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s202/a">section 202(a) of title 18</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id529b185e-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/a/24"><num value="24">(24)</num><content> grant incentive awards to its employees pursuant to chapter 45 of title 5, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id529b185f-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The Commission shall have such other powers and duties and shall perform such other functions as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter, and may delegate to any member or designated person such powers as may be appropriate other than the power to establish general policy statements and guidelines pursuant to section 994(a)(1) and (2), the issuance of general policies and promulgation of rules and regulations pursuant to subsection (a)(1) of this section, and the decisions as to the factors to be considered in establishment of categories of offenses and offenders pursuant to section 994(b). The Commission shall, with respect to its activities under subsections (a)(9), (a)(10), (a)(11), (a)(12), (a)(13), (a)(14), (a)(15), (a)(16), (a)(17), and (a)(18), to the extent practicable, utilize existing resources of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts and the Federal Judicial Center for the purpose of avoiding unnecessary duplication.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id529b1860-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> Upon the request of the Commission, each Federal agency is authorized and directed to make its services, equipment, personnel, facilities, and information available to the greatest practicable extent to the Commission in the execution of its functions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id529b1861-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> A simple majority of the membership then serving shall constitute a quorum for the conduct of business. Other than for the promulgation of guidelines and policy statements pursuant to section 994, the Commission may exercise its powers and fulfill its duties by the vote of a simple majority of the members present.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id529b1862-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6" identifier="/us/usc/t28/s995/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> Except as otherwise provided by law, the Commission shall maintain and make available for public inspection a record of the final vote of each member on any action taken by it.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id529b1863-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/tII/s217/a">Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 217(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2024">98 Stat. 2024</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tVII">Pub. L. 100–690, title VII</ref>, §§ 7104, 7105, 7106(b), <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4418">102 Stat. 4418</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/650/tIII/s325/b/5">Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 325(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="1990-12-01">Dec. 1, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/5121">104 Stat. 5121</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/322/tXXVIII/s280005/c/1">Pub. L. 103–322, title XXVIII, § 280005(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-09-13">Sept. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2097">108 Stat. 2097</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/177/tV/s501/a">Pub. L. 110–177, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-07">Jan. 7, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/2541">121 Stat. 2541</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id529b1864-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id529b1865-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id529b1866-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/110/177/s501">Pub. L. 110–177, § 501</ref>, temporarily added subsec. (f). See Termination Date of 2008 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/103/322">Pub. L. 103–322</ref> substituted “Chair” for “Chairman”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a)(22). <ref href="/us/pl/101/650">Pub. L. 101–650</ref> struck out “and” after semicolon at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s7105">Pub. L. 100–690, § 7105</ref>, substituted “Level 6 of the Senior Executive Service Schedule (<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5382">5 U.S.C. 5382</ref>)” for “grade 18 of the General Schedule pay rates (<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5332">5 U.S.C. 5332</ref>)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(23). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s7104">Pub. L. 100–690, § 7104</ref>, added par. (23).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(24). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s7106/b">Pub. L. 100–690, § 7106(b)</ref>, added par. (24).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id529b1867-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="terminationDate" id="id529b1868-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/177/tV/s501/b">Pub. L. 110–177, title V, § 501(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-07">Jan. 7, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/2542">121 Stat. 2542</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/177/tV/s501/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall cease to have force and effect on <date date="2010-09-30">September 30, 2010</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id529b1869-3a70-11f1-9e0c-dcbb1364dae6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/s235/a/1/B/i">section 235(a)(1)(B)(i) of Pub. L. 98–473</ref>, set out as an Effective Date; Savings Provision note under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s3551">section 3551 of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
