<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb954899b-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s1002"><num value="1002">§ 1002.</num><heading> Political recommendations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb954899c-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s1002/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, each appointment, promotion, assignment, transfer, or designation, interim or otherwise, of an officer or employee in the Postal Service (except a Governor or member of the Postal Regulatory Commission) shall be made without regard to any recommendation or statement, oral or written, with respect to any person who requests or is under consideration for such appointment, promotion, assignment, transfer, or designation, made by—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb954899d-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s1002/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> any Member of the Senate or House of Representatives (including the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb954899e-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s1002/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> any elected official of the government of any State (including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico) or of any county, city, or other political subdivision of such State or Commonwealth;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb954899f-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s1002/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> any official of a national political party or of a political party of any State (including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico), county, city, or other subdivision of such State or Commonwealth; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb95489a0-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s1002/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> any other individual or organization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb95489a1-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s1002/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in subsection (e) of this section, a person or organization referred to in clause (1), (2), (3), or (4) of subsection (a) of this section is prohibited from making or transmitting to the Postal Service, or to any other officer or employee of the Government of the United States, any recommendation or statement, oral or written, with respect to any person who requests or is under consideration for any such appointment, promotion, assignment, transfer, or designation. The Postal Service and any officer or employee of the Government of the United States, subject to subsection (e) of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb95489a2-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s1002/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> shall not solicit, request, consider, or accept any such recommendation or statement; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb95489a3-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s1002/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> shall return any such written recommendation or statement received by him, appropriately marked as in violation of this section, to the person or organization making or transmitting the same.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb95489a4-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s1002/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> A person who requests or is under consideration for any such appointment, promotion, assignment, transfer, or designation is prohibited from requesting or soliciting any such recommendation or statement from any person or organization except a statement of the type referred to in subsection (e)(2) of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb95489a5-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s1002/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> Each employment form of the Postal Service used in connection with any such appointment, promotion, assignment, transfer, or designation shall contain appropriate language in boldface type informing all persons concerned of the provisions of this section. During the time any such appointment, promotion, assignment, transfer, or designation is under consideration, appropriate notice of the provisions of this section printed in boldface type shall be posted in the post office concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb95489a6-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s1002/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><chapeau> The Postal Service or any authorized officer or employee of the Government of the United States may solicit, accept, and consider, and any other individual or organization may furnish or transmit to the Postal Service or such authorized officer or employee, any statement with respect to a person who requests or is under consideration for such appointment, promotion, assignment, transfer, or designation, if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb95489a7-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s1002/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the statement is furnished pursuant to a request or requirement of the Postal Service and consists solely of an evaluation of the work performance, ability, aptitude, and general qualifications of such person;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb95489a8-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s1002/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the statement relates solely to the character and residence of such person;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb95489a9-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s1002/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the statement is furnished pursuant to a request made by an authorized representative of the Government of the United States solely in order to determine whether such person meets the loyalty, suitability, and character requirements for employment with the Government of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb95489aa-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s1002/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the statement is furnished by a former employer of such person pursuant to a request of the Postal Service, and consists solely of an evaluation of the work performance, ability, aptitude, and general qualifications of such person during his employment with such former employer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb95489ab-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s1002/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> The Postal Service shall take any action it determines necessary and proper, including but not limited to suspension, removal from office, or disqualification from the Postal Service, to enforce the provisions of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb95489ac-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s1002/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> The provisions of this section shall not affect the right of an officer or employee of the Postal Service to petition Congress as authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7211">section 7211 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb95489ad-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/375">Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/729">84 Stat. 729</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/tVII/s703/c/5">Pub. L. 95–454, title VII, § 703(c)(5)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1217">92 Stat. 1217</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/435/tVI/s604/a">Pub. L. 109–435, title VI, § 604(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3241">120 Stat. 3241</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb95489ae-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb95489af-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb95489b0-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/109/435">Pub. L. 109–435</ref> substituted “Postal Regulatory Commission” for “Postal Rate Commission”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/95/454">Pub. L. 95–454</ref> substituted “section 7211” for “section 7102”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb95489b1-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb95489b2-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/454">Pub. L. 95–454</ref> effective 90 days after <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/s907">section 907 of Pub. L. 95–454</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1101">section 1101 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb95489b3-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1971-03-01">Mar. 1, 1971</date>, pursuant to Resolution No. 71–13 of the Board of Governors. See <ref href="/us/pl/91/375/s15/a">section 15(a) of Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t39/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
