<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb9711232-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s3682"><num value="3682">§ 3682.</num><heading> Size and weight limits</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Postal Service may establish size and weight limitations for mail matter in the market-dominant category of mail consistent with regulations the Postal Regulatory Commission may prescribe under section 3622. The Postal Service may establish size and weight limitations for mail matter in the competitive category of mail consistent with its authority under section 3632.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idb9711233-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/375">Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, <date date="1970-08-12">Aug. 12, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/765">84 Stat. 765</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/70/tI/s1331/e/4">Pub. L. 96–70, title I, § 1331(e)(4)</ref>, <date date="1979-09-27">Sept. 27, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/482">93 Stat. 482</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/242/s1/a">Pub. L. 97–242, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/300">96 Stat. 300</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/435/tX/s1010/b">Pub. L. 109–435, title X, § 1010(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3261">120 Stat. 3261</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb9711234-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb9711235-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb9711236-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—<ref href="/us/pl/109/435">Pub. L. 109–435</ref> amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section read as follows: “The Postal Service may establish size and weight limitations for mail matter in the same manner as prescribed for changes in mail classification under subchapter II of this chapter.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—<ref href="/us/pl/97/242">Pub. L. 97–242</ref> struck out subsecs. (a) and (b) and designation “(c)” before “The Postal Service” and in resulting undesignated paragraph substituted “mail matter” and “mail classification” for “letter mail” and “classification”, respectively. Former subsecs. (a) and (b) had provided that the maximum weight of mail other than letter mail was 40 pounds, that the maximum size was 78 inches in girth and length combined before <date date="1971-07-01">July 1, 1971</date>, and 84 inches in girth and length combined on and after <date date="1971-07-01">July 1, 1971</date>, and that the maximum size on mail, other than letter mail, was 100 inches in girth and length combined and the maximum weight was 70 pounds if the mail (1) was mailed at, or addressed for delivery at, other than first-class post offices or on rural or star routes, (2) contained baby fowl, live plants, trees, shrubs, or agricultural commodities but not the manufactured products of those commodities, (3) would have been entitled to be mailed under former <ref href="/us/usc/t39/s4554">section 4554 of this title</ref>, (4) was addressed to or mailed at any Armed Forces post office outside the 50 States, or (5) was addressed to or mailed in the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the States of Alaska and Hawaii, or a possession of the United States including the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/96/70">Pub. L. 96–70</ref> struck out “the Canal Zone and” after “United States including”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb9711237-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb9711238-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/242/s1/b">Pub. L. 97–242, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/300">96 Stat. 300</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/242/s1/b">“The size and weight limitations for other than letter mail established by subsections (a) and (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t39/s3682">section 3682 of title 39</ref>, United States Code, as in effect on the day prior to the effective date of this section [<date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>], shall remain in effect until changed pursuant to section 3682 of such title, as amended, by subsection (a) of this section.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb9711239-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1979 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/70">Pub. L. 96–70</ref> effective <date date="1979-10-01">Oct. 1, 1979</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/70/s3304">section 3304 of Pub. L. 96–70</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3601">section 3601 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb971123a-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1971-01-20">Jan. 20, 1971</date>, pursuant to Resolution No. 71–10 of the Board of Governors. See <ref href="/us/pl/91/375/s15/a">section 15(a) of Pub. L. 91–375</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t39/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
