<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb9521811-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s502"><num value="502">§ 502.</num><heading> Commissioners</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9521812-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s502/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Postal Regulatory Commission is composed of 5 Commissioners, appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Commissioners shall be chosen solely on the basis of their technical qualifications, professional standing, and demonstrated expertise in economics, accounting, law, or public administration, and may be removed by the President only for cause. Each individual appointed to the Commission shall have the qualifications and expertise necessary to carry out the enhanced responsibilities accorded Commissioners under the Postal Accountability and Enhancement Act. Not more than 3 of the Commissioners may be adherents of the same political party.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9521813-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s502/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> No Commissioner shall be financially interested in any enterprise in the private sector of the economy engaged in the delivery of mail matter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9521814-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s502/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> A Commissioner may continue to serve after the expiration of his term until his successor has qualified, except that a Commissioner may not so continue to serve for more than 1 year after the date upon which his term otherwise would expire under subsection (f).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9521815-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s502/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> One of the Commissioners shall be designated as Chairman by, and shall serve in the position of Chairman at the pleasure of, the President.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9521816-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s502/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> The Commissioners shall by majority vote designate a Vice Chairman of the Commission. The Vice Chairman shall act as Chairman of the Commission in the absence of the Chairman.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9521817-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3" identifier="/us/usc/t39/s502/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> The Commissioners shall serve for terms of 6 years.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb9521818-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/109/435/tVI/s601/a/1">Pub. L. 109–435, title VI, § 601(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3238">120 Stat. 3238</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb9521819-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb952181a-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb952181b-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Postal Accountability and Enhancement Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/109/435">Pub. L. 109–435</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3198">120 Stat. 3198</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 2006 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t39/s101">section 101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb952181c-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb952181d-2930-11f1-bc69-dbd19d1ebdf3"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section not to affect the appointment or tenure of any person serving as a Commissioner on the Postal Regulatory Commission under an appointment made before <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, or any nomination made before that date, but when any such office becomes vacant, the appointment to fill that office to be made in accordance with this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/435/s601/b">section 601(b) of Pub. L. 109–435</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2006 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t39/s501">section 501 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
