<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idab8a160d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s10148"><num value="10148">§ 10148.</num><heading> Ready Reserve: failure to satisfactorily perform prescribed training</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab8a160e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s10148/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> A member of the Ready Reserve covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s10147">section 10147 of this title</ref> who fails in any year to perform satisfactorily the training duty prescribed in that section, as determined by the Secretary concerned under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, may be ordered without his consent to perform additional active duty for training for not more than 45 days. If the failure occurs during the last year of his required membership in the Ready Reserve, his membership is extended until he performs that additional active duty for training, but not for more than six months.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab8a160f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s10148/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> A member of the Army National Guard of the United States or the Air National Guard of the United States who fails in any year to perform satisfactorily the training duty prescribed by or under law for members of the Army National Guard or the Air National Guard, as the case may be, as determined by the Secretary concerned, may, upon the request of the Governor of the State (or, in the case of the District of Columbia, the commanding general of the District of Columbia National Guard) be ordered, without his consent, to perform additional active duty for training for not more than 45 days. A member ordered to active duty under this subsection shall be ordered to duty as a Reserve of the Army or as a Reserve of the Air Force, as the case may be.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idab8a1610-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tXVI/s1661/a/1">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1661(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2974">108 Stat. 2974</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idab8a1611-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idab8a1612-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idab8a1613-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in section 270(b), (c) of this title, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s1661/a/2/A">Pub. L. 103–337, § 1661(a)(2)(A)</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idab8a1614-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idab8a1615-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1994-12-01">Dec. 1, 1994</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s1691">section 1691 of Pub. L. 103–337</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s10001">section 10001 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tXVI/s1661/a/5/B">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1661(a)(5)(B)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2980">108 Stat. 2980</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tXVI/s1661/a/5/B">“Section 10148(b) [<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s10148/b">10 U.S.C. 10148(b)</ref>], as added by paragraph (1), applies only to persons who became members of the Army National Guard of the United States or the Air National Guard of the United States after <date date="1961-10-04">October 4, 1961</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
