<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida868feb7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1073a"><num value="1073a">§ 1073a.</num><heading> Contracts for health care: best value contracting</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida868feb8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1073a/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>Under regulations prescribed by the administering Secretaries, health care contracts shall be awarded in the administration of this chapter to the offeror or offerors that will provide the best value to the United States to the maximum extent consistent with furnishing high-quality health care in a manner that protects the fiscal and other interests of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida868feb9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1073a/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Factors Considered</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In the determination of best value under subsection (a)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida868feba-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1073a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> consideration shall be given to the factors specified in the regulations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida868febb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1073a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> greater weight shall be accorded to technical and performance-related factors than to cost and price-related factors.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida868febc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1073a/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority under the regulations prescribed under subsection (a) shall apply to any contract in excess of $5,000,000.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida868febd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tVII/s722/a">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title VII, § 722(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/695">113 Stat. 695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida868febe-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida868febf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida868fec0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Comptroller General Review of Defense Health Agency Oversight of Transition Between Managed Care Support Contractors for the TRICARE Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tVII/s737">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VII, § 737</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1821">132 Stat. 1821</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tVII/s737">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefing and Report on Current Transition.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Comptroller General of the United States shall provide to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a briefing and a report on a review by the Comptroller General of the oversight conducted by the Defense Health Agency with respect to the current transition between managed care support contractors for the TRICARE program. The briefing shall be provided by not later than <date date="2019-07-01">July 1, 2019</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The briefing and report under paragraph (1) shall each include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> A description and assessment of the extent to which the Defense Health Agency provided guidance and oversight to the outgoing and incoming managed care support contractors for the TRICARE program during the transition described in paragraph (1) and before the start of health care delivery by the incoming contractor.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> A description and assessment of any issues with health care delivery under the TRICARE program as a result of or in connection with the transition, and, with respect to such issues—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the effect, if any, of the guidance and oversight provided by the Defense Health Agency during the transition on such issues; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the solutions developed by the Defense Health Agency for remediating any deficiencies in managed care support for the TRICARE program in connection with such issues.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> A description and assessment of the extent to which the Defense Health Agency has reviewed any lessons learned from past transitions between managed care support contractors for the TRICARE program, and incorporated such lessons into the transition.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> A review of the Department of Defense briefing provided in accordance with the provisions of the Report of the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives to Accompany H.R. 5515 (115th Congress; House Report 115–676) on TRICARE Managed Care Support Contractor Reporting.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report on Future Transitions</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 270 days after the completion of any future transition between managed care support contractors for the TRICARE program, the Comptroller General shall submit to the committees of Congress referred to in subsection (a)(1) a report on a review by the Comptroller General of the oversight conducted by the Defense Health Agency with respect to such transition. The report shall include each description and assessment specified in subparagraphs (A) through (C) of subsection (a)(2) with respect to such transition.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">TRICARE Program Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘TRICARE program’ has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1072">section 1072 of title 10</ref>, United States Code.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida868fec1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Value-Based Purchasing and Acquisition of Managed Care Support Contracts for TRICARE Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tVII/s707">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title VII, § 707</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/301">137 Stat. 301</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tVII/s707">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>To the extent practicable, the Secretary of Defense shall seek to expand the TRICARE Competitive Plans Demonstration Project to not fewer than five locations not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">TRICARE Competitive Plans Demonstration Project Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘TRICARE Competitive Plans Demonstration Project’ means the project designed to test the contract acquisition strategy of providing an opportunity for local, regional, and national health plans to participate in the competition for managed care support functions under the TRICARE program, in accordance with section 705(c)(3) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<ref href="/us/pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1073a">10 U.S.C. 1073a</ref> note).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tVII/s705">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VII, § 705</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2201">130 Stat. 2201</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tVII/s715">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VII, § 715</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1438">131 Stat. 1438</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tVII/s716">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VII, § 716</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1453">133 Stat. 1453</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tVII/s716">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Value-based Health Care.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall develop and implement value-based incentive programs as part of any contract awarded under chapter 55 of title 10, United States Code, for the provision of health care services to covered beneficiaries to encourage health care providers under the TRICARE program (including physicians, hospitals, and other persons and facilities involved in providing such health care services) to improve the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The quality of health care provided to covered beneficiaries under the TRICARE program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The experience of covered beneficiaries in receiving health care under the TRICARE program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> The health of covered beneficiaries.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Value-based incentive programs.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Development</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In developing value-based incentive programs under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> link payments to health care providers under the TRICARE program to improved performance with respect to quality, cost, and reducing the provision of inappropriate care;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> consider the characteristics of the population of covered beneficiaries affected by the value-based incentive program;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> consider how the value-based incentive program would affect the receipt of health care under the TRICARE program by such covered beneficiaries;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> establish or maintain an assurance that such covered beneficiaries will have timely access to health care during the operation of the value-based incentive program;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="v">“(v)</num><content> ensure that such covered beneficiaries do not incur any additional costs by reason of the value-based incentive program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="vi">“(vi)</num><content> consider such other factors as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Scope and metrics</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>With respect to a value-based incentive program developed and implemented under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall ensure that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the size, scope, and duration of the value-based incentive program is reasonable in relation to the purpose of the value-based incentive program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the value-based incentive program relies on the core quality performance metrics adopted pursuant to section 728 [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1073b">section 1073b of this title</ref> and enacting provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1071">section 1071 of this title</ref>].</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of existing models</inline>.—</heading><content>In developing a value-based incentive program under paragraph (1), the Secretary may adapt a value-based incentive program conducted by a TRICARE managed care support contractor, the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, or any other Federal Government, State government, or commercial health care program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Execution of Contracting Responsibility</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>With respect to any acquisition of managed care support services under the TRICARE program initiated after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 [<date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>], the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment shall be responsible for—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> decisions relating to such acquisition;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> approving the acquisition strategy; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> conducting pre-solicitation, pre-award, and post-award acquisition reviews.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Acquisition of Contracts.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Strategy</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than <date date="2018-01-01">January 1, 2018</date>, the Secretary of Defense shall develop and implement a strategy to ensure that managed care support contracts under the TRICARE program entered into with private sector entities—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> improve access to health care for covered beneficiaries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> improve health outcomes for covered beneficiaries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> improve the quality of health care received by covered beneficiaries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> enhance the experience of covered beneficiaries in receiving health care; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> lower per capita costs to the Department of Defense of health care provided to covered beneficiaries.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability of strategy.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The strategy required by paragraph (1) shall apply to all managed care support contracts under the TRICARE program entered into with private sector entities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Modification of contracts</inline>.—</heading><content>Contracts entered into prior to the implementation of the strategy required by paragraph (1) shall be modified to ensure consistency with such strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Local, regional, and national health plans</inline>.—</heading><content>In developing and implementing the strategy required by paragraph (1), the Secretary shall ensure that local, regional, and national health plans have an opportunity to participate in the competition for managed care support contracts under the TRICARE program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Continuous innovation</inline>.—</heading><content>The strategy required by paragraph (1) shall include incentives for the incorporation of innovative ideas and solutions into managed care support contracts under the TRICARE program through the use of teaming agreements, subcontracts, and other contracting mechanisms that can be used to develop and continuously refresh high-performing networks of health care providers at the national, regional, and local level.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements of strategy</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The strategy required by paragraph (1) shall provide for the following with respect to managed care support contracts under the TRICARE program:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The maximization of flexibility in the design and configuration of networks of individual and institutional health care providers, including a focus on the development of high-performing networks of health care providers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The establishment of an integrated medical management system between military medical treatment facilities and health care providers in the private sector that, when appropriate, effectively coordinates and integrates health care across the continuum of care.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> With respect to telehealth services—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the maximization of the use of such services to provide real-time interactive communications between patients and health care providers and remote patient monitoring; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the use of standardized payment methods to reimburse health care providers for the provision of such services.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> The use of value-based reimbursement methodologies, including through the use of value-based incentive programs under subsection (a), that transfer financial risk to health care providers and managed care support contractors.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> The use of financial incentives for contractors and health care providers to receive an equitable share in the cost savings to the Department resulting from improvement in health outcomes for covered beneficiaries and the experience of covered beneficiaries in receiving health care.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> The use of incentives that emphasize prevention and wellness for covered beneficiaries receiving health care services from private sector entities to seek such services from high-value health care providers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> The adoption of a streamlined process for enrollment of covered beneficiaries to receive health care and timely assignment of primary care managers to covered beneficiaries.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> The elimination of the requirement for a referral to be authorized prior receiving specialty care services at a facility of the Department of Defense or through the TRICARE program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> The use of incentives to encourage covered beneficiaries to participate in medical and lifestyle intervention programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rural, remote, and isolated areas</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In developing and implementing the strategy required by paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> assess the unique characteristics of providing health care services in Alaska, Hawaii, and the territories and possessions of the United States, and in rural, remote, or isolated locations in the contiguous 48 States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> consider the various challenges inherent in developing robust networks of health care providers in those locations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> develop a provider reimbursement rate structure in those locations that ensures—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> timely access of covered beneficiaries to health care services;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the delivery of high-quality primary and specialty care;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> improvement in health outcomes for covered beneficiaries; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> an enhanced experience of care for covered beneficiaries; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><chapeau> ensure that managed care support contracts under the TRICARE program in those locations will—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> establish individual and institutional provider networks that will provide timely access to care for covered beneficiaries, including pursuant to such networks relating to an Indian tribe or tribal organization that is party to the Alaska Native Health Compact with the Indian Health Service or has entered into a contract with the Indian Health Service to provide health care in rural Alaska or other locations in the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> deliver high-quality care, better health outcomes, and a better experience of care for covered beneficiaries.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report Prior to Certain Contract Modifications</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 60 days before the date on which the Secretary of Defense first modifies a contract awarded under chapter 55 of title 10, United States Code, to implement a value-based incentive program under subsection (a), or the managed care support contract acquisition strategy under subsection (c), the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on any implementation plan of the Secretary with respect to such value-based incentive program or managed care support contract acquisition strategy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Comptroller General Report.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Secretary submits the report under subsection (d), the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report that assesses the compliance of the Secretary of Defense with the requirements of subsection (a) and subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include an assessment of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> Whether the approach of the Department of Defense for acquiring managed care support contracts under the TRICARE program—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> improves access to care;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> improves health outcomes;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> improves the experience of care for covered beneficiaries; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> lowers per capita health care costs.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> Whether the Department has, in its requirements for managed care support contracts under the TRICARE program, allowed for—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> maximum flexibility in network design and development;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> integrated medical management between military medical treatment facilities and network providers;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> the maximum use of the full range of telehealth services;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> the use of value-based reimbursement methods that transfer financial risk to health care providers and managed care support contractors;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="v">“(v)</num><content> the use of prevention and wellness incentives to encourage covered beneficiaries to seek health care services from high-value providers;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="vi">“(vi)</num><content> a streamlined enrollment process and timely assignment of primary care managers;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="vii">“(vii)</num><content> the elimination of the requirement to seek authorization for referrals for specialty care services;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="viii">“(viii)</num><content> the use of incentives to encourage covered beneficiaries to engage in medical and lifestyle intervention programs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ix">“(ix)</num><content> the use of financial incentives for contractors and health care providers to receive an equitable share in cost savings resulting from improvements in health outcomes and the experience of care for covered beneficiaries.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> Whether the Department has considered, in developing requirements for managed care support contracts under the TRICARE program, the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> The unique characteristics of providing health care services in Alaska, Hawaii, and the territories and possessions of the United States, and in rural, remote, or isolated locations in the contiguous 48 States;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> The various challenges inherent in developing robust networks of health care providers in those locations.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><chapeau> A provider reimbursement rate structure in those locations that ensures—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> timely access of covered beneficiaries to health care services;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> the delivery of high-quality primary and specialty care;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="III">     “(III)</num><content> improvement in health outcomes for covered beneficiaries; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="IV">     “(IV)</num><content> an enhanced experience of care for covered beneficiaries.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The terms ‘covered beneficiary’ and ‘TRICARE program’ have the meaning given those terms in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1072">section 1072 of title 10</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> The term ‘high-performing networks of health care providers’ means networks of health care providers that, in addition to such other requirements as the Secretary of Defense may specify for purposes of this section, do the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Deliver high quality health care as measured by leading health quality measurement organizations such as the National Committee for Quality Assurance and the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Achieve greater efficiency in the delivery of health care by identifying and implementing within such network improvement opportunities that guide patients through the entire continuum of care, thereby reducing variations in the delivery of health care and preventing medical errors and duplication of medical services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Improve population-based health outcomes by using a team approach to deliver case management, prevention, and wellness services to high-need and high-cost patients.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><chapeau> Focus on preventive care that emphasizes—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> early detection and timely treatment of disease;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> periodic health screenings; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> education regarding healthy lifestyle behaviors.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> Coordinate and integrate health care across the continuum of care, connecting all aspects of the health care received by the patient, including the patient’s health care team.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><chapeau> Facilitate access to health care providers, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> after-hours care;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> urgent care; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> through telehealth appointments, when appropriate.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> Encourage patients to participate in making health care decisions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> Use evidence-based treatment protocols that improve the consistency of health care and eliminate ineffective, wasteful health care practices.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
