<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida88cb335-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1094a"><num value="1094a">§ 1094a.</num><heading> Continuing medical education requirements: system for monitoring physician compliance</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense shall establish a mechanism for ensuring that each person under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of a military department who provides health care under this chapter as a physician satisfies the continuing medical education requirements applicable to the physician.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="ida88cb336-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/105/261/dA/tVII/s734/b/1">Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title VII, § 734(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2073">112 Stat. 2073</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida88cb337-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida88cb338-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida88cb339-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Implementation</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/261/dA/tVII/s734/c/2">Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title VII, § 734(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2073">112 Stat. 2073</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/261/dA/tVII/s734/c/2">“The system required by <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1094a">section 1094a of title 10</ref>, United States Code (as added by subsection (b)), shall take effect on the date that is three years after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida88cb33a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Oversight of Graduate Medical Education Programs of Military Departments</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tVII/s749">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VII, § 749</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2242">130 Stat. 2242</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tVII/s749">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Process</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall establish and implement a process to provide oversight of the graduate medical education programs of the military departments to ensure that such programs fully support the operational medical force readiness requirements for health care providers of the Armed Forces and the medical readiness of the Armed Forces. The process shall include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> A process to review such programs to ensure, to the extent practicable, that such programs are—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> conducted jointly among the military departments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> focused on, and related to, operational medical force readiness requirements.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> A process to minimize duplicative programs relating to such programs among the military departments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> A process to ensure that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> assignments of faculty, support staff, and students within such programs are coordinated among the military departments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Secretary optimizes resources by using military medical treatment facilities as training platforms when and where most appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> A process to review and, if necessary, restructure or realign, such programs to sustain and improve operational medical force readiness.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary establishes the process under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report that describes such process. The report shall include a description of each graduate medical education program of the military departments, categorized by the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Programs that provide direct support to operational medical force readiness.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Programs that provide indirect support to operational medical force readiness.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Academic programs that provide other medical support.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Comptroller General Review and Report.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Review</inline>.—</heading><content>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a review of the process established under subsection (a), including with respect to each process described in paragraphs (1) through (4) of such subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Secretary submits the report under subsection (b), the Comptroller General shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives the review conducted under paragraph (1), including an assessment of the elements of the process established under subsection (a).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida88cb33b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Joint Pilot Program for Providing Graduate Medical Education and Training for Physicians</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tVII/s725/a">Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title VII, § 725(a)</ref>–(d), <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2599">116 Stat. 2599</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tVII/s725/a">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall jointly carry out a pilot program under which graduate medical education and training is provided to military physicians and physician employees of the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs through one or more programs carried out in military medical treatment facilities of the Department of Defense and medical centers of the Department of Veterans Affairs. The pilot program shall begin not later than <date date="2003-01-01">January 1, 2003</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cost-Sharing Agreement</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretaries shall enter into an agreement for carrying out the pilot program. The agreement shall establish means for each Secretary to assist in paying the costs, with respect to individuals under the jurisdiction of that Secretary, incurred by the other Secretary in providing medical education and training under the pilot program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Existing Authorities</inline>.—</heading><content>To carry out the pilot program, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs may use authorities provided to them under this subtitle [subtitle C (§§ 721–726) of title VII of div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/107/314">Pub. L. 107–314</ref>, amending <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1104">section 1104 of this title</ref> and sections 8110 and 8111 of Title 38, Veterans’ Benefits, enacting provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1074g">section 1074g of this title</ref> and sections 8110 and 8111 of Title 38, and repealing provisions set out as a note under this section], <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s8111">section 8111 of title 38</ref>, United States Code (as amended by section 721(a)), and other laws relating to the furnishing or support of medical education and the cooperative use of facilities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination of Program</inline>.—</heading><content>The pilot program under this section shall terminate on <date date="2008-07-31">July 31, 2008</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida88cb33c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Joint DOD–VA Pilot Program for Providing Graduate Medical Education and Training for Physicians</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tVII/s738">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title VII, § 738</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1173">115 Stat. 1173</ref>, authorized a pilot program providing graduate medical education and training for physicians to be carried out jointly by the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tVII/s725/e">Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title VII, § 725(e)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2599">116 Stat. 2599</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
