<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida8965100-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1113"><num value="1113">§ 1113.</num><heading> Payments from the Fund</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8965101-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1113/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> There shall be paid from the Fund amounts payable for the costs of all uniformed service retiree health care programs for the benefit of members or former members of a participating uniformed service who are entitled to retired or retainer pay and are medicare eligible, and eligible dependents who are medicare eligible.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8965102-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1113/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The assets of the Fund are hereby made available for payments under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8965103-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1113/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8965104-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1113/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense may transfer periodically from the Fund to applicable appropriations of the Department of Defense, or to applicable appropriations of other departments or agencies, such amounts as the Secretary determines necessary to cover the costs chargeable to those appropriations for uniformed service retiree health care programs for beneficiaries under those programs who are medicare-eligible. Such transfers may include amounts necessary for the administration of such programs. Amounts so transferred shall be merged with and be available for the same purposes and for the same time period as the appropriation to which transferred. Upon a determination that all or part of the funds transferred from the Fund are not necessary for the purposes for which transferred, such amounts may be transferred back to the Fund. This transfer authority is in addition to any other transfer authority that may be available to the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8965105-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1113/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A transfer from the Fund under paragraph (1) may not be made to an appropriation after the end of the second fiscal year after the fiscal year that the appropriation is available for obligation. A transfer back to the Fund under paragraph (1) may not be made after the end of the second fiscal year after the fiscal year for which the appropriation to which the funds were originally transferred is available for obligation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8965106-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1113/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall by regulation establish the method or methods for calculating amounts to be transferred under subsection (c). Such method or methods may be based (in whole or in part) on a proportionate share of the volume (measured as the Secretary determines appropriate) of health care services provided or paid for under uniformed service retiree health care programs for beneficiaries under those programs who are medicare-eligible in relation to the total volume of health care services provided or paid for under Department of Defense health care programs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8965107-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1113/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> The regulations prescribed by the Secretary under subsection (d) shall be provided to the Comptroller General not less than 60 days before such regulations become effective. The Comptroller General shall, not later than 30 days after receiving such regulations, report to the Secretary of Defense and Congress on the adequacy and appropriateness of the regulations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8965108-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1113/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> If the Secretary of Defense enters into an agreement with another administering Secretary pursuant to section 1111(c), the Secretary of Defense may take the actions described in subsections (c), (d), and (e) on behalf of the beneficiaries and programs of the other participating uniformed service.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida8965109-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title VII, § 713(a)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–180; amended <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tVII/s711/c">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title VII, § 711(c)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1165">115 Stat. 1165</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida896510a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida896510b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida896510c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/s711/c/1">Pub. L. 107–107, § 711(c)(1)</ref>, amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) read as follows: “There shall be paid from the Fund amounts payable for Department of Defense retiree health care programs for medicare-eligible beneficiaries.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c) to (f). <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/s711/c/2">Pub. L. 107–107, § 711(c)(2)</ref>, added subsecs. (c) to (f).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida896510d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida896510e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2001 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/107">Pub. L. 107–107</ref> effective as if included in the enactment of this chapter by <ref href="/us/pl/106/398">Pub. L. 106–398</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/s711/f">section 711(f) of Pub. L. 107–107</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1111">section 1111 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="ida896510f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title VII, § 713(b)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–184, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">“Sections 1113 and 1116 of title 10, United States Code (as added by subsection (a)), shall take effect on <date date="2002-10-01">October 1, 2002</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
