<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida89d5532-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142"><num value="1142">§ 1142.</num><heading> Preseparation counseling; transmittal of certain records to Department of Veterans Affairs</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida89d5533-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida89d5534-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Within the time periods specified in paragraph (3), the Secretary concerned shall (except as provided in paragraph (4)) provide for individual preseparation counseling of each member of the armed forces whose discharge (regardless of character of discharge) or release from active duty is anticipated as of a specific date. A notation of the provision of such counseling with respect to each matter specified in subsection (b), signed by the member, shall be placed in the service record of each member receiving such counseling.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida89d5535-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida89d5536-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In carrying out this section, the Secretary concerned shall use the services available under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1144">section 1144 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida89d5537-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Preseparation counseling may be provided in person to the extent practicable. If the Secretary concerned determines that it is infeasible for a member to attend such counseling in person, such member may receive such counseling remotely, with online access to modules and reading materials.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida89d5538-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida89d5539-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In the case of an anticipated retirement, preseparation counseling shall commence as soon as possible during the 24-month period preceding the anticipated retirement date. In the case of a separation other than a retirement, preseparation counseling shall commence not later than 365 days before the anticipated date. Except as provided in subparagraph (B), in no event shall preseparation counseling commence later than 365 days before the date of retirement or other separation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida89d553a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In the event that a retirement or other separation is unanticipated until there are 365 or fewer days before the anticipated retirement or separation date, or in the event a member of a reserve component is being demobilized under circumstances in which (as determined by the Secretary concerned) operational requirements make the 365-day requirement under subparagraph (A) unfeasible, preseparation counseling shall begin as soon as possible within the remaining period of service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida89d553b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense may implement a system to track how many, and what percentage of, members begin to receive preseparation counseling within time periods specified in this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida89d553c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida89d553d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary concerned shall not provide preseparation counseling to a member who is being discharged or released before the completion of the first 180 continuous days of active duty of the member.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida89d553e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Subparagraph (A) shall not apply in the case of a member who is being retired or separated for disability.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida89d553f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/a/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> For purposes of calculating the days of active duty of a member under subparagraph (A), the Secretary concerned shall exclude any day on which—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5540-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/a/4/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the member performed full-time training duty or annual training duty; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5541-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/a/4/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the member attended, while in the active military service, a school designated as a service school by law or by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida89d5542-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/a/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> The Secretary concerned may waive the requirement for preseparation counseling under paragraph (1) in the case of a member of the reserve components if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5543-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/a/4/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the member requests such a waiver;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5544-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/a/4/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the member received preseparation counseling during the period of three years preceding the date of such request; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5545-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/a/4/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> matters covered by such counseling, specified in subsection (b), have not changed since the member last received such counseling.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida89d5546-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Matters To Be Covered By Counseling</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Counseling under this section shall include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5547-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A discussion of the educational assistance benefits to which the member is entitled under the Montgomery GI Bill and other educational assistance programs because of the member’s service in the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5548-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A description (to be developed with the assistance of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs) of the compensation and vocational rehabilitation benefits to which the member may be entitled under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, if the member is being medically separated or is being retired under chapter 61 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5549-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> An explanation of the procedures for and advantages of affiliating with the Selected Reserve.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d554a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> Provision of information on civilian occupations and related assistance programs, including information concerning—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida89d554b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> certification and licensure requirements that are applicable to civilian occupations, including State-submitted and approved lists of military training and skills that satisfy occupational certifications and licenses;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida89d554c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> civilian occupations that correspond to military occupational specialties; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida89d554d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Government and private-sector programs for job search and job placement assistance, including information regarding the placement programs established under sections 1152 and 1153 of this title and the Troops-to-Teachers Program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d554e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> If the member has a spouse, inclusion of the spouse, at the discretion of the member and the spouse, when counseling regarding the matters covered by paragraphs (9), (10), and (16) is provided, job placement counseling for the spouse, and the provision of information on survivor benefits available under the laws administered by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d554f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Information concerning the availability of relocation assistance services and other benefits and services available to persons leaving military service, as provided under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1144">section 1144 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5550-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Information concerning the availability of medical and dental coverage following separation from active duty, including the opportunity to elect into the conversion health policy provided under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1145">section 1145 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5551-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> Counseling (for the member and dependents) on the effect of career change on individuals and their families and the availability to the member and dependents of suicide prevention resources following separation from the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5552-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5553-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/9/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Financial planning assistance, including information on budgeting, saving, credit, loans and debt management,,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002058">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002058"><num>1</num> So in original.</note> and taxes.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5554-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/9/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Individualized assistance regarding matters described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5555-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> The creation of a transition plan for the member to attempt to achieve the educational, training, employment, and financial objectives of the member and, if the member has a spouse, the spouse of the member.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5556-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> Information concerning the availability of mental health services and the treatment of post-traumatic stress disorder, anxiety disorders, depression, suicidal ideations, or other mental health conditions associated with service in the armed forces and information concerning the availability of treatment options and resources to address substance abuse, including alcohol, prescription drug, and opioid abuse.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5557-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> Information concerning the priority of service for veterans in the receipt of employment, training, and placement services provided under qualified job training programs of the Department of Labor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5558-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> Information concerning veterans small business ownership and entrepreneurship programs of the Small Business Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5559-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> Information concerning employment and reemployment rights and obligations under chapter 43 of title 38.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d555a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content> Information concerning veterans preference in Federal employment and Federal procurement opportunities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d555b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/16"><num value="16">(16)</num><content> Information on home loan services and housing assistance benefits available under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and counseling on responsible borrowing practices.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d555c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/17"><num value="17">(17)</num><content> A description, developed in consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, of health care and other benefits to which the member may be entitled under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and information regarding the means by which the member can receive additional counseling regarding the member’s actual entitlement to such benefits and apply for such benefits.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d555d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/18"><num value="18">(18)</num><content> A description, developed in consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, of the assistance and support services for family caregivers of eligible veterans under the program conducted by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1720G">section 1720G of title 38</ref>, including the veterans covered by the program, the caregivers eligible for assistance and support through the program, and the assistance and support available through the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d555e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/b/19"><num value="19">(19)</num><content> Information regarding how to file claims for benefits available to the member under laws administered by the Secretaries of Defense and Veterans Affairs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida89d555f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Counseling Pathways</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida89d5560-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Each Secretary concerned, in consultation with the Secretaries of Labor and Veterans Affairs, shall establish at least three pathways for members of the military department concerned (including one pathway for members of the reserve components) receiving individualized counseling under this section. The Secretaries shall design the pathways to address the needs of members, based on the following factors:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5561-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Rank.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5562-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Term of service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5563-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Gender.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5564-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Whether the member was a member of a regular or reserve component of an armed force.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5565-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Potential or confirmed disability.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5566-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> Potential or confirmed character of discharge (including expedited discharge and discharge under conditions other than honorable).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5567-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> Health (including mental health).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5568-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> Military occupational specialty.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5569-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><chapeau> Whether the member intends, after separation, retirement, or discharge, to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida89d556a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/I/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> seek employment;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida89d556b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/I/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> enroll in a program of higher education;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida89d556c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/I/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> enroll in a program of vocational training; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida89d556d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/I/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> become an entrepreneur.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d556e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><content> The educational history of the member.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d556f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/K"><num value="K">(K)</num><content> The employment history of the member.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5570-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/L"><num value="L">(L)</num><chapeau> Whether the member has secured—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida89d5571-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/L/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> employment;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida89d5572-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/L/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> enrollment in a program of education; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida89d5573-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/L/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> enrollment in a program of vocational training.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5574-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/M"><num value="M">(M)</num><content> Child care requirements of the member (including whether a dependent of the member is enrolled in the Exceptional Family Member Program).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5575-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/N"><num value="N">(N)</num><content> The employment status of other adults in the household of the member.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5576-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/O"><num value="O">(O)</num><content> The location of the duty station of the member (including whether the member was separated from family while on duty).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5577-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/P"><num value="P">(P)</num><content> The effects of operating tempo and personnel tempo on the member and the household of the member.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5578-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/1/R"><num value="R">(R)</num><content> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002059">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002059"><num>2</num> So in original. There is no subpar. (Q).</note> Other factors the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretaries of Labor and Veterans Affairs, determine appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida89d5579-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Each member described in subsection (a) shall meet in person or by video conference with a counselor before beginning counseling under this section to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d557a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> take a self-assessment designed by the Secretary concerned (in consultation with the Secretaries of Labor and Veterans Affairs) to ensure that the Secretary concerned places the member in the appropriate pathway under this subsection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d557b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> receive information from the counselor regarding reenlistment in the armed forces; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d557c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> receive information from the counselor regarding resources (including resources regarding military sexual trauma)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida89d557d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> for members of the armed forces separated, retired, or discharged;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida89d557e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> located in the community in which the member will reside after separation, retirement, or discharge.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida89d557f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> At the meeting under paragraph (2), the member may elect to have the Secretary concerned (in consultation with the Secretaries of Labor and Veterans Affairs) provide the contact information of the member to the resources described in paragraph (2)(C).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida89d5580-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transmittal of Medical Information to Department of Veterans Affairs</inline>.—</heading><content>In the case of a member being medically separated or being retired under chapter 61 of this title, the Secretary concerned shall ensure (subject to the consent of the member) that a copy of the member’s service medical record (including any results of a Physical Evaluation Board) is transmitted to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs within 60 days of the separation or retirement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida89d5581-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Joint Service Transcript</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary concerned shall provide a copy of the joint service transcript of a member described in subsection (a) to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5582-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> that member—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida89d5583-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> at the meeting with a counselor under subsection (c)(2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida89d5584-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> on the day the member separates, retires, or is discharged; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida89d5585-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1142/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the Secretary of Veterans Affairs on the day the member separates, retires, or is discharged.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida89d5586-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tV/s502/a/1">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1552">104 Stat. 1552</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/dA/tX/s1061/a/5">Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1061(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1472">105 Stat. 1472</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dD/tXLIV">Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLIV</ref>, §§ 4401, 4441(b), 4462(b), <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2701">106 Stat. 2701</ref>, 2730, 2740; <ref href="/us/pl/103/35/tII/s201/i/1">Pub. L. 103–35, title II, § 201(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-05-31">May 31, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/100">107 Stat. 100</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tXIII/s1332/c">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XIII, § 1332(c)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1797">107 Stat. 1797</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1087(a)(9)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–290; <ref href="/us/pl/107/103/tIII/s302/a">Pub. L. 107–103, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-27">Dec. 27, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/991">115 Stat. 991</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tV/s594">Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 594</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3281">119 Stat. 3281</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/dA/tX/s1073/a/13">Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2473">123 Stat. 2473</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/56/tII/s221/b">Pub. L. 112–56, title II, § 221(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-11-21">Nov. 21, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/716">125 Stat. 716</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/dA/tV">Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 513, 529, 533(c), <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1393">125 Stat. 1393</ref>, 1402, 1404; <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dA/tV/s541/c">Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title V, § 541(c)</ref>, title X, § 1076(f)(12), title XVI, § 1699(c)(1), <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1735">126 Stat. 1735</ref>, 1952, 2092; <ref href="/us/pl/114/92/dA/tV/s552">Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title V, § 552</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/823">129 Stat. 823</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tV/s562">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 562</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2138">130 Stat. 2138</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tV">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 541(a), 542(d), <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1393">131 Stat. 1393</ref>, 1395; <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tV">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 552(a)(1), 553(b)(2), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1769">132 Stat. 1769</ref>, 1772; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tV/s561">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 561</ref>, title XVII, § 1731(a)(26), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1394">133 Stat. 1394</ref>, 1813; <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tV/s571">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 571</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/275">137 Stat. 275</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tV/s571">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 571</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1909">138 Stat. 1909</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tV">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 571(a)–(d), 572, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/884-886">139 Stat. 884–886</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida89d5587-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida89d5588-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida89d5589-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s571/a">Pub. L. 119–60, § 571(a)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A) and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s571/b">Pub. L. 119–60, § 571(b)</ref>, added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s571/c">Pub. L. 119–60, § 571(c)</ref>, added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s571/d">Pub. L. 119–60, § 571(d)</ref>, which directed amendment of par. (9) of subsec. (a), by designating existing provisions as subpar. (A), inserting “and debt management,” after “loans”, and adding subpar. (B), was executed to par. (9) of subsec. (b), to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(M) to (P), (R). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s572">Pub. L. 119–60, § 572</ref>, added subpars. (M) to (P) and redesignated former subpar. (M) as (R).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159">Pub. L. 118–159</ref> inserted “(including one pathway for members of the reserve components)” after “military department concerned” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2023—Subsec. (c)(1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s571/1">Pub. L. 118–31, § 571(1)</ref>, substituted “Potential or confirmed disability” for “Disability”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s571/2">Pub. L. 118–31, § 571(2)</ref>, substituted “Potential or confirmed character” for “Character”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (b)(19). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s561">Pub. L. 116–92, § 561</ref>, added par. (19).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s1731/a/26">Pub. L. 116–92, § 1731(a)(26)</ref>, substituted “paragraph (2)(C)” for “paragraph (2)(B)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—<ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s552/a/1/A">Pub. L. 115–232, § 552(a)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “certain” for “medical” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s552/a/1/B/i">Pub. L. 115–232, § 552(a)(1)(B)(i)</ref>, inserted “(regardless of character of discharge)” after “discharge”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s552/a/1/B/ii">Pub. L. 115–232, § 552(a)(1)(B)(ii)</ref>, substituted “not later than 365 days before” for “as soon as possible during the 12-month period preceding”, “365 days” for “90 days”, and “retirement or other separation” for “discharge or release”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s552/a/1/B/iii">Pub. L. 115–232, § 552(a)(1)(B)(iii)</ref>, substituted “365” for “90” and “365-day” for “90-day”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s553/b/2">Pub. L. 115–232, § 553(b)(2)</ref>, struck out “the public and community service jobs program carried out under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1143a">section 1143a of this title</ref>, and” after “including”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s552/a/1/C">Pub. L. 115–232, § 552(a)(1)(C)</ref>, (D), added subsec. (c) and redesignated former subsec. (c) as (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s552/a/1/E">Pub. L. 115–232, § 552(a)(1)(E)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—Subsec. (b)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s542/d">Pub. L. 115–91, § 542(d)</ref>, inserted “, including State-submitted and approved lists of military training and skills that satisfy occupational certifications and licenses” before semicolon at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(18). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s541/a">Pub. L. 115–91, § 541(a)</ref>, added par. (18).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (b)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328">Pub. L. 114–328</ref> inserted before period at end “and information concerning the availability of treatment options and resources to address substance abuse, including alcohol, prescription drug, and opioid abuse”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (a)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/114/92/s552/1">Pub. L. 114–92, § 552(1)</ref>, substituted “the first 180 continuous days of active duty of the member” for “that member’s first 180 days of active duty”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/114/92/s552/2">Pub. L. 114–92, § 552(2)</ref>, added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (b)(4)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s541/c">Pub. L. 112–239, § 541(c)</ref>, struck out “under section 2302 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6672">20 U.S.C. 6672</ref>)” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1076/f/12">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1076(f)(12)</ref>, substituted “training,” for “training,,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(13). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1699/c/1">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1699(c)(1)</ref>, struck out “and the National Veterans Business Development Corporation” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/112/56">Pub. L. 112–56</ref> substituted “shall” for “may”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/s513">Pub. L. 112–81, § 513</ref>, inserted “or in the event a member of a reserve component is being demobilized under circumstances in which (as determined by the Secretary concerned) operational requirements make the 90-day requirement under subparagraph (A) unfeasible,” after “or separation date,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/s529/1">Pub. L. 112–81, § 529(1)</ref>, substituted “inclusion of the spouse, at the discretion of the member and the spouse, when counseling regarding the matters covered by paragraphs (9), (10), and (16) is provided, job placement counseling for the spouse, and the provision of information on survivor benefits available under the laws administered by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Veterans Affairs” for “job placement counseling for the spouse”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/s533/c">Pub. L. 112–81, § 533(c)</ref>, inserted before period at end “and the availability to the member and dependents of suicide prevention resources following separation from the armed forces”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/s529/2">Pub. L. 112–81, § 529(2)</ref>, inserted before period at end “, including information on budgeting, saving, credit, loans, and taxes”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/s529/3">Pub. L. 112–81, § 529(3)</ref>, substituted “, employment, and financial” for “and employment”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(16). <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/s529/4">Pub. L. 112–81, § 529(4)</ref>, added par. (16) and struck out former par. (16) which read as follows: “Contact information for housing counseling assistance.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(17). <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/s529/5">Pub. L. 112–81, § 529(5)</ref>, inserted before period at end “, and information regarding the means by which the member can receive additional counseling regarding the member’s actual entitlement to such benefits and apply for such benefits”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (b)(4)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/s1073/a/13/A">Pub. L. 111–84, § 1073(a)(13)(A)</ref>, substituted “the Troops-to-Teachers Program under section 2302 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6672">20 U.S.C. 6672</ref>)” for “the Troops-to-Teachers Program Act of 1999 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s9301">20 U.S.C. 9301</ref> et seq.)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(15). <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/s1073/a/13/B">Pub. L. 111–84, § 1073(a)(13)(B)</ref>, substituted “Federal” for “federal” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/s594/1">Pub. L. 109–163, § 594(1)</ref>, substituted “Provision of information on civilian occupations and related assistance programs, including information concerning—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) certification and licensure requirements that are applicable to civilian occupations;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) civilian occupations that correspond to military occupational specialties; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C)”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">for “Information concerning”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(11) to (17). <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/s594/2">Pub. L. 109–163, § 594(2)</ref>, added pars. (11) to (17).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/103/s302/a/1">Pub. L. 107–103, § 302(a)(1)</ref>, amended first sentence generally. Prior to amendment, first sentence read as follows: “As soon as possible before, but in no event later than 90 days before, the date of the discharge or release from active duty of a member of the armed forces, the Secretary concerned shall provide for individual preseparation counseling of the member.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/107/103/s302/a/2">Pub. L. 107–103, § 302(a)(2)</ref>, added pars. (3) and (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/106/398">Pub. L. 106–398</ref> substituted “sections 1152 and 1153 of this title and the Troops-to-Teachers Program Act of 1999 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s9301">20 U.S.C. 9301</ref> et seq.)” for “sections 1151, 1152, and 1153 of this title”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/103/160">Pub. L. 103–160</ref> substituted “programs established under sections 1151, 1152, and 1153 of this title” for “program established under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1151">section 1151 of this title</ref> to assist members to obtain employment as elementary or secondary school teachers or teachers’ aides”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/35">Pub. L. 103–35</ref> substituted “job placement assistance, including the public and community service jobs program carried out under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1143a">section 1143a of this title</ref>, and information regarding the placement program established under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1151">section 1151 of this title</ref> to assist members to obtain employment as elementary or secondary school teachers or teachers’ aides” for “job placement assistance and information regarding the placement program established under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1151">section 1151 of this title</ref> to assist members obtain employment as elementary or secondary school teachers or teachers’ aides., including the public and community service jobs program carried out under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1143a">section 1143a of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s4401/a">Pub. L. 102–484, § 4401(a)</ref>, substituted “As soon as possible before, but in no event later than 90 days before, the date of the discharge” for “Upon the discharge”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s4462/b">Pub. L. 102–484, § 4462(b)</ref>, inserted before period at end “, including the public and community service jobs program carried out under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1143a">section 1143a of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s4441/b">Pub. L. 102–484, § 4441(b)</ref>, inserted before period at end “and information regarding the placement program established under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1151">section 1151 of this title</ref> to assist members obtain employment as elementary or secondary school teachers or teachers’ aides.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s4401/b">Pub. L. 102–484, § 4401(b)</ref>, added par. (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/102/190">Pub. L. 102–190</ref> substituted period for semicolon at end.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida89d558a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida89d558b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2011 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/56/tII/s221/c">Pub. L. 112–56, title II, § 221(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-11-21">Nov. 21, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/716">125 Stat. 716</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/56/tII/s221/c">“The amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1144">section 1144 of this title</ref>] shall take effect on the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2011-11-21">Nov. 21, 2011</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida89d558c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Notice of Options for Naturalization Upon Separation</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tV/s523/b">Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title V, § 523(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1687">135 Stat. 1687</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tV/s523/b">“The Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services, and in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall provide to a member of the Armed Forces who is not a citizen of the United States, upon separation of such member, notice of options for naturalization under title III of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1401">8 U.S.C. 1401</ref> et seq.)[.] Such notice shall inform the member of existing programs or services that may aid in the naturalization process of such member.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida89d558d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Inclusion of Question Regarding Immigration Status on Preseparation Counseling Checklist (DD Form 2648)</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tV/s570C">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 570C</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1399">133 Stat. 1399</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tV/s570C">“Not later than <date date="2020-09-30">September 30, 2020</date>, the Secretary of Defense shall modify the preseparation counseling checklist for active component, active guard reserve, active reserve, full time support, and reserve program administrator service members (DD Form 2648) to include a specific block wherein a member of the Armed Forces may indicate that the member would like to receive information regarding the immigration status of that member and expedited naturalization.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida89d558e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Connections of Members Retiring or Separating From the Armed Forces With Community-Based Organizations and Related Entities</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tV/s570F">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 570F</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1401">133 Stat. 1401</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tV/s573">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title V, § 573</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/887">139 Stat. 887</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tV/s573">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall jointly seek to enter into memoranda of understanding or other agreements with State veterans agencies under which information from Department of Defense Form DD–2648 on individuals undergoing retirement, discharge, or release from the Armed Forces is transmitted to one or more State veterans agencies, as elected by such individuals, to provide or connect veterans to benefits or services as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Assistance in preparation of resumes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Training for employment interviews.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Employment recruitment training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Other services leading directly to a successful transition from military life to civilian life.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Healthcare, including care for mental health.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> Transportation or transportation-related services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> Housing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> Such other benefits or services as the Secretaries jointly consider appropriate for purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Information Transmitted</inline>.—</heading><content>The information transmitted on individuals as described in subsection (a) shall be such information on Form DD–2648 as the Secretaries jointly consider appropriate to facilitate community-based organizations and related entities in providing or connecting such individuals to benefits and services as described in subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Modification of Form DD–</inline>2648.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall make such modifications to Form DD–2648 as the Secretary considers appropriate to allow an individual filling out the form to indicate—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> an email address at which the individual may be contacted to receive or be connected to benefits or services described in subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> if the individual would like to opt-out of the transmittal of the individual’s information to and through a State veterans agency as described in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Opt-out of Information Sharing</inline>.—</heading><content>Information on an individual shall be transmitted to and through a State veterans agency as described in subsection (a) unless the individual indicates pursuant to subsection (c)(2) that the individual would like to opt out of such transmittal.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Storage and Transfer of Information.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall seek to enter into memoranda of understanding or other agreements with the State veterans agencies described in subsection (a) to create or modify a Department system to store and transfer information under this section to information systems of such State veterans agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Compliance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall ensure that any agreement entered into under paragraph (1) is in compliance with—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> applicable provisions of law relating to privacy and personally identifiable information; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> applicable policies relating to cybersecurity of Department information systems and State information systems.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Use of Information</inline>.—</heading><content>Information transferred under this section may only be used by a State for the purpose of providing or connecting veterans to benefits or services as described in subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida89d558f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Deadline for Counseling Pathways</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tV/s552/a/2">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 552(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1770">132 Stat. 1770</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tV/s552/a/2">“Each Secretary concerned shall carry out subsection (c) of such section [<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1142/c">10 U.S.C. 1142(c)</ref>], as amended by paragraph (1), not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida89d5590-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Notification of Members of the Armed Forces Undergoing Certain Administrative Separations of Potential Eligibility for Veterans Benefits</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tV/s528">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title V, § 528</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1383">131 Stat. 1383</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tV/s528">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notification Required</inline>.—</heading><content>A member of the Armed Forces who receives an administrative separation or mandatory discharge under conditions other than honorable shall be provided written notification that the member may petition the Veterans Benefits Administration of the Department of Veterans Affairs to receive, despite the characterization of the member’s service, certain benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deadline for Notification</inline>.—</heading><content>Notification under subsection (a) shall be provided to a member described in such subsection in conjunction with the member’s notification of the administrative separation or mandatory discharge or as soon thereafter as practicable.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida89d5591-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Participation of Potential Caregivers in Appropriate Preseparation Counseling</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tV/s541/b">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title V, § 541(b)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1393">131 Stat. 1393</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tV/s541/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In accordance with procedures established by the Secretary of Defense, each Secretary of a military department shall take appropriate actions to achieve the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> To determine whether each member of the Armed Forces under the jurisdiction of such Secretary who is undergoing preseparation counseling pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1142">section 1142 of title 10</ref>, United States Code (as amended by subsection (a)), and who may require caregiver services after separation from the Armed Forces has identified an individual to provide such services after the member’s separation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> In the case of a member described in subparagraph (A) who has identified an individual to provide caregiver services after the member’s separation, at the election of the member, to permit such individual to participate in appropriate sessions of the member’s preseparation counseling in order to inform such individual of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the assistance and support services available to caregivers of members after separation from the Armed Forces; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the manner in which the member’s transition to civilian life after separation may likely affect such individual as a caregiver.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Caregivers</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this subsection, individuals who provide caregiver services refers to individuals (including a spouse, partner, parent, sibling, adult child, other relative, or friend) who provide physical or emotional assistance to former members of the Armed Forces during and after their transition from military life to civilian life following separation from the Armed Forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deadline for commencement</inline>.—</heading><content>Each Secretary of a miliary [sic] department shall commence the actions required pursuant to this subsection by not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>].”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida89d5592-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Application of Preseparation Counseling Requirements to Coast Guard</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tV/s543/a">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 543(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2769">108 Stat. 2769</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tV/s543/a">“As soon as possible after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>], the Secretary of Transportation shall implement the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1142">section 1142 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, for the Coast Guard.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida89d5593-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Limitation on Funding To Carry Out <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s543">Section 543 of Pub. L. 103–337</ref></heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tV/s543/h">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 543(h)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2772">108 Stat. 2772</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tV/s543/h">“Funds appropriated or otherwise made available to the Department of Defense, the Department of Education, the Department of Labor, or the Department of Veterans Affairs may not be used to carry out subsection (a) [set out above] or the amendments made by this section [amending sections 1144 and 1151 to 1153 of this title and provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1143">section 1143 of this title</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
