<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida743913e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115"><num value="115">§ 115.</num><heading> Personnel strengths: requirement for annual authorization</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida743913f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Active-Duty, Selected Reserve, and Space Force End Strengths To Be Authorized by Law</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Congress shall authorize personnel strength levels for each fiscal year for each of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439140-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The end strength for the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Marine Corps for (A) active-duty personnel who are to be paid from funds appropriated for active-duty personnel unless on active duty pursuant to subsection (b), and (B) active-duty personnel and full-time National Guard duty personnel who are to be paid from funds appropriated for reserve personnel unless on active duty or full-time National Guard duty pursuant to subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439141-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The end strength for the Selected Reserve of each reserve component of the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439142-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The end strength for the Space Force for members in space force active status.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7439143-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certain Reserves on Active Duty To Be Authorized by Law</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7439144-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Congress shall annually authorize the maximum number of members of a reserve component permitted to be on active duty or full-time National Guard duty at any given time who are called or ordered to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439145-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> active duty under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12301/d">section 12301(d) of this title</ref> for the purpose of providing operational support, as prescribed in regulation issued by the Secretary of Defense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439146-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> full-time National Guard duty under <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s502/f/1/B">section 502(f)(1)(B) of title 32</ref> for the purpose of providing operational support when authorized by the Secretary of Defense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439147-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> active duty under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12301/d">section 12301(d) of this title</ref> or full-time National Guard duty under <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s502/f/1/B">section 502(f)(1)(B) of title 32</ref> for the purpose of preparing for and performing funeral honors functions for funerals of veterans under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1491">section 1491 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439148-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> active duty or retained on active duty under sections 12301(g) of this title while in a captive status; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439149-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> active duty or retained on active duty under 12301(h) or 12322 of this title for the purpose of medical evaluation or treatment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida743914a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> A member of a reserve component who exceeds either of the following limits shall be included in the strength authorized under subparagraph (A) or subparagraph (B), as appropriate, of subsection (a)(1):</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida743914b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A call or order to active duty or full-time National Guard duty that specifies a period greater than three years.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida743914c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The cumulative periods of active duty and full-time National Guard duty performed by the member exceed 1825 days in the previous 2190 days.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida743914d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> In determining the period of active service under paragraph (2), the following periods of active service performed by a member shall not be included:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida743914e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> All periods of active duty performed by a member who has not previously served in the Selected Reserve of the Ready Reserve.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida743914f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> All periods of active duty or full-time National Guard duty for which the member is exempt from strength accounting under paragraphs (1) through (8) of subsection (i).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7439150-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> As part of the budget justification materials submitted by the Secretary of Defense to Congress in support of the end strength authorizations required under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(1) for fiscal year 2009 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Secretary shall provide the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439151-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The number of members, specified by reserve component, authorized under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) who were serving on active duty or full-time National Guard duty for operational support beyond each of the limits specified under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (2) at the end of the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year for which the budget justification materials are submitted.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439152-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The number of members, specified by reserve component, on active duty for operational support who, at the end of the fiscal year for which the budget justification materials are submitted, are projected to be serving on active duty or full-time National Guard duty for operational support beyond such limits.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439153-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/b/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The number of members, specified by reserve component, on active duty or full-time National Guard duty for operational support who are included in, and counted against, the end strength authorizations requested under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439154-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/b/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> A summary of the missions being performed by members identified under subparagraphs (A) and (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7439155-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Appropriations for Military Personnel</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>No funds may be appropriated for any fiscal year to or for—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439156-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the use of active-duty personnel or full-time National Guard duty personnel of any of the armed forces (other than the Coast Guard) unless the end strength for such personnel of that armed force for that fiscal year has been authorized by law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439157-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the use of the Selected Reserve of any reserve component of the armed forces unless the end strength for the Selected Reserve of that component for that fiscal year has been authorized by law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439158-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the use of members of the Space Force in space force active status unless the end strength for the Space Force for that fiscal year for members in space force active status has been authorized by law; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439159-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the use of reserve component personnel to perform active duty or full-time National Guard duty under subsection (b) unless the strength for such personnel for that reserve component for that fiscal year has been authorized by law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida743915a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Military Technician (Dual Status) End Strengths To Be Authorized by Law</inline>.—</heading><content>Congress shall authorize for each fiscal year both the minimum end strength for non-temporary military technicians (dual status) and the end strength for temporary military technicians (dual status) for each reserve component of the Army and Air Force. Funds available to the Department of Defense for any fiscal year may not be used for the pay of a military technician (dual status) during that fiscal year unless the technician fills a position that is within the number of such positions authorized by law for that fiscal year for the reserve component of that technician. This subsection applies without regard to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s129">section 129 of this title</ref>. In each budget submitted by the President to Congress under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105">section 1105 of title 31</ref>, the minimum end strength for non-temporary military technicians (dual status), and the end strength for temporary military technicians (dual status), requested for each reserve component of the Army and Air Force shall be specifically set forth.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida743915b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">End-of-Quarter Strength Levels</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida743915c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe and include in the budget justification documents submitted to Congress in support of the President’s budget for the Department of Defense for any fiscal year the Secretary’s proposed end-of-quarter strengths for each of the first three quarters of the fiscal year for which the budget is submitted, in addition to the Secretary’s proposed fiscal-year end-strengths for that fiscal year. Such end-of-quarter strengths shall be submitted for each category of personnel for which end strengths are required to be authorized by law under subsection (a) or (d). The Secretary shall ensure that resources are provided in the budget at a level sufficient to support the end-of-quarter and fiscal-year end-strengths as submitted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida743915d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida743915e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> After annual end-strength levels required by subsections (a) and (d) are authorized by law for a fiscal year, the Secretary of Defense shall promptly prescribe end-of-quarter strength levels for the first three quarters of that fiscal year applicable to each such end-strength level. Such end-of-quarter strength levels shall be established for any fiscal year as levels to be achieved in meeting each of those annual end-strength levels authorized by law in accordance with subsection (a) (as such levels may be adjusted pursuant to subsection (f)) and subsection (d).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida743915f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> At least annually, the Secretary of Defense shall establish for each of the armed forces (other than the Coast Guard) the maximum permissible variance of actual strength for an armed force at the end of any given quarter from the end-of-quarter strength established pursuant to subparagraph (A). Such variance shall be such that it promotes the maintaining of the strength necessary to achieve the end-strength levels authorized in accordance with subsection (a) (as adjusted pursuant to subsection (f)) and subsection (d).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7439160-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Whenever the Secretary establishes an end-of-quarter strength level under subparagraph (A) of paragraph (2), or modifies a strength level under the authority provided in subparagraph (B) of paragraph (2), the Secretary shall notify the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives of that strength level or of that modification, as the case may be.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7439161-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority for Secretary of Defense Variances for Active-Duty and Selected Reserve Strengths</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Upon determination by the Secretary of Defense that such action is in the national interest, the Secretary may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439162-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> vary the end strength authorized pursuant to subsection (a)(1)(A) for a fiscal year for any of the armed forces by a number equal to not more than 3 percent of that end strength;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439163-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> vary the end strength authorized pursuant to subsection (a)(1)(B) for a fiscal year for any of the armed forces by a number equal to not more than 3 percent of that end strength;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439164-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> vary the end strength authorized pursuant to subsection (a)(2) for a fiscal year for the Selected Reserve of any of the reserve components by a number equal to not more than 3 percent of that end strength; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439165-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> vary the maximum strength authorized pursuant to subsection (b)(1) for a fiscal year for certain reserves on active duty for any of the reserve components by a number equal to not more than 10 percent of that strength.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7439166-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority for Service Secretary Variances for Active-duty and Selected Reserve End Strengths</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7439167-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Upon determination by the Secretary of a military department that such action would enhance manning and readiness in essential units or in critical specialties or ratings, the Secretary may—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439168-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> vary the end strength pursuant to subsection (a)(1)(A) for a fiscal year for the armed force or forces under the jurisdiction of that Secretary by a number not equal to more than 2 percent of such authorized end strength;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439169-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> vary the end strength pursuant to subsection (a)(1)(B) for a fiscal year for the armed force or forces under the jurisdiction of that Secretary by a number not equal to more than 2 percent of such authorized end strength; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida743916a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/g/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> vary the end strength pursuant to subsection (a)(2) for a fiscal year for the Selected Reserve of the reserve component of the armed force or forces under the jurisdiction of that Secretary by a number equal to not more than 2 percent of such authorized end strength.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida743916b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any variance under paragraph (1)(A) of the end strength for an armed force for a fiscal year shall be counted as part of the variance for that armed force for that fiscal year authorized under subsection (f)(1). Any variance under paragraph (1)(B) of the end strength for the Selected Reserve of a reserve component of an armed force for a fiscal year shall be counted as part of the variance for that Selected Reserve for that fiscal year authorized under subsection (f)(3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida743916c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of the military department concerned shall promptly notify the congressional defense committees if such Secretary exceeds a variance under paragraph (1), and at least once every 90 days thereafter for so long as such end strength is outside such variance. Each such notification shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida743916d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/g/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Modified projected end strengths for active and reserve components of the armed force or forces for which such Secretary exceeds such variance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida743916e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/g/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> An identification of any budgetary effects projected as a result of such modified end strength projections.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida743916f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/g/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> An explanation of any effects on readiness resulting from such modified end strength projections.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7439170-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Adjustment When Coast Guard is Operating as a Service in the Navy</inline>.—</heading><content>The authorized strength of the Navy under subsection (a)(1) is increased by the authorized strength of the Coast Guard during any period when the Coast Guard is operating as a service in the Navy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7439171-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certain Personnel Excluded From Counting for Active-Duty End Strengths</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In counting personnel for the purpose of the end strengths authorized pursuant to subsection (a)(1), persons in the following categories shall be excluded:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439172-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Members of a reserve component ordered to active duty under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12301/a">section 12301(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439173-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Members of a reserve component in an active status ordered to active duty under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12301/b">section 12301(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439174-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Members of the Ready Reserve ordered to active duty under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12302">section 12302 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439175-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/i/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Members of the Selected Reserve of the Ready Reserve or members of the Individual Ready Reserve mobilization category described in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s10144/b">section 10144(b) of this title</ref> ordered to active duty under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12304">section 12304 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439176-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/i/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Members of the National Guard called into Federal service under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12406">section 12406 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439177-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/i/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Members of the militia called into Federal service under chapter 13 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439178-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/i/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Members of the National Guard on full-time National Guard duty under <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s502/f/1/A">section 502(f)(1)(A) of title 32</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7439179-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/i/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> Members of reserve components on active duty for training or full-time National Guard duty for training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida743917a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/i/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> Members of the Selected Reserve of the Ready Reserve on active duty to support programs described in section 1321(a) of the Department of Defense Cooperative Threat Reduction Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3711/a">50 U.S.C. 3711(a)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida743917b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/i/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> Members of the National Guard on active duty or full-time National Guard duty for the purpose of carrying out drug interdiction and counter-drug activities under <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s112">section 112 of title 32</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida743917c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/i/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> Members of a reserve component on active duty under section 10(b)(2) of the Military Selective Service Act (50 U.S.C. App. 460(b)(2)) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002000">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002000"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> for the administration of the Selective Service System.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida743917d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/i/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> Members of the National Guard on full-time National Guard duty for the purpose of providing command, administrative, training, or support services for the National Guard Challenge Program authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s509">section 509 of title 32</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida743917e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s115/i/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> Members of the National Guard on full-time National Guard duty involuntarily and performing homeland defense activities under chapter 9 of title 32.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida743917f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXIV/s1483/a">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1483(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1710">104 Stat. 1710</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/dA/tIII/s312/a">Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title III, § 312(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1335">105 Stat. 1335</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tIV">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title IV</ref>, §§ 401(c), 415, title V, § 513(a)(1), title X, § 1061(c), title XV, § 1501(c)(3), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/286">110 Stat. 286</ref>, 288, 305, 442, 498; <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tIV/s413/b">Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title IV, § 413(b)</ref>, title V, § 522(i)(1), <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1720">111 Stat. 1720</ref>, 1736; <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tIV/s415">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title IV, § 415</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/587">113 Stat. 587</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title IV, § 422], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–96; <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tIV">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title IV</ref>, §§ 421(a), 422, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1076">115 Stat. 1076</ref>, 1077; <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tIV/s403">Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2525">116 Stat. 2525</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tIV/s403/a">Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IV, § 403(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1450">117 Stat. 1450</ref>, 1451; <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/dA/tIV/s416/a">Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title IV, § 416(a)</ref>–(d), title V, § 512(b), <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1866">118 Stat. 1866</ref>, 1867, 1880; <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tX/s1071/a/1">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1071(a)(1)</ref>, (g)(1)(A), <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2398">120 Stat. 2398</ref>, 2402; <ref href="/us/pl/110/181/dA/tIV">Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title IV</ref>, §§ 416(b), 417, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/91">122 Stat. 91</ref>, 92; <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/dA/tIV/s418">Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title IV, § 418</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2268">123 Stat. 2268</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tIV/s416">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title IV, § 416</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2093">130 Stat. 2093</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tX/s1081/a/2">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1594">131 Stat. 1594</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tXII/s1204/a/4">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1204(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/2017">132 Stat. 2017</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tIV/s415/a">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IV, § 415(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3558">134 Stat. 3558</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tIV/s415">Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title IV, § 415</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1675">135 Stat. 1675</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tIV/s402/b">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title IV, § 402(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2551">136 Stat. 2551</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tIV/s402">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/235">137 Stat. 235</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tIV/s402/a">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>–(c)(2), <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1862">138 Stat. 1862</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida7439180-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I84" topic="prospectiveAmendment" id="ida7439181-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered fontsize8 smallCaps">Amendment of Section</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tIV/s402/c">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title IV, § 402(c)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1862">138 Stat. 1862</ref>, provided that, effective upon the date specified under paragraph (2) of <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s1736/a">section 1736(a) of Pub. L. 118–31</ref> (set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s20001">section 20001 of this title</ref>) for the expiration of the authority provided by paragraph (1) of that section, this section is amended as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(1) in subsection (f)—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(A) in the subsection heading, by striking “and Selected Reserve” and inserting “, Selected Reserve, and Space Force”; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(B) in paragraph (1), by striking “subsection (a)(1)(A)” and inserting “paragraph (1)(A) or (3) of subsection (a)”; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(2) in subsection (g)—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(A) in the subsection heading, by striking “and Selected Reserve” and inserting “, Selected Reserve, and Space Force”; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(B) in paragraph (1)(A), by striking “subsection (a)(1)(A)” and inserting “paragraph (1)(A) or (3) of subsection (a)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">See 2024 Amendment notes below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida7439182-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="ida7439183-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 10(b)(2) of the Military Selective Service Act, referred to in subsec. (i)(11), was classified to section 460(b)(2) of the former Appendix to Title 50, War and National Defense, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3809/b/2">section 3809(b)(2) of Title 50</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="ida7439184-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 115, added <ref href="/us/pl/93/155/tVIII/s803/a">Pub. L. 93–155, title VIII, § 803(a)</ref>, <date date="1973-11-16">Nov. 16, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/612">87 Stat. 612</ref>, § 138(b)–(d); amended <ref href="/us/pl/94/361/tIII/s302">Pub. L. 94–361, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1976-07-14">July 14, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/924">90 Stat. 924</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/107/tIII/s303/b">Pub. L. 96–107, title III, § 303(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-11-09">Nov. 9, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/806">93 Stat. 806</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/513/tI/s102">Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2840">94 Stat. 2840</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/22/s2/b">Pub. L. 97–22, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1981-07-10">July 10, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/124">95 Stat. 124</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/86/tIX">Pub. L. 97–86, title IX</ref>, §§ 902, 903, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1113">95 Stat. 1113</ref>, 1114; <ref href="/us/pl/97/252/tIV/s402/a">Pub. L. 97–252, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-08">Sept. 8, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/725">96 Stat. 725</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/295/s1/3">Pub. L. 97–295, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1982-10-12">Oct. 12, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1289">96 Stat. 1289</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/145/tXII/s1208">Pub. L. 99–145, title XII, § 1208</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/723">99 Stat. 723</ref>; renumbered § 115, <ref href="/us/pl/99/433/tI">Pub. L. 99–433, title I</ref>, §§ 101(a)(2), 110(b)(4), (5), <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/994">100 Stat. 994</ref>, 1002; <ref href="/us/pl/99/661/dA/tIV">Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title IV</ref>, §§ 411(c) [(d)], 413, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3861">100 Stat. 3861</ref>, 3862; <ref href="/us/pl/100/26/s7/j/2">Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(j)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/283">101 Stat. 283</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/456/dA/tVI/s641">Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title VI, § 641</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1987">102 Stat. 1987</ref>, related to annual authorization of personnel strengths and annual manpower requirements reports, prior to repeal and reenactment as sections 115, 115a, 115b [now 10541], 123a, and 129a of this title by <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s1483/a">Pub. L. 101–510, § 1483(a)</ref>, (b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida7439185-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s402/a/2/A">Pub. L. 118–159, § 402(a)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “, Selected Reserve, and Space Force” for “and Selected Reserve” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s402/a/2/B">Pub. L. 118–159, § 402(a)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Marine Corps” for “each of the armed forces (other than the Coast Guard)” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s402/a/1">Pub. L. 118–159, § 402(a)(1)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s402/b">Pub. L. 118–159, § 402(b)</ref>, added par. (3) and redesignated former par. (3) as (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s402/c/1/A">Pub. L. 118–159, § 402(c)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “, Selected Reserve, and Space Force” for “and Selected Reserve” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s402/c/1/B">Pub. L. 118–159, § 402(c)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “paragraph (1)(A) or (3) of subsection (a)” for “subsection (a)(1)(A)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s402/c/2/A">Pub. L. 118–159, § 402(c)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “, Selected Reserve, and Space Force” for “and Selected Reserve” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s402/c/2/B">Pub. L. 118–159, § 402(c)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “paragraph (1)(A) or (3) of subsection (a)” for “subsection (a)(1)(A)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2023—Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s402/1">Pub. L. 118–31, § 402(1)</ref>, substituted “not more than 3 percent” for “not more than 2 percent”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s402/2">Pub. L. 118–31, § 402(2)</ref>, added subpars. (A) to (C) and struck out former subpars. (A) and (B) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(A) vary the end strength pursuant to subsection (a)(1)(A) for a fiscal year for the armed force or forces under the jurisdiction of that Secretary by a number not equal to more than two percent of such authorized end strength; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) vary the end strength pursuant to subsection (a)(2) for a fiscal year for the Selected Reserve of the reserve component of the armed force or forces under the jurisdiction of that Secretary by a number equal to not more than one percent of such authorized end strength.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s402/b/1">Pub. L. 117–263, § 402(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “vary” for “increase” in pars. (1), (2), and (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1)(A), (B). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s402/b/2/A">Pub. L. 117–263, § 402(b)(2)(A)</ref>, added subpars. (A) and (B) and struck out former subpars. (A) and (B) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(A) increase the end strength authorized pursuant to subsection (a)(1)(A) for a fiscal year for the armed force under the jurisdiction of that Secretary or, in the case of the Secretary of the Navy, for any of the armed forces under the jurisdiction of that Secretary, by a number equal to not more than 2 percent of such authorized end strength; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) increase the end strength authorized pursuant to subsection (a)(2) for a fiscal year for the Selected Reserve of the reserve component of the armed force under the jurisdiction of that Secretary or, in the case of the Secretary of the Navy, for the Selected Reserve of the reserve component of any of the armed forces under the jurisdiction of that Secretary, by a number equal to not more than 2 percent of such authorized end strength.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s402/b/2/B">Pub. L. 117–263, § 402(b)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “variance” for “increase” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s402/b/2/C">Pub. L. 117–263, § 402(b)(2)(C)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (b)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81">Pub. L. 117–81</ref> substituted “1825 days in the previous 2190 days” for “1095 days in the previous 1460 days”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s415/a/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 415(a)(2)</ref>, which directed substitution of “the minimum end strength for non-temporary military technicians (dual status), and the end strength for temporary military technicians (dual status), requested” for “the end strength requested for military technicians (dual status)” in the third sentence, was executed in the fourth sentence, to reflect to the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s415/a/1">Pub. L. 116–283, § 415(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “both the minimum end strength for non-temporary military technicians (dual status) and the end strength for temporary military technicians (dual status)” for “the end strength for military technicians (dual status)” in the first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (i)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232">Pub. L. 115–232</ref> substituted “chapter 13” for “chapter 15”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—Subsec. (i)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91">Pub. L. 115–91</ref> substituted “section 1321(a) of the Department of Defense Cooperative Threat Reduction Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3711/a">50 U.S.C. 3711(a)</ref>)” for “section 1203(b) of the Cooperative Threat Reduction Act of 1993 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s5952/b">22 U.S.C. 5952(b)</ref>)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (b)(1)(B), (C). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s416/1">Pub. L. 114–328, § 416(1)</ref>, substituted “502(f)(1)(B)” for “502(f)(2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s416/2">Pub. L. 114–328, § 416(2)</ref>, substituted “502(f)(1)(A)” for “502(f)(1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/111/84">Pub. L. 111–84</ref> amended subsec. (g) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (g) related to authority for service secretary variances for active-duty end strengths.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/110/181/s416/b">Pub. L. 110–181, § 416(b)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/110/181/s417">Pub. L. 110–181, § 417</ref>, substituted “3 percent” for “2 percent”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s1071/g/1/A">Pub. L. 109–364, § 1071(g)(1)(A)</ref>, made technical correction to directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s416/a/1">Pub. L. 108–375, § 416(a)(1)</ref>. See 2004 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s1071/a/1/A">Pub. L. 109–364, § 1071(a)(1)(A)</ref>, struck out heading and text of subsec. (i) enacted by <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s512/b">Pub. L. 108–375, § 512(b)</ref>. Text read as follows: “In counting full-time National Guard duty personnel for the purpose of end-strengths authorized pursuant to subsection (a)(1), persons involuntarily performing homeland defense activities under chapter 9 of title 32 shall be excluded.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(13). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s1071/a/1/B">Pub. L. 109–364, § 1071(a)(1)(B)</ref>, added par. (13).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s416/a/1">Pub. L. 108–375, § 416(a)(1)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s1071/g/1/A">Pub. L. 109–364, § 1071(g)(1)(A)</ref>, inserted “unless on active duty pursuant to subsection (b)” after “funds appropriated for active-duty personnel”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s416/a/2">Pub. L. 108–375, § 416(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “unless on active duty or full-time National Guard duty pursuant to subsection (b)” after “reserve personnel”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s416/a/4">Pub. L. 108–375, § 416(a)(4)</ref>, added subsec. (b). Former subsec. (b) redesignated (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s416/a/3">Pub. L. 108–375, § 416(a)(3)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (b) as (c). Former subsec. (c) redesignated (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s416/b">Pub. L. 108–375, § 416(b)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s416/a/3">Pub. L. 108–375, § 416(a)(3)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (c) as (d). Former subsec. (d) redesignated (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s416/a/3">Pub. L. 108–375, § 416(a)(3)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (d) as (e). Former subsec. (e) redesignated (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s416/d/1/A">Pub. L. 108–375, § 416(d)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “subsection (a) or (d)” for “subsection (a) or (c)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s416/d/1/B">Pub. L. 108–375, § 416(d)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “subsections (a) and (d)” for “subsections (a) and (c)” in subpar. (A) and substituted “pursuant to subsection (f)) and subsection (d)” for “pursuant to subsection (e)) and subsection (c)” in subpars. (A) and (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s416/c/1">Pub. L. 108–375, § 416(c)(1)</ref>, struck out “End” after “Reserve” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s416/a/3">Pub. L. 108–375, § 416(a)(3)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (e) as (f). Former subsec. (f) redesignated (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s416/c/2">Pub. L. 108–375, § 416(c)(2)</ref>–(4), added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s416/a/3">Pub. L. 108–375, § 416(a)(3)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (f) as (g). Former subsec. (g) redesignated (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s416/d/2">Pub. L. 108–375, § 416(d)(2)</ref>, substituted “subsection (f)(1)” for “subsection (e)(1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s416/a/3">Pub. L. 108–375, § 416(a)(3)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (g) as (h). Former subsec. (h) redesignated (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s512/b">Pub. L. 108–375, § 512(b)</ref>, added subsec. (i) relating to certain full-time National Guard duty personnel excluded from counting for full-time National Guard duty end strengths.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s416/d/3">Pub. L. 108–375, § 416(d)(3)</ref>, amended heading and text of subsec. (i) generally, substituting provisions relating to 12 categories of personnel excluded from counting for active-duty end strengths for provisions relating to 11 categories of active-duty personnel excluded from counting for active-duty end strengths.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s416/a/3">Pub. L. 108–375, § 416(a)(3)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (h) as (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsecs. (a), (b). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/s403/b/1">Pub. L. 108–136, § 403(b)(1)</ref>, (2), inserted headings.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/s403/a/1">Pub. L. 108–136, § 403(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(3), redesignated subsec. (g) as (c), transferred it to appear after subsec. (b), and inserted heading. Former subsec. (c) redesignated (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/s403/a/3">Pub. L. 108–136, § 403(a)(3)</ref>, added subsec. (d). Former subsec. (d) redesignated (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/s403/a/1">Pub. L. 108–136, § 403(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(4), redesignated subsec. (c) as (e), transferred it to appear after subsec. (d), and inserted heading. Former subsec. (e) redesignated (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/s403/b/5">Pub. L. 108–136, § 403(b)(5)</ref>, inserted heading and, in par. (2), substituted “subsection (e)(1)” for “subsection (c)(1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/s403/a/1">Pub. L. 108–136, § 403(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(6), redesignated subsec. (e) as (g), transferred it to appear after subsec. (f), and inserted heading. Former subsec. (g) redesignated (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/s403/a/2">Pub. L. 108–136, § 403(a)(2)</ref>, (b)(7), redesignated subsec. (d) as (h), transferred it to appear at end of section, and inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s403/a">Pub. L. 107–314, § 403(a)</ref>, substituted “3 percent” for “2 percent”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s403/b">Pub. L. 107–314, § 403(b)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/s421/a">Pub. L. 107–107, § 421(a)</ref>, substituted “2 percent” for “1 percent”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(10), (11). <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/s422">Pub. L. 107–107, § 422</ref>, added pars. (10) and (11).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (d)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/106/398">Pub. L. 106–398</ref> added par. (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/106/65">Pub. L. 106–65</ref> added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s522/i/1">Pub. L. 105–85, § 522(i)(1)</ref>, inserted “(dual status)” after “military technicians” in first sentence and after “military technician” in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s413/b">Pub. L. 105–85, § 413(b)</ref>, inserted at end “In each budget submitted by the President to Congress under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105">section 1105 of title 31</ref>, the end strength requested for military technicians (dual status) for each reserve component of the Army and Air Force shall be specifically set forth.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1061/c/1">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1061(c)(1)</ref>, struck out par. (3) which read as follows: “The average military training student loads for each of the armed forces (other than the Coast Guard).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1061/c/2">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1061(c)(2)</ref>, inserted “or” at end of par. (1), substituted a period for “; or” at end of par. (2), and struck out par. (3) which read as follows: “training military personnel in the training categories described in subsection (f) of any of the armed forces (other than the Coast Guard) unless the average student load of that armed force for that fiscal year has been authorized by law.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s401/c">Pub. L. 104–106, § 401(c)</ref>, substituted “1 percent” for “0.5 percent”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1501/c/3/A">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1501(c)(3)(A)</ref>, substituted “section 12302” for “section 673”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1501/c/3/B">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1501(c)(3)(B)</ref>, substituted “section 12304” for “section 673b”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1501/c/3/C">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1501(c)(3)(C)</ref>, substituted “section 12406” for “section 3500 or 8500”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s415">Pub. L. 104–106, § 415</ref>, added par. (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1061/c/3">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1061(c)(3)</ref>, struck out subsec. (f) which read as follows: “Authorization under subsection (a)(3) is not required for unit or crew training student loads, but is required for student loads for the following individual training categories:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) Recruit and specialized training.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) Flight training.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(3) Professional training in military and civilian institutions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(4) Officer acquisition training.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s513/a/1">Pub. L. 104–106, § 513(a)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/s312/a/1">Pub. L. 102–190, § 312(a)(1)</ref>, struck out par. (4) which read as follows: “The end strength for civilian personnel for each component of the Department of Defense.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2) to (4). <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/s312/a/2">Pub. L. 102–190, § 312(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “or” at end of par. (2), substituted a period for “; or” at end of par. (3), and struck out par. (4) which read as follows: “the use of the civilian personnel of any component of the Department of Defense unless the end strength for civilian personnel of that component for that fiscal year has been authorized by law.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida7460286-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida7460287-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2024 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tIV/s402/c/3">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title IV, § 402(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1862">138 Stat. 1862</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tIV/s402/c/3">“The amendments made by paragraphs (1) and (2) [amending this section] shall take effect upon the date specified under paragraph (2) of section 1736(a) of the Space Force Personnel Management Act (title XVII of <ref href="/us/pl/118/31">Public Law 118–31</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/137/677">137 Stat. 677</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s20001">10 U.S.C. 20001</ref> note] for the expiration of the authority provided by paragraph (1) of that section.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida7460288-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tIV/s415/b">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IV, § 415(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3558">134 Stat. 3558</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tIV/s415/b">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect on the day after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>]. The amendment made by subsection (a)(2) shall apply with respect to budgets submitted by the President to Congress under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105">section 1105 of title 31</ref>, United States Code, after such effective date.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida7460289-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2006 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tX/s1071/g">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1071(g)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2402">120 Stat. 2402</ref>, provided that the amendment made by section 1071(g)(1)(A) is effective as of <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, and as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/108/375">Pub. L. 108–375</ref> as enacted.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida746028a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2003 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tIV/s403/d">Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IV, § 403(d)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1452">117 Stat. 1452</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tIV/s403/d">“Subsection (d) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s115">section 115 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)(3), shall apply with respect to the budget request for fiscal year 2005 and thereafter.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida746028b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tV/s513/a/2">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 513(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/305">110 Stat. 305</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tV/s513/a/2">“The amendment made by paragraph (1) [amending this section] does not apply with respect to fiscal year 1995.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tXV/s1501/c">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/498">110 Stat. 498</ref>, provided that the amendment made by that section is effective as of <date date="1994-12-01">Dec. 1, 1994</date>, and as if included as an amendment made by the Reserve Officer Personnel Management Act, title XVI of <ref href="/us/pl/103/337">Pub. L. 103–337</ref>, as originally enacted.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida746028c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/375/dA/tIV/s416/m">Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title IV, § 416(m)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1869">118 Stat. 1869</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/375/dA/tIV/s416/m">“The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe by regulation the meaning of the term ‘operational support’ for purposes of paragraph (1) of subsection (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s115">section 115 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="ida746028d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida746028e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Additional Authority for Increases of Army Active Duty Personnel End Strengths for Fiscal Years 2008 and 2009</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/375/dA/tIV/s403">Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1863">118 Stat. 1863</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tIV/s403">Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3219">119 Stat. 3219</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tIV/s403">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2169">120 Stat. 2169</ref>, which authorized the Secretary of Defense, for each of fiscal years 2008 and 2009, to establish the active-duty end strengths for the Army and the Marine Corps at numbers greater than the numbers otherwise authorized by law up to the numbers equal to the fiscal-year 2007 baseline plus 20,000 with respect to the Army and plus 4,000 with respect to the Marine Corps, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/110/181/dA/tIV/s403/h">Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title IV, § 403(h)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/87">122 Stat. 87</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida746028f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Authorization for Increase in Active-Duty End Strengths for Fiscal Year 1996</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tIV/s432">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title IV, § 432</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/290">110 Stat. 290</ref>, authorized $112,000,000 to be appropriated to the Department of Defense for fiscal year 1996 to increase the number of active-component military personnel for that fiscal year and provided that end-strength authorizations would each be deemed to be increased as necessary.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7460290-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">End Strengths for Military Technicians (Dual Status)</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tIV/s413">Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title IV, § 413</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3221">119 Stat. 3221</ref>, which authorized the minimum number of military technicians (dual status) as of the last day of a fiscal year for each of the reserve components of the Army and the Air Force, was from the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2006 and was repeated in provisions of subsequent authorization acts which are not set out in the Code. Similar provisions were contained in the following prior authorization acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/375/dA/tIV/s413">Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title IV, § 413</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1865">118 Stat. 1865</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tIV/s413">Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IV, § 413</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1453">117 Stat. 1453</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tIV/s413">Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title IV, § 413</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2527">116 Stat. 2527</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tIV/s413">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title IV, § 413</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1070">115 Stat. 1070</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title IV, § 413], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–93.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tIV/s413">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title IV, § 413</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/586">113 Stat. 586</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/261/dA/tIV/s413">Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title IV, § 413</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1997">112 Stat. 1997</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tIV/s413/a">Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title IV, § 413(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1720">111 Stat. 1720</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tIV/s413/a">Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title IV, § 413(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2507">110 Stat. 2507</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tV/s513/b">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 513(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/305">110 Stat. 305</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7460291-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Comptroller General Review of Proposed Army End Strength Allocations</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/tV/s552">Pub. L. 104–106, title V, § 552</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/319">110 Stat. 319</ref>, provided that, during fiscal years 1996 through 2001, the Comptroller General was (1) to analyze the plans of the Secretary of the Army for the allocation of assigned active component end strengths for the Army through the requirements process known as Total Army Analysis 2003 and through any subsequent similar requirements process of the Army that was conducted before 2002, (2) to consider whether the proposed active component end strengths and planned allocation of forces for that period was sufficient to implement the national military strategy, and (3) to submit to Congress an annual report by Mar. 1 of each year through 2002 on the Comptroller General’s findings and conclusions, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tV/s595">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 595</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1126">115 Stat. 1126</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7460292-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effect of Reserve Component on Computation of End Strength Limitation for Active Forces for Fiscal Year 1995</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tXIII/s1316/c">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XIII, § 1316(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2899">108 Stat. 2899</ref>, provided that a member of a reserve component who is on active duty under a call or order to active duty for 180 days or more for activities under former <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s168">section 168 of this title</ref> shall not be counted (under subsec. (a)(1) of this section) against the applicable end strength limitation for members of the Armed Forces on active duty for fiscal year 1995 prescribed in <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s401">section 401 of Pub. L. 103–337</ref>, formerly set out below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7460293-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">End Strengths for Active Forces</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3218">119 Stat. 3218</ref>, which authorized specified strengths for Armed Forces active duty personnel as of <date date="2006-09-30">Sept. 30, 2006</date>, and provided that costs for that fiscal year of active duty personnel of the Army and the Marine Corps in excess of specified amounts would be paid out of funds authorized to be appropriated for that fiscal year for a contingent emergency reserve fund or as an emergency supplemental appropriation, was from the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2006 and was repeated in provisions of subsequent authorization acts which are not set out in the Code. Similar provisions were contained in the following prior authorization acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/375/dA/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1862">118 Stat. 1862</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1450">117 Stat. 1450</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2524">116 Stat. 2524</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1069">115 Stat. 1069</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title IV, § 401], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–92.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/585">113 Stat. 585</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/261/dA/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1995">112 Stat. 1995</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1719">111 Stat. 1719</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2503">110 Stat. 2503</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tIV/s401/a">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/285">110 Stat. 285</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2743">108 Stat. 2743</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tIV">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title IV</ref>, §§ 401, 403, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1639">107 Stat. 1639</ref>, 1640.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dA/tIV">Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title IV</ref>, §§ 401, 402, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2397">106 Stat. 2397</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/190/dA/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title IV, § 401</ref>, title VI, § 664, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1349">105 Stat. 1349</ref>, 1399.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tIV">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title IV</ref>, §§ 401, 402, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1543">104 Stat. 1543</ref>, 1544; <ref href="/us/pl/102/25/tII">Pub. L. 102–25, title II</ref>, §§ 201(a), 202, 205(a), <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/79">105 Stat. 79</ref>, 80; <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tXV/s1502/c/4/A">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(c)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/507">110 Stat. 507</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1431">103 Stat. 1431</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tIV/s401/d">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title IV, § 401(d)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1544">104 Stat. 1544</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/456/dA/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1963">102 Stat. 1963</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/180/dA/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1081">101 Stat. 1081</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/661/dA/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3859">100 Stat. 3859</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/145/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 99–145, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/618">99 Stat. 618</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/525/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 98–525, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2516">98 Stat. 2516</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/94/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 98–94, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/629">97 Stat. 629</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/97/252/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 97–252, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1982-09-08">Sept. 8, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/725">96 Stat. 725</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/97/86/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 97–86, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1104">95 Stat. 1104</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/97/252/tIX/s903">Pub. L. 97–252, title IX, § 903</ref>, <date date="1982-09-08">Sept. 8, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/729">96 Stat. 729</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/96/342/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 96–342, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1980-09-08">Sept. 8, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1082">94 Stat. 1082</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/97/39/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 97–39, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1981-08-14">Aug. 14, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/940">95 Stat. 940</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/96/107/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 96–107, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1979-11-09">Nov. 9, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/806">93 Stat. 806</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/485/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 95–485, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1978-10-20">Oct. 20, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1613">92 Stat. 1613</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/79/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 95–79, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1977-07-30">July 30, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/326">91 Stat. 326</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/94/361/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 94–361, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1976-07-14">July 14, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/924">90 Stat. 924</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/94/106/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 94–106, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1975-10-07">Oct. 7, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/532">89 Stat. 532</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/93/365/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 93–365, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1974-08-05">Aug. 5, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/401">88 Stat. 401</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/93/155/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 93–155, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1973-11-16">Nov. 16, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/607">87 Stat. 607</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/92/436/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 92–436, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1972-09-26">Sept. 26, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/735">86 Stat. 735</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7460294-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Minimum Number of Navy Health Professions Officers</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/190/dA/tVII/s718/b">Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title VII, § 718(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1404">105 Stat. 1404</ref>, provided that, of the total number of officers authorized to be serving on active duty in Navy on last day of a fiscal year, 12,510 were to be available only for assignment to duties in health profession specialties, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tV/s564/d/2">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 564(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/327">110 Stat. 327</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7460295-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Limitations on Reductions in Medical Personnel</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tVII/s711">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title VII, § 711</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1582">104 Stat. 1582</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/dA/tVII/s718/a">Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title VII, § 718(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1404">105 Stat. 1404</ref>, prohibited Secretary of Defense from reducing number of medical personnel of Department of Defense below baseline number unless Secretary certified to Congress that number of such personnel being reduced was excess to current and projected needs of military departments, and such reduction would not result in increase in cost of health care services provided under Civilian Health and Medical Program of the Uniformed Services, and, in case of military medical personnel, included in certification information on strength levels for individual category of medical personnel involved in reduction as of <date date="1989-09-30">Sept. 30, 1989</date>, projected requirements of Department over 5-fiscal year period following fiscal year in which certification was submitted for medical personnel in category of medical personnel involved, and strength level recommended for each component of Armed Forces for most recent fiscal year for which Secretary submitted recommendations pursuant to former <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s115a/g/1">section 115a(g)(1) of this title</ref> for personnel in category of medical personnel involved, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tV/s564/d/1">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 564(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/327">110 Stat. 327</ref>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s129c">section 129c of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7460296-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Operation Desert Shield Increase in End Strengths of Active Duty Personnel; Authority; Certification</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXI/s1117">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XI, § 1117</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1637">104 Stat. 1637</ref>, authorized Secretary of Defense, after determining that operational requirements of Operation Desert Shield so require, to increase the end strengths of active duty personnel for fiscal year 1991 by an amount not greater than 0.5 percent of the total end strengths authorized by <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s401">section 401 of Pub. L. 101–510</ref>, set out above, and required certification by Secretary to Committees on Armed Services of Senate and House of Representatives of necessity of such increase, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/102/25/tII/s204">Pub. L. 102–25, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/80">105 Stat. 80</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
