<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida8a963a5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174"><num value="1174">§ 1174.</num><heading> Separation pay upon involuntary discharge or release from active duty</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963a6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regular Officers</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963a7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A regular officer who is discharged under chapter 36 of this title (except under section 630(1)(A) or 643 of such chapter) or under section 580 or 8372 of this title and who has completed six or more, but less than twenty, years of active service immediately before that discharge is entitled to separation pay computed under subsection (d)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963a8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A regular commissioned officer of the Army, Navy, Air Force or Marine Corps who is discharged under section 630(1)(A), 643, or 1186 of this title, and a regular warrant officer of the Army, Navy, Air Force or Marine Corps who is separated under section 1165 or 1166 of this title, who has completed six or more, but less than twenty, years of active service immediately before that discharge or separation is entitled to separation pay computed under subsection (d)(1) or (d)(2), as determined by the Secretary of the military department concerned, unless the Secretary concerned determines that the conditions under which the officer is discharged or separated do not warrant payment of such pay.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963a9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2), an officer discharged under any provision of chapter 36 of this title for twice failing of selection for promotion to the next higher grade is not entitled to separation pay under this section if either (or both) of those failures of selection for promotion was by the action of a selection board to which the officer submitted a request in writing not to be selected for promotion or who otherwise directly caused his nonselection through written communication to the Board under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s614/b">section 614(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963aa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2), an officer who is subject to discharge under any provision of chapter 36 of this title or under section 580 or 8372 of this title by reason of having twice failed of selection for promotion to the next higher grade is not entitled to separation pay under this section if that officer, after such second failure of selection for promotion, is selected for, and declines, continuation on active duty for a period that is equal to or more than the amount of service required to qualify the officer for retirement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963ab-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regular Enlisted Members</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963ac-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A regular enlisted member of an armed force who is discharged involuntarily or as the result of the denial of the reenlistment of the member and who has completed six or more, but less than 20, years of active service immediately before that discharge is entitled to separation pay computed under subsection (d) unless the Secretary concerned determines that the conditions under which the member is discharged do not warrant payment of such pay.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963ad-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Separation pay of an enlisted member shall be computed under paragraph (1) of subsection (d), except that such pay shall be computed under paragraph (2) of such subsection in the case of a member who is discharged under criteria prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963ae-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other Members</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963af-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), a member of an armed force other than a regular member who is discharged or released from active duty and who has completed six or more, but fewer than 20, years of active service immediately before that discharge or release is entitled to separation pay computed under subsection (d)(1) or (d)(2), as determined by the Secretary concerned, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8a963b0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the member’s discharge or release from active duty is involuntary; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8a963b1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the member was not accepted for an additional tour of active duty for which he volunteered.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963b2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If the Secretary concerned determines that the conditions under which a member described in paragraph (1) is discharged or separated do not warrant separation pay under this section, that member is not entitled to that pay.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963b3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A member described in paragraph (1) who was not on the active-duty list when discharged or separated is not entitled to separation pay under this section unless such member had completed at least six years of continuous active duty immediately before such discharge or release. For purposes of this paragraph, a period of active duty is continuous if it is not interrupted by a break in service of more than 30 days.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963b4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> In the case of an officer who is subject to discharge or release from active duty under a law or regulation requiring that an officer who has failed of selection for promotion to the next higher grade for the second time be discharged or released from active duty and who, after such second failure of selection for promotion, is selected for, and declines, continuation on active duty—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8a963b5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> if the period of time for which the officer was selected for continuation on active duty is less than the amount of service that would be required to qualify the officer for retirement, the officer’s discharge or release from active duty shall be considered to be involuntary for purposes of paragraph (1)(A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8a963b6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if the period of time for which the officer was selected for continuation on active duty is equal to or more than the amount of service that would be required to qualify the officer for retirement, the officer’s discharge or release from active duty shall not be considered to be involuntary for the purposes of paragraph (1)(A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963b7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Amount of Separation Pay</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The amount of separation pay which may be paid to a member under this section is—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8a963b8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> 10 percent of the product of (A) his years of active service, and (B) 12 times the monthly basic pay to which he was entitled at the time of his discharge or release from active duty; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8a963b9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> one-half of the amount computed under clause (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963ba-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement for Service in Ready Reserve; Exceptions To Eligibility</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963bb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963bc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> As a condition of receiving separation pay under this section, a person otherwise eligible for that pay shall be required to enter into a written agreement with the Secretary concerned to serve in the Ready Reserve of a reserve component for a period of not less than three years following the person’s discharge or release from active duty. If the person has a service obligation under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s651">section 651 of this title</ref> or under any other provision of law that is not completed at the time the person is discharged or released from active duty, the three-year obligation under this subsection shall begin on the day after the date on which the person completes the person’s obligation under such section or other provision of law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963bd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Each person who enters into an agreement referred to in subparagraph (A) who is not already a Reserve of an armed force and who is qualified shall, upon such person’s discharge or release from active duty, be enlisted or appointed, as appropriate, as a Reserve and be transferred to a reserve component.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963be-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> A member who is discharged or released from active duty is not eligible for separation pay under this section if the member—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8a963bf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is discharged or released from active duty at his request;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8a963c0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is discharged or released from active duty during an initial term of enlistment or an initial period of obligated service, unless the member is an officer discharged or released under the authority of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s647">section 647 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8a963c1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> is released from active duty for training; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8a963c2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/e/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> upon discharge or release from active duty, is immediately eligible for retired or retainer pay based on his military service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963c3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Counting Fractional Years of Service</inline>.—</heading><content>In determining a member’s years of active service for the purpose of computing separation pay under this section, each full month of service that is in addition to the number of full years of service creditable to the member is counted as one-twelfth of a year and any remaining fractional part of a month is disregarded.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963c4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coordination With Other Separation or Severance Pay Benefits</inline>.—</heading><content>A period for which a member has previously received separation pay under this section or severance pay or readjustment pay under any other provision of law based on service in the armed forces may not be included in determining the years of service that may be counted in computing the separation pay of the member under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963c5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coordination With Retired or Retainer Pay and Disability Compensation</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963c6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A member who has received separation pay under this section, or separation pay, severance pay, or readjustment pay under any other provision of law, based on service in the armed forces, and who later qualifies for retired or retainer pay under this title or title 14 shall have deducted from each payment of such retired or retainer pay an amount, in such schedule of monthly installments as the Secretary of Defense shall specify, taking into account the financial ability of the member to pay and avoiding the imposition of undue financial hardship on the member and member’s dependents, until the total amount deducted is equal to the total amount of separation pay, severance pay, and readjustment pay so paid.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963c7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A member who has received separation pay under this section, or severance pay or readjustment pay under any other provision of law, based on service in the armed forces shall not be deprived, by reason of his receipt of such separation pay, severance pay, or readjustment pay, of any disability compensation to which he is entitled under the laws administered by the Department of Veterans Affairs, but there shall be deducted from that disability compensation an amount equal to the total amount of separation pay, severance pay, and readjustment pay received, less the amount of Federal income tax withheld from such pay (such withholding being at the flat withholding rate for Federal income tax withholding, as in effect pursuant to regulations prescribed under chapter 24 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986). Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, no deduction may be made from disability compensation for the amount of any separation pay, severance pay, or readjustment pay received because of an earlier discharge or release from a period of active duty if the disability which is the basis for that disability compensation was incurred or aggravated during a later period of active duty.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963c8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special Rule for Members Receiving Sole Survivorship Discharge</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963c9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A member of the armed forces who receives a sole survivorship discharge shall be entitled to separation pay under this section even though the member has completed less than six years of active service immediately before that discharge. Subsection (e) shall not apply to a member who receives a sole survivorship discharge.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963ca-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The amount of the separation pay to be paid to a member pursuant to this subsection shall be based on the years of active service actually completed by the member before the member’s sole survivorship discharge.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963cb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> In this subsection, the term “sole survivorship discharge” means the separation of a member from the armed forces, at the request of the member, pursuant to the Department of Defense policy permitting the early separation of a member who is the only surviving child in a family in which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8a963cc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/i/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> the father or mother or one or more siblings—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida8a963cd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/i/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> served in the armed forces; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida8a963ce-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/i/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> was killed, died as a result of wounds, accident, or disease, is in a captured or missing in action status, or is permanently 100 percent disabled or hospitalized on a continuing basis (and is not employed gainfully because of the disability or hospitalization); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8a963cf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/i/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the death, status, or disability did not result from the intentional misconduct or willful neglect of the parent or sibling and was not incurred during a period of unauthorized absence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963d0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations; Crediting of Other Commissioned Service</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963d1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations, which shall be uniform for the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force, for the administration of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8a963d2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1174/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Active commissioned service in the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration or the Public Health Service shall be credited as active service in the armed forces for the purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida8a963d3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/96/513/tI/s109/c">Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 109(c)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2870">94 Stat. 2870</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/97/22/s10/b/10/A">Pub. L. 97–22, § 10(b)(10)(A)</ref>, <date date="1981-07-10">July 10, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/137">95 Stat. 137</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/94/tIX">Pub. L. 98–94, title IX</ref>, §§ 911(a), (b), 923(b), title X, § 1007(c)(2), <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/639">97 Stat. 639</ref>, 640, 643, 662; <ref href="/us/pl/98/498/tIII/s320/a/2">Pub. L. 98–498, title III, § 320(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2308">98 Stat. 2308</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tXVI/s1621/a/1">Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1621(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1602">103 Stat. 1602</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tV/s501/a">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 501(a)</ref>–(d), (g), (h), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1549-1551">104 Stat. 1549–1551</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/dA/tXI/s1131/6">Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1131(6)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1506">105 Stat. 1506</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tV/s501/a">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1644">107 Stat. 1644</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tV/s560/c">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 560(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2778">108 Stat. 2778</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tVI/s653/a">Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title VI, § 653(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2583">110 Stat. 2583</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tX/s1073/a/22">Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(22)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1901">111 Stat. 1901</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/261/dA/tV/s502/a">Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 502(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2003">112 Stat. 2003</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 508(a), (b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–107; <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/dA/tV/s501/c/2">Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 501(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1874">118 Stat. 1874</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/317/s3">Pub. L. 110–317, § 3</ref>, <date date="2008-08-29">Aug. 29, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3527">122 Stat. 3527</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/32/tIII/s318/a">Pub. L. 111–32, title III, § 318(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-06-24">June 24, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1873">123 Stat. 1873</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/dA/tX/s1075/b/17">Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(17)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4370">124 Stat. 4370</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tVIII/s809/a">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1840">132 Stat. 1840</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tIX/s924/b/1/K">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(1)(K)</ref>, (3)(S), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3820">134 Stat. 3820</ref>, 3821; <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tXVII/s1722/i/2">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1722(i)(2)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/673">137 Stat. 673</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida8a963d4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida8a963d5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="ida8a963d6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Chapter 24 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, referred to in subsec. (h)(2), is classified generally to chapter 24 (§ 3401 et seq.) of Title 26, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida8a963d7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2023—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31">Pub. L. 118–31</ref> substituted “or Marine Corps” for “, Marine Corps, or Space Force” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s924/b/3/S">Pub. L. 116–283, § 924(b)(3)(S)</ref>, substituted “Marine Corps, or Space Force” for “or Marine Corps” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s924/b/1/K">Pub. L. 116–283, § 924(b)(1)(K)</ref>, substituted “Marine Corps, and Space Force” for “and Marine Corps”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (a)(1), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232">Pub. L. 115–232</ref> substituted “section 580 or 8372” for “section 580 or 6383”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383">Pub. L. 111–383</ref> substituted “armed forces” for “Armed Forces” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (h)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/32">Pub. L. 111–32</ref> amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “A member who has received separation pay under this section, or separation pay, severance pay, or readjustment pay under any other provision of law, based on service in the armed forces, and who later qualifies for retired or retainer pay under this title or title 14 shall have deducted from each payment of such retired or retainer pay so much of such pay as is based on the service for which he received separation pay under this section or separation pay, severance pay, or readjustment pay under any other provision of law until the total amount deducted is equal to the total amount of separation pay, severance pay, and readjustment pay received.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsecs. (i), (j). <ref href="/us/pl/110/317">Pub. L. 110–317</ref> added subsec. (i) and redesignated former subsec. (i) as (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (e)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375">Pub. L. 108–375</ref> inserted “, unless the member is an officer discharged or released under the authority of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s647">section 647 of this title</ref>” after “obligated service”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 508(a)], added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 508(b)], added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/261">Pub. L. 105–261</ref> added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85">Pub. L. 105–85</ref> struck out “, 1177,” before “or 6383 of this title”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (h)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/201">Pub. L. 104–201</ref> inserted “, less the amount of Federal income tax withheld from such pay (such withholding being at the flat withholding rate for Federal income tax withholding, as in effect pursuant to regulations prescribed under chapter 24 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986)” before period at end of first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/337">Pub. L. 103–337</ref> inserted “, 1177,” after “section 580”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/160">Pub. L. 103–160</ref> substituted “six” for “five”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/190">Pub. L. 102–190</ref> substituted “section 580” for “section 564”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s501/a/1">Pub. L. 101–510, § 501(a)(1)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s501/g/1">Pub. L. 101–510, § 501(g)(1)</ref>, substituted “or under section 564 or 6383 of this title” for “, under section 564 or 6383 of this title, or under section 603 or 604 of the Defense Officer Personnel Management Act” and struck out “or release” after “that discharge”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s501/b/1">Pub. L. 101–510, § 501(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “six or more” for “five or more”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s501/a/2">Pub. L. 101–510, § 501(a)(2)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (b) as subsec. (a)(2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s501/a/3">Pub. L. 101–510, § 501(a)(3)</ref>, added subsec. (b). Former subsec. (b) redesignated (a)(2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s501/h/1">Pub. L. 101–510, § 501(h)(1)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s501/g/2">Pub. L. 101–510, § 501(g)(2)</ref>, struck out “after <date date="1981-09-14">September 14, 1981</date>,” after “member who” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s501/b/1">Pub. L. 101–510, § 501(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “six or more” for “five or more” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s501/b/2">Pub. L. 101–510, § 501(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “at least six years” for “at least five years”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s501/h/2">Pub. L. 101–510, § 501(h)(2)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s501/c/1/A">Pub. L. 101–510, § 501(c)(1)(A)</ref>, struck out “or $30,000, whichever is less” after “active duty”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s501/c/1/B">Pub. L. 101–510, § 501(c)(1)(B)</ref>, struck out “, but in no event more than $15,000” after “under clause (1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s501/d">Pub. L. 101–510, § 501(d)</ref>, amended subsec. (e) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (e) read as follows: “A member who—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) is discharged or released from active duty at his request;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) is released from active duty for training; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(3) upon discharge or release from active duty, is immediately eligible for retired or retainer pay based on his military service;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">is not eligible for separation pay under this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s501/h/3">Pub. L. 101–510, § 501(h)(3)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s501/h/4">Pub. L. 101–510, § 501(h)(4)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s501/c/2">Pub. L. 101–510, § 501(c)(2)</ref>, struck out “(1)” after “(g)” and struck out par. (2) which read as follows: “The total amount that a member may receive in separation pay under this section and severance pay and readjustment pay under any other provision of law, other than <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1212">section 1212 of this title</ref>, based on service in the armed forces may not exceed $30,000.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s501/h/5">Pub. L. 101–510, § 501(h)(5)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s501/h/6">Pub. L. 101–510, § 501(h)(6)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (h)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/189">Pub. L. 101–189</ref> substituted “Department of Veterans Affairs” for “Veterans’ Administration”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (h)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/498">Pub. L. 98–498</ref> substituted “separation pay, severance pay,” for “severance pay” before “or readjustment pay” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/98/94/s911/a">Pub. L. 98–94, § 911(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (c) generally, designating existing provisions as par. (1) and existing pars. (1) and (2) as subpars. (A) and (B), respectively, and in provisions preceding subpar. (A) substituted “Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), a member” for “A member” and “fewer than 20, years of active service immediately before that discharge or release is entitled to separation pay” for “less than twenty, years of active service immediately before that discharge or release is entitled, unless the Secretary concerned determines that the conditions under which the member is discharged or separated do not warrant such pay, to separation pay”, and added pars. (2) and (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/98/94/s923/b">Pub. L. 98–94, § 923(b)</ref>, amended subsec. (f) generally, substituting “each full month of service that is in addition to the number of full years of service creditable to the member is counted as one-twelfth of a year and any remaining fractional part of a month is disregarded” for “a part of a year that is six months or more is counted as a whole year and a part of a year that is less than six months is disregarded”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/94/s911/b">Pub. L. 98–94, § 911(b)</ref>, inserted “, other than <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1212">section 1212 of this title</ref>,” after “any other provision of law”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/98/94/s1007/c/2">Pub. L. 98–94, § 1007(c)(2)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/22">Pub. L. 97–22</ref> substituted “after <date date="1981-09-14">September 14, 1981</date>,” for “on or after the effective date of the Defense Officer Personnel Management Act”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida8a963d8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida8a963d9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2018 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/115/232">Pub. L. 115–232</ref> effective <date date="2019-02-01">Feb. 1, 2019</date>, with provision for the coordination of amendments and special rule for certain redesignations, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s800">section 800 of Pub. L. 115–232</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida8a963da-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2009 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/32/tIII/s318/c">Pub. L. 111–32, title III, § 318(c)</ref>, <date date="2009-06-24">June 24, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1874">123 Stat. 1874</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/32/tIII/s318/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1175">section 1175 of this title</ref>] shall apply to any repayments of separation pay, severance pay, readjustment pay, special separation benefit, or voluntary separation incentive, that occur on or after the date of enactment [<date date="2009-06-24">June 24, 2009</date>], including any ongoing repayment actions that were initiated prior to this amendment.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida8a963db-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/110/317">Pub. L. 110–317</ref> applicable with respect to any sole survivorship discharge granted after <date date="2001-09-11">Sept. 11, 2001</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/317/s10">section 10 of Pub. L. 110–317</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2108">section 2108 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida8a963dc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2004 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/375">Pub. L. 108–375</ref> effective on the first day of the first month beginning more than 180 days after <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s501/g">section 501(g) of Pub. L. 108–375</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s531">section 531 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida8a963dd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2000 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 508(c)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–107, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">“Paragraph (4) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1174/a">section 1174(a) of title 10</ref>, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), and paragraph (4) of section 1174(c) of such title, as added by subsection (b), shall apply with respect to any offer of selective continuation on active duty that is declined on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida8a963de-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/261">Pub. L. 105–261</ref> applicable with respect to selection boards convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s611/a">section 611(a) of this title</ref> on or after <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/261/s502/c">section 502(c) of Pub. L. 105–261</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s617">section 617 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida8a963df-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/178/tVIII/s8208">Pub. L. 105–178, title VIII, § 8208</ref>, <date date="1998-06-09">June 9, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/495">112 Stat. 495</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/178/tVIII/s8208">“The amendment made by section 653 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1997 (<ref href="/us/pl/104/201">Public Law 104–201</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/110/2583">110 Stat. 2583</ref>) to subsection (h)(2) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1174">section 1174 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, shall apply to any payment of separation pay under the special separation benefits program under section 1174a of that title that was made during the period beginning on <date date="1991-12-05">December 5, 1991</date>, and ending on <date date="1996-09-30">September 30, 1996</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tVI/s653/b">Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title VI, § 653(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2583">110 Stat. 2583</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tVI/s653/b">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall take effect on <date date="1996-10-01">October 1, 1996</date>, and shall apply to payments of separation pay, severance pay, or readjustment pay that are made after <date date="1996-09-30">September 30, 1996</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida8a963e0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1993 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tV/s501/b">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 501(b)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1644">107 Stat. 1644</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tV/s501/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to any regular officer who is discharged after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The amendment made by subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to an officer who on the date of the enactment of this Act has five or more, but less than six, years of active service in the Armed Forces.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida8a963e1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1991 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/190">Pub. L. 102–190</ref> effective <date date="1992-02-01">Feb. 1, 1992</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/s1132">section 1132 of Pub. L. 102–190</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s521">section 521 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida8a963e2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tV/s501/e">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 501(e)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1550">104 Stat. 1550</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tV/s501/e">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), subsection (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1174">section 1174 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), and the amendments made by subsections (b), (c), and (d) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to a member of the Armed Forces who is discharged, or released from active duty, after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The amendments made by subsection (b) [amending this section] shall not apply in the case of a member (other than a regular enlisted member) of the Armed Forces who (A) is serving on active duty on the date of the enactment of this Act, (B) is discharged, or released from active duty, after that date; and (C) on that date has five or more, but less than six, years of active service in the Armed Forces.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida8a963e3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1983 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/94/tIX/s911/c">Pub. L. 98–94, title IX, § 911(c)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/640">97 Stat. 640</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/94/tIX/s911/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall take effect on <date date="1983-10-01">October 1, 1983</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/98/94/tIX/s923/g">Pub. L. 98–94, title IX, § 923(g)</ref>, <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/644">97 Stat. 644</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/94/tIX/s923/g">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 1401, 1402, 1402a, 3991, 3992, 6151, 6328, 6330, 6404, 8991, and 8992 of this title, <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s423">section 423 of Title 14</ref>, Coast Guard, section 853<i>o</i> of Title 33, Navigation and Navigable Waters, and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s212">section 212 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare] shall apply with respect to (1) the computation of retired or retainer pay of any individual who becomes entitled to that pay after <date date="1983-09-30">September 30, 1983</date>, and (2) the recomputation of retired pay under section 1402, 1402a, 3992 [now 7362], or 8992 [now 9362] of title 10, United States Code, of any individual who after <date date="1983-09-30">September 30, 1983</date>, becomes entitled to recompute retired pay under any such section.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida8a963e4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/97/22/s10/b">Pub. L. 97–22, § 10(b)</ref>, <date date="1981-07-10">July 10, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/137">95 Stat. 137</ref>, provided that the amendment made by that section is effective <date date="1981-09-15">Sept. 15, 1981</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="ida8a963e5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1981-09-15">Sept. 15, 1981</date>, but the authority to prescribe regulations under this section effective on <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/513/s701">section 701 of Pub. L. 96–513</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1980 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida8a963e6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Transition Provisions Under Defense Officer Personnel Management Act</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions to prevent extinction or premature termination of rights, duties, penalties, or proceedings that existed or were begun prior to the effective date of <ref href="/us/pl/96/513">Pub. L. 96–513</ref> and otherwise to allow for an orderly transition to the system of officer personnel management put in place under <ref href="/us/pl/96/513">Pub. L. 96–513</ref>, see section 601 et seq. of <ref href="/us/pl/96/513">Pub. L. 96–513</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s611">section 611 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
