<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida8abad50-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a"><num value="1175a">§ 1175a.</num><heading> Voluntary separation pay and benefits</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad51-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Under regulations approved by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary concerned may provide voluntary separation pay and benefits in accordance with this section to eligible members of the armed forces who are voluntarily separated from active duty in the armed forces.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad52-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible Members</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad53-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (2), a member of the armed forces is eligible for voluntary separation pay and benefits under this section if the member—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8abad54-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> has served on active duty for more than 6 years but not more than 20 years;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8abad55-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> has served at least 5 years of continuous active duty immediately preceding the date of the member’s separation from active duty;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8abad56-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> has not been approved for payment of a voluntary separation incentive under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1175">section 1175 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8abad57-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> meets such other requirements as the Secretary concerned may prescribe, which may include requirements relating to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida8abad58-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/b/1/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> years of service, skill, rating, military specialty, or competitive category;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida8abad59-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/b/1/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> grade or rank;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida8abad5a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/b/1/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> remaining period of obligated service; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida8abad5b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/b/1/D/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> any combination of these factors; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8abad5c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> requests separation from active duty.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad5d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The following members are not eligible for voluntary separation pay and benefits under this section:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8abad5e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Members discharged with disability severance pay under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1212">section 1212 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8abad5f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Members transferred to the temporary disability retired list under section 1202 or 1205 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8abad60-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Members being evaluated for disability retirement under chapter 61 of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8abad61-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Members who have been previously discharged with voluntary separation pay.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8abad62-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/b/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Members who are subject to pending disciplinary action or who are subject to administrative separation or mandatory discharge under any other provision of law or regulations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad63-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary concerned shall determine each year the number of members to be separated, and provided separation pay and benefits, under this section during the fiscal year beginning in such year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad64-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Separation</inline>.—</heading><content>Each eligible member of the armed forces whose request for separation from active duty under subsection (b)(1)(E) is approved shall be separated from active duty.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad65-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional Service in Ready Reserve</inline>.—</heading><content>Of the number of members of the armed forces to be separated from active duty in a fiscal year, as determined under subsection (b)(3), the Secretary concerned shall determine a number of such members, in such skill and grade combinations as the Secretary concerned shall designate, who shall serve in the Ready Reserve, after separation from active duty, for a period of not less than three years, as a condition of the receipt of voluntary separation pay and benefits under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad66-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Separation Pay and Benefits</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad67-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A member of the armed forces who is separated from active duty under subsection (c) shall be paid voluntary separation pay in accordance with subsection (g) in an amount determined by the Secretary concerned pursuant to subsection (f).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad68-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> A member who is not entitled to retired or retainer pay upon separation shall be entitled to the benefits and services provided under—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8abad69-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> chapter 58 of this title during the 180-day period beginning on the date the member is separated (notwithstanding any termination date for such benefits and services otherwise applicable under the provisions of such chapter); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8abad6a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> sections 452 and 453(c) of title 37.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad6b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Computation of Voluntary Separation Pay</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary concerned shall specify the amount of voluntary separation pay that an individual or defined group of members of the armed forces may be paid under subsection (e)(1). No member may receive as voluntary separation pay an amount greater than four times the full amount of separation pay for a member of the same pay grade and years of service who is involuntarily separated under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1174">section 1174 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad6c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Payment of Voluntary Separation Pay</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad6d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Voluntary separation pay under this section may be paid in a single lump sum.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad6e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> In the case of a member of the armed forces who, at the time of separation under subsection (c), has completed at least 15 years, but less than 20 years, of active service, voluntary separation pay may be paid, at the election of the Secretary concerned, in—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8abad6f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/g/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a single lump sum;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8abad70-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/g/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> installments over a period not to exceed 10 years; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8abad71-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/g/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a combination of lump sum and such installments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad72-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coordination With Retired or Retainer Pay and Disability Compensation</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad73-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A member who is paid voluntary separation pay under this section and who later qualifies for retired or retainer pay under this title or title 14 shall have deducted from each payment of such retired or retainer pay an amount, in such schedule of monthly installments as the Secretary concerned shall specify, until the total amount deducted from such retired or retainer pay is equal to the total amount of voluntary separation pay so paid.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad74-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad75-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C), a member who is paid voluntary separation pay under this section shall not be deprived, by reason of the member’s receipt of such pay, of any disability compensation to which the member is entitled under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, but there shall be deducted from such disability compensation an amount, in such schedule of monthly installments as the Secretary concerned shall specify, until the total amount deducted from such disability compensation is equal to the total amount of voluntary separation pay so paid, less the amount of Federal income tax withheld from such pay (such withholding being at the flat withholding rate for Federal income tax withholding, as in effect pursuant to regulations prescribed under chapter 24 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad76-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> No deduction shall be made from the disability compensation paid to an eligible disabled uniformed services retiree under section 1413, or to an eligible combat-related disabled uniformed services retiree under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1413a">section 1413a of this title</ref>, who is paid voluntary separation pay under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad77-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/h/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> No deduction may be made from the disability compensation paid to a member for the amount of voluntary separation pay received by the member because of an earlier discharge or release from a period of active duty if the disability which is the basis for that disability compensation was incurred or aggravated during a later period of active duty.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad78-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The requirement under this subsection to repay voluntary separation pay following retirement from the armed forces does not apply to a member who was eligible to retire at the time the member applied and was accepted for voluntary separation pay and benefits under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad79-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/h/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Secretary concerned may waive the requirement to repay voluntary separation pay under paragraphs (1) and (2) if the Secretary determines that recovery would be against equity and good conscience or would be contrary to the best interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad7a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Retirement Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term “retirement” includes a transfer to the Fleet Reserve or Fleet Marine Corps Reserve.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad7b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Repayment for Members Who Return to Active Duty</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad7c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraphs (2), (3), and (4), a member of the armed forces who, after having received all or part of voluntary separation pay under this section, returns to active duty shall have deducted from each payment of basic pay, in such schedule of monthly installments as the Secretary concerned shall specify, until the total amount deducted from such basic pay equals the total amount of voluntary separation pay received.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad7d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Members who are involuntarily recalled to active duty or full-time National Guard duty in accordance with section 12301(a), 12301(b), 12301(g), 12302, 12303, 12304, 12304a, or 12304b of this title or <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s502/f/1/A">section 502(f)(1)(A) of title 32</ref> shall not be subject to this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad7e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/j/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Members who are recalled or perform active duty or full-time National Guard duty in accordance with section 101(d)(1), 101(d)(2), 101(d)(5), 12301(d) (insofar as the period served is less than 180 consecutive days with the consent of the member), 12319, or 12503 of this title, or section 114, 115, or 502(f)(1)(B) of title 32 (insofar as the period served is less than 180 consecutive days with consent of the member), shall not be subject to this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad7f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/j/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> This subsection shall not apply to a member who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8abad80-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/j/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is involuntarily recalled to active duty or full-time National Guard duty; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8abad81-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/j/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the course of such duty, incurs a service-connected disability rated as total under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s1155">section 1155 of title 38</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad82-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/j/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense may waive, in whole or in part, repayment required under paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines that recovery would be against equity and good conscience or would be contrary to the best interests of the United States. The authority in this paragraph may be delegated only to the Undersecretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness and the Principal Deputy Undersecretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad83-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination of Authority</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad84-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/k/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The authority to separate a member of the armed forces from active duty under subsection (c) shall terminate on <date date="2030-12-31">December 31, 2030</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8abad85-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1175a/k/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A member who separates by the date specified in paragraph (1) may continue to be provided voluntary separation pay and benefits under this section until the member has received the entire amount of pay and benefits to which the member is entitled under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida8abad86-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tVI/s643/a/1">Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title VI, § 643(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3306">119 Stat. 3306</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tVI/s623/a/1">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title VI, § 623(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2256">120 Stat. 2256</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/dA/tX/s1073/a/14">Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(14)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2473">123 Stat. 2473</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/dA/tX/s1075/b/18">Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(18)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4370">124 Stat. 4370</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/dA/tV/s526">Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 526</ref>, title VI, § 631(f)(4)(A), <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1401">125 Stat. 1401</ref>, 1465; <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dA/tX/s1076/a/9">Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(a)(9)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1948">126 Stat. 1948</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tV">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 508(c), 526, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2109">130 Stat. 2109</ref>, 2117; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tVI/s603">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1423">133 Stat. 1423</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tVI/s626/c/4">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VI, § 626(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2628">136 Stat. 2628</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tVI/s612">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title VI, § 612</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/907">139 Stat. 907</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida8abad87-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida8abad88-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="ida8abad89-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Chapter 24 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, referred to in subsec. (h)(2)(A), is classified generally to chapter 24 (§ 3401 et seq.) of Title 26, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida8abad8a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (k)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60">Pub. L. 119–60</ref> substituted “<date date="2030-12-31">December 31, 2030</date>” for “<date date="2025-12-31">December 31, 2025</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (e)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Pub. L. 117–263</ref> substituted “sections 452 and 453(c)” for “sections 474 and 476”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (j)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s603/1">Pub. L. 116–92, § 603(1)</ref>, substituted “paragraphs (2), (3), and (4)” for “paragraphs (2) and (3)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s603/2">Pub. L. 116–92, § 603(2)</ref>, (3), added par. (4) and redesignated former par. (4) as (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (j)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s526/1">Pub. L. 114–328, § 526(1)</ref>, substituted “12304, 12304a, or 12304b” for “or 12304” and “502(f)(1)(A)” for “502(f)(1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s526/2">Pub. L. 114–328, § 526(2)</ref>, substituted “502(f)(1)(B)” for “502(f)(2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s508/c">Pub. L. 114–328, § 508(c)</ref>, substituted “<date date="2025-12-31">December 31, 2025</date>” for “<date date="2018-12-31">December 31, 2018</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (e)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1076/a/9">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1076(a)(9)</ref>, made technical amendment to directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/s631/f/4/A">Pub. L. 112–81, § 631(f)(4)(A)</ref>. See 2011 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (e)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/s631/f/4/A">Pub. L. 112–81, § 631(f)(4)(A)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1076/a/9">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1076(a)(9)</ref>, substituted “474” for “404” and “476” for “406”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383">Pub. L. 111–383</ref> substituted “this title” for “title 10”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/s526">Pub. L. 112–81, § 526</ref>, substituted “<date date="2018-12-31">December 31, 2018</date>” for “<date date="2012-12-31">December 31, 2012</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (h)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/84">Pub. L. 111–84</ref> substituted “qualifies” for “qualities”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s623/a/1">Pub. L. 109–364, § 623(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “four” for “two”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s623/a/2">Pub. L. 109–364, § 623(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “2012” for “2008”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida8abad8b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida8abad8c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2013 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dA/tX/s1076/a">Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1947">126 Stat. 1947</ref>, provided that the amendment made by section 1076(a)(9) is effective <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, and as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/112/81">Pub. L. 112–81</ref> as enacted.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida8abad8d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Limitation on Applicability</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tVI/s643/b">Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title VI, § 643(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3310">119 Stat. 3310</ref>, which provided that, during the period beginning on <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, and ending on <date date="2008-12-31">Dec. 31, 2008</date>, members eligible for separation and for voluntary separation pay and benefits under this section would be limited to officers who had met the eligibility requirements of this section, but had not completed more than 12 years of active service as of the date of separation, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tVI/s623/a/3">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title VI, § 623(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2256">120 Stat. 2256</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
