<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idab9addc6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207"><num value="12207">§ 12207.</num><heading> Commissioned officers: service credit upon original appointment</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab9addc7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab9addc8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> For the purpose of determining the grade and the rank within grade of a person receiving an original appointment as a reserve commissioned officer (other than a commissioned warrant officer) in the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps, the person shall be credited at the time of the appointment with any commissioned service (other than service as a commissioned warrant officer) performed before such appointment as a regular officer, or as a reserve officer in an active status, in any armed force, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, or the Public Health Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab9addc9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations, which shall apply uniformly among the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Marine Corps, to authorize the Secretary of the military department concerned to limit the amount of prior commissioned service with which a person receiving an original appointment may be credited under paragraph (1), or to deny any such credit, in the case of a person who at the time of such appointment is credited with constructive service under subsection (b) or (e).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab9addca-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab9addcb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, a person who is receiving an original appointment as a reserve commissioned officer (other than a commissioned warrant officer) of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps, and who has special training or experience, or advanced education (if applicable), shall be credited with constructive service for such education, training, or experience, as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab9addcc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> One year for each year of advanced education beyond the baccalaureate degree level, for persons appointed or designated in, or assigned to, officer categories requiring such advanced education or an advanced degree as a prerequisite for such appointment, designation, or assignment. In determining the number of years of constructive service to be credited under this subparagraph to officers in any professional field, the Secretary concerned shall credit an officer with, but with not more than, the number of years of advanced education required by a majority of institutions that award degrees in that professional field for completion of the advanced education or award of the advanced degree.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab9addcd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab9addce-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/b/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Credit for any period of advanced education in a health profession (other than medicine and dentistry) beyond the baccalaureate degree level which exceeds the basic education criteria for such appointment, designation, or assignment, if such advanced education will be directly used by the armed force concerned.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab9addcf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/b/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Credit for experience in a health profession (other than medicine or dentistry), if such experience will be directly used by the armed force concerned.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab9addd0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Additional credit of (i) not more than one year for internship or equivalent graduate medical, dental, or other formal health professional training required by the armed forces, and (ii) not more than one year for each additional year of such graduate-level training or experience creditable toward certification in a speciality required by the armed force concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab9addd1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> Additional credit as follows:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab9addd2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/b/1/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> For special training or experience in a particular officer field as designated by the Secretary concerned, if such training or experience is directly related to the operational needs of the armed force concerned.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab9addd3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/b/1/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> During fiscal years 2021 through 2025, for advanced education in an officer field so designated, if such education is directly related to the operational needs of the armed force concerned.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab9addd4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Additional credit for experience as a physician or dentist, if appointed, assigned, or designated as a medical or dental officer.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab9addd5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab9addd6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> If the Secretary of Defense determines that the number of officers in a health profession described in subparagraph (B) who are serving in an active status in a reserve component of the Army, Navy, or Air Force in grades below major or lieutenant commander is critically below the number needed in such health profession by such reserve component in such grades, the Secretary of Defense may authorize the Secretary of the military department concerned to credit any person who is receiving an original appointment as an officer for service in such health profession with a period of constructive credit in such amount (in addition to any amount credited such person under paragraph (1)) as will result in the grade of such person being that of captain or, in the case of the Navy Reserve, lieutenant.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab9addd7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> The types of health professions referred to in subparagraph (A) include the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab9addd8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/b/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Any health profession performed by officers in the Medical Corps of the Army or the Navy or by officers of the Air Force designated as a medical officer.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab9addd9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/b/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Any health profession performed by officers in the Dental Corps of the Army or the Navy or by officers of the Air Force designated as a dental officer.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab9addda-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/b/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Any health profession performed by officers in the Medical Service Corps of the Army or the Navy or by officers of the Air Force designated as a medical service officer or biomedical sciences officer.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab9adddb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/b/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> Any health profession performed by officers in the Army Medical Specialist Corps.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab9adddc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/b/2/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> Any health profession performed by officers of the Nurse Corps of the Army or the Navy or by officers of the Air Force designated as a nurse.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab9adddd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/b/2/B/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> Any health profession performed by officers in the Veterinary Corps of the Army or by officers designated as a veterinary officer.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab9addde-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The amount of constructive service credit credited to an officer under this subsection may not exceed the amount required in order for the officer to be eligible for an original appointment as a reserve officer of the Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps in the grade of colonel or as a reserve officer of the Navy in the grade of captain.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab9adddf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Constructive service credited an officer under this subsection is in addition to any service credited that officer under subsection (a) and shall be credited at the time of the original appointment of the officer or assignment to or designation in an officer category in which advanced education or training or special experience is required.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab9adde0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> Constructive service may not be credited under subsection (b) for education, training, or experience obtained while serving as a commissioned officer (other than a warrant officer) on active duty or in an active status. However, in the case of an officer who completes advanced education or receives an advanced degree while on active duty or in an active status and in less than the number of years normally required to complete such advanced education or receive such advanced degree, constructive service may, subject to regulations prescribed under subsection (a)(2), be credited to the officer under subsection (b)(1)(A) to the extent that the number of years normally required to complete such advanced education or receive such advanced degree exceeds the actual number of years in which such advanced education or degree is obtained by the officer.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab9adde1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> If the Secretary of Defense determines that the number of qualified judge advocates serving on the active-duty list of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps in grades below lieutenant commander or major is critically below the number needed by that armed force in those grades, the Secretary of Defense may authorize the Secretary of the military department concerned to credit any person who is receiving an original appointment with a view to assignment to the Judge Advocate General’s Corps of the Army or appointment to the Judge Advocate General’s Corps of the Navy, or who is receiving an original appointment in the Air Force or Marine Corps with a view to designation as a judge advocate, with a period of constructive service in such an amount (in addition to any amount credited such person under subsection (b)) as will result in the grade of such person being that of captain or, in the case of the Navy, lieutenant, and the date of rank of such person being junior to that of all other officers of the same grade serving on the active-duty list.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab9adde2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><chapeau> Constructive service credited an officer under subsection (b) or (d) shall be used only for determining the officer’s—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab9adde3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> initial grade as a reserve officer;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab9adde4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> rank in grade; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab9adde5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> service in grade for promotion eligibility.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab9adde6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12207/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> The grade and position on the reserve active-status list of a person receiving an appointment as a reserve officer who at the time of appointment is credited with service under this section shall be determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense based upon the amount of service credited.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idab9adde7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added § 596b and renumbered § 12207, <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tXVI">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI</ref>, §§ 1634, 1662(c)(2), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2965">108 Stat. 2965</ref>, 2990; amended <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tV/s515/b/1/LL">Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(b)(1)(LL)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3234">119 Stat. 3234</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/181/dA/tV/s512">Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 512</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/98">122 Stat. 98</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tV/s512/a">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title V, § 512(a)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1376">131 Stat. 1376</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tV/s502/b">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 502(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1739">132 Stat. 1739</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tV/s502/b">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 502(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3564">134 Stat. 3564</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idab9adde8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idab9adde9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idab9addea-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in sections 3353, 5600, and 8353 of this title, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s1629/a/1">Pub. L. 103–337, § 1629(a)(1)</ref>, (c)(1) and <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1501/c/26">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1501(c)(26)</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idab9addeb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s502/b/1">Pub. L. 116–283, § 502(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “and who has special training or experience, or advanced education (if applicable),” for “or a designation in, or an assignment to, an officer category in which advanced education or training is required and who has advanced education or training,” in introductory provisions. Amendment was executed to reflect the probable intent of Congress due to omission of words “by striking” in directory language.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s502/b/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 502(b)(2)</ref>, added subpar. (D) and struck out former subpar. (D) which read as follows: “Additional credit for special training or experience in a particular officer career field as designated by the Secretary concerned, if such training or experience is directly related to the operational needs of the armed force concerned.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (b)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s502/b/1/A">Pub. L. 115–232, § 502(b)(1)(A)</ref>, added subpar. (D) and struck out former subpar. (D) which read as follows: “Additional credit, in unusual cases, based on special experience in a particular field.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s502/b/1/B">Pub. L. 115–232, § 502(b)(1)(B)</ref>, added par. (3) and struck out former par. (3) which read as follows: “Except as authorized by the Secretary concerned in individual cases and under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense in the case of officers covered by paragraph (2), the amount of constructive service credited an officer under this subsection may not exceed the amount required in order for the officer to be eligible for an original appointment as a reserve officer of the Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps in the grade of major or as a reserve officer of the Navy in the grade of lieutenant commander.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e) to (g). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s502/b/2">Pub. L. 115–232, § 502(b)(2)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (f) and (g) as (e) and (f), respectively, substituted “or (d)” for “, (d), or (e)” in introductory provisions of subsec. (e), and struck out former subsec. (e) which related to constructive service credited to commissioned officers with cyberspace-related experience or advanced education in reserve active-status.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s512/a/1">Pub. L. 115–91, § 512(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “or (e)” after “subsection (b)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s512/a/3">Pub. L. 115–91, § 512(a)(3)</ref>, added subsec. (e). Former subsec. (e) redesignated (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s512/a/2">Pub. L. 115–91, § 512(a)(2)</ref>, (4), redesignated subsec. (e) as (f) and substituted “, (d), or (e)” for “or (d)”. Former subsec. (f) redesignated (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s512/a/2">Pub. L. 115–91, § 512(a)(2)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (f) as (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/110/181/s512/a">Pub. L. 110–181, § 512(a)</ref>, amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “If the Secretary of Defense determines that the number of medical or dental officers serving in an active status in a reserve component of the Army, Navy, or Air Force in grades below major or lieutenant commander is critically below the number needed by such reserve component in such grades, the Secretary of Defense may authorize the Secretary of the military department concerned to credit any person who is receiving an original appointment for service as a medical or dental officer with a period of constructive credit in such amount (in addition to any amount credited such person under subsection (b)) as will result in the grade of such person being that of captain or, in the case of the Navy Reserve, lieutenant.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/110/181/s512/b">Pub. L. 110–181, § 512(b)</ref>, substituted “officers covered by paragraph (2)” for “a medical or dental officer”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/109/163">Pub. L. 109–163</ref> substituted “Navy Reserve” for “Naval Reserve”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s1662/c/2">Pub. L. 103–337, § 1662(c)(2)</ref>, renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s596b">section 596b of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idab9addec-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idab9added-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1996-10-01">Oct. 1, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s1691/b/1">section 1691(b)(1) of Pub. L. 103–337</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s10001">section 10001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idab9addee-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Annual Report</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions requiring submission to Congress of reports on the use of the authorities in subsec. (b)(1)(D) of this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s502/c">section 502(c) of Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s533">section 533 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
