<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idab9d27ae-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12303"><num value="12303">§ 12303.</num><heading> Ready Reserve: members not assigned to, or participating satisfactorily in, units</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab9d27af-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12303/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President may order to active duty any member of the Ready Reserve of an armed force who—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab9d27b0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12303/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> is not assigned to, or participating satisfactorily in, a unit of the Ready Reserve;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab9d27b1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12303/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> has not fulfilled his statutory reserve obligation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab9d27b2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12303/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> has not served on active duty for a total of 24 months.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab9d27b3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12303/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> A member who is ordered to active duty under this section may be required to serve on active duty until his total service on active duty equals 24 months. If his enlistment or other period of military service would expire before he has served the required period under this section, it may be extended until he has served the required period.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab9d27b4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12303/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><chapeau> To achieve fair treatment among members of the Ready Reserve who are being considered for active duty under this section, appropriate consideration shall be given to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab9d27b5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12303/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> family responsibilities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab9d27b6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12303/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> employment necessary to maintain the national health, safety, or interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idab9d27b7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/90/40/s6/1">Pub. L. 90–40, § 6(1)</ref>, <date date="1967-06-30">June 30, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/105">81 Stat. 105</ref>, § 673a; renumbered § 12303, <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tXVI/s1662/e/2">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2992">108 Stat. 2992</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idab9d27b8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idab9d27b9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idab9d27ba-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/337">Pub. L. 103–337</ref> renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s673a">section 673a of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idab9d27bb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idab9d27bc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 11366. Authorization To Order Ready Reserve to Active Duty; Extension of Military Service</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 11366, <date date="1967-08-04">Aug. 4, 1967</date>, 32 F.R. 11411, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 13286, § 64, <date date="2003-02-28">Feb. 28, 2003</date>, 68 F.R. 10629, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By virtue of the authority vested in me by section 673a [now 12303] of title 10 of the United States Code, and by <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref> of the United States Code, and as President of the United States, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. (a) The Secretary of Defense is hereby authorized and empowered to exercise the authority vested in the President by section 673a [now 12303] of title 10 of the United States Code, to order to active duty any member of the Ready Reserve of an armed force (except the Coast Guard when not operating as a service in the Navy) who—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(1) is not assigned to, or participating satisfactorily in, a unit of the Ready Reserve;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(2) has not fulfilled his statutory reserve obligation; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(3) has not served on active duty for a total of 24 months.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) In pursuance of the provisions of section 673a [now 12303] of title 10 of the United States Code, the Secretary of Defense is hereby authorized to require a member ordered to active duty under the authority of this Order to serve on active duty until his total service on active duty equals 24 months. If the enlistment or period of military service of a member of the Ready Reserve ordered to active duty under this authority would expire before he has served the required period of active duty prescribed herein, his enlistment or period of military service may be extended until he has served the required period.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) In pursuance of the provisions of section 673a [now 12303] of title 10 of the United States Code, and in order to achieve fair treatment among members of the Ready Reserve who are being considered for active duty under this authority, appropriate consideration shall be given to—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(1) family responsibilities; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(2) employment necessary to maintain the national health, safety, or interest.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. The Secretary of Homeland Security is hereby authorized and empowered to exercise the authority vested in the President by section 673a [now 12303] of the title 10 of the United States Code, with respect to any member of the Ready Reserve of the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, under the same conditions as such authority may be exercised by the Secretary of Defense under this Order with respect to any member of the Ready Reserve of any other armed force.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. (a) The Secretary of Defense may designate any of the Secretaries of the military departments of the Department of Defense to exercise the authority vested in him by section 1 of this Order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Secretary of Homeland Security may designate the Commandant of the United States Coast Guard to exercise the authority vested in him by section 2 of this Order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 4. Executive Order No. 11327 of <date date="1967-02-15">February 15, 1967</date>, is superseded except with respect to members of the Ready Reserve ordered to active duty under the authority of that Order.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idab9d27bd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 11406. Assigning Authority To Order Ready Reserve to Active Duty</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 11406, <date date="1968-04-10">Apr. 10, 1968</date>, 33 F.R. 5735, authorized Secretary of Defense and, when designated by him, any of Secretaries of military departments of Department of Defense to exercise authority vested in President until <date date="1968-06-30">June 30, 1968</date> by paragraph (e) of title I of the Department of Defense Appropriation Act, 1967 (<ref href="/us/stat/80/981">80 Stat. 981</ref>) to order any unit in the Ready Reserve to active duty for a period not to exceed 24 months.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
