<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idaba45408-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12602"><num value="12602">§ 12602.</num><heading> Members of Army National Guard of United States and Air National Guard of United States: credit for service as members of National Guard</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaba45409-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12602/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> For the purposes of laws providing benefits for members of the Army National Guard of the United States and their dependents and beneficiaries—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaba4540a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12602/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> military training, duty, or other service performed by a member of the Army National Guard of the United States in his status as a member of the Army National Guard for which he is entitled to pay from the United States shall be considered military training, duty, or other service, as the case may be, in Federal service as a Reserve of the Army;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaba4540b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12602/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> full-time National Guard duty performed by a member of the Army National Guard of the United States shall be considered active duty in Federal service as a Reserve of the Army; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaba4540c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12602/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> inactive-duty training performed by a member of the Army National Guard of the United States in his status as a member of the Army National Guard, in accordance with regulations prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s502">section 502 of title 32</ref> or other express provision of law, shall be considered inactive-duty training in Federal service as a Reserve of the Army.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaba4540d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12602/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> For the purposes of laws providing benefits for members of the Air National Guard of the United States and their dependents and beneficiaries—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaba4540e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12602/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> military training, duty, or other service performed by a member of the Air National Guard of the United States in his status as a member of the Air National Guard for which he is entitled to pay from the United States shall be considered military training, duty, or other service, as the case may be, in Federal service as a Reserve of the Air Force;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaba4540f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12602/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> full-time National Guard duty performed by a member of the Air National Guard of the United States shall be considered active duty in Federal service as a Reserve of the Air Force; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaba45410-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s12602/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> inactive-duty training performed by a member of the Air National Guard of the United States in his status as a member of the Air National Guard, in accordance with regulations prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s502">section 502 of title 32</ref> or other express provision of law, shall be considered inactive-duty training in Federal service as a Reserve of the Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idaba45411-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tXVI/s1662/g/1">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2995">108 Stat. 2995</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idaba45412-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idaba45413-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idaba45414-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in sections 3686 and 8686 of this title, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s1662/g/2">Pub. L. 103–337, § 1662(g)(2)</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idaba45415-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idaba45416-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1994-12-01">Dec. 1, 1994</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s1691">section 1691 of Pub. L. 103–337</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s10001">section 10001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
