<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida756a4e8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s129c"><num value="129c">§ 129c.</num><heading> Medical personnel: limitations on reductions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida756a4e9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s129c/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Reduction</inline>.—</heading><content>For any fiscal year, the Secretary of Defense may not make a reduction in the number of medical personnel of the Department of Defense described in subsection (b) unless the Secretary makes a certification for that fiscal year described in subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida756a4ea-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s129c/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered Reductions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Subsection (a) applies to a reduction in the number of medical personnel of the Department of Defense as of the end of a fiscal year to a number that is less than—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida756a4eb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s129c/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> 95 percent of the number of such personnel at the end of the immediately preceding fiscal year; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida756a4ec-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s129c/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> 90 percent of the number of such personnel at the end of the third fiscal year preceding the fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida756a4ed-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s129c/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certification</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A certification referred to in subsection (a) with respect to reductions in medical personnel of the Department of Defense for any fiscal year is a certification by the Secretary of Defense to Congress that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida756a4ee-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s129c/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the number of medical personnel being reduced is excess to the current and projected needs of the Department of Defense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida756a4ef-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s129c/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> such reduction will not result in an increase in the cost of health care services provided under the Civilian Health and Medical Program of the Uniformed Services under chapter 55 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida756a4f0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s129c/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Policy for Implementing Reductions</inline>.—</heading><content>Whenever the Secretary of Defense directs that there be a reduction in the total number of military medical personnel of the Department of Defense, the Secretary shall require that the reduction be carried out so as to ensure that the reduction is not exclusively or disproportionately borne by any one of the armed forces and is not exclusively or disproportionately borne by either the active or the reserve components.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida756a4f1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s129c/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term “medical personnel” means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida756a4f2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s129c/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the members of the armed forces covered by the term “medical personnel” as defined in section 115a(e)(2) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002004">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002004"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida756a4f3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s129c/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the civilian personnel of the Department of Defense assigned to military medical facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida756a4f4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tV/s564/a/1">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 564(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/325">110 Stat. 325</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tX/s1073/a/4">Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1900">111 Stat. 1900</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida756a4f5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida756a4f6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="ida756a4f7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t10/s115a/e/2">Section 115a(e)(2) of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (e)(1), was redesignated as <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s115a/f/2">section 115a(f)(2) of this title</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tIV/s422/b/1/A">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title IV, § 422(b)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/850">139 Stat. 850</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="ida756a4f8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tVII/s711">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title VII, § 711</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1582">104 Stat. 1582</ref>, as amended, which was set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s115">section 115 of this title</ref>, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s564/d/1">Pub. L. 104–106, § 564(d)(1)</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida756a4f9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85">Pub. L. 105–85</ref> substituted “section 115a(e)(2)” for “section 115a(g)(2)”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida756a4fa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida756a4fb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Limitation on Reduction of Military Medical Manning End Strength: Certification Requirement and Other Reforms</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tVII/s741/a">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VII, § 741(a)</ref>, (d), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2676">136 Stat. 2676</ref>, 2680, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tVII/s713/1">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title VII, § 713(1)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/921">139 Stat. 921</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tVII/s713/1">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), and in addition to the limitation under section 719 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Public Law 116–92</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/133/1454">133 Stat. 1454</ref>), as most recently amended by section 731 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022 (<ref href="/us/pl/117/81">Public Law 117–81</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/135/1795">135 Stat. 1795</ref>), during the 10-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], neither the Secretary of Defense nor a Secretary concerned may reduce military medical end strength authorizations, and following such period, neither may reduce such authorizations unless the Secretary of Defense issues a waiver pursuant to paragraph (6).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The limitation under paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Administrative billets of a military department that have remained unfilled since at least <date date="2018-10-01">October 1, 2018</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Billets identified as non-clinical in the budget of the President for fiscal year 2020 submitted to Congress pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105/a">section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, United States Code, except that the number of such billets may not exceed 1,700.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Medical headquarters billets of the military departments not assigned to, or providing direct support to, operational commands.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report on composition of military medical workforce requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretaries of the military departments, shall conduct an assessment of current military medical manning requirements (taking into consideration factors including future operational planning, training, and beneficiary healthcare) and submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report containing the findings of such assessment. Such assessment shall be informed by the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The National Defense Strategy submitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s113/g">section 113(g) of title 10</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The National Military Strategy prepared under section 153(b) of such title.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> The campaign plans of the combatant commands.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Theater strategies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> The joint medical estimate under section 732 of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<ref href="/us/pl/115/232">Public Law 115–232</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/132/1817">132 Stat. 1817</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> The plan of the Department of Defense on integrated medical operations, as updated pursuant to paragraph (1) of section 724(a) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022 (<ref href="/us/pl/117/81">Public Law 117–81</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/135/1793">135 Stat. 1793</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1096">10 U.S.C. 1096</ref> note).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> The plan of the Department of Defense on global patient movement, as updated pursuant to paragraph (2) of such section 724(a).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> The biosurveillance program of the Department of Defense established pursuant to Department of Defense Directive 6420.02 (relating to biosurveillance).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> Requirements for graduate medical education.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="J">“(J)</num><content> The report of the COVID–19 Military Health System Review Panel under section 731 of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/134/3698">134 Stat. 3698</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="K">“(K)</num><content> The report of the Inspector General of the Department of Defense titled ‘Evaluation of Department of Defense Military Medical Treatment Facility Challenges During the Coronavirus Disease-2019 (COVID-19) Pandemic in Fiscal Year 2021 (DODIG-2022-081)’ and published on <date date="2022-04-05">April 5, 2022</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="L">“(L)</num><content> Reports of the Comptroller General of the United States relating to military health system reforms undertaken on or after January, 1, 2017, including any such reports relating to military medical manning and force composition mix.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="M">“(M)</num><content> Such other reports as may be determined appropriate by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certification</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate a certification containing the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> A certification of the completion of a comprehensive review of military medical manning, including with respect to the medical corps (or other health- or medical-related component of a military department), designator, profession, occupation, and rating of medical personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> A justification for any proposed increase, realignment, reduction, or other change to the specialty or occupational composition of military medical end strength authorizations, which may include compliance with a requirement or recommendation set forth in a strategy, plan, or other matter specified in paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> A certification that, in the case that any change to such specialty or occupational composition is required, a vacancy resulting from such change may not be filled with a position other than a health- or medical-related position until such time as there are no military medical billets remaining to fill the vacancy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> A risk analysis associated with the potential realignment or reduction of any military medical end strength authorizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> An identification of any plans of the Department to backfill military medical personnel positions with civilian personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> A plan to address persistent vacancies for civilian personnel in health- or medical-related positions, and a risk analysis associated with the hiring, onboarding, and retention of such civilian personnel, taking into account provider shortfalls across the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> A comprehensive plan to mitigate any risk identified pursuant to subparagraph (D) or (F), including with respect to funding necessary for such mitigation across fiscal years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Process required</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretaries of the military departments, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense and the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, shall develop and submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate a process for the authorization of proposed modifications to the composition of the medical manning force mix across the military departments while maintaining compliance with the limitation under paragraph (1). Such process shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> take into consideration the funding required for any such proposed modification; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> include distinct processes for proposed increases and proposed decreases, respectively, to the medical manning force mix of each military department.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Waiver.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Following the conclusion of the 10-year period specified in paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense may waive the prohibition under such subsection if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the report requirement under paragraph (3), the certification requirement under paragraph (4), and the process requirement under paragraph (5) have been completed;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the Secretary determines that the waiver is necessary and in the interests of the national security of the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> the waiver is issued in writing.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notification to congress</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than five days after issuing a waiver under subparagraph (A), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate a notification of the waiver (including the text of the waiver and a justification for the waiver) and provide to such committees a briefing on the components of the waiver.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The term ‘medical personnel’ has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s115a/e">section 115a(e) of title 10</ref>, United States Code [now <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s115a/f">10 U.S.C. 115a(f)</ref>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘Secretary concerned’ has the meaning given that term in section 101(a) of such title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The term ‘theater strategy’ means an overarching construct outlining the vision of a combatant commander for the integration and synchronization of military activities and operations with other national power instruments to achieve the strategic objectives of the United States.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida756a4fc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prohibition on Conversion of Military Medical and Dental Positions to Civilian Medical and Dental Positions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/181/dA/tVII/s721/a">Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title VII, § 721(a)</ref>–(d), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/198">122 Stat. 198</ref>, 199, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/dA/tVII/s701">Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2372">123 Stat. 2372</ref>, prohibited the Secretary of a military department from converting any military medical or dental position to a civilian medical or dental position on or after <date date="2007-10-01">Oct. 1, 2007</date>, and required restoration of certain converted positions to military positions, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tVII/s721/c">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VII, § 721(c)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2228">130 Stat. 2228</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida75914fd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Requirement To Certify and Report on Conversion of Military Medical and Dental Positions to Civilian Medical and Dental Positions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tVII/s742">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title VII, § 742</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2306">120 Stat. 2306</ref>, which prohibited the Secretary of a military department from converting any military medical or dental position to a civilian medical or dental position in a fiscal year until the Secretary submitted to the Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives with respect to that fiscal year a certification that the conversions within that department would not increase cost or decrease quality of care or access to care, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/110/181/dA/tVII/s721/e">Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title VII, § 721(e)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/199">122 Stat. 199</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida75914fe-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prohibition on Conversions of Military Medical and Dental Positions to Civilian Medical Positions Until Submission of Certification</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tVII/s744">Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title VII, § 744</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3360">119 Stat. 3360</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tVII/s744">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Conversions.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission of certification</inline>.—</heading><content>A Secretary of a military department may not convert any military medical or dental position to a civilian medical or dental position until the Secretary submits to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a certification that the conversions within that department will not increase cost or decrease quality of care or access to care. Such a certification may not be submitted before <date date="2006-06-01">June 1, 2006</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report with certification</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A Secretary submitting such a certification shall include with the certification a written report that includes—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the methodology used by the Secretary in making the determinations necessary for the certification, including the extent to which the Secretary took into consideration the findings of the Comptroller General in the report under subsection (b)(3);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the results of a market survey in each affected area of the availability of civilian medical and dental care providers in such area in order to determine whether the civilian medical and dental care providers available in such area are adequate to fill the civilian positions created by the conversion of military medical and dental positions to civilian positions in such area; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> any action taken by the Secretary in response to recommendations in the Comptroller General report under subsection (b)(3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement for Study.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Comptroller General shall conduct a study on the effect of conversions of military medical and dental positions to civilian medical or dental positions on the defense health program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Matters covered</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The study shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The number of military medical and dental positions, by grade and specialty, planned for conversion to civilian medical or dental positions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The number of military medical and dental positions, by grade and specialty, converted to civilian medical or dental positions since <date date="2004-10-01">October 1, 2004</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> The ability of the military health care system to fill the civilian medical and dental positions required, by specialty.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> The degree to which access to health care is affected in both the direct and purchased care system, including an assessment of the effects of any increased shifts in patient load from the direct care to the purchased care system, or any delays in receipt of care in either the direct or purchased care system because of lack of direct care providers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> The degree to which changes in military manpower requirements affect recruiting and retention of uniformed medical and dental personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> The degree to which conversion of the military positions meets the joint medical and dental readiness requirements of the uniformed services, as determined jointly by all the uniformed services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> The effect of the conversions of military medical positions to civilian medical and dental positions on the defense health program, including costs associated with the conversions, with a comparison of the estimated costs versus the actual costs incurred by the number of conversions since <date date="2004-10-01">October 1, 2004</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> The effectiveness of the conversions in enhancing medical and dental readiness, health care efficiency, productivity, quality, and customer satisfaction.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report on study</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2006-05-01">May 1, 2006</date>, the Comptroller General shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives a report containing the results of the study under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The term ‘military medical or dental position’ means a position for the performance of health care functions within the Armed Forces held by a member of the Armed Forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘civilian medical or dental position’ means a position for the performance of health care functions within the Department of Defense held by an employee of the Department or of a contractor of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The term ‘affected area’ means an area in which military medical or dental positions were converted to civilian medical or dental positions before <date date="2004-10-01">October 1, 2004</date>, or in which such conversions are scheduled to occur in the future.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The term ‘uniformed services’ has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1072/1">section 1072(1) of title 10</ref>, United States Code.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida75914ff-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Special Transition Rule for Fiscal Year 1996</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tV/s564/b">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 564(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/326">110 Stat. 326</ref>, provided that, for purposes of applying subsec. (b)(1) of this section during fiscal year 1996, the number against which the percentage limitation of 95 percent was to be computed would be the number of medical personnel of the Department of Defense as of the end of fiscal year 1994, rather than the number as of the end of fiscal year 1995.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
