<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idabb2ab66-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14303"><num value="14303">§ 14303.</num><heading> Eligibility for consideration for promotion: minimum years of service in grade</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb2ab67-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14303/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Officers in Pay Grades</inline> O–1 <inline class="small-caps">and</inline> O–2.—</heading><chapeau>An officer who is on the reserve active-status list of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps and holds a permanent appointment in the grade of second lieutenant or first lieutenant as a reserve officer of the Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps, or in the grade of ensign or lieutenant (junior grade) as a reserve officer of the Navy, may not be promoted to the next higher grade, or granted Federal recognition in that grade, until the officer has completed the following years of service in grade:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb2ab68-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14303/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Eighteen months, in the case of an officer holding a permanent appointment in the grade of second lieutenant or ensign.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb2ab69-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14303/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Two years, in the case of an officer holding a permanent appointment in the grade of first lieutenant or lieutenant (junior grade).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb2ab6a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14303/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Officers in Pay Grades</inline> O–3 <inline class="small-caps">and Above</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Subject to subsection (d), an officer who is on the reserve active-status list of the Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps and holds a permanent appointment in a grade above first lieutenant, or who is on the reserve active-status list of the Navy in a grade above lieutenant (junior grade), may not be considered for selection for promotion to the next higher grade, or examined for Federal recognition in the next higher grade, until the officer has completed the following years of service in grade:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb2ab6b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14303/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Three years, in the case of an officer of the Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps holding a permanent appointment in the grade of captain, major, or lieutenant colonel or in the case of a reserve officer of the Navy holding a permanent appointment in the grade of lieutenant, lieutenant commander, or commander.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb2ab6c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14303/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> One year, in the case of an officer of the Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps holding a permanent appointment in the grade of colonel or brigadier general or in the case of a reserve officer of the Navy holding a permanent appointment in the grade of captain or rear admiral (lower half).</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">This subsection does not apply to an adjutant general or assistant adjutant general of a State or to an appointment in a higher grade which is based upon a specific provision of law.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb2ab6d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14303/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority To Lengthen Minimum Period in Grade</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary concerned may prescribe a period of service in grade for eligibility for promotion, in the case of officers to whom subsection (a) applies, or for eligibility for consideration for promotion, in the case of officers to whom subsection (b) applies, that is longer than the applicable period specified in that subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb2ab6e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14303/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Waivers To Ensure Two Below-the-Zone Considerations</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14307/b">section 14307(b) of this title</ref>, the Secretary of the military department concerned may waive subsection (b) to the extent necessary to ensure that officers described in paragraph (1) of that subsection have at least two opportunities for consideration for promotion to the next higher grade as officers below the promotion zone.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idabb2ab6f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tXVI/s1611">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2933">108 Stat. 2933</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idabb2ab70-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idabb2ab71-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idabb2ab72-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1996-10-01">Oct. 1, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s1691/b/1">section 1691(b)(1) of Pub. L. 103–337</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s10001">section 10001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
