<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idabb03b24-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301"><num value="14301">§ 14301.</num><heading> Eligibility for consideration for promotion: general rules</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb03b25-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">One-Year Rule</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An officer is eligible under this chapter for consideration for promotion by a promotion board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14101/a">section 14101(a) of this title</ref> only if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb03b26-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the officer is on the reserve active-status list of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb03b27-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> during the one-year period ending on the date of the convening of the promotion board the officer has continuously performed service on either the reserve active-status list or the active-duty list (or on a combination of both lists).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb03b28-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement for Consideration of All Officers In and Above the Zone</inline>.—</heading><content>Whenever a promotion board (other than a vacancy promotion board) is convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14101/a">section 14101(a) of this title</ref> for consideration of officers in a competitive category who are eligible under this chapter for consideration for promotion to the next higher grade, each officer in the promotion zone, and each officer above the promotion zone, for that grade and competitive category shall be considered for promotion.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb03b29-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certain Officers Not To Be Considered</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A promotion board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14101/a">section 14101(a) of this title</ref> may not consider for promotion to the next higher grade any of the following officers:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb03b2a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An officer whose name is on a promotion list for that grade as a result of recommendation for promotion to that grade by an earlier selection board convened under that section or <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14502">section 14502 of this title</ref> or under chapter 36 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb03b2b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An officer who is recommended for promotion to that grade in the report of an earlier selection board convened under a provision referred to in paragraph (1), in the case of such a report that has not yet been approved by the President.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb03b2c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> An officer who has been approved for Federal recognition by a board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t32/s307">section 307 of title 32</ref> and nominated by the President for promotion to that grade as a reserve of the Army or of the Air Force as the case may be, if that nomination is pending before the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb03b2d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> An officer who has been nominated by the President for promotion to that grade under any other provision of law, if that nomination is pending before the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb03b2e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> An officer in the grade of first lieutenant or, in the case of the Navy, lieutenant (junior grade) who is on an approved all-fully-qualified-officers list under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14308/b/4">section 14308(b)(4) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb03b2f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> An officer excluded under subsection (j).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb03b30-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Officers Below the Zone</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of the military department concerned may, by regulation, prescribe procedures to limit the officers to be considered by a selection board from below the promotion zone to those officers who are determined to be exceptionally well qualified for promotion. The regulations shall include criteria for determining which officers below the promotion zone are exceptionally well qualified for promotion.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb03b31-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certain Reserve Officers of the Air Force</inline>.—</heading><content>A reserve officer of the Air Force who (1) is in the Air National Guard of the United States and holds the grade of lieutenant colonel, colonel, or brigadier general, or (2) is in the Air Force Reserve and holds the grade of colonel or brigadier general, is not eligible for consideration for promotion by a mandatory promotion board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14101/a">section 14101(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb03b32-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Nonconsideration of Officers Scheduled for Removal From Reserve Active-status List</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of the military department concerned may, by regulation, preclude from consideration by a selection board by which an officer would otherwise be eligible to be considered, an officer who has an established separation date that is within 90 days after the date the board is convened or an approved retirement date.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb03b33-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Brigadier Generals</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb03b34-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> An officer who is a reserve component brigadier general of the Army or the Air Force who is not eligible for consideration for promotion under subsection (a) because the officer is not on the reserve active status list (as required by paragraph (1) of that subsection for such eligibility) is nevertheless eligible for consideration for promotion to the grade of major general by a promotion board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14101/a">section 14101(a) of this title</ref> if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb03b35-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> as of the date of the convening of the promotion board, the officer has been in an inactive status for less than one year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb03b36-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> immediately before the date of the officer’s most recent transfer to an inactive status, the officer had continuously served on the reserve active status list or the active-duty list (or a combination of the reserve active status list and the active-duty list) for at least one year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb03b37-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> An officer who is a reserve component brigadier general of the Army or the Air Force who is on the reserve active status list but who is not eligible for consideration for promotion under subsection (a) because the officer’s service does not meet the one-year-of-continuous-service requirement under paragraph (2) of that subsection is nevertheless eligible for consideration for promotion to the grade of major general by a promotion board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14101/a">section 14101(a) of this title</ref> if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb03b38-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/g/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the officer was transferred from an inactive status to the reserve active status list during the one-year period preceding the date of the convening of the promotion board;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb03b39-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/g/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> immediately before the date of the officer’s most recent transfer to an active status, the officer had been in an inactive status for less than one year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb03b3a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/g/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> immediately before the date of the officer’s most recent transfer to an inactive status, the officer had continuously served for at least one year on the reserve active status list or the active-duty list (or a combination of the reserve active status list and the active-duty list).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb2ab3b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Officers on Educational Delay</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An officer on the reserve active-status list is ineligible for consideration for promotion, but shall remain on the reserve active-status list, while the officer—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb2ab3c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> is pursuing a program of graduate level education in an educational delay status approved by the Secretary concerned; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb2ab3d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> is receiving from the Secretary financial assistance in connection with the pursuit of that program of education while in that status.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb2ab3e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reserve Officers Employed as Military Technician (dual Status)</inline>.—</heading><content>A reserve officer of the Army or Air Force employed as a military technician (dual status) under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s10216">section 10216 of this title</ref> who has been retained beyond the mandatory removal date for years of service pursuant to subsection (f) of such section or <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14702/a/2">section 14702(a)(2) of this title</ref> is not eligible for consideration for promotion by a mandatory promotion board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14101/a">section 14101(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb2ab3f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority To Allow Officers To Opt Out of Selection Board Consideration</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb2ab40-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of a military department may provide that an officer under the jurisdiction of the Secretary may, upon the officer’s request and with the approval of the Secretary, be excluded from consideration by a selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14101/a">section 14101(a) of this title</ref> to consider officers for promotion to the next higher grade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb2ab41-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Secretary concerned may only approve a request under paragraph (1) if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb2ab42-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/j/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the basis for the request is to allow an officer to complete a broadening assignment, advanced education, another assignment of significant value to the Department, training, or a career progression requirement delayed by the assignment, education, or training;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb2ab43-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/j/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Secretary determines the exclusion from consideration is in the best interest of the military department concerned; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb2ab44-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/j/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the officer has not previously failed of selection for promotion to the grade for which the officer requests the exclusion from consideration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb2ab45-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14301/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certain Officers Not to Be Considered for Selection for Promotion</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of the military department concerned may provide that an officer who is in an active status, but is in a duty status in which the only points the officer accrues under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12732/a/2">section 12732(a)(2) of this title</ref> are pursuant to subparagraph (C)(i) of that section (relating to membership in a reserve component), shall not be considered for selection for promotion until completion of two years of service in such duty status. Any such officer may remain on the reserve active-status list.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idabb2ab46-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tXVI/s1611">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2931">108 Stat. 2931</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tV">Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 503(b), (c), 514(b), <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1724">111 Stat. 1724</ref>, 1725, 1732; <ref href="/us/pl/105/261/dA/tV/s514">Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 514</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2008">112 Stat. 2008</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tV/s513/a">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 513(a)</ref>, title X, § 1066(a)(32), <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/593">113 Stat. 593</ref>, 772; <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tV/s505/c/1/B">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 505(c)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1087">115 Stat. 1087</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tV/s521">Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title V, § 521</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2540">116 Stat. 2540</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/dA/tV/s517">Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 517</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1397">125 Stat. 1397</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tV">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 505(b), 513, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1743">132 Stat. 1743</ref>, 1752; <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tV">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 503(c), 505(a)(2), <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1868">138 Stat. 1868</ref>, 1869.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idabb2ab47-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idabb2ab48-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idabb2ab49-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s503/c">Pub. L. 118–159, § 503(c)</ref>, amended subsec. (f) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Secretary of the military department concerned may, by regulation, provide for the exclusion from consideration for promotion by a promotion board of any officer otherwise eligible to be considered by the board who has an established date for removal from the reserve active-status list that is not more than 90 days after the date on which the selection board for which the officer would otherwise be eligible is to be convened.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s505/a/2">Pub. L. 118–159, § 505(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “training,” after “Department,” and substituted “assignment, education, or training” for “assignment or education”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s505/b/1/A">Pub. L. 115–232, § 505(b)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “Certain Officers Not” for “Previously Selected Officers Not Eligible” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s505/b/1/B">Pub. L. 115–232, § 505(b)(1)(B)</ref>, added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s505/b/2">Pub. L. 115–232, § 505(b)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s513">Pub. L. 115–232, § 513</ref>, added subsec. (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/112/81">Pub. L. 112–81</ref> added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/107/314">Pub. L. 107–314</ref> amended subsec. (g) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “A reserve component brigadier general of the Army or the Air Force who is in an inactive status is eligible (notwithstanding subsection (a)) for consideration for promotion to major general by a promotion board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14101/a">section 14101(a) of this title</ref> if the officer—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) has been in an inactive status for less than one year as of the date of the convening of the promotion board; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) had continuously served for at least one year on the reserve active status list or the active duty list (or a combination of both) immediately before the officer’s most recent transfer to an inactive status.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (c)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/107/107">Pub. L. 107–107</ref> added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (g)(1), (2). <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/s1066/a/32">Pub. L. 106–65, § 1066(a)(32)</ref>, substituted “one year” for “1 year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/s513/a">Pub. L. 106–65, § 513(a)</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/105/261">Pub. L. 105–261</ref> added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s503/b/1">Pub. L. 105–85, § 503(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “grade any of the following officers:” for “grade—” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s503/b/2">Pub. L. 105–85, § 503(b)(2)</ref>, (3), substituted “An officer” for “an officer” and “title.” for “title;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s503/b/6">Pub. L. 105–85, § 503(b)(6)</ref>, added par. (2). Former par. (2) redesignated (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s503/b/2">Pub. L. 105–85, § 503(b)(2)</ref>, (4), substituted “An officer” for “an officer” and “be.” for “be; or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s503/c">Pub. L. 105–85, § 503(c)</ref>, inserted “, if that nomination is pending before the Senate” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s503/b/5">Pub. L. 105–85, § 503(b)(5)</ref>, redesignated par. (2) as (3) and substituted “that grade” for “the next higher grade”. Former par. (3) redesignated (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s503/b/2">Pub. L. 105–85, § 503(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “An officer” for “an officer”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s503/c">Pub. L. 105–85, § 503(c)</ref>, inserted “, if that nomination is pending before the Senate” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s503/b/5">Pub. L. 105–85, § 503(b)(5)</ref>, redesignated par. (3) as (4) and substituted “that grade” for “the next higher grade”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e) to (g). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s514/b">Pub. L. 105–85, § 514(b)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (f) and (g) as (e) and (f), respectively, and struck out former subsec. (e) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(e) <inline class="small-caps">Reserve Officers of the Army; Consideration for Brigadier General and Major General</inline>.—In the case of officers of the Army, if the Secretary of the Army determines that vacancies are authorized or anticipated in the reserve grades of major general or brigadier general for officers who are on the reserve active-status list and who are not assigned to units organized to serve as a unit and the Secretary convenes a mandatory promotion board under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14101/a">section 14101(a) of this title</ref> to consider officers for promotion to fill such vacancies, the Secretary may limit the officers to be considered by that board to those determined to be exceptionally well qualified for promotion under such criteria and procedures as the Secretary may by regulation prescribe.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idabb2ab4a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idabb2ab4b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1999 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tV/s513/b">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 513(b)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/593">113 Stat. 593</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tV/s513/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Subsection (h) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14301">section 14301 of title 10</ref>, United States Code (as added by subsection (a)), shall apply with respect to boards convened under section 14101(a) of such title before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Secretary of the military department concerned, upon receipt of request submitted in a form and manner prescribed by the Secretary, shall expunge from the military records of an officer any indication of a failure of selection of the officer for promotion by a board referred to in paragraph (1) while the officer was ineligible for consideration by that board by reason of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14301/h">section 14301(h) of title 10</ref>, United States Code.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idabb2ab4c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 503(b), (c) of <ref href="/us/pl/105/85">Pub. L. 105–85</ref> effective <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, and applicable with respect to selection boards that are convened under section 611(a), 14101(a), or 14502 of this title on or after <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s503/d">section 503(d) of Pub. L. 105–85</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s619">section 619 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idabb2ab4d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1996-10-01">Oct. 1, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s1691/b/1">section 1691(b)(1) of Pub. L. 103–337</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s10001">section 10001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
