<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idabb51c09-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14312"><num value="14312">§ 14312.</num><heading> Delay of promotion: voluntary</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb51c0a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14312/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority for Voluntary Delays</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb51c0b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14312/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of the military department concerned may, by regulation, permit delays of a promotion of an officer who is recommended for promotion by a mandatory selection board convened under section 14101(a) or a special selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14502">section 14502 of this title</ref> at the request of the officer concerned. Such delays, in the case of any promotion, may extend for any period not to exceed three years from the date on which the officer would otherwise be promoted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb51c0c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14312/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Regulations under this section shall provide that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb51c0d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14312/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a request for such a delay of promotion must be submitted by the officer concerned before the delay may be approved; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb51c0e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14312/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> denial of such a request shall not be considered to be a failure of selection for promotion unless the officer declines to accept a promotion under circumstances set forth in subsection (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb51c0f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14312/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effect of Approval of Request</inline>.—</heading><content>If a request for delay of a promotion under subsection (a) is approved, the officer’s name shall remain on the promotion list during the authorized period of delay (unless removed under any other provision of law). Upon the end of the period of the authorized delay, or at any time during such period, the officer may accept the promotion, which shall be effective on the date of acceptance. Such an acceptance of a promotion shall be made in accordance with regulations prescribed under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb51c10-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14312/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effect of Declining a Promotion</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An officer’s name shall be removed from the promotion list and, if the officer is serving in a grade below colonel or, in the case of the Navy, captain, the officer shall be considered to have failed of selection for promotion if any of the following applies:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb51c11-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14312/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary concerned has not authorized voluntary delays of promotion under subsection (a) to the grade concerned and the officer declines to accept an appointment to a higher grade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb51c12-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14312/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary concerned has authorized voluntary delays of promotion under subsection (a), but has denied the request of the officer for a delay of promotion and the officer then declines to accept an appointment to a higher grade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb51c13-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14312/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary concerned has approved the request of an officer for a delay of promotion and, upon the end of the period of delay authorized in accordance with regulations prescribed under subsection (a), the officer then declines to accept an appointment to a higher grade.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idabb51c14-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tXVI/s1611">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2941">108 Stat. 2941</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idabb51c15-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idabb51c16-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idabb51c17-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1996-10-01">Oct. 1, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s1691/b/1">section 1691(b)(1) of Pub. L. 103–337</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s10001">section 10001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
