<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idabb2abe8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14311"><num value="14311">§ 14311.</num><heading> Delay of promotion: involuntary</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb2abe9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14311/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Delay During Investigations and Proceedings</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb2abea-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14311/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the appointment of an officer to a higher grade may be delayed if any of the following applies before the date on which the appointment would otherwise be made:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb2abeb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14311/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Sworn charges against the officer have been received by an officer exercising general court-martial jurisdiction over the officer and the charges have not been disposed of.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb2abec-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14311/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> An investigation is being conducted to determine whether disciplinary action of any kind should be brought against the officer.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb2abed-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14311/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> A board of officers has been convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14903">section 14903 of this title</ref> to review the record of the officer.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb2abee-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14311/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> A criminal proceeding in a Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction is pending against the officer.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb2abef-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14311/a/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Substantiated adverse information about the officer that is material to the decision to appoint the officer is under review by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb2abf0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14311/a/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> The Secretary of the military department concerned determines that credible information of adverse nature, including a substantiated adverse finding or conclusion described in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14107/a/3/A">section 14107(a)(3)(A) of this title</ref>, with respect to the officer will result in the convening of a special selection review board under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14502a">section 14502a of this title</ref> to review the officer and recommend whether the recommendation for promotion of the officer should be sustained.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb2abf1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14311/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If disciplinary action is not taken against the officer, if the charges against the officer are withdrawn or dismissed, if the officer is not separated by the Secretary of the military department concerned as the result of having been required to show cause for retention, if the officer is acquitted of the charges, or if, after a review of substantiated adverse information about the officer regarding the requirement for exemplary conduct set forth in section 7233, 8167, or 9233 of this title, as applicable, the officer is determined to be among the officers best qualified for promotion, as the case may be, then (unless action to delay the officer’s appointment to the higher grade has been taken under subsection (b)) the officer shall be retained on the promotion list (including an approved all-fully-qualified-officers list, if applicable), list of officers found qualified for Federal recognition, or list of officers nominated by the President to the Senate for appointment in a higher reserve grade and shall, upon promotion to the next higher grade, have the same date of rank, the same effective date for the pay and allowances of the grade to which promoted, and the same position on the reserve active-status list as the officer would have had if no delay had intervened, unless the Secretary concerned determines that the officer was unqualified for promotion for any part of the delay. If the Secretary makes such a determination, the Secretary may adjust such date of rank, effective date of pay and allowances, and position on the reserve active-status list as the Secretary considers appropriate under the circumstances.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb2abf2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14311/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In the case of an officer whose promotion is delayed pursuant to paragraph (1)(F) and whose recommendation for promotion is sustained, authorities for the promotion of the officer are specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14502a/f">section 14502a(f) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb51bf3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14311/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Delay for Lack of Qualifications</inline>.—</heading><content>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the appointment of an officer to a higher grade may also be delayed if there is cause to believe that the officer has not met the requirement for exemplary conduct set forth in section 7233, 8167, or 9233 of this title, as applicable, or is mentally, physically, morally, or professionally unqualified to perform the duties of the grade to which selected. If it is later determined by a civilian official of the Department of Defense (not below the level of Secretary of a military department) that the officer is qualified for promotion to the higher grade and, after a review of adverse information regarding the requirement for exemplary conduct set forth in section 7233, 8167, or 9233 of this title, as applicable, the officer is determined to be among the officers best qualified for promotion to the higher grade, the officer shall be retained on the promotion list (including an approved all-fully-qualified-officers list, if applicable), the list of officers found qualified for Federal recognition, or list of officers nominated by the President to the Senate for appointment in a higher reserve grade, and shall, upon promotion to that grade, have the same date of rank, the same effective date for pay and allowances of that grade, and the same position on the reserve active-status list as the officer would have had if no delay had intervened, unless the Secretary concerned determines that the officer was unqualified for promotion for any part of the delay. If the Secretary makes such a determination, the Secretary may adjust such date of rank, effective date of pay and allowances, and position on the reserve active-status list as the Secretary considers appropriate under the circumstances.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb51bf4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14311/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice to Officer</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb51bf5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14311/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The appointment of an officer to a higher grade may not be delayed under subsection (a) or (b) unless the officer is given written notice of the grounds for the delay. The preceding sentence does not apply if it is impracticable to give the officer written notice before the date on which the appointment to the higher grade would otherwise take effect, but in such a case the written notice shall be given as soon as practicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb51bf6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14311/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An officer whose promotion is delayed under subsection (a) or (b) shall be given an opportunity to make a written statement to the Secretary of the military department concerned in response to the action taken. The Secretary shall give consideration to any such statement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb51bf7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14311/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2), in the case of an officer whose promotion is delayed pursuant to subsection (a)(1)(F), requirements applicable to notice and opportunity for response to such delay are specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14502a/c/3">section 14502a(c)(3) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb51bf8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14311/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Maximum Length of Delay in Promotion</inline>.—</heading><content>The appointment of an officer to a higher grade may not be delayed under subsection (a) or (b) for more than six months after the date on which the officer would otherwise have been promoted unless the Secretary concerned specifies a further period of delay. An officer’s appointment may not be delayed more than 90 days after final action has been taken in any criminal case against the officer in a Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction or more than 90 days after final action has been taken in any court-martial case against the officer. Except for court action, a promotion may not be delayed more than 18 months after the date on which the officer would otherwise have been promoted.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb51bf9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14311/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Delay Because of Limitations on Officer Strength in Grade or Duties to Which Assigned</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb51bfa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14311/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the promotion of a reserve officer on the reserve active-status list who is serving on active duty, or who is on full-time National Guard duty for administration of the reserves or the National Guard, to a grade to which the strength limitations of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12011">section 12011 of this title</ref> apply shall be delayed if necessary to ensure compliance with those strength limitations. The delay shall expire when the Secretary determines that the delay is no longer required to ensure such compliance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb51bfb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14311/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The promotion of an officer described in paragraph (1) shall also be delayed while the officer is on duty described in that paragraph unless the Secretary of the military department concerned, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, determines that the duty assignment of the officer requires a higher grade than the grade currently held by the officer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb51bfc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14311/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The date of rank and position on the reserve active-status list of a reserve officer whose promotion to or Federal recognition in the next higher grade was delayed under paragraph (1) or (2) solely as the result of the limitations imposed under the regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense or contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12011">section 12011 of this title</ref> shall be the date on which the officer would have been promoted to or recognized in the higher grade had such limitations not existed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb51bfd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14311/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> If an officer whose promotion is delayed under paragraph (1) or (2) completes the period of active duty or full-time National Guard duty that the officer is required by law or regulation to perform as a member of a reserve component, the officer may request release from active duty or full-time National Guard duty. If the request is granted, the officer’s promotion shall be effective upon the officer’s release from such duty. The date of rank and position on the reserve active-status list of the officer shall be the date the officer would have been promoted to or recognized in the higher grade had the limitations imposed under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12011">section 12011 of this title</ref> not existed. If an officer whose promotion is delayed under paragraph (1) or (2) has not completed the period of active duty or full-time National Guard duty that the officer is required by law or regulation to perform as a member of a reserve component, the officer may be retained on active duty or on full-time National Guard duty in the grade in which the officer was serving before the officer’s being found qualified for Federal recognition or the officer’s selection for the promotion until the officer completes that required period of duty.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idabb51bfe-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tXVI/s1611">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2939">108 Stat. 2939</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tV/s505/c/2/B">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 505(c)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1088">115 Stat. 1088</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tV/s511/b">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 511(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2182">120 Stat. 2182</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/dA/tX/s1075/g/4">Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(g)(4)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4377">124 Stat. 4377</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tVIII/s809/a">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1840">132 Stat. 1840</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tV/s505/b/3">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 505(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3572">134 Stat. 3572</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idabb51bff-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idabb51c00-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idabb51c01-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in sections 3363(e), 3380(b), 5902(d), 8363(g), and 8380(b) of this title, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s1629/a/1">Pub. L. 103–337, § 1629(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(2), (c)(1).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idabb51c02-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (a)(1)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s505/b/3/A/i">Pub. L. 116–283, § 505(b)(3)(A)(i)</ref>, added subpar. (F).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s505/b/3/A/ii">Pub. L. 116–283, § 505(b)(3)(A)(ii)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s505/b/3/B">Pub. L. 116–283, § 505(b)(3)(B)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsecs. (a)(2), (b). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232">Pub. L. 115–232</ref> substituted “section 7233, 8167, or 9233” for “section 3583, 5947, or 8583” in subsec. (a)(2) and in two places in subsec. (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383">Pub. L. 111–383</ref> made technical amendment to directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s511/b/3">Pub. L. 109–364, § 511(b)(3)</ref>. See 2006 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s511/b/1">Pub. L. 109–364, § 511(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Secretary of Defense” for “Secretary of the military department concerned” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s511/b/2/A">Pub. L. 109–364, § 511(b)(2)(A)</ref>, added subpar. (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s511/b/2/B">Pub. L. 109–364, § 511(b)(2)(B)</ref>, struck out “or” after “show cause for retention,” and inserted “or if, after a review of substantiated adverse information about the officer regarding the requirement for exemplary conduct set forth in section 3583, 5947, or 8583 of this title, as applicable, the officer is determined to be among the officers best qualified for promotion,” after “of the charges,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s511/b/3">Pub. L. 109–364, § 511(b)(3)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s1075/g/4">Pub. L. 111–383, § 1075(g)(4)</ref>, inserted “has not met the requirement for exemplary conduct set forth in section 3583, 5947, or 8583 of this title, as applicable, or” before “is mentally, physically,” and substituted “If it is later determined by a civilian official of the Department of Defense (not below the level of Secretary of a military department) that the officer is qualified for promotion to the higher grade and, after a review of adverse information regarding the requirement for exemplary conduct set forth in section 3583, 5947, or 8583 of this title, as applicable, the officer is determined to be among the officers best qualified for promotion to the higher grade” for “If the Secretary concerned later determines that the officer is qualified for promotion to the higher grade”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s511/b/1">Pub. L. 109–364, § 511(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Secretary of Defense” for “Secretary of the military department concerned”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/s505/c/2/B/i">Pub. L. 107–107, § 505(c)(2)(B)(i)</ref>, inserted “(including an approved all-fully-qualified-officers list, if applicable)” after “on the promotion list”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/s505/c/2/B/ii">Pub. L. 107–107, § 505(c)(2)(B)(ii)</ref>, inserted “(including an approved all-fully-qualified-officers list, if applicable)” after “on the promotion list” in second sentence.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idabb51c03-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idabb51c04-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2018 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/115/232">Pub. L. 115–232</ref> effective <date date="2019-02-01">Feb. 1, 2019</date>, with provision for the coordination of amendments and special rule for certain redesignations, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s800">section 800 of Pub. L. 115–232</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idabb51c05-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2011 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/383/dA/tX/s1075/g">Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(g)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4376">124 Stat. 4376</ref>, provided that amendment by section 1075(g)(4) is effective as of <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, and as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/109/364">Pub. L. 109–364</ref> as enacted.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idabb51c06-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2006 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/364">Pub. L. 109–364</ref> effective <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, and applicable with respect to officers on promotion lists established on or after such date, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s511/e">section 511(e) of Pub. L. 109–364</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s624">section 624 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idabb51c07-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1996-10-01">Oct. 1, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s1691/b/1">section 1691(b)(1) of Pub. L. 103–337</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s10001">section 10001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idabb51c08-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Delays in Promotions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tXVI/s1684/a">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1684(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3024">108 Stat. 3024</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tXVI/s1684/a">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> A delay in a promotion that is in effect on the day before the effective date of this title [<date date="1996-10-01">Oct. 1, 1996</date>, see section 1691(b)(1), (2) of <ref href="/us/pl/103/337">Pub. L. 103–337</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s10001">section 10001 of this title</ref>] under the laws and regulations in effect on that date shall continue in effect on and after that date as if the promotion had been delayed under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14311">section 14311 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, as added by this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The delay of the promotion of a reserve officer of the Army or the Air Force which was in effect solely to achieve compliance with limitations set out in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s524">section 524 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, or with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense with respect to sections 3380(c) and 8380(c) of title 10, United States Code, as in effect on the day before the effective date of this title, shall continue in effect as if the promotion had been delayed under section 14311(e) of such title, as added by this title.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
