<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida76c285c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s144"><num value="144">§ 144.</num><heading> Director of Small Business Programs</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida76c285d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s144/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Director</inline>.—</heading><content>There is a Director of Small Business Programs in the Department of Defense. The Director is appointed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida76c285e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s144/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Office of Small Business Programs</inline>.—</heading><content>The Office of Small Business Programs of the Department of Defense is the office that is established within the Office of the Secretary of Defense under section 15(k) of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s644/k">15 U.S.C. 644(k)</ref>). The Director of Small Business Programs is the head of such office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida76c285f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s144/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Duties and Powers</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida76c2860-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s144/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Director of Small Business Programs shall, subject to paragraph (2), perform such duties regarding small business programs of the Department of Defense, and shall exercise such powers regarding those programs, as the Secretary of Defense may prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida76c2861-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s144/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Section 15(k) of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s644/k">15 U.S.C. 644(k)</ref>), except for the designations of the Director and the Office, applies to the Director of Small Business Programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida76c2862-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tIX/s904/b/1">Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title IX, § 904(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3400">119 Stat. 3400</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida76c2863-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida76c2864-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="ida76c2865-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tIX/s904/a">Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title IX, § 904(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3399">119 Stat. 3399</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tIX/s904/a">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Positions redesignated</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The following positions within the Department of Defense are redesignated as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The Director of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization of the Department of Defense is redesignated as the Director of Small Business Programs of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The Director of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization of the Department of the Army is redesignated as the Director of Small Business Programs of the Department of the Army.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> The Director of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization of the Department of the Navy is redesignated as the Director of Small Business Programs of the Department of the Navy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> The Director of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization of the Department of the Air Force is redesignated as the Director of Small Business Programs of the Department of the Air Force.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Offices redesignated</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The following offices within the Department of Defense are redesignated as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization of the Department of Defense is redesignated as the Office of Small Business Programs of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization of the Department of the Army is redesignated as the Office of Small Business Programs of the Department of the Army.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> The Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization of the Department of the Navy is redesignated as the Office of Small Business Programs of the Department of the Navy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> The Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization of the Department of the Air Force is redesignated as the Office of Small Business Programs of the Department of the Air Force.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">References</inline>.—</heading><content>Any reference in any law, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to a position or office redesignated by paragraph (1) or (2) shall be deemed to be a reference to the position or office as so redesignated.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida76c2866-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Establishment of Project Spectrum</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXVIII/s1807">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title XVIII, § 1807</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1240">139 Stat. 1240</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXVIII/s1807">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of the Office of Small Business Programs of the Department of Defense shall establish and maintain a program to be known as ‘Project Spectrum’ to provide to covered entities an online platform of digital resources, training, and services that increase awareness of, and facilitate compliance with, the requirements of the defense acquisition system established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3102">section 3102 of title 10</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement for Coordination</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In carrying out the requirements of subsection (a), the Director of Small Business Programs shall coordinate with other elements of the Department of Defense to ensure resources, training, or services made available through Project Spectrum are aligned with Department-wide policies and guidance related to the defense acquisition system, including coordination with—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the Chief Information Officer of the Department of Defense, particularly regarding cybersecurity resources and alignment with the Cybersecurity Maturity Model Certification program or successor program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for International and Industry Engagement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> the President of the Defense Acquisition University;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> the Director of the Defense Logistics Agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> the Director of the Defense Counterintelligence and Security Agency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> the Executive Director of the Department of Defense Cyber Crime Center.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Performance Metrics</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than <date date="2026-04-01">April 1, 2026</date>, the Director of Small Business Programs, in coordination with elements and individuals in subsection (b), shall establish performance metrics to measure the outcomes associated with Project Spectrum. Such metrics shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> cybersecurity-related activities and tools, to be evaluated in coordination with Chief Information Officer of the Department of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> foreign ownership, control, or influence activities and tools, to be evaluated in coordination with the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> any additional performance metrics the Director determines necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefing Required</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2026-05-01">May 1, 2026</date>, the Director of Small Business Programs shall provide to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives a briefing on the performance metrics required by subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sunset</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority for Project Spectrum, and the requirements of the section, shall terminate on <date date="2031-12-31">December 31, 2031</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered Entity Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘covered entity’ means an entity that is a small business or a medium business that contracts with, or seeks to enter into a contract with, the Department of Defense that is registered to access the online platform of Project Spectrum.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida76c2867-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Role of the Directors of Small Business Programs in Acquisition Processes of the Department of Defense</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dA/tXVI/s1611">Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2063">126 Stat. 2063</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/239/dA/tXVI/s1611">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guidance Required</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall develop and issue guidance to ensure that the head of each Office of Small Business Programs of the Department of Defense is a participant as early as practicable in the acquisition processes—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> of the Department, in the case of the Director of Small Business Programs in the Department of Defense; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> of the military department concerned, in the case of the Director of Small Business Programs in the Department of the Army, in the Department of the Navy, and in the Department of the Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Matters To Be Included</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Such guidance shall, at a minimum—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> require the Director of Small Business Programs in the Department of Defense—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> to provide advice to the Defense Acquisition Board; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> to provide advice to the Information Technology Acquisition Board; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> require coordination between the chiefs of staff of the Armed Forces and the service acquisition executives, as appropriate (or their designees), and the Director of Small Business Programs in each military department as early as practical in the relevant acquisition processes.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
