<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idabb766de-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14504"><num value="14504">§ 14504.</num><heading> Effect of failure of selection for promotion: reserve first lieutenants of the Army, Air Force, and Marine Corps and reserve lieutenants (junior grade) of the Navy</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb766df-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14504/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">General Rule</inline>.—</heading><content>A first lieutenant on the reserve active-status list of the Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps or a lieutenant (junior grade) on the reserve active-status list of the Navy who has failed of selection for promotion to the next higher grade for the second time and whose name is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion to the next higher grade shall be separated in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14513">section 14513 of this title</ref> not later than the first day of the seventh month after the month in which the Secretary concerned releases the promotion results of the board which considered the officer for the second time to the public.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb766e0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14504/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading><content>Subsection (a) does not apply (1) in the case of an officer retained as provided by regulation of the Secretary of the military department concerned in order to meet planned mobilization needs for a period not in excess of 24 months beginning with the date on which the Secretary concerned releases the promotion results of the board which considered the officer for the second time to the public, or (2) as provided in section 12646 or 12686 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb766e1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14504/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Officers in Grade of First Lieutenant or Lieutenant (Junior Grade) Found Not Fully Qualified for Promotion</inline>.—</heading><content>For the purposes of this chapter, an officer of the Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps on a reserve active-status list who holds the grade of first lieutenant, and an officer of the Navy on a reserve active-status list who holds the grade of lieutenant (junior grade), shall be treated as having failed of selection for promotion if the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that the officer would be eligible for consideration for promotion to the next higher grade by a selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14101/a">section 14101(a) of this title</ref> if such a board were convened but is not fully qualified for promotion when recommending for promotion under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14308/b/4">section 14308(b)(4) of this title</ref> all fully qualified officers of the officer’s armed force in such grade who would be eligible for such consideration.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idabb766e2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tXVI/s1611">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2950">108 Stat. 2950</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tV/s505/b/2">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 505(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1087">115 Stat. 1087</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tV/s505/b/4">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 505(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1870">138 Stat. 1870</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXVII/s1701/a/42">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(a)(42)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1210">139 Stat. 1210</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idabb766e3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idabb766e4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idabb766e5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60">Pub. L. 119–60</ref> substituted “the Secretary” for “the the Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s505/b/4/A">Pub. L. 118–159, § 505(b)(4)(A)</ref>, substituted “the Secretary concerned releases the promotion results of the board which considered the officer for the second time to the public” for “the President approves the report of the board which considered the officer for the second time”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s505/b/4/B">Pub. L. 118–159, § 505(b)(4)(B)</ref>, substituted “the Secretary concerned releases the promotion results of the board which considered the officer for the second time to the public” for “President approves the report of the selection board which resulted in the second failure”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/107/107">Pub. L. 107–107</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idabb766e6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idabb766e7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1996-10-01">Oct. 1, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s1691/b/1">section 1691(b)(1) of Pub. L. 103–337</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s10001">section 10001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
