<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idabb9d77c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14701"><num value="14701">§ 14701.</num><heading> Selection of officers for continuation on the reserve active-status list</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb9d77d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14701/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consideration for Continuation</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb9d77e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14701/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb9d77f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14701/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A reserve officer of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps described in subparagraph (B) who is required to be removed from the reserve active-status list under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14504">section 14504 of this title</ref>, or a reserve officer of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps who is required to be removed from the reserve active-status list under section 14505, 14506, or 14507 of this title, may be considered for continuation on the reserve active-status list under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb9d780-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14701/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> A reserve officer covered by this subparagraph is a reserve officer of the Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps who holds the grade of first lieutenant, or a reserve officer of the Navy who holds the grade of lieutenant (junior grade), and who—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb9d781-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14701/a/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> is a health professions officer; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idabb9d782-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14701/a/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> is actively pursuing an undergraduate program of education leading to a baccalaureate degree.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb9d783-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14701/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The consideration of a reserve officer for continuation on the reserve active-status list pursuant to this paragraph is subject to the needs of the service and to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14509">section 14509 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb9d784-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14701/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A reserve officer who holds the grade of captain in the Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps or the grade of lieutenant in the Navy and who is subject to separation under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14513">section 14513 of this title</ref> may not be continued on the reserve active-status list under this subsection for a period which extends beyond the last day of the month in which the officer completes 20 years of commissioned service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb9d785-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14701/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A reserve officer who holds the grade of major or lieutenant commander and who is subject to separation under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14513">section 14513 of this title</ref> may not be continued on the reserve active-status list under this subsection for a period which extends beyond the last day of the month in which the officer completes 24 years of commissioned service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb9d786-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14701/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> A reserve officer who holds the grade of lieutenant colonel or commander and who is subject to separation under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14514">section 14514 of this title</ref> may not be continued on the reserve active-status list under this subsection for a period which extends beyond the last day of the month in which the officer completes 33 years of commissioned service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb9d787-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14701/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> A reserve officer who holds the grade of colonel in the Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps or the grade of captain in the Navy and who is subject to separation under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14514">section 14514 of this title</ref> may not be continued on the reserve active-status list under this subsection for a period which extends beyond the last day of the month in which the officer completes 35 years of commissioned service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb9d788-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14701/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> An officer who is selected for continuation on the reserve active-status list under regulations prescribed under paragraph (1) but who declines to continue on that list shall be separated in accordance with section 14513 or 14514 of this title, as the case may be.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb9d789-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14701/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Each officer who is continued on the reserve active-status list under this section, who is not subsequently promoted or continued on the active-status list, and whose name is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion to the next higher grade shall (unless sooner separated under another provision of law) be separated in accordance with section 14513 or 14514 of this title, as appropriate, upon the expiration of the period for which the officer was continued on the reserve active-status list.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb9d78a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14701/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Continuation of Health Professions Officers</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb9d78b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14701/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding subsection (a)(6), a health professions officer obligated to a period of service incurred under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s16201">section 16201 of this title</ref> who is required to be removed from the reserve active-status list under section 14504, 14505, 14506, or 14507 of this title and who has not completed a service obligation incurred under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s16201">section 16201 of this title</ref> shall be retained on the reserve active-status list until the completion of such service obligation and then discharged, unless sooner retired or discharged under another provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb9d78c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14701/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary concerned may waive the applicability of paragraph (1) to any officer if the Secretary determines that completion of the service obligation of that officer is not in the best interest of the service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb9d78d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14701/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A health professions officer who is continued on the reserve active-status list under this subsection who is subsequently promoted or whose name is on a list of officers recommended for promotion to the next higher grade is not required to be discharged or retired upon completion of the officer’s service obligation. Such officer may continue on the reserve active-status list as other officers of the same grade unless separated under another provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idabb9d78e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s14701/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idabb9d78f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tXVI/s1611">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2954">108 Stat. 2954</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 522], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–108; <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tV/s511/a">Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 511(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1459">117 Stat. 1459</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tV/s511">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title V, § 511</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3357">128 Stat. 3357</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idabb9d790-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idabb9d791-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idabb9d792-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/s511/a">Pub. L. 113–291, § 511(a)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A), substituted “A reserve officer of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps described in subparagraph (B) who is required to be removed from the reserve active-status list under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14504">section 14504 of this title</ref>, or a reserve officer of” for “A reserve officer of” and “of this title, may” for “of this title may, subject to the needs of the service and to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14509">section 14509 of this title</ref>,”, and added subpars. (B) and (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/s511/b">Pub. L. 113–291, § 511(b)</ref>, added subsec. (b) and redesignated former subsec. (b) as (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/s511/a/1/A">Pub. L. 108–136, § 511(a)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense” for “by a selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14101/b">section 14101(b) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/s511/a/1/B">Pub. L. 108–136, § 511(a)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “under regulations prescribed under paragraph (1)” for “as a result of the convening of a selection board under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14101/b">section 14101(b) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b) to (d). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/s511/a/2">Pub. L. 108–136, § 511(a)(2)</ref>, (3), redesignated subsec. (d) as (b) and struck out former subsecs. (b) and (c) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(b) <inline class="small-caps">Approval of Secretary Concerned</inline>.—Continuation of an officer on the reserve active-status list under this section pursuant to action of a continuation board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14101/b">section 14101(b) of this title</ref> is subject to the approval of the Secretary of the military department concerned.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(c) <inline class="small-caps">Instructions To Continuation Boards</inline>.—A continuation board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14101/b">section 14101(b) of this title</ref> to consider officers for continuation on the reserve active-status list under this section shall act in accordance with the instructions and directions provided to the board by the Secretary of the military department concerned.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/106/398">Pub. L. 106–398</ref> substituted “A reserve officer” for “Upon application, a reserve officer”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idabb9d793-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idabb9d794-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1996-10-01">Oct. 1, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s1691/b/1">section 1691(b)(1) of Pub. L. 103–337</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s10001">section 10001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
