<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida8d8ff1f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482"><num value="1482">§ 1482.</num><heading> Expenses incident to death</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8d8ff20-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> Incident to the recovery, care, and disposition of the remains of any decedent covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1481">section 1481 of this title</ref>, the Secretary concerned may pay the necessary expenses of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff21-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Recovery and identification of the remains.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff22-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Notification to the next of kin or other appropriate person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff23-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Preparation of the remains for burial, including cremation if requested by the person designated to direct disposition of the remains.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff24-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Furnishing of a uniform or other clothing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff25-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Furnishing of a casket or urn, or both, with outside box.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff26-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Hearse service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff27-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Funeral director’s services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff28-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff29-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/a/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Transportation of the remains, and travel and transportation allowances as specified in regulations prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t37/s464">section 464 of title 37</ref> for an escort of one person, to the place, subject to subparagraph (B), selected by the person designated to direct disposition of the remains or, if such a selection is not made, to a national or other cemetery which is selected by the Secretary and in which burial of the decedent is authorized.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff2a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/a/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The person designated to direct disposition of the remains may select two places under subparagraph (A) if the second place is a national cemetery. If that person selects two places, the Secretary concerned may pay for transportation to the second place only by means of reimbursement under subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff2b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/a/8/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> When transportation of the remains includes transportation by aircraft under section 562 of the John Warner National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2007 (<ref href="/us/pl/109/364">Public Law 109–364</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1482">10 U.S.C. 1482</ref> note), the Secretary concerned shall provide, to the maximum extent practicable, for delivery of the remains by air to the commercial, general aviation, or military airport nearest to the place selected by the designee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff2c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> Interment or inurnment of the remains.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff2d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> In the case of a decedent under the jurisdiction of a Secretary of a military department at the time of death, enduring care of remains interred in a foreign cemetery if the burial location was designated by such Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff2e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/a/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff2f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/a/11/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Delivery of personal effects of a decedent to the next of kin or other appropriate person.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff30-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/a/11/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> If the Secretary concerned enters into an agreement with an entity to carry out subparagraph (A), the Secretary concerned may, at the request of the person described in such subparagraph, pursue a claim against such entity that arises from the failure of such entity to substantially perform such subparagraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff31-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/a/11/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> If an entity described in subparagraph (B) fails to substantially perform subparagraph (A) by damaging, losing, or destroying the personal effects of a decedent, the Secretary concerned shall reimburse the person designated under subsection (c) the greater of $1,000 or the fair market value of such damage, loss, or destruction. The Secretary concerned may request, from the person designated under subsection (c), proof of fair market value and ownership of the personal effects.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8d8ff32-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> If an individual pays any expense payable by the United States under this section, the Secretary concerned shall reimburse him or his representative in an amount not larger than that normally incurred by the Secretary in furnishing the supply or service concerned. If reimbursement by the United States is also authorized under another provision of law or regulation, the individual may elect under which provision to be reimbursed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8d8ff33-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><chapeau> The following persons may be designated to direct disposition of the remains of a decedent covered by this chapter:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff34-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The person identified by the decedent on the record of emergency data maintained by the Secretary concerned (DD Form 93 or any successor to that form), as the Person Authorized to Direct Disposition (PADD), regardless of the relationship of the designee to the decedent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff35-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The surviving spouse of the decedent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff36-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Blood relatives of the decedent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff37-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Adoptive relatives of the decedent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff38-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> If no person covered by paragraphs (1) through (4) can be found, a person standing in loco parentis to the decedent.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8d8ff39-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><chapeau> When the remains of a decedent covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1481">section 1481 of this title</ref>, whose death occurs after <date date="1961-01-01">January 1, 1961</date>, are determined to be nonrecoverable, the person who would have been designated under subsection (c) to direct disposition of the remains if they had been recovered may be—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff3a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> presented with a flag of the United States; however, if the person designated by subsection (c) is other than a parent of the deceased member, a flag of equal size may also be presented to the parents, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff3b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> reimbursed by the Secretary concerned for the necessary expenses of a memorial service.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">However, the amount of the reimbursement shall be determined in the manner prescribed in subsection (b) for an interment, but may not be larger than that authorized when the United States provides the grave site. A claim for reimbursement under this subsection may be allowed only if it is presented within two years after the date of death or the date the person who would have been designated under subsection (c) to direct disposition of the remains, if they had been recovered, receives notification that the member has been reported or determined to be dead under authority of chapter 10 of title 37, whichever is later.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8d8ff3c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Presentation of Flag of the United States</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8d8ff3d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In the case of a decedent covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1481">section 1481 of this title</ref>, the Secretary concerned may pay the necessary expenses for the presentation of a flag of the United States to the following persons:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff3e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The person designated under subsection (c) to direct disposition of the remains of the decedent.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff3f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The parents or parent of the decedent, if the person to be presented a flag under subparagraph (A) is other than a parent of the decedent.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff40-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The surviving spouse of the decedent (including a surviving spouse who remarries after the decedent’s death), if the person to be presented a flag under subparagraph (A) is other than the surviving spouse.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff41-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/e/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Each child of the decedent, regardless of whether the person to be presented a flag under subparagraph (A) is a child of the decedent.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8d8ff42-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Secretary concerned may pay the necessary expenses for the presentation of a flag to the person designated to direct the disposition of the remains of a member of the Reserve of an armed force under his jurisdiction who dies under honorable circumstances as determined by the Secretary and who is not covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1481">section 1481 of this title</ref> if, at the time of such member’s death, he—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff43-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> was a member of the Ready Reserve; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff44-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> had performed at least twenty years of service as computed under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12732">section 12732 of this title</ref> and was not entitled to retired pay under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12731">section 12731 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8d8ff45-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A flag to be presented to a person under subparagraph (B), (C), or (D) of paragraph (1) shall be of equal size to the flag presented under subparagraph (A) of such paragraph to the person designated to direct disposition of the remains of the decedent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8d8ff46-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> This subsection does not apply to a military prisoner who dies while in the custody of the Secretary concerned and while under a sentence that includes a discharge.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8d8ff47-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> In this subsection:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff48-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/e/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The term “parent” includes a natural parent, a stepparent, a parent by adoption, or a person who for a period of not less than one year before the death of the decedent stood in loco parentis to the decedent. Preference under paragraph (1)(B) shall be given to the persons who exercised a parental relationship at the time of, or most nearly before, the death of the decedent.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8d8ff49-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/e/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The term “child” has the meaning prescribed by <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1477/d">section 1477(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8d8ff4a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> The payment of expenses incident to the recovery, care, and disposition of a decedent covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1481/a/9">section 1481(a)(9) of this title</ref> is limited to the payment of expenses described in paragraphs (1) through (5) of subsection (a) and air transportation of the remains from a location outside the United States to a point of entry in the United States. Such air transportation may be provided without reimbursement on a space-available basis in military or military-chartered aircraft. The Secretary concerned may pay any other expenses relating to the remains of such a decedent that are authorized to be paid under this section only on a reimbursable basis. Amounts reimbursed to the Secretary concerned under this subsection shall be credited to appropriations available, at the time of reimbursement, for the payment of such expenses.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8d8ff4b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8d8ff4c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The payment of expenses incident to the recovery, care, and disposition of the remains of a decedent covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1481/a/10">section 1481(a)(10) of this title</ref> is limited to those expenses that, as determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, would not have been incurred but for the retention of those remains for purposes of a forensic pathology investigation by the Armed Forces Medical Examiner under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1471">section 1471 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8d8ff4d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In a case covered by paragraph (1), if the person designated under subsection (c) to direct disposition of the remains of a decedent does not direct disposition of the remains that were retained for the forensic pathology investigation, the Secretary may pay for the transportation of those remains to, and interment or inurnment of those remains in, an appropriate place selected by the Secretary, in lieu of the transportation authorized to be paid under paragraph (8) of subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8d8ff4e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In a case covered by paragraph (1), expenses that may be paid do not include expenses with respect to an escort under paragraph (8) of subsection (a), whether or not on a reimbursable basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8d8ff4f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1482/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Secretary concerned may pay any other expenses relating to the remains of such a decedent that are authorized to be paid under this section on a reimbursable basis. Amounts reimbursed to the Secretary concerned under this subsection shall be credited to appropriations available at the time of reimbursement for the payment of such expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida8d8ff50-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(<ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041">Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/113">70A Stat. 113</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/716">Pub. L. 85–716</ref>, <date date="1958-08-21">Aug. 21, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/708">72 Stat. 708</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/397">Pub. L. 91–397</ref>, <date date="1970-09-01">Sept. 1, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/837">84 Stat. 837</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/487">Pub. L. 91–487</ref>, <date date="1970-10-22">Oct. 22, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1086">84 Stat. 1086</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/292">Pub. L. 93–292</ref>, <date date="1974-05-28">May 28, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/176">88 Stat. 176</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/649">Pub. L. 93–649</ref>, <date date="1975-01-08">Jan. 8, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2361">88 Stat. 2361</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tVI">Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title VI</ref>, §§ 652(a)(3), 653(a)(6), title XVI, § 1622(c)(4), <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1461">103 Stat. 1461</ref>, 1462, 1604; <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tVI/s652/a/2">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title VI, § 652(a)(2)</ref>, title XVI, § 1671(c)(8), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2793">108 Stat. 2793</ref>, 3014; <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tXV/s1501/c/19">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(c)(19)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/499">110 Stat. 499</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tVI/s638/b/1">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title VI, § 638(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1147">115 Stat. 1147</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/181/dA/tV/s591">Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 591</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/138">122 Stat. 138</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/417">Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title V, § 581, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4472">122 Stat. 4472</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/dA/tV/s528">Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 528</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1402">125 Stat. 1402</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tVI">Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title VI</ref>, §§ 621(e), 651(a)(2)–(c), <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/784">127 Stat. 784</ref>, 787, 788; <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tVI/s632">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VI, § 632</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1431">131 Stat. 1431</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tV/s573/a">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 573(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1404">133 Stat. 1404</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tVI/s641">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VI, § 641</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2633">136 Stat. 2633</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida8d8ff51-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note topic="historicalAndRevision" id="ida8d8ff52-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<html:table class="HNR" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc: c3,L2,tp7,s10,xls80,xs80,tp7,s10,xls80,xs80; " id="ida8d8ff53-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 38pt;" />
<html:col style="width:84pt ; max-width:84pt;" />
<html:col style="width:84pt ; max-width:84pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style=""><html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Historical and Revision Notes</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="min-width: 38.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Revised section</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:84.0pt ; max-width:84.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (U.S. Code)</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:84.0pt ; max-width:84.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (Statutes at Large)</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em; margin-bottom:0em;" class="leaders"><html:span>1482(a)</html:span></html:p><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em; margin-bottom:0em; margin-top:0em;"> </html:p><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em; margin-bottom:0em; margin-top:0em;"> </html:p><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em; margin-bottom:0em; margin-top:0em;"> </html:p><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em; margin-bottom:0em; margin-top:0em;"> </html:p><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em; margin-bottom:0em; margin-top:0em;"> </html:p><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em; margin-bottom:0em; margin-top:0em;" class="leaders"><html:span>1482(b)</html:span></html:p><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em; margin-bottom:0em; margin-top:0em;"> </html:p><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em; margin-top:0em;" class="leaders"><html:span>1482(c)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em; margin-bottom:0em;">5:2152 (less 1st 27 words, as applicable to armed forces).</html:p><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em; margin-bottom:0em; margin-top:0em;">5:2153 (1st 18 words, as applicable to armed forces).</html:p><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em; margin-bottom:0em; margin-top:0em;">5:2161 (as applicable to armed forces).</html:p><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em; margin-top:0em;">5:2162 (as applicable to armed forces).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:a href="/us/act/1954-07-15/ch507">July 15, 1954, ch. 507</html:a>, §§ 2 (less 1st 25 words, as applicable to armed forces), 3 (1st 16 words, as applicable to armed forces), 11 (as applicable to armed forces), 12 (as applicable to armed forces), <html:a href="/us/stat/68/478">68 Stat. 478</html:a>, 480, 481.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (a), the list of payable expenses has been rearranged to produce a generally chronological result. The words “person designated” are substituted for the words “person recognized as the person.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (a)(4), the words “articles of” are omitted as surplusage.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (a)(8), the word “place” is substituted for the words “town or city”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (a)(10), the words “other than honorable” are omitted, since a person cannot be sentenced to an honorable discharge.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (b), the words “If an individual pays” are substituted for the words “In any case where expenses * * * are borne by individuals”. The second sentence of 5:2161 is omitted as executed. The last sentence is substituted for the last sentence of 5:2161.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (c), 5:2162 (1st sentence) is omitted since the Secretary has inherent authority to issue regulations appropriate to exercising his statutory functions. The introductory language is substituted for 5:2162 (1st 22 words of 2d sentence). The words “ascertained and” are omitted as surplusage.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida8db6f54-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida8db6f55-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (a)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Pub. L. 117–263</ref> added par. (11).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (a)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Pub. L. 116–92</ref> amended par. (8) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (8) read as follows: “Transportation of the remains, and travel and transportation allowances as specified in regulations prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t37/s464">section 464 of title 37</ref> for an escort of one person, to the place selected by the person designated to direct disposition of the remains or, if such a selection is not made, to a national or other cemetery which is selected by the Secretary and in which burial of the decedent is authorized. When transportation of the remains includes transportation by aircraft under section 562 of the John Warner National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2007 (<ref href="/us/pl/109/364">Public Law 109–364</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1482">10 U.S.C. 1482</ref> note), the Secretary concerned shall provide, to the maximum extent practicable, for delivery of the remains by air to the commercial, general aviation, or military airport nearest to the place selected by the designee.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—Subsec. (a)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91">Pub. L. 115–91</ref> added par. (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (a)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s621/e">Pub. L. 113–66, § 621(e)</ref>, substituted “and travel and transportation allowances as specified in regulations prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t37/s464">section 464 of title 37</ref>” for “and roundtrip transportation and prescribed allowances”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s651/b">Pub. L. 113–66, § 651(b)</ref>, inserted “or inurnment” after “Interment”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s651/c">Pub. L. 113–66, § 651(c)</ref>, substituted “The Secretary concerned may pay any other expenses relating to the remains of such a decedent that are authorized to be paid under this section only on a reimbursable basis.” for “The Secretary concerned shall pay all other expenses authorized to be paid under this subsection only on a reimbursable basis.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s651/a/2">Pub. L. 113–66, § 651(a)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/112/81">Pub. L. 112–81</ref> substituted “The” for “Only the” in introductory provisions, added par. (1), redesignated former pars. (1) to (4) as (2) to (5), respectively, and substituted “paragraphs (1) through (4)” for “clauses (1)–(3)” in par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (a)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/110/181">Pub. L. 110–181</ref> inserted at end “When transportation of the remains includes transportation by aircraft under section 562 of the John Warner National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2007 (<ref href="/us/pl/109/364">Public Law 109–364</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1482">10 U.S.C. 1482</ref> note), the Secretary concerned shall provide, to the maximum extent practicable, for delivery of the remains by air to the commercial, general aviation, or military airport nearest to the place selected by the designee.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(10), (11). <ref href="/us/pl/110/417/s581/b">Pub. L. 110–417, § 581(b)</ref>, struck out pars. (10) and (11) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(10) Presentation of a flag of the United States to the person designated to direct disposition of the remains, except in the case of a military prisoner who dies while in the custody of the Secretary and while under a sentence that includes a discharge.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(11) Presentation of a flag of equal size to the flag presented under paragraph (10) to the parents or parent, if the person to be presented a flag under paragraph (10) is other than the parent of the decedent. For the purpose of this paragraph, the term ‘parent’ includes a natural parent, a stepparent, a parent by adoption or a person who for a period of not less than one year before the death of the decedent stood in loco parentis to him, and preference under this paragraph shall be given to the persons who exercised a parental relationship at the time of, or most nearly before, the death of the decedent.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/110/417/s581/a">Pub. L. 110–417, § 581(a)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (2), redesignated former pars. (1) and (2) of subsec. (e) as subpars. (A) and (B), respectively, of par. (2), inserted subsec. (e) heading, and added pars. (1) and (3) to (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsecs. (d) to (g). <ref href="/us/pl/107/107">Pub. L. 107–107</ref> redesignated subsecs. (e) to (g) as (d) to (f), respectively, and struck out former subsec. (d) which read as follows: “When, as a result of a disaster involving the multiple deaths of persons covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1481">section 1481 of this title</ref>, the Secretary concerned has possession of commingled remains that cannot be individually identified, and burial of those remains in a common grave in a national cemetery is considered necessary, he may, for the interment services of each known decedent, pay the expenses of round-trip transportation to the cemetery of (1) the person who would have been designated under subsection (c) to direct disposition of the remains if individual identification had been made, and (2) two additional persons selected by that person who are closely related to the decedent. The transportation expenses authorized to be paid under this subsection may not exceed the transportation allowances authorized for members of the armed forces for travel on official business, but no per diem allowance may be paid.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106">Pub. L. 104–106</ref> inserted “section” before “12731”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s1671/c/8">Pub. L. 103–337, § 1671(c)(8)</ref>, substituted “section 12732” for “section 1332” and “12731” for “section 1331”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s652/a/2">Pub. L. 103–337, § 652(a)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/s653/a/6/A">Pub. L. 101–189, § 653(a)(6)(A)</ref>, substituted  “expenses  of  the  following:”  for  “expenses of—” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1) to (9). <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/s653/a/6/B">Pub. L. 101–189, § 653(a)(6)(B)</ref>, (C), in each of pars. (1) to (9), capitalized first letter of first word and substituted period for semicolon at the end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/s653/a/6/B">Pub. L. 101–189, § 653(a)(6)(B)</ref>, (D), capitalized first letter of first word and substituted period for “; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/s653/a/6/B">Pub. L. 101–189, § 653(a)(6)(B)</ref>, (E), capitalized first letter of first word, substituted “paragraph” for “clause” in four places, and substituted “decedent. For the” for “decedent; for the”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/189">Pub. L. 101–189</ref>, §§ 652(a)(3), 1622(c)(4), substituted “the date of death” for “the effective date of this subsection, or the date of death,” and “chapter 10 of title 37” for “chapter 10, title 37” in last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/93/649">Pub. L. 93–649</ref> inserted provision relating to date of notification of death under authority of chapter 10, title 37, to that person who would have been designated under subsection (c) to direct disposition of the remains, had they been recovered.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/93/292">Pub. L. 93–292</ref> added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (a)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/91/397">Pub. L. 91–397</ref> added cl. (11).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/91/487">Pub. L. 91–487</ref> added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/85/716">Pub. L. 85–716</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida8db6f56-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida8db6f57-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tXV/s1501/c">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/498">110 Stat. 498</ref>, provided that the amendment made by that section is effective as of <date date="1994-12-01">Dec. 1, 1994</date>, and as if included as an amendment made by the Reserve Officer Personnel Management Act, title XVI of <ref href="/us/pl/103/337">Pub. L. 103–337</ref>, as originally enacted.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida8db6f58-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s652/a/2">section 652(a)(2) of Pub. L. 103–337</ref> applicable with respect to remains of, and incidental expenses incident to recovery, care, and disposition of, an individual who dies after <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s652/a/3">section 652(a)(3) of Pub. L. 103–337</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1481">section 1481 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s1671/c/8">section 1671(c)(8) of Pub. L. 103–337</ref> effective <date date="1994-12-01">Dec. 1, 1994</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s1691">section 1691 of Pub. L. 103–337</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s10001">section 10001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida8db6f59-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Department of Defense Policy and Procedures on Media Access at Ceremonies for Dignified Transfer of Remains of Members of the Armed Forces Who Die Overseas</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/84/dA/tV/s542/a">Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 542(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2299">123 Stat. 2299</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/84/dA/tV/s542/a">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Policy required</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2010-04-01">April 1, 2010</date>, the Secretary of Defense shall prescribe a policy guaranteeing media access at ceremonies for the dignified transfer of remains of members of the Armed Forces who die while located or serving overseas (in this section referred to as ‘military decedents’) when approved by the primary next of kin of such military decedents.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Procedures</inline>.—</heading><content>The policy developed under paragraph (1) shall include procedures to be followed by the military departments in conducting appropriate ceremonies for the dignified transfer of remains of military decedents. The procedures shall be uniform across the military departments except to the extent necessary to reflect the traditional practices or customs of a particular military department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The policy developed under paragraph (1) shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Provision for access by media representatives to transfers described in paragraph (1) if approved in advance by the primary next of kin of the military decedent or their designee.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Procedures for designating with certainty who is authorized to make the decision to approve media access at transfer ceremonies described in that paragraph under reasonable, foreseeable circumstances.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Conditions for coverage that media representatives must comply with during such transfer ceremonies, and procedures for ensuring agreement in advance by media representatives with the conditions for coverage prescribed by military authorities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Procedures for the waiver by the primary next of kin or other designees of Departmental polices relating to delays in release of casualty information to the media and general public, when such waiver is required.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida8db6f5a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Transportation of Remains of Casualties</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tV/s580A/b">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 580A(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1408">133 Stat. 1408</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tV/s573">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 573</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2601">136 Stat. 2601</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tV/s573">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transportation for Family</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall extend travel privileges via Invitational Travel Authorization to family members of members of the Armed Forces who die outside of the United States and whose remains are returned to the United States through the mortuary facility at Dover Air Force Base, Delaware.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transportation of Deceased Military Member</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In the event of a death that requires the Secretary concerned to provide a death benefit under subchapter II of chapter 75 of title 10, United States Code, such Secretary—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> shall provide the next of kin or other appropriate person a commercial air travel use waiver for the transportation of deceased remains of military member who dies outside of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a theater of combat operations; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> may provide the next of kin or other appropriate person a commercial air travel use waiver for the transportation of deceased remains of military member who dies inside a theater of combat operations.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tV/s562">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 562</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2220">120 Stat. 2220</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tV">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 573(b), 580A(a), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1404">133 Stat. 1404</ref>, 1408, <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tVI/s642">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title VI, § 642</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/912">139 Stat. 912</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tVI/s642">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Required Transportation</inline>.—</heading><content>In the case of a member of the Armed Forces who dies outside of the United States and whose remains are returned to the United States through the mortuary facility at Dover Air Force Base, Delaware, the Secretary concerned, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, shall provide transportation of the remains of that member from Dover Air Force Base to the applicable escorted remains destination in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1482/a/8">section 1482(a)(8) of title 10</ref>, United States Code, and this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Escorted Remains Destination</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘escorted remains destination’ means the place to which remains are authorized to be transported under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1482/a/8">section 1482(a)(8) of title 10</ref>, United States Code. If the person designated to direct disposition of the remains selects two places under such section, the term means only the first of those two places.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Air Transportation From Dover AFB.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Military transportation</inline>.—</heading><content>If transportation of remains under subsection (a) includes transportation by air, such transportation (except as provided under paragraph (2)) shall be made by military aircraft or military-contracted aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Alternative transportation by aircraft</inline>.—</heading><content>The provisions of paragraph (1) shall not be applicable to the transportation of remains by air to the extent that the person designated to direct disposition of the remains directs otherwise.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Primary mission</inline>.—</heading><content>When remains are transported by military aircraft or military-contracted aircraft under this section, the primary mission of the aircraft providing that transportation shall be the transportation of such remains. However, more than one set of remains may be transported on the same flight.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary concerned may waive the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (3) as the Secretary considers necessary to meet mission requirements during—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a time of war;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a national emergency requiring the use of significant personnel and aircraft;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> a large-scale combat operation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> a contingency operation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Escort.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary concerned shall ensure that remains transported under this section are continuously escorted from Dover Air Force Base to the applicable escorted remains destination by a member of the Armed Forces in an appropriate grade, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other escort</inline>.—</heading><content>If a specific military escort is requested by the person designated to direct disposition of such remains and the Secretary approves that request, then the Secretary is not required to provide an additional military escort under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Honor Guard Detail.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Provision of detail</inline>.—</heading><content>Except in a case in which the person designated to direct disposition of remains requests that no military honor guard be present, the Secretary concerned shall ensure that an honor guard detail is provided in each case of the transportation of remains under this section. The honor guard detail shall be in addition to the escort provided for the transportation of remains under section (d).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Composition</inline>.—</heading><content>An honor guard detail provided under this section shall consist of sufficient members of the Armed Forces to perform the duties specified in paragraph (3). The members of the honor guard detail shall be in uniform.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Except to the extent that the person designated to direct disposition of remains requests that any of the following functions not be performed, an honor guard detail under this section—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> travel with the remains during transportation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> meet the remains at the place to which transportation by air (or by rail or motor vehicle, if applicable) is made for the transfer of the remains;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> shall provide appropriate honors at the arrival of the remains referred to in subparagraph (A)(ii) (unless airline or other security requirements do not permit such honors to be provided); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> shall participate in the transfer of the remains from an aircraft, when airport and airline security requirements permit, by carrying out the remains with a flag draped over the casket to a hearse or other form of ground transportation for travel to a funeral home or other place designated by the person designated to direct disposition of such remains.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secretary Concerned Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘Secretary concerned’ has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101/a/9">section 101(a)(9) of title 10</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effective Date</inline>.—</heading><content>This section shall take effect at such time as may be prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, but not later than <date date="2007-01-01">January 1, 2007</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
