<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida8ddba02-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501"><num value="1501">§ 1501.</num><heading> System for accounting for missing persons</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8ddba03-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Responsibility for Missing Persons</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8ddba04-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8ddba05-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall designate a single organization within the Department of Defense to have responsibility for Department matters relating to missing persons from past conflicts, including accounting for missing persons and persons whose remains have not been recovered from the conflict in which they were lost.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8ddba06-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The organization designated under this paragraph shall be a Defense Agency or other entity of the Department of Defense outside the military departments and is referred to in this chapter as the “designated Defense Agency”.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8ddba07-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The head of the organization designated under this paragraph is referred to in this chapter as the “designated Agency Director”.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8ddba08-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of Defense, the responsibilities of the designated Agency Director shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8ddba09-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Policy, control, and oversight of the program established under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1509">section 1509 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8ddba0a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Responsibility for accounting for missing persons from past conflicts, including locating, recovering, and identifying missing persons from past conflicts or their remains after hostilities have ceased.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8ddba0b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Coordination for the Department of Defense with other departments and agencies of the United States on all matters concerning missing persons from past conflicts.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8ddba0c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Dissemination of appropriate information on the status of missing persons from past conflicts to authorized family members.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8ddba0d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/a/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Establishment of a means for communication between officials of the designated Defense Agency and family members of missing persons from past conflicts, veterans service organizations, concerned citizens, and the public on the Department’s efforts to account for missing persons from past conflicts, including a readily available means for communication of their views and recommendations to the designated Agency Director.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8ddba0e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In carrying out the responsibilities established under this subsection, the designated Agency Director shall be responsible for the coordination for such purposes within the Department of Defense among the military departments, the Joint Staff, and the commanders of the combatant commands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8ddba0f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The designated Agency Director shall establish policies, which shall apply uniformly throughout the Department of Defense, for personnel accounting (including locating, recovering, and identifying missing persons from past conflicts or their remains after hostilities have ceased).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8ddba10-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Uniform DoD Procedures</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8ddba11-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe procedures, to apply uniformly throughout the Department of Defense, for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8ddba12-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the determination of the status of persons described in subsection (c); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8ddba13-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> for the systematic, comprehensive, and timely collection, analysis, review, dissemination, and periodic update of information related to such persons.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8ddba14-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Such procedures may provide for the delegation by the Secretary of Defense of any responsibility of the Secretary under this chapter to the Secretary of a military department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8ddba15-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Such procedures shall be prescribed in a single directive applicable to all elements of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8ddba16-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> As part of such procedures, the Secretary may provide for the extension, on a case-by-case basis, of any time limit specified in section 1502, 1503, or 1504 of this title. Any such extension may not be for a period in excess of the period with respect to which the extension is provided. Subsequent extensions may be provided on the same basis.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8ddba17-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered Persons</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8ddba18-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1502">Section 1502 of this title</ref> applies in the case of any member of the armed forces on active duty—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8ddba19-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> who becomes involuntarily absent as a result of a hostile action or under circumstances suggesting that the involuntary absence is a result of a hostile action; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8ddba1a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> whose status is undetermined or who is unaccounted for.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8ddba1b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1502">Section 1502 of this title</ref> applies in the case of any other person who is a citizen of the United States and a civilian officer or employee of the Department of Defense or (subject to paragraph (3)) an employee of a contractor of the Department of Defense—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8ddba1c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> who serves in direct support of, or accompanies, the armed forces in the field under orders and becomes involuntarily absent as a result of a hostile action or under circumstances suggesting that the involuntary absence is a result of a hostile action; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8ddba1d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> whose status is undetermined or who is unaccounted for.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8ddba1e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall determine, with regard to a pending or ongoing military operation, the specific employees, or groups of employees, of contractors of the Department of Defense to be considered to be covered by this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8ddba1f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Primary Next of Kin</inline>.—</heading><content>The individual who is primary next of kin of any person described in subsection (c) may for purposes of this chapter designate another individual to act on behalf of that individual as primary next of kin. The Secretary concerned shall treat an individual so designated as if the individual designated were the primary next of kin for purposes of this chapter. A designation under this subsection may be revoked at any time by the person who made the designation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8ddba20-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination of Applicability of Procedures When Missing Person Is Accounted for</inline>.—</heading><content>The provisions of this chapter relating to boards of inquiry and to the actions by the Secretary concerned on the reports of those boards shall cease to apply in the case of a missing person upon the person becoming accounted for or otherwise being determined to be in a status other than missing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8ddba21-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1501/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secretary Concerned</inline>.—</heading><content>In this chapter, the term “Secretary concerned” includes, in the case of a civilian officer or employee of the Department of Defense or an employee of a contractor of the Department of Defense, the Secretary of the military department or head of the element of the Department of Defense employing the officer or employee or contracting with the contractor, as the case may be.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida8ddba22-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tV/s569/b/1">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 569(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/336">110 Stat. 336</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tV/s578/a/1">Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title V, § 578(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2536">110 Stat. 2536</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tV/s599/a/1">Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title V, § 599(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1766">111 Stat. 1766</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tX/s1066/a/13">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1066(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/771">113 Stat. 771</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tV/s551">Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title V, § 551</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2551">116 Stat. 2551</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/dA/tV/s582/a">Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 582(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1928">118 Stat. 1928</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/dA/tIX/s901/g">Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title IX, § 901(g)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4322">124 Stat. 4322</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tV/s581/a">Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title V, § 581(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/773">127 Stat. 773</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tIX/s916/a">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title IX, § 916(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3476">128 Stat. 3476</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tIX/s953/a">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title IX, § 953(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2376">130 Stat. 2376</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida8ddba23-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida8ddba24-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida8ddba25-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s953/a/1">Pub. L. 114–328, § 953(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “from past conflicts” after “matters relating to missing persons”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s953/a/2/A">Pub. L. 114–328, § 953(a)(2)(A)</ref>, (B), redesignated subpar. (B) as (A) and struck out former subpar. (A) which read as follows: “Policy, control, and oversight within the Department of Defense of the entire process for investigation and recovery related to missing persons, including matters related to search, rescue, escape, and evasion.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s953/a/2/B">Pub. L. 114–328, § 953(a)(2)(B)</ref>, (C), redesignated subpar. (C) as (B) and inserted “from past conflicts” after “missing persons” in two places. Former subpar. (B) redesignated (A).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(C), (D). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s953/a/2/B">Pub. L. 114–328, § 953(a)(2)(B)</ref>, redesignated subpars. (D) and (E) as (C) and (D), respectively. Former subpar. (C) redesignated (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(E), (F). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s953/a/2/B">Pub. L. 114–328, § 953(a)(2)(B)</ref>, (C), redesignated subpar. (F) as (E) and inserted “from past conflicts” after “missing persons” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s953/a/3/B">Pub. L. 114–328, § 953(a)(3)(B)</ref>, inserted “from past conflicts” after “missing persons”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s953/a/3/A">Pub. L. 114–328, § 953(a)(3)(A)</ref>, which directed striking out “for personal recovery (including search, rescue, escape, and evasion) and” was executed by striking out “for personnel recovery (including search, rescue, escape, and evasion) and” after “Department of Defense,”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s953/a/4">Pub. L. 114–328, § 953(a)(4)</ref>, struck out par. (5) which read as follows: “The designated Agency Director shall establish procedures to be followed by Department of Defense boards of inquiry, and by officials reviewing the reports of such boards, under this chapter.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/113/291">Pub. L. 113–291</ref> amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) related to responsibility for missing personnel, consisting of pars. (1) to (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (a)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66">Pub. L. 113–66</ref> added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s901/g/1">Pub. L. 111–383, § 901(g)(1)</ref>, substituted “Responsibility for Missing Personnel” for “Office for Missing Personnel” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s901/g/2/A">Pub. L. 111–383, § 901(g)(2)(A)</ref>–(C), in introductory provisions, substituted “designate within the Office of the Secretary of Defense an official as the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Prisoner of War/Missing Personnel Affairs to have responsibility for Department of Defense matters” for “establish within the Office of the Secretary of Defense an office to have responsibility for Department of Defense policy”, struck out “Such office shall be known as the Defense Prisoner of War/Missing Personnel Office.” after “persons.”, and substituted “of the official designated under this paragraph” for “of the office”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(B), (C). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s901/g/2/D">Pub. L. 111–383, § 901(g)(2)(D)</ref>–(F), added subpar. (B) and redesignated former subpar. (B) as (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s901/g/4">Pub. L. 111–383, § 901(g)(4)</ref>, added par. (2). Former par. (2) redesignated (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s901/g/3">Pub. L. 111–383, § 901(g)(3)</ref>, (5), redesignated par. (2) as (3), struck out “of the office” after “responsibilities”, and substituted “official designated under paragraph (1) and (2)” for “head of the office”. Former par. (3) redesignated (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s901/g/3">Pub. L. 111–383, § 901(g)(3)</ref>, (6), redesignated par. (3) as (4), substituted “designated official” for “office”, and inserted “and for personnel accounting (including locating, recovering, and identifying missing persons or their remains after hostilities have ceased)” after “evasion)”. Former par. (4) redesignated (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s901/g/3">Pub. L. 111–383, § 901(g)(3)</ref>, (7), redesignated par. (4) as (5) and substituted “designated official” for “office”. Former par. (5) redesignated (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s901/g/3">Pub. L. 111–383, § 901(g)(3)</ref>, redesignated par. (5) as (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s901/g/8/A/ii">Pub. L. 111–383, § 901(g)(8)(A)(ii)</ref>, which directed the substitution of “activity” for “office” both places appearing, was executed by making the substitution in three places to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s901/g/8/A/i">Pub. L. 111–383, § 901(g)(8)(A)(i)</ref>, inserted “The Secretary of Defense shall establish an activity to account for personnel who are missing or whose remains have not been recovered from the conflict in which they were lost. This activity shall be known as the Defense Prisoner of War/Missing Personnel Office.” after “(A)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s901/g/8/B">Pub. L. 111–383, § 901(g)(8)(B)</ref>, substituted “activity” for “to the office”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s901/g/8/C">Pub. L. 111–383, § 901(g)(8)(C)</ref>, substituted “activity” for “to the office” and “of the activity” for “of the office”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s901/g/8/D">Pub. L. 111–383, § 901(g)(8)(D)</ref>, substituted “activity” for “office”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (a)(5)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375">Pub. L. 108–375</ref> designated existing provisions as cl. (i), inserted “, whether temporary or permanent,” after “civilian personnel”, and added cl. (ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s551/b">Pub. L. 107–314, § 551(b)</ref>, inserted “Such office shall be known as the Defense Prisoner of War/Missing Personnel Office.” after first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s551/a">Pub. L. 107–314, § 551(a)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/106/65">Pub. L. 106–65</ref> substituted “described” for “prescribed” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s599/a/1/A">Pub. L. 105–85, § 599(a)(1)(A)</ref>, added subsec. (c) and struck out former subsec. (c) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(c) <inline class="small-caps">Covered Persons</inline>.—<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1502">Section 1502 of this title</ref> applies in the case of any member of the armed forces on active duty who becomes involuntarily absent as a result of a hostile action, or under circumstances suggesting that the involuntary absence is a result of a hostile action, and whose status is undetermined or who is unaccounted for.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s599/a/1/B">Pub. L. 105–85, § 599(a)(1)(B)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/s578/a/1/A">Pub. L. 104–201, § 578(a)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “applies in the case of” for “applies in the case of the following persons:” and “any member” for “(1) Any member” and struck out par. (2) which read as follows: “Any civilian employee of the Department of Defense, and any employee of a contractor of the Department of Defense, who serves with or accompanies the armed forces in the field under orders who becomes involuntarily absent as a result of a hostile action, or under circumstances suggesting that the involuntary absence is a result of a hostile action, and whose status is undetermined or who is unaccounted for.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/s578/a/1/B">Pub. L. 104–201, § 578(a)(1)(B)</ref>, struck out subsec. (f) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(f) <inline class="small-caps">Secretary Concerned</inline>.—In this chapter, the term ‘Secretary concerned’ includes, in the case of a civilian employee of the Department of Defense or contractor of the Department of Defense, the Secretary of the military department or head of the element of the Department of Defense employing the employee or contracting with the contractor, as the case may be.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida8ddba26-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida8ddba27-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2011 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/383">Pub. L. 111–383</ref> effective <date date="2011-01-01">Jan. 1, 2011</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s901/p">section 901(p) of Pub. L. 111–383</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s131">section 131 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida8ddba28-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Authority To Enter Into Agreements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tX/s1063/b">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title X, § 1063(b)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/401">137 Stat. 401</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tX/s1063/b">“The Director of the Defense POW/MIA Accounting Agency may enter into agreements with universities or research organizations under which such universities or research organizations agree to provide additional capabilities for specialized missions or research requirements relating to expanding accounting for persons missing from designated past conflicts.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida8ddba29-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Recovery and Identification of Remains of Certain World War II Servicemen Lost in Pacific Theater of Operations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tV/s576">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 576</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/624">113 Stat. 624</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tX/s1048/g/3">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(g)(3)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1228">115 Stat. 1228</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tX/s1048/g/3">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Recovery of Remains</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall make every reasonable effort to search for, recover, and identify the remains of United States servicemen lost in the Pacific theater of operations during World War II (including in New Guinea) while engaged in flight operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> In order to provide high priority to carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense shall consider increasing the number of personnel assigned to the Central Identification Laboratory, Hawaii.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Not later than <date date="2000-09-30">September 30, 2000</date>, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report setting forth the efforts made to accomplish the objectives specified in paragraph (1). The Secretary shall include in the report a statement of the backlog of cases at the Central Identification Laboratory, Hawaii, shown by conflict, and the status of the joint manning plan required by section 566(c) of the Strom Thurmond National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1999 (<ref href="/us/pl/105/261">Public Law 105–261</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/112/2029">112 Stat. 2029</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Diplomatic Intervention if Required</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of State, upon request by the Secretary of Defense, shall work with officials of governments of nations in the area that was covered by the Pacific theater of operations of World War II to seek to overcome any diplomatic obstacles that may impede the Secretary of Defense from carrying out the objectives specified in subsection (a)(1).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida8ddba2a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">POW/MIA Intelligence Analysis</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tIX/s934">Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title IX, § 934</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1866">111 Stat. 1866</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tX/s1066/c/4">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1066(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/773">113 Stat. 773</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tX/s1066/c/4">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Intelligence Analysis</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of Central Intelligence, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall provide intelligence analysis on matters concerning prisoners of war and missing persons (as defined in chapter 76 of title 10, United States Code) to all departments and agencies of the Federal Government involved in such matters.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Intelligence in Analysis of POW/MIA Cases in Department of Defense</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the Defense Prisoner of War/Missing Personnel Office of the Department of Defense takes into full account all intelligence regarding matters concerning prisoners of war and missing persons (as defined in chapter 76 of title 10, United States Code) in analyzing cases involving such persons.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Reference to the Director of Central Intelligence or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency in the Director’s capacity as the head of the intelligence community deemed to be a reference to the Director of National Intelligence. Reference to the Director of Central Intelligence or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency in the Director’s capacity as the head of the Central Intelligence Agency deemed to be a reference to the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency. See section 1081(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/108/458">Pub. L. 108–458</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3001">section 3001 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida8ddba2b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Congressional Statement of Purpose</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tV/s569/a">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 569(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/336">110 Stat. 336</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tV/s569/a">“The purpose of this section [enacting this chapter and <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s655">section 655 of this title</ref>, amending sections 552, 553, 555, and 556 of Title 37, Pay and Allowances of the Uniformed Services, and enacting provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5561">section 5561 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees] is to ensure that any member of the Armed Forces (and any Department of Defense civilian employee or contractor employee who serves with or accompanies the Armed Forces in the field under orders) who becomes missing or unaccounted for is ultimately accounted for by the United States and, as a general rule, is not declared dead solely because of the passage of time.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
