<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida8ec1111-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1562"><num value="1562">§ 1562.</num><heading> Database on domestic violence incidents</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8ec1112-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1562/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Database on Domestic Violence Incident</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a central database of information on the incidents of domestic violence involving members of the armed forces.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8ec1113-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1562/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reporting of Information for the Database</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall require that the Secretaries of the military departments maintain and report annually to the administrator of the database established under subsection (a) any information received on the following matters:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8ec1114-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1562/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Each domestic violence incident reported to a commander, a law enforcement authority of the armed forces, or a family advocacy program of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8ec1115-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1562/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The number of those incidents that involve evidence determined sufficient for supporting disciplinary action and, for each such incident, a description of the substantiated allegation and the action taken by command authorities in the incident.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8ec1116-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1562/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The number of those incidents that involve evidence determined insufficient for supporting disciplinary action and for each such case, a description of the allegation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida8ec1117-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tV/s594/a">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 594(a)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/643">113 Stat. 643</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida8ee8218-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida8ee8219-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida8ee821a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Improvements to Department of Defense Domestic Violence Programs</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/383/dA/tV/s543">Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 543</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4218">124 Stat. 4218</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tV/s544/b">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title V, § 544(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3374">128 Stat. 3374</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tV/s544/b">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation of Outstanding Comptroller General Recommendations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Consistent with the recommendations contained in the report of the Comptroller General of the United States titled ‘Status of Implementation of GAO’s 2006 Recommendations on the Department of Defense’s Domestic Violence Program’ (GAO–10–577R), the Secretary of Defense shall complete, not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>], implementation of actions to address the following recommendations:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Adequate personnel</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall develop a plan to ensure that adequate personnel are available to implement recommendations made by the Defense Task Force on Domestic Violence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Domestic violence training data for chaplains</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall develop a plan to collect domestic violence training data for chaplains.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Oversight framework</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall develop an oversight framework for Department of Defense domestic violence programs, to include oversight of implementation of recommendations made by the Defense Task Force on Domestic Violence, including budgeting, communication initiatives, and policy compliance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation Report</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] an implementation report within 90 days of the completion of actions outlined in subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida8ee821b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Comptroller General Review and Report</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tV/s575">Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 575</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1486">117 Stat. 1486</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tV/s575">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Review</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>During the two-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>], the Comptroller General shall review and assess the progress of the Department of Defense in implementing the recommendations of the Defense Task Force on Domestic Violence. In reviewing the status of the Department’s efforts, the Comptroller General should specifically focus on—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the efforts of the Department to ensure confidentiality for victims and accountability and education of commanding officers and chaplains; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the resources that the Department of Defense has provided toward such implementation, including personnel, facilities, and other administrative support, in order to ensure that necessary resources are provided to the organization within the Office of the Secretary of Defense with direct responsibility for oversight of implementation by the military departments of recommendations of the Task Force in order for that organization to carry out its duties and responsibilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>The Comptroller General shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives a report on the results of the review and assessment under subsection (a) not later than 30 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>].”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida8ee821c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Defense Task Force on Domestic Violence</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tV/s591">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 591</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/639">113 Stat. 639</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tV/s575">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 575</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1123">115 Stat. 1123</ref>, directed the Secretary of Defense to establish a Department of Defense Task Force on Domestic Violence; required the task force to submit to the Secretary of Defense a long-term, strategic plan to address matters relating to domestic violence within the military more effectively, to review the victims’ safety program under <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/s592">Pub. L. 106–65, § 592</ref>, set out below, and other matters relating to acts of domestic violence involving members of the Armed Forces, and to submit to the Secretary an annual report on its activities and activities of the military departments; directed the Secretary to submit the report and the Secretary’s evaluation of the report to committees of Congress; and provided for the termination of the task force on <date date="2003-04-24">Apr. 24, 2003</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida8ee821d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Incentive Program for Improving Responses to Domestic Violence Involving Members of the Armed Forces and Military Family Members</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tV/s592">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 592</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/642">113 Stat. 642</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tV/s592">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading><content>The purpose of this section is to provide a program for the establishment on military installations of collaborative projects involving appropriate elements of the Armed Forces and the civilian community to improve, strengthen, or coordinate prevention and response efforts to domestic violence involving members of the Armed Forces, military family members, and others.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a program to provide funds and other incentives to commanders of military installations for the following purposes:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> To improve coordination between military and civilian law enforcement authorities in policies, training, and responses to, and tracking of, cases involving military domestic violence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> To develop, implement, and coordinate with appropriate civilian authorities tracking systems (A) for protective orders issued to or on behalf of members of the Armed Forces by civilian courts, and (B) for orders issued by military commanders to members of the Armed Forces ordering them not to have contact with a dependent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> To strengthen the capacity of attorneys and other legal advocates to respond appropriately to victims of military domestic violence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> To assist in educating judges, prosecutors, and legal offices in improved handling of military domestic violence cases.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> To develop and implement more effective policies, protocols, orders, and services specifically devoted to preventing, identifying, and responding to domestic violence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> To develop, enlarge, or strengthen victims’ services programs, including sexual assault and domestic violence programs, developing or improving delivery of victims’ services, and providing confidential access to specialized victims’ advocates.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> To develop and implement primary prevention programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> To improve the response of health care providers to incidents of domestic violence, including the development and implementation of screening protocols.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Priority</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall give priority in providing funds and other incentives under the program to installations at which the local program will emphasize building or strengthening partnerships and collaboration among military organizations such as family advocacy program, military police or provost marshal organizations, judge advocate organizations, legal offices, health affairs offices, and other installation-level military commands between those organizations and appropriate civilian organizations, including civilian law enforcement, domestic violence advocacy organizations, and domestic violence shelters.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applications</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall establish guidelines for applications for an award of funds under the program to carry out the program at an installation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Awards</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall determine the award of funds and incentives under this section. In making a determination of the installations to which funds or other incentives are to be provided under the program, the Secretary shall consult with an award review committee consisting of representatives from the Armed Forces, the Department of Justice, the Department of Health and Human Services, and organizations with a demonstrated expertise in the areas of domestic violence and victims’ safety.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida8ee821e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Uniform Department of Defense Policies for Responses to Domestic Violence</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tV/s593">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 593</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/643">113 Stat. 643</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tV/s593">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Standard guidelines to be used by the Secretaries of the military departments for negotiating agreements with civilian law enforcement authorities relating to acts of domestic violence involving members of the Armed Forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> A requirement (A) that when a commanding officer issues to a member of the Armed Forces under that officer’s command an order that the member not have contact with a specified person that a written copy of that order be provided within 24 hours after the issuance of the order to the person with whom the member is ordered not to have contact, and (B) that there be a system of recording and tracking such orders.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Standard guidelines on the factors for commanders to consider when seeking to substantiate allegations of domestic violence by a person subject to the Uniform Code of Military Justice and when determining appropriate action for such allegations that are so substantiated.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> A standard training program for all commanding officers in the Armed Forces, including a standard curriculum, on the handling of domestic violence cases.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deadline</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall carry out subsection (a) not later than six months after the date on which the Secretary receives the first report of the Defense Task Force on Domestic Violence under section 591(e) [set out as a note above].”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
