<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida8f33e45-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a"><num value="1566a">§ 1566a.</num><heading> Voting assistance: voter assistance offices</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8f33e46-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Designation of Offices on Military Installations as Voter Assistance Offices</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense under subsection (f), the Secretaries of the military departments shall designate offices on installations under their jurisdiction, or at such installations as the Secretary of the military department concerned shall determine are best located to provide access to voter assistance services for all covered individuals in a particular location, to provide absent uniformed services voters, particularly those individuals described in subsection (b), and their family members with the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8f33e47-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Information on voter registration procedures and absentee ballot procedures (including the official post card form prescribed under section 101 of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1973ff">42 U.S.C. 1973ff</ref>)).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002070">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002070"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8f33e48-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Information and assistance, if requested, including access to the Internet where practicable, to register to vote in an election for Federal office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8f33e49-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Information and assistance, if requested, including access to the Internet where practicable, to update the individual’s voter registration information, including instructions for absent uniformed services voters to change their address by submitting the official post card form prescribed under section 101 of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act to the appropriate State election official.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8f33e4a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Information and assistance, if requested, to request an absentee ballot under the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1973ff">42 U.S.C. 1973ff</ref> et seq.).<sup>1</sup></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8f33e4b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered Individuals</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The individuals described in this subsection are absent uniformed services voters who—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8f33e4c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> are undergoing a permanent change of duty station;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8f33e4d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> are deploying overseas for at least six months;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8f33e4e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> are returning from an overseas deployment of at least six months; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8f33e4f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> otherwise request assistance related to voter registration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8f33e50-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Timing of Provision of Assistance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense under subsection (f) shall ensure, to the maximum extent practicable and consistent with military necessity, that the assistance provided under subsection (a) is provided to a covered individual described in subsection (b)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8f33e51-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> if described in subsection (b)(1), as part of the administrative in-processing of the covered individual upon arrival at the new duty station of the covered individual;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8f33e52-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> if described in subsection (b)(2), as part of the administrative out-processing of the covered individual in preparation for deployment from the home duty station of the covered individual;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8f33e53-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> if described in subsection (b)(3), as part of the administrative in-processing of the covered individual upon return to the home duty station of the covered individual; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8f33e54-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> if described in subsection (b)(4), at the time the covered individual requests such assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8f33e55-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Outreach</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of each military department, or the Presidential designee, shall take appropriate actions to inform absent uniformed services voters of the assistance available under subsection (a), including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8f33e56-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the availability of information and voter registration assistance at offices designated under subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8f33e57-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the time, location, and manner in which an absent uniformed services voter may utilize such assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8f33e58-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority To Designate Voting Assistance Offices as Voter Registration Agency on Military Installations</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense may authorize the Secretaries of the military departments to designate offices on military installations as voter registration agencies under section 7(a)(2) of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1973gg–5/a/2">42 U.S.C. 1973gg–5(a)(2)</ref>) <sup>1</sup> for all purposes of such Act. Any office so designated shall discharge the requirements of this section, under the regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense under subsection (f).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8f33e59-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8f33e5a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations relating to the administration of the requirements of this section. The regulations shall be prescribed before the regularly scheduled general election for Federal office held in November 2010, and shall be implemented for such general election for Federal office and for each succeeding election for Federal office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8f33e5b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary of a military department shall provide the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives with notice of any decision by the Secretary to close a voter assistance office that was designated on an installation before the date of the enactment of this paragraph. The notice shall include the rational for the closure, the timing of the closure, the number of covered individuals supported by the office, and the plan for providing the assistance available under subsection (a) to covered individuals after the closure of the office.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8f33e5c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8f33e5d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “absent uniformed services voter” has the meaning given that term in section 107(1) of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1973ff–6/1">42 U.S.C. 1973ff–6(1)</ref>).<sup>1</sup></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8f33e5e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “Federal office” has the meaning given that term in section 107(3) of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1973ff–6/3">42 U.S.C. 1973ff–6(3)</ref>).<sup>1</sup></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8f33e5f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1566a/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “Presidential designee” means the official designated by the President under section 101(a) of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1973ff/a">42 U.S.C. 1973ff(a)</ref>).<sup>1</sup></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida8f33e60-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/dA/tV/s583/b/1">Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 583(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2328">123 Stat. 2328</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/dA/tX/s1075/b/21">Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(21)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4370">124 Stat. 4370</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tV/s592">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title V, § 592</ref>, title X, § 1071(e)(2), <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3395">128 Stat. 3395</ref>, 3509.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida8f33e61-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida8f33e62-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="ida8f33e63-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/99/410">Pub. L. 99–410</ref>, <date date="1986-08-28">Aug. 28, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/924">100 Stat. 924</ref>, which was formerly classified principally to subchapter I–G (§ 1973ff et seq.) of chapter 20 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering in Title 52, Voting and Elections, and is now classified principally to chapter 203 (§ 20301 et seq.) of Title 52. Sections 101 and 107 of the Act are now classified to sections 20301 and 20310, respectively, of Title 52. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Voter Registration Act of 1993, referred to in subsec. (e), is <ref href="/us/pl/103/31">Pub. L. 103–31</ref>, <date date="1993-05-20">May 20, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/77">107 Stat. 77</ref>, which was formerly classified principally to subchapter I–H (§ 1973gg et seq.) of chapter 20 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering in Title 52, Voting and Elections, and is now classified principally to chapter 205 (§ 20501 et seq.) of Title 52. Section 7 of the Act is now classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t52/s20506">section 20506 of Title 52</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida8f33e64-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/s1071/e/2">Pub. L. 113–291, § 1071(e)(2)</ref>, which directed substitution of “Under” for “Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2010 and under” in introductory provisions, could not be executed because of the prior amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/s592/a/1">Pub. L. 113–291, § 592(a)(1)</ref>. See below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/113/291/s592/a">Pub. L. 113–291, § 592(a)</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted “Under” for “Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2010 and under” and inserted “, or at such installations as the Secretary of the military department concerned shall determine are best located to provide access to voter assistance services for all covered individuals in a particular location,” after “their jurisdiction”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/s592/b">Pub. L. 113–291, § 592(b)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383">Pub. L. 111–383</ref> inserted closing parenthesis before period at end.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
