<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida9019610-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1701"><num value="1701">§ 1701.</num><heading> Management policies</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9019611-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1701/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Policies and Procedures</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish policies and procedures for the effective management (including accession, education, training, and career development) of persons serving in acquisition positions in the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9019612-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1701/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Uniform Implementation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall ensure that, to the maximum extent practicable, acquisition workforce policies and procedures established in accordance with this chapter are uniform in their implementation throughout the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida9019613-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXII/s1202/a">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1638">104 Stat. 1638</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida9019614-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida9019615-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="ida9019616-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXII/s1211">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1211</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1667">104 Stat. 1667</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXII/s1211">“Except as otherwise provided in this title [see Short Title note below], this title and the amendments made by this title, including chapter 87 of title 10, United States Code (as added by section 1202), shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="ida9019617-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXII/s1201">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1201</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1638">104 Stat. 1638</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXII/s1201">“This title [enacting this chapter, sections 5379 and 5380 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, and <ref href="/us/usc/t37/s317">section 317 of Title 37</ref>, Pay and Allowances of the Uniformed Services, amending sections 101 and 2435 of this title and sections 4107, 4301, 5102, 5532, 5724, 5742, 5924, 5942, 8344, and 8468 of Title 5, repealing sections 1621 to 1624 of this title, enacting provisions set out as notes under this section and sections 1621 to 1623, 1705, 1721, 1722, 1724, 1733, 1734, 1746, 1761, 1762, and 2435 of this title, sections 3326, 5380, and 5532 of Title 5, and <ref href="/us/usc/t37/s317">section 317 of Title 37</ref>, and repealing provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2304">section 2304 of this title</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Defense Acquisition Workforce Improvement Act’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9019618-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXII/s1210/a">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1210(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1667">104 Stat. 1667</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXII/s1210/a">“Unless otherwise provided in this title [see Short Title note above] and in subsection (b) [set out below], the Secretary of Defense shall promulgate regulations to implement this title and the amendments made by this title not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9019619-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Principal Technology Transition Advisor</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tVIII/s806">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title VIII, § 806</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/317">137 Stat. 317</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tVIII/s838">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 838</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1988">138 Stat. 1988</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tVIII/s838">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>], each service acquisition executive of a military department shall designate a Principal Technology Transition Advisor who shall advise each Secretary of a military department on the transition of technologies, including technologies from science and technology programs of the Department, private commercial entities, research institutions, and universities, to fulfill identified and potential warfighter requirements for the military department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Advisor Status</inline>.—</heading><content>The Principal Technology Transition Advisor of a military department designated under subsection (a) shall be a member of the Senior Executive Service or a general officer and directly report to the service acquisition executive of such military department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Principal Technology Transition Advisor of a military department designated under subsection (a) shall do the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Identify technologies being researched, developed, tested, or evaluated by science and technology programs of the Department, including Defense research facilities (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4125/b">section 4125(b) of title 10</ref>, United States Code), that the military department may use to meet identified and potential warfighter requirements, including technologies for which the Department owns and maintains the intellectual property rights.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Consult with Department of Defense innovation programs to identify technologies from private commercial entities, research institutions, universities, and other entities that the military department may use to meet identified and potential warfighter requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Make recommendations to the service acquisition executive of the military department regarding the acquisition of technologies identified under paragraphs (1) and (2) for acquisition decisions at the service acquisition executive level.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Inform program managers (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1737">section 1737 of title 10</ref>, United States Code) and other relevant acquisition officials of the military department of relevant technologies identified under paragraphs (1) and (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Develop policies and processes for promoting to small business concerns (as defined under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s632">15 U.S.C. 632</ref>)) and nontraditional defense contractors (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3014">section 3014 of title 10</ref>, United States Code) opportunities to license intellectual property developed by the Department, including opportunities and methods for small business concerns and nontraditional defense contractors to engage with the Department regarding such licensing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> Develop and maintain metrics tracking the outcomes of projects and other activities of the military department for which the military department expended amounts designated as budget activity 3 (Advanced Technology Development), budget activity 4 (Advanced Component Development and Prototypes), and budget activity 5 (System Development and Demonstration), as those budget activity classifications are set forth in volume 2B, chapter 5 of the Department of Defense Financial Management Regulation (DOD 7000.14-R).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">DARPA Detailees Authorized.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, upon a request from the Principal Technology Transition Advisor of a military department, may detail personnel of the Agency to such military department for a period not to exceed one year to provide technology transition support for technology of the Agency that is to be acquired by such military department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Extension</inline>.—</heading><content>The Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering may extend a detail under paragraph (1) for a period of not more than 6 additional months.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Congressional Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than one year after the designation of the Principal Technology Transition Advisor of a military department under subsection (a), and annually thereafter, the Principal Technology Transition Advisor of such military department shall submit to Congress a report on the following for the one-year period preceding the submission of the report:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The activities of the Principal Technology Transition Advisor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The outcomes of projects and other activities described in subsection (c)(6), including the metrics described in such subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the term ‘Department’ means the Department of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the term ‘Department of Defense innovation programs’ means the Defense Innovation Unit of the Department of Defense, AFWERX of the Air Force, and other programs sponsored by the Department of Defense, or any component thereof, with a focus on accelerating the adoption of emerging technologies for mission-relevant applications or innovation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the terms ‘military department’ and ‘service acquisition executive’ have the meanings given such terms in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101/a">section 101(a) of title 10</ref>, United States Code.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida901961a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Acquisition Workforce Incentives Relating to Training on, and Agreements With, Certain Start-Up Businesses</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tVIII/s834">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VIII, § 834</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2713">136 Stat. 2713</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tVIII/s834">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Training.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Curricula</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], the Director of the Acquisition Innovation Research Center shall make recommendations on one or more curricula for members of the acquisition workforce on financing and operations of start-up businesses, which may include the development of new curricula, the modification of existing curricula, or the adoption of curricula from another agency, academia, or the private sector.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><content>Courses under curricula recommended under paragraph (1) shall be offered with varying course lengths and level of study.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Incentives</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall develop a program to offer incentives to a member of the acquisition workforce that completes a curriculum developed, modified, or adopted under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional training materials</inline>.—</heading><content>In recommending curricula under paragraph (1), the Director of the Acquisition Innovation Research Center shall consider and incorporate appropriate training materials from university, college, trade-school, or private-sector curricula in business, law, or public policy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exchanges.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a pilot program under which the Secretary shall, in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1599g">section 1599g of title 10</ref>, United States Code, arrange for the temporary assignment of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> one or more members of the acquisition workforce to a start-up business; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> an employee of a start-up business to an office of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Priority</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall prioritize for participation in the pilot program described under paragraph (1)(A) members of the acquisition workforce who have completed a curriculum required under paragraph (1) [probably means par. (1) of subsec. (a)].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may not carry out the pilot program authorized by this subsection after the date that is three years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Conferences</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall identify existing conferences sponsored by the Department of Defense that might be expanded to include opportunities for sharing knowledge and best practices on software acquisition issues. Such opportunities shall maximize participation between members of the acquisition workforce, employees of start-up businesses, and investors in start-up businesses.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pilot Program.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall establish a pilot program to test the feasibility of innovative approaches to negotiating and establishing intellectual property and data rights in agreements with start-up businesses for the procurement of software and software-embedded systems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> ensure that a member of the acquisition workforce who has completed a curriculum required under subsection (a) is able to exercise authority to apply an approach described in paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> provide incentives to such member to exercise such authority.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An approach described in paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Flexible and tailored requirements relating to the acquisition and licensing of intellectual property and data rights in the software and software-embedded systems to be acquired under the agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> An identification and definition of the technical interoperability standards required for such software and software-embedded systems.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Flexible mechanisms for access and delivery of code for such software, including documentation of the costs and benefits of each such mechanism.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may not carry out the pilot program authorized by this subsection after the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The term ‘Acquisition Innovation Research Center’ means the acquisition research organization within a civilian college or university that is described under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4142/a">section 4142(a) of title 10</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘acquisition workforce’ has the meaning given in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101">section 101 of title 10</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The term ‘start-up business’ means a small business that has been in existence for 5 years or less.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida901961b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Continuation of Pay</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXI/s1114/c/2">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XI, § 1114(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3895">134 Stat. 3895</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXI/s1114/c/2">“The repeal in paragraph (1) [repealing <ref href="/us/pl/114/92/s1111">section 1111 of Pub. L. 114–92</ref>, formerly set out as a note below] shall not be interpreted to prohibit the payment of basic pay at rates fixed under such section 1111 before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>] for positions having terms that continue after that date.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida901961c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Exchange Program for Acquisition Workforce Employees</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tVIII/s884">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 884</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1915">132 Stat. 1915</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tVIII/s884">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program Authorized</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish an exchange program under which the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment shall arrange for the temporary assignment of civilian personnel in the Department of Defense acquisition workforce.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The purposes of the exchange program established pursuant to subsection (a) are—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to familiarize personnel from the acquisition workforce with the equities, priorities, processes, culture, and workforce of the acquisition-related defense agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to enable participants in the exchange program to return the expertise gained through their exchanges to their original organizations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> to improve communication between and integration of the organizations that support the policy, implementation, and oversight of defense acquisition through lasting relationships.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Participants.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Number of participants</inline>.—</heading><content>The Under Secretary shall select not less than 10 and no more than 20 participants per year for participation in the exchange program established under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Criteria for selection</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Under Secretary shall select participants for the exchange program established under subsection (a) from among mid-career employees and based on—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the qualifications and desire to participate in the program of the employee; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the technical needs and capacities of the acquisition workforce, as applicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Terms</inline>.—</heading><content>Exchanges pursuant to the exchange program established under subsection (a) shall be for terms of one to two years, as determined and negotiated by the Under Secretary. The terms may begin and end on a rolling basis.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guidance and Implementation.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guidance</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>], the Under Secretary shall develop and submit to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] interim guidance on the form and contours of the exchange program established under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary shall implement the guidance developed under paragraph (1).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida901961d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pilot Program on Temporary Exchange of Financial Management and Acquisition Personnel</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/92/dA/tXI/s1110">Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title XI, § 1110</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1030">129 Stat. 1030</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXVIII/s1806/e/3/A">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1806(e)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4156">134 Stat. 4156</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/286/s4/c/19">Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(c)(19)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4356">136 Stat. 4356</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/286/s4/c/19">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense may carry out a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of the temporary assignment of covered employees of the Department of Defense to nontraditional defense contractors and of covered employees of such contractors to the Department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered Employees; Nontraditional Defense Contractors.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered employees</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An employee of the Department of Defense or a nontraditional Defense contractor is a covered employee for purposes of this section if the employee—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> works in the field of financial management or in the acquisition field;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> is considered by the Secretary of Defense to be an exceptional employee; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> is compensated at not less than the GS–11 level (or the equivalent).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Nontraditional defense contractors</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this section, the term ‘nontraditional defense contractor’ has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3014">section 3014 of title 10</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Agreements.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall provide for a written agreement among the Department of Defense, the nontraditional defense contractor concerned, and the employee concerned regarding the terms and conditions of the employee’s assignment under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An agreement under this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> shall require, in the case of an employee of the Department, that upon completion of the assignment, the employee will serve in the civil service for a period at least equal to three times the length of the assignment, unless the employee is sooner involuntarily separated from the service of the employee’s agency; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> shall provide that if the employee of the Department or of the contractor (as the case may be) fails to carry out the agreement, or if the employee is voluntarily separated from the service of the employee’s agency before the end of the period stated in the agreement, the employee shall be liable to the United States for payment of all expenses of the assignment unless that failure or voluntary separation was for good and sufficient reason, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Debt to the united states</inline>.—</heading><content>An amount for which an employee is liable under paragraph (2)(B) shall be treated as a debt due the United States. The Secretary may waive, in whole or in part, collection of such a debt based on a determination that the collection would be against equity and good conscience and not in the best interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading><content>An assignment under this section may, at any time and for any reason, be terminated by the Department of Defense or the nontraditional defense contractor concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Duration</inline>.—</heading><content>An assignment under this section shall be for a period of not less than three months and not more than one year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Status of Federal Employees Assigned to Contractors</inline>.—</heading><content>An employee of the Department of Defense who is assigned to a nontraditional defense contractor under this section shall be considered, during the period of assignment, to be on detail to a regular work assignment in the Department for all purposes. The written agreement established under subsection (c) shall address the specific terms and conditions related to the employee’s continued status as a Federal employee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Terms and Conditions for Private Sector Employees</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An employee of a nontraditional defense contractor who is assigned to a Department of Defense organization under this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> shall continue to receive pay and benefits from the contractor from which such employee is assigned;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> shall be deemed to be an employee of the Department of Defense for the purposes of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> chapter 73 of title 5, United States Code;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> sections 201, 203, 205, 207, 208, 209, 603, 606, 607, 643, 654, 1905, and 1913 of title 18, United States Code, and any other conflict of interest statute;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> sections 1343, 1344, and 1349(b) of title 31, United States Code;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> chapter 171 and <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1346/b">section 1346(b) of title 28</ref>, United States Code (popularly known as the Federal Tort Claims Act), and any other Federal tort liability statute;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> chapter 131 of title 5, United States Code;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> chapter 21 of title 41, United States Code; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> subchapter I of chapter 81 of title 5, United States Code, relating to compensation for work-related injuries; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> may not have access, while the employee is assigned to a Department organization, to any trade secrets or to any other nonpublic information which is of commercial value to the contractor from which such employee is assigned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition Against Charging Certain Costs to Federal Government</inline>.—</heading><content>A nontraditional defense contractor may not charge the Department of Defense or any other agency of the Federal Government, as direct or indirect costs under a Federal contract, the costs of pay or benefits paid by the contractor to an employee assigned to a Department organization under this section for the period of the assignment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consideration</inline>.—</heading><content>In providing for assignments of employees under this section, the Secretary of Defense shall take into consideration the question of how assignments might best be used to help meet the needs of the Department of Defense with respect to the training of employees in financial management or in acquisition.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="j">“(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Numerical Limitations.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Department employees</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The number of employees of the Department of Defense who may be assigned to nontraditional defense contractors under this section at any given time may not exceed the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Five employees in the field of financial management.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Five employees in the acquisition field.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Nontraditional defense contractor employees</inline>.—</heading><content>The total number of nontraditional defense contractor employees who may be assigned to the Department under this section at any given time may not exceed 10 such employees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="k">“(k)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination of Authority for Assignments</inline>.—</heading><content>No assignment of an employee may commence under this section after <date date="2019-09-30">September 30, 2019</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida901961e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pilot Program on Enhanced Pay Authority for Certain Acquisition and Technology Positions in the Department of Defense</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/114/92/dA/tXI/s1111">Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title XI, § 1111</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1032">129 Stat. 1032</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tIX/s902/9">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(9)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1543">133 Stat. 1543</ref>, which authorized a pilot program on enhanced pay authority for certain acquisition and technology positions in the Department of Defense, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXI/s1114/c/1">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XI, § 1114(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3895">134 Stat. 3895</ref>. See Continuation of Pay note above and <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1701b">section 1701b of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida901961f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pilot Program on Direct Hire Authority for Veteran Technical Experts Into the Defense Acquisition Workforce</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/92/dA/tXI/s1112">Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title XI, § 1112</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1033">129 Stat. 1033</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/92/dA/tXI/s1112">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pilot Program</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense may carry out a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of appointing qualified veteran candidates to positions described in subsection (b) in the defense acquisition workforce of the military departments without regard to the provisions of subchapter I of chapter 33 of title 5, United States Code. The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program in each military department through the service acquisition executive of such military department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Positions</inline>.—</heading><content>The positions described in this subsection are scientific, technical, engineering, and mathematics positions, including technicians, within the defense acquisition workforce.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading><content>Authority under subsection (a) may not, in any calendar year and with respect to any military department, be exercised with respect to a number of candidates greater than the number equal to 1 percent of the total number of positions in the acquisition workforce of that military department that are filled as of the close of the fiscal year last ending before the start of such calendar year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The term ‘employee’ has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2105">section 2105 of title 5</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘veteran’ has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s101">section 101 of title 38</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority to appoint candidates to positions under the pilot program shall expire on the date that is five years after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effect on existing appointments</inline>.—</heading><content>The termination by paragraph (1) of the authority in subsection (a) shall not affect any appointment made under that authority before the termination date specified in paragraph (1) in accordance with the terms of such appointment.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida903df10-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Direct Hire Authority for Technical Experts Into the Defense Acquisition Workforce</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/92/dA/tXI/s1113">Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title XI, § 1113</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1033">129 Stat. 1033</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/92/dA/tXI/s1113">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>Each Secretary of a military department may appoint qualified candidates possessing a scientific or engineering degree to positions described in subsection (b) for that military department without regard to the provisions of subchapter I of chapter 33 of title 5, United States Code.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading><content>Positions described in this subsection are scientific and engineering positions within the defense acquisition workforce.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading><content>Authority under this section may not, in any calendar year and with respect to any military department, be exercised with respect to a number of candidates greater than the number equal to 5 percent of the total number of scientific and engineering positions within the acquisition workforce of that military department that are filled as of the close of the fiscal year last ending before the start of such calendar year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Nature of Appointment</inline>.—</heading><content>Any appointment under this section shall be treated as an appointment on a full-time equivalent basis, unless such appointment is made on a term or temporary basis.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Employee Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘employee’ has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2105">section 2105 of title 5</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority to make appointments under this section shall not be available after <date date="2020-12-31">December 31, 2020</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida903df11-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Coordination of Human Systems Integration Activities Related to Acquisition Programs</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/181/dA/tII/s231">Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title II, § 231</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/45">122 Stat. 45</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tVIII/s811/f">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 811(f)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1845">132 Stat. 1845</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tIX/s902/10">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(10)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1543">133 Stat. 1543</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tIX/s902/10">“The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, shall coordinate and manage human systems integration activities throughout the acquisition programs of the Department of Defense.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida903df12-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Requirements for Senior Department of Defense Officials Seeking Employment With Defense Contractors</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/181/dA/tVIII/s847">Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title VIII, § 847</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/243">122 Stat. 243</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tVIII/s855">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title VIII, § 855</ref>, title X, § 1071(b)(2)(C), <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3460">128 Stat. 3460</ref>, 3506; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tVIII/s821">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VIII, § 821</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2709">136 Stat. 2709</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tVIII/s821">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement to Seek and Obtain Written Opinion.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Request</inline>.—</heading><content>An official or former official of the Department of Defense described in subsection (c) who, within two years after leaving service in the Department of Defense, expects to receive compensation from a Department of Defense contractor, shall, prior to accepting such compensation, request a written opinion regarding the applicability of post-employment restrictions to activities that the official or former official may undertake on behalf of a contractor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission of request</inline>.—</heading><content>A request for a written opinion under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in writing to an ethics official of the Department of Defense having responsibility for the organization in which the official or former official serves or served and shall set forth all information relevant to the request, including information relating to government positions held and major duties in those positions, actions taken concerning future employment, positions sought, and future job descriptions, if applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Written opinion</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 30 days after receiving a request by an official or former official of the Department of Defense described in subsection (c), the appropriate ethics counselor shall provide such official or former official a written opinion regarding the applicability or inapplicability of post-employment restrictions to activities that the official or former official may undertake on behalf of a contractor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contractor requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>A Department of Defense contractor may not knowingly provide compensation to a former Department of Defense official described in subsection (c) within two years after such former official leaves service in the Department of Defense, without first determining that the former official has sought and received (or has not received after 30 days of seeking) a written opinion from the appropriate ethics counselor regarding the applicability of post-employment restrictions to the activities that the former official is expected to undertake on behalf of the contractor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Administrative actions</inline>.—</heading><content>In the event that an official or former official of the Department of Defense described in subsection (c), or a Department of Defense contractor, knowingly fails to comply with the requirements of this subsection, the Secretary of Defense may take any of the administrative actions set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s2105">section 2105 of title 41</ref>, United States Code[,] that the Secretary of Defense determines to be appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Recordkeeping Requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>Each request for a written opinion made pursuant to this section, and each written opinion provided pursuant to such a request, shall be retained by the Department of Defense in a central database or repository maintained by the General Counsel of the Department for not less than five years beginning on the date on which the written opinion was provided.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered Department of Defense Officials</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An official or former official of the Department of Defense is covered by the requirements of this section if such official or former official—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> participated personally and substantially in an acquisition as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s131">section 131 of title 41</ref>, United States Code[,] with a value in excess of $10,000,000 and serves or served—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> in an Executive Schedule position under subchapter II of chapter 53 of title 5, United States Code;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> in a position in the Senior Executive Service under subchapter VIII of chapter 53 of title 5, United States Code; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> in a general or flag officer position compensated at a rate of pay for grade O–7 or above under <ref href="/us/usc/t37/s201">section 201 of title 37</ref>, United States Code; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> serves or served as a program manager, deputy program manager, procuring contracting officer, administrative contracting officer, source selection authority, member of the source selection evaluation board, or chief of a financial or technical evaluation team for a contract in an amount in excess of $10,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term ‘post-employment restrictions’ includes—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> chapter 21 of title 41, United States Code;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s207">section 207 of title 18</ref>, United States Code; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> any other statute or regulation restricting the employment or activities of individuals who leave government service in the Department of Defense.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida903df13-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Government Performance of Critical Acquisition Functions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tVIII/s820">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title VIII, § 820</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2330">120 Stat. 2330</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/dA/tVIII/s805/c">Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title VIII, § 805(c)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2403">123 Stat. 2403</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/dA/tVIII/s835/a">Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VIII, § 835(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1507">125 Stat. 1507</ref>, which related to government performance of critical acquisition functions, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dA/tVIII/s824/b">Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title VIII, § 824(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1833">126 Stat. 1833</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida903df14-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Demonstration Project Relating to Certain Personnel Management Policies and Procedures</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dD/tXLIII/s4308">Pub. L. 104–106, div. D, title XLIII, § 4308</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/669">110 Stat. 669</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tVIII/s845">Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title VIII, § 845</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1845">111 Stat. 1845</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tVIII/s813/b">Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title VIII, § 813(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2609">116 Stat. 2609</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tXI/s1112">Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title XI, § 1112</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1634">117 Stat. 1634</ref>, which encouraged the Secretary of Defense to commence a demonstration project relating to improving the personnel management policies or procedures that apply to the acquisition workforce of the Department of Defense and supporting personnel, was repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1762">section 1762 of this title</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/dA/tVIII/s872/a/1">Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title VIII, § 872(a)(1)</ref>, (b), <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4300">124 Stat. 4300</ref>, 4302.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida903df15-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Evaluation by Comptroller General</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXII/s1208">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1208</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1665">104 Stat. 1665</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/102/25/tVII/s704/b/2">Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 704(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/119">105 Stat. 119</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dA/tVIII/s812/g">Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title VIII, § 812(g)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2452">106 Stat. 2452</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tXV/s1502/c/4/A">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(c)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/507">110 Stat. 507</ref>, provided for evaluation by Comptroller General of actions taken by Secretary of Defense to carry out requirements of Defense Acquisition Workforce Improvement Act and submission of annual reports to Congress, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/tI/s1031/b/1">Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1031(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/714">109 Stat. 714</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida903df16-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Deadlines for Qualification Requirements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXII/s1210/b">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1210(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1667">104 Stat. 1667</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXII/s1210/b">“Not later than <date date="1992-10-01">October 1, 1992</date>, the Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to implement sections 1723, 1724, and [former] 1732 of title 10, United States Code (as added by section 1202).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
