<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida903dfa7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1707"><num value="1707">§ 1707.</num><heading> Cadre of intellectual property experts</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida903dfa8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1707/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cadre</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, shall establish a cadre of personnel who are experts in intellectual property matters. The purpose of the cadre is to ensure a consistent, strategic, and highly knowledgeable approach to acquiring or licensing intellectual property by providing expert advice, assistance, and resources to the acquisition workforce on intellectual property matters, including acquiring or licensing intellectual property.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida903dfa9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1707/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Leadership Structure</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Under Secretary—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida903dfaa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1707/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> shall establish an appropriate leadership structure and office within which the cadre shall be managed; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida903dfab-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1707/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> shall determine the appropriate official to whom members of the cadre shall report.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida903dfac-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1707/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The cadre of experts shall be assigned to a program office or an acquisition command within a military department to advise, assist, and provide resources to a program manager or portfolio acquisition executive on intellectual property matters at various stages of the life cycle of a system. In performing such duties, the experts shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida903dfad-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1707/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> interpret and provide counsel on laws, regulations, and policies relating to intellectual property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida903dfae-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1707/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> advise and assist in the development of an acquisition strategy, product support strategy, and intellectual property strategy for a system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9064faf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1707/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> conduct or assist with financial analysis and valuation of intellectual property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9064fb0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1707/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> assist in the drafting of a solicitation, contract, or other transaction;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9064fb1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1707/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> interact with or assist in interactions with contractors, including communications and negotiations with contractors on solicitations and awards; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9064fb2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1707/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> conduct or assist with mediation if technical data delivered pursuant to a contract is incomplete or does not comply with the terms of agreements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9064fb3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1707/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Administration.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9064fb4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1707/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In order to achieve the purpose set forth in subsection (a), the Under Secretary shall ensure the cadre has the appropriate number of staff and such staff possesses the necessary skills, knowledge, and experience to carry out the duties under subsection (b), including in relevant areas of law, contracting, acquisition, logistics, engineering, financial analysis, and valuation. The Under Secretary, in coordination with the Defense Acquisition University and in consultation with academia and industry, shall develop a career path, including development opportunities, exchanges, talent management programs, and training, for the cadre. The Under Secretary may use existing authorities to staff the cadre, including those in paragraphs (2), (3), (4), and (6).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9064fb5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1707/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Civilian personnel from within the Office of the Secretary of Defense, Joint Staff, military departments, Defense Agencies, and combatant commands may be assigned to serve as members of the cadre, upon request of the Director.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9064fb6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1707/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Under Secretary may use the authorities for highly qualified experts under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s9903">section 9903 of title 5</ref>, to hire experts as members of the cadre who are skilled professionals in intellectual property and related matters.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9064fb7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1707/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Under Secretary may enter into a contract with a private-sector entity for specialized expertise to support the cadre. Such entity may be considered a covered Government support contractor, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3775/a">section 3775(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9064fb8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1707/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> In establishing the cadre, the Under Secretary shall give preference to civilian employees of the Department of Defense, rather than members of the armed forces, to maintain continuity in the cadre.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9064fb9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1707/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The Under Secretary is authorized to use amounts in the Defense Acquisition Workforce Development Fund for the purpose of recruitment, training, and retention of the cadre, including paying salaries of newly hired members of the cadre for up to three years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida9064fba-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added and amended <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXVIII/s1877">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1877</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4291">134 Stat. 4291</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXVIII/s1802/b/1/A">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802(b)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1227">139 Stat. 1227</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida9064fbb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida9064fbc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="ida9064fbd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 1707, added <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXII/s1202/a">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XII, § 1202(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1639">104 Stat. 1639</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tIX/s904/d/1">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title IX, § 904(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1728">107 Stat. 1728</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tX/s1048/b/2">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1225">115 Stat. 1225</ref>, related to personnel in the Office of the Secretary of Defense and in the Defense Agencies, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tVIII/s831/a">Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title VIII, § 831(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1549">117 Stat. 1549</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="ida9064fbe-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The text of subsec. (b) of section 2322 of title, which was transferred to this section and amended by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1877/b">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1877(b)</ref>–(e), was based on <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tVIII/s802/a/1">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VIII, § 802(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1450">131 Stat. 1450</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida9064fbf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60">Pub. L. 119–60</ref> substituted “portfolio acquisition executive” for “program executive officer” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1877/b/1">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1877(b)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (b)(1) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2322">section 2322 of this title</ref> as subsec. (a) of this section and inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1877/b/3">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1877(b)(3)</ref>, (c), redesignated subsec. (b)(2) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2322">section 2322 of this title</ref> as subsec. (b) of this section, inserted heading, inserted dash after “Secretary”, and reorganized remainder of text into designated pars. (1) and (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1877/b/3">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1877(b)(3)</ref>, (d), redesignated subsec. (b)(3) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2322">section 2322 of this title</ref> as subsec. (c) of this section, inserted heading, and redesignated subpars. (A) to (F) as pars. (1) to (6), respectively. Amendment by section 1877(d) was executed to subsec. (c) of this section to reflect the probable intent of Congress, notwithstanding directory language amending subsec. (c) of section “17017”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1877/b/3">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1877(b)(3)</ref>, (e)(1), (2), redesignated subsec. (b)(4) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2322">section 2322 of this title</ref> as subsec. (d) of this section, inserted heading, and redesignated subpars. (A) to (F) as pars. (1) to (6), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1877/e/3">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1877(e)(3)</ref>, in first sentence, substituted “subsection (a)” for “paragraph (1)” and “subsection (b)” for “paragraph (2)” and, in third sentence, substituted “paragraphs (2), (3), (4), and (6)” for “subparagraphs (B), (C), (D), and (F)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1877/e/4">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1877(e)(4)</ref>, substituted “section 3775(a)” for “section 2320”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida9064fc0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="ida9064fc1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section and amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> effective <date date="2022-01-01">Jan. 1, 2022</date>, with additional provisions for delayed implementation and applicability of existing law, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1801/d">section 1801(d) of Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2021 Amendment note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9064fc2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pilot Program on Intellectual Property Evaluation for Acquisition Programs</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tVIII/s801">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1481">133 Stat. 1481</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tVIII/s801">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pilot Program</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>], the Secretary of Defense and the Secretaries of the military departments may jointly carry out a pilot program to assess mechanisms to evaluate intellectual property (such as technical data deliverables and associated license rights), including commercially available intellectual property valuation analysis and techniques, in acquisition programs for which each such Secretary is responsible to better understand the benefits associated with these mechanisms on—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the development of cost-effective intellectual property strategies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the assessment and management of the value and acquisition costs of intellectual property during acquisition and sustainment activities (including source selection evaluation factors) throughout the acquisition lifecycle for any acquisition program selected by such Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the use of a commercial product (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s103">section 103 of title 41</ref>, United States Code, as in effect on <date date="2020-01-01">January 1, 2020</date>), commercial service (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s103a">section 103a of title 41</ref>, United States Code, as in effect on <date date="2020-01-01">January 1, 2020</date>), or nondevelopmental item (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s110">section 110 of title 41</ref>, United States Code) as an alternative to a product or service to be specifically developed for a selected acquisition program, including evaluation of the benefits of reduced risk regarding cost, schedule, and performance associated with commercial products, commercial services, and nondevelopmental items.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Activities</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Activities carried out under the pilot program may include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> Establishment of a team of Department of Defense and private sector subject matter experts (which may include the cadre of intellectual property experts established under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2322/b">section 2322(b) of title 10</ref>, United States Code [see <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1707">10 U.S.C. 1707</ref>]) to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> recommend acquisition programs to be selected for the pilot program established under subsection (a);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> recommend criteria for the consideration of types of commercial products, commercial services, or nondevelopmental items that can used as an alternative to a product or service to be specifically developed for a selected acquisition program; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> identify, to the maximum extent practicable at each milestone established for each selected acquisition program, intellectual property evaluation techniques to obtain quantitative and qualitative analysis of intellectual property during the procurement, production and deployment, and operations and support phases for the [sic] each selected acquisition program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Assessment of commercial valuation techniques for intellectual property for use by the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Assessment of the feasibility of agency-level oversight to standardize intellectual property evaluation practices and procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Assessment of contracting mechanisms to speed delivery of intellectual property to the Armed Forces or reduce sustainment costs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Assessment of agency acquisition planning to ensure procurement of appropriate intellectual property deliverables and intellectual property rights necessary for Government-planned sustainment activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><chapeau> Engagement with the private sector to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> support the development of strategies and program requirements to aid in acquisition planning for intellectual property;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> support the development and improvement of intellectual property strategies as part of life-cycle sustainment plans; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> propose and implement alternative and innovative methods of intellectual property valuation, prioritization, and evaluation techniques for intellectual property.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> Recommendations to the relevant program manager of an acquisition program selected under subsection (a), including evaluation techniques and contracting mechanisms for acquisition and sustainment activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than <date date="2020-11-01">November 1, 2020</date>, and annually thereafter through <date date="2023-11-01">November 1, 2023</date>, the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretaries concerned, shall submit to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] a joint report on the pilot program conducted under this section. The report shall, at a minimum, include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> a description of the acquisition programs selected by the Secretary concerned;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> a description of the specific activities in subsection (c) that were performed under each program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> an assessment of the effectiveness of the activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> an assessment of improvements to acquisition or sustainment activities related to the pilot program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> an assessment of the results related to the pilot program, including any cost savings and improvement to mission success during the operations and support phase of the selected acquisition program.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
