<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida77a803b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s176"><num value="176">§ 176.</num><heading> Armed Forces Institute of Pathology</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida77a803c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s176/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida77a803d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s176/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> There is in the Department of Defense an Institute to be known as the Armed Forces Institute of Pathology (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Institute”), which has the responsibilities, functions, authority, and relationships set forth in this section. The Institute shall be a joint entity of the three military departments, subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida77a803e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s176/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Institute shall consist of a Board of Governors, a Director, two Deputy Directors, and a staff of such professional, technical, and clerical personnel as may be required.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida77a803f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s176/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Board of Governors shall consist of the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Health Affairs, who shall serve as chairman of the Board of Governors, the Assistant Secretary of Health and Human Services for Health, the Surgeons General of the Army, Navy, and Air Force, the Under Secretary for Health of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and a former Director of the Institute, as designated by the Secretary of Defense, or the designee of any of the foregoing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida77a8040-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s176/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Director and the Deputy Directors shall be appointed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida77a8041-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s176/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida77a8042-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s176/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In carrying out the provisions of this section, the Institute is authorized to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida77a8043-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s176/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> contract with the American Registry of Pathology (established under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s177">section 177 of this title</ref>) for cooperative enterprises in medical research, consultation, and education between the Institute and the civilian medical profession under such conditions as may be agreed upon between the Board of Governors and the American Registry of Pathology;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida77a8044-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s176/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> make available at no cost to the American Registry of Pathology such space, facilities, equipment, and support services within the Institute as the Board of Governors deems necessary for the accomplishment of their mutual cooperative enterprises; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida77a8045-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s176/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> contract with the American Registry of Pathology for the services of such professional, technical, or clerical personnel as are necessary to fulfill their cooperative enterprises.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida77a8046-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s176/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> No contract may be entered into under paragraph (1) which obligates the Institute to make outlays in advance of the enactment of budget authority for such outlays.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida77a8047-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s176/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The Director is authorized, with the approval of the Board of Governors, to enter into agreements with the American Registry of Pathology for the services at any time of not more than six distinguished pathologists or scientists of demonstrated ability and experience for the purpose of enhancing the activities of the Institute in education, consultation, and research. Such pathologists or scientists may be appointed by the Director to administrative positions within the components or subcomponents of the Institute and may be authorized by the Director to exercise any or all professional duties within the Institute, notwithstanding any other provision of law. The Secretary of Defense, on a case-by-case basis, may waive the limitation on the number of distinguished pathologists or scientists with whom agreements may be entered into under this subsection if the Secretary determines that such waiver is in the best interest of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida77a8048-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s176/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall promulgate such regulations as may be necessary to prescribe the organization, functions, and responsibilities of the Institute.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida77a8049-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/94/361/tVIII/s811/b">Pub. L. 94–361, title VIII, § 811(b)</ref>, <date date="1976-07-14">July 14, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/933">90 Stat. 933</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/96/513/tV/s511/6">Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 511(6)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2920">94 Stat. 2920</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tXVI/s1621/a/1">Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1621(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1602">103 Stat. 1602</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tVII/s733">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title VII, § 733</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1697">107 Stat. 1697</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tIX/s903/f/1">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title IX, § 903(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/402">110 Stat. 402</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tIX/s901">Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title IX, § 901</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2617">110 Stat. 2617</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tX/s1048/a/4">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title X, § 1048(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1222">115 Stat. 1222</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida77a804a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida77a804b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida77a804c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/107/107">Pub. L. 107–107</ref> substituted “Under Secretary for Health” for “Chief Medical Director”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s903/a">Pub. L. 104–106, § 903(a)</ref>, (f)(1), which directed amendment of subsec. (a)(3), eff. <date date="1997-01-31">Jan. 31, 1997</date>, by substituting “official in the Department of Defense with principal responsibility for health affairs” for “Assistant Secretary of Defense for Health Affairs” and “Under Secretary for Health of the Department of Veterans Affairs” for “Chief Medical Director of the Department of Veterans Affairs”, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/104/201">Pub. L. 104–201</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/160">Pub. L. 103–160</ref> inserted at end “The Secretary of Defense, on a case-by-case basis, may waive the limitation on the number of distinguished pathologists or scientists with whom agreements may be entered into under this subsection if the Secretary determines that such waiver is in the best interest of the Department of Defense.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/101/189">Pub. L. 101–189</ref> substituted “Department of Veterans Affairs” for “Veterans’ Administration”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/96/513/s511/6/A">Pub. L. 96–513, § 511(6)(A)</ref>, substituted “Secretary of Health and Human Services” for “Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/96/513/s511/6/B">Pub. L. 96–513, § 511(6)(B)</ref>, inserted “of this title” after “177”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida77a804d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida77a804e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/513">Pub. L. 96–513</ref> effective <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/513/s701/b/3">section 701(b)(3) of Pub. L. 96–513</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida77a804f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Establishment of Joint Pathology Center</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/181/dA/tVII/s722">Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title VII, § 722</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/199">122 Stat. 199</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/181/dA/tVII/s722">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense proposed to disestablish all elements of the Armed Forces Institute of Pathology, except the National Medical Museum and the Tissue Repository, as part of the recommendations of the Secretary for the closure of Walter Reed Army Medical Center in the 2005 round of defense base closure and realignment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Defense Base Closure and Realignment Commission altered, but did not reject, the proposal of the Secretary of Defense to disestablish the Armed Forces Institute of Pathology.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The Commission’s recommendation that the Armed Forces Institute of Pathology’s ‘capabilities not specified in this recommendation will be absorbed into other DOD, Federal, or civilian facilities’ provides the flexibility to retain a Joint Pathology Center as a Department of Defense or Federal entity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sense of Congress</inline>.—</heading><content>It is the sense of Congress that the Armed Forces Institute of Pathology has provided important medical benefits to the Armed Forces and to the United States and that the Federal Government should retain a Joint Pathology Center.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment required</inline>.—</heading><content>The President shall establish and maintain a Joint Pathology Center that shall function as the reference center in pathology for the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment within dod</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in paragraph (3), the Joint Pathology Center shall be established in the Department of Defense, consistent with the final recommendations of the 2005 Defense Base Closure and Realignment Commission, as approved by the President.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment in another department</inline>.—</heading><content>If the President makes a determination, within 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>], that the Joint Pathology Center cannot be established in the Department of Defense, the Joint Pathology Center shall be established as an element of a Federal agency other than the Department of Defense. The President shall incorporate the selection of such agency into the determination made under this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Services</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Joint Pathology Center shall provide, at a minimum, the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Diagnostic pathology consultation services in medicine, dentistry, and veterinary sciences.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Pathology education, to include graduate medical education, including residency and fellowship programs, and continuing medical education.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Diagnostic pathology research.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Maintenance and continued modernization of the Tissue Repository and, as appropriate, utilization of the Repository in conducting the activities described in paragraphs (1) through (3).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida77a8050-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">National Museum of Health and Medicine</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tX/s1067">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title X, § 1067</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2851">108 Stat. 2851</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/78/tVII/s702">Pub. L. 105–78, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1997-11-13">Nov. 13, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1524">111 Stat. 1524</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/78/tVII/s702">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>It is the purpose of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to display and interpret the collections of the Armed Forces Institute of Pathology currently located at Walter Reed Medical Center; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to designate the public facility of the Armed Forces Institute of Pathology as the National Museum of Health and Medicine.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading><content>The public facility of the Armed Forces Institute of Pathology shall also be known as the National Museum of Health and Medicine.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida77a8051-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Congressional Findings and Declaration</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/94/361/tVIII/s811/a">Pub. L. 94–361, title VIII, § 811(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-07-14">July 14, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/933">90 Stat. 933</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/94/361/tVIII/s811/a">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> The Congress hereby finds and declares that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Armed Forces Institute of Pathology offers unique pathologic support to national and international medicine;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Institute contains the Nation’s most comprehensive collection of pathologic specimens for study and a staff of prestigious pathologists engaged in consultation, education, and research;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the activities of the Institute are of unique and vital importance in support of the health care of the Armed Forces of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> the activities of the Institute are also of unique and vital importance in support of the civilian health care system of the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> the Institute provides an important focus for the exchange of information between civilian and military medicine, to the benefit of both; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> it is important to the health of the American people and of the members of the Armed Forces of the United States that the Institute continue its activities in serving both the military and civilian sectors in education, consultation, and research in the medical, dental, and veterinary sciences.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Congress further finds and declares that beneficial cooperative efforts between private individuals, professional societies, and other entities on the one hand and the Armed Forces Institute of Pathology on the other can be carried out most effectively through the establishment of a private corporation.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
