<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida914a827-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1784a"><num value="1784a">§ 1784a.</num><heading> Education and training opportunities for military spouses to expand employment and portable career opportunities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida914a828-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1784a/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Programs and Tuition Assistance</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida914a829-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1784a/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may establish programs to assist the spouse of a member of the armed forces described in subsection (b) in achieving—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida914a82a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1784a/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the education and training required for a degree or credential at an accredited college, university, or technical school in the United States that expands employment and portable career opportunities for the spouse; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida914a82b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1784a/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the education prerequisites and professional licensure or credential required, by a government or government sanctioned licensing body, for an occupation that expands employment and portable career opportunities for the spouse.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida914a82c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1784a/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> As an alternative to, or in addition to, establishing a program under this subsection, the Secretary may provide tuition assistance to an eligible spouse who is pursuing education, training, or a license or credential to expand the spouse’s employment and portable career opportunities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida914a82d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1784a/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible Spouses</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida914a82e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1784a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Assistance under this section is limited to a spouse of a member of the armed forces who is serving on active duty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida914a82f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1784a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A spouse who is eligible for a program under this section and begins a course of education or training for a degree, license, or credential described in subsection (a) may not become ineligible to complete such course of education or training solely because the member to whom the spouse is married is promoted to a higher grade.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida914a830-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1784a/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Subsection (b) does not include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida914a831-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1784a/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a person who is married to, but legally separated from, a member of the armed forces under court order or statute of any State or territorial possession of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida914a832-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1784a/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a spouse of a member of the armed forces who is also a member of the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida914a833-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1784a/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Doula and IBCLC Certifications</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In carrying out the programs authorized by subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide assistance to the spouse of a member of the armed forces described in subsection (b) with obtaining certification—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida914a834-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1784a/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> as a doula or International Board Certified Lactation Consultant; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida914a835-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1784a/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> provided by an organization that receives reimbursement under the extramedical maternal health providers demonstration project required by section 746 of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1073">10 U.S.C. 1073</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida914a836-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1784a/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Portable Career Opportunities Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term “portable career” includes an occupation identified by the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, as requiring education and training that results in a credential that is recognized nationwide by industry or specific businesses.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida914a837-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1784a/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to govern the availability and use of assistance under this section. The Secretary shall ensure that programs established under this section do not result in inequitable treatment for spouses of members of the armed forces who are also members, since they are excluded from participation in the programs under subsection (c)(2).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida914a838-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/110/417">Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title V, § 582(a), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4473">122 Stat. 4473</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tV/s576">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 576</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1406">133 Stat. 1406</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tVI/s634">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title VI, § 634</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/297">137 Stat. 297</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida914a839-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida914a83a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida914a83b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2023—Subsecs. (d) to (f). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31">Pub. L. 118–31</ref> added subsec. (d) and redesignated former subsecs. (d) and (e) as (e) and (f), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Pub. L. 116–92</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida914a83c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida914a83d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">First Expansion of the My Career Advancement Account Program for Military Spouses</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tV/s580F">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 580F</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1410">133 Stat. 1410</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tV/s586">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 586</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3655">134 Stat. 3655</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tV/s586">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Professional License or Certification; Associate’s Degree</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall modify the My Career Advancement Account program of the Department of Defense to ensure that military spouses participating in the program may receive financial assistance for the pursuit or maintenance (including continuing education courses) of a license, certification, or Associate’s degree in any career field or occupation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">National Testing</inline>.—</heading><content>Financial assistance under subsection (a) may be applied to the costs of national tests that may earn a participating military spouse course credits required for a degree approved under the program (including the College Level Examination Program tests).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida914a83e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Improvement of My Career Advancement Account Program for Military Spouses</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tV/s574">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 574</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1780">132 Stat. 1780</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tV/s574">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Outreach on Availability of Program</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall take appropriate actions to ensure that military spouses who are eligible for participation in the My Career Advancement Account program of the Department of Defense are, to the extent practicable, made aware of the program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Comptroller General Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>], the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report setting forth such recommendations as the Comptroller General considers appropriate regarding the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Mechanisms to increase awareness of the My Career Advancement Account program of the Department of Defense among military spouses who are eligible to participate in the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Mechanisms to increase participation in the My Career Advancement Account program among military spouses who are eligible to participate in the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Training for Installation Career Counselors on Program</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretaries of the military departments shall take appropriate actions to ensure that career counselors at military installations receive appropriate training and current information on eligibility for and use of benefits under the My Career Advancement Account program, including financial assistance to cover costs associated with professional recertification, portability of occupational licenses, professional credential exams, and other mechanisms in connection with the portability of professional licenses.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
