<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida916f282-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1791"><num value="1791">§ 1791.</num><heading> Funding for military child care</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida916f283-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1791/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Policy</inline>.—</heading><content>It is the policy of Congress that the amount of appropriated funds available during a fiscal year for operating expenses for military child development centers and programs shall be not less than 115 percent of the amount of child care fee receipts that are estimated to be received by the Department of Defense during that fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida916f284-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1791/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Responsibility for Allocations of Certain Funds</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall be responsible for the allocation of Office of the Secretary of Defense level funds for military child development programs for children from birth through 12 years of age, and may not delegate such responsibility to the military departments.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida916f285-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tV/s568/a/1">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 568(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/332">110 Stat. 332</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tV/s584">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 584</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3654">134 Stat. 3654</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tV/s582">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 582</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/280">137 Stat. 280</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida916f286-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida916f287-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="ida916f288-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this subchapter were contained in <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tXV">Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XV</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1589">103 Stat. 1589</ref>, which was set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s113">section 113 of this title</ref>, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s568/e/2">Pub. L. 104–106, § 568(e)(2)</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida916f289-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2023—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31">Pub. L. 118–31</ref> inserted “115 percent of” after “not less than”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—<ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), inserted heading, and added subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida916f28a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida916f28b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Child Care Services and Youth Program Services for Dependents: Period of Services for a Member With a Spouse Seeking Employment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tV/s589">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 589</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1914">138 Stat. 1914</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tV/s589">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Period</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of a military department may provide a covered member with covered services for a period of at least 180 days.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> entitle a covered member to covered services; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> give priority to a covered member for purposes of a determination regarding who shall receive covered services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> The term ‘covered member’ means a member of the Armed Forces—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> who has a dependent child; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> whose spouse is seeking employment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘covered services’ means child care services or youth program services provided or paid for by the Secretary of Defense under subchapter II of chapter 88 of title 10, United States Code.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida916f28c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Public Reporting on Certain Military Child Care Programs</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tV/s579C">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 579C</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2608">136 Stat. 2608</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tV/s579C">“Not later than <date date="2023-09-30">September 30, 2023</date>, and each calendar quarter thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall post, on a publicly accessible website of the Department of Defense, information regarding the Military Child Care in Your Neighborhood and Military Child Care in Your Neighborhood-Plus programs, disaggregated by State, ZIP code, and Armed Force. Such information shall include whether each such provider is nationally accredited or rated by the Quality Rating and Improvement System of the State.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida916f28d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Authority for Department of Defense Program To Promote Early Literacy Among Certain Young Children</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tVII/s722">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VII, § 722</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2663">136 Stat. 2663</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tVII/s722">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense may carry out a program to promote early literacy among young children in child development centers and libraries located on installations of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Activities</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Activities under the program under subsection (a) shall include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The provision of training on early literacy promotion to appropriate personnel of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The purchase and distribution of age-appropriate books to covered caregivers assigned to or serving at an installation of the Department with a child development center or library at which the Secretary is carrying out the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The dissemination to covered caregivers of education materials on early literacy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Such other activities as the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Locations</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary may conduct the activities under subsection (b) at any child development center or library located on an installation of the Department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefing</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], the Secretary shall provide to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate a briefing on the extent to which the authority under subsection (a) is used, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> a description of any activities carried out under the program so authorized; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> an evaluation of the potential expansion of such program to be included as a part of the pediatric primary care of young children and to be carried out in military medical treatment facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> [sic] <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The term ‘covered caregiver’ means a member of the Armed Forces who is a caregiver of a young child.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘young child’ means any child from birth to the age of five years old, inclusive.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida916f28e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Improvement of Department of Defense Child Development Centers and Increased Availability of Child Care for Children of Military Personnel</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dB/tXXVIII/s2816">Pub. L. 117–81, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2816</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/2194">135 Stat. 2194</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/81/dB/tXXVIII/s2816">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Safety Inspection of Child Development Centers</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>], each Secretary of a military department shall complete an inspection of all facilities under the jurisdiction of that Secretary used as a child development center to identify any unresolved safety issues, including lead, asbestos, and mold, that adversely impact the facilities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefing on Results of Safety Inspections and Remediation Plans.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefing required</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2022-03-01">March 1, 2022</date>, each Secretary of a military department shall brief the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives regarding the results of the safety inspections conducted of child development centers under the jurisdiction of that Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Required elements of briefing</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In the briefing required by paragraph (1), the Secretary of a military department shall provide the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> A list of any child development centers under the jurisdiction of that Secretary considered to be in poor or failing condition. In the case of each child development center included on this list, the Secretary shall provide a remediation plan for the child development center, which shall include the following elements:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> An estimate of the funding required to complete the remediation plan.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> The Secretary’s funding strategy to complete the remediation plan.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> Any additional statutory authorities the Secretary needs to complete the remediation plan</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> A list of life-threatening and non-life-threatening violations during the previous three years recorded at child development centers under the jurisdiction of that Secretary that are not included on the list required by subparagraph (A), which shall include the name of the installation where the violation occurred and date of inspection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> A list of what that Secretary considers a life-threatening and non-life-threatening violation, including with regard to the presence of lead, asbestos, and mold.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> A list of how often the 90-day remediation requirement has been waived and the name of each child development center under the jurisdiction of that Secretary at which a waiver was granted.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> Data on child development center closures under the jurisdiction of that Secretary due to a non-life-threatening violation not remedied within 90 days.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> An additional plan to conduct preventive maintenance on other child development centers under the jurisdiction of that Secretary to prevent additional child development centers from degrading to poor or failing condition.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Partnerships Encouraged for Child Care for Children of Military Personnel</inline>.—</heading><content>Beginning one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and pursuant to such regulations as the Secretary of Defense may prescribe, each Secretary of a military department is encouraged to enter into agreements with public and private entities to provide child care to the children of personnel (including members of the Armed Forces and civilian employees of the Department of Defense) under the jurisdiction of that Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Status Updates</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 12 months thereafter, each Secretary of a military department shall brief the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives on the progress made by that Secretary—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> in implementing the child development center remediation plans required by subsection (b)(2)(A) for child development centers under the jurisdiction of that Secretary considered to be in ‘poor’ or ‘failing’ condition, including details about projects planned, funded, under construction, and completed under the plans;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> in conducting preventive maintenance on other child development centers under the jurisdiction of that Secretary pursuant to the preventive maintenance plan required by subsection (b)(2)(F); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> in entering into partnerships encouraged by subsection (c), including with regard to each partnership—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the terms of the agreement, including cost to the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the number of children described in such subparagraph projected to receive child care under the partnership; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> if applicable, the actual number of such children who received child care under the partnership during the previous year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Child Development Center Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘child development center’ has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2871/2">section 2871(2) of title 10</ref>, United States Code, and includes facilities identified as a child care center or day care center.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida916f28f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">24-Hour Child Care</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tV/s588">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 588</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3656">134 Stat. 3656</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tV/s588">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> 24-<inline class="small-caps">Hour Child Care</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Secretary of Defense determines it feasible, pursuant to the study conducted pursuant to subsection (b), the Secretary shall furnish child care to each child of a member of the Armed Forces or civilian employee of the Department of Defense while that member or employee works on rotating shifts at a military installation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Feasibility Study; Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report setting forth the results of a study, conducted by the Secretary for purposes of this section, on the feasibility of furnishing child care described in subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The report required by subsection (b) shall include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The results of the study described in that subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> If the Secretary determines that furnishing child care available as described in subsection (a) is feasible, such matters as the Secretary determines appropriate in connection with furnishing such child care, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> an identification of the installations at which such child care would be beneficial to members of the Armed Forces, civilian employees of the Department, or both;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> an identification of any barriers to making such child care available at the installations identified pursuant to subparagraph (A);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> an assessment whether the child care needs of members of the Armed Forces and civilian employees of the Department described in subsection (a) would be better met by an increase in assistance for child care fees;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> a description and assessment of the actions, if any, being taken to furnish such child care at the installations identified pursuant to subparagraph (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> such recommendations for legislative or administrative action the Secretary determines appropriate to make such child care available at the installations identified pursuant to subparagraph (A), or at any other military installation.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida916f290-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pilot Program To Provide Financial Assistance to Members of the Armed Forces for In-Home Child Care</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tV/s589">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 589</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3657">134 Stat. 3657</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tVI/s624">Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title VI, § 624</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1772">135 Stat. 1772</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tV/s586">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title V, § 586</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/893">139 Stat. 893</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tV/s586">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than <date date="2021-03-01">March 1, 2021</date>, the Secretary of Defense shall establish a pilot program to provide financial assistance to members of the Armed Forces who pay for services provided by in-home child care providers. In carrying out the pilot program, the Secretary shall take the following steps:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Determine the needs of military families who request services provided by in-home child care providers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Determine the appropriate amount of financial assistance to provide to military families described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> Determine the appropriate qualifications for an in-home child care provider for whose services the Secretary shall provide financial assistance to a military family. In carrying out this paragraph, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> take into consideration qualifications for in-home child care providers in the private sector; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> ensure that the qualifications the Secretary determines appropriate under this paragraph are comparable to the qualifications for a provider of child care services in a military child development center or family home day care.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Establish a marketing and communications plan to inform members of the Armed Forces who live in the locations described in subsection (b) about the pilot program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Locations.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program in the five locations that the Secretary determines have the greatest demand for child care services for children of members of the Armed Forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Secretary may carry out the pilot program at other locations the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Interim reports</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than one year after the Secretary establishes the pilot program and thrice annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives an interim report on the pilot program. Each interim report shall include the following elements:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The number of military families participating in the pilot program, disaggregated by location and duration of participation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The amount of financial assistance provided to participating military families in each location.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Metrics by which the Secretary carries out subsection (a)(3)(B);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> The feasibility of expanding the pilot program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> Legislation or administrative action that the Secretary determines necessary to make the pilot program permanent.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> Any other information the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Final report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than one year before the termination of the pilot program, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a final report on the pilot program. The final report shall include the following elements:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The elements specified in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The recommendation of the Secretary whether to make the pilot program permanent.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading><content>The pilot program shall terminate on <date date="2029-12-31">December 31, 2029</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The term ‘in-home child care provider’ means an individual who provides child care services in the home of the child.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The terms ‘military child development center’ and ‘family home day care’ have the meanings given those terms in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1800">section 1800 of title 10</ref>, United States Code.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida916f291-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Reduction in Wait Lists for Child Care at Military Installations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tV/s580/c">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 580(c)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1407">133 Stat. 1407</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tV/s580/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Remedial action</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall take steps the Secretary determines necessary to reduce the waiting lists for child care at military installations to ensure that members of the Armed Forces have meaningful access to child care during tours of duty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than <date date="2020-06-01">June 1, 2020</date>, the Secretary of Defense shall provide a report to the Committees on Armed Forces of the Senate and the House of Representative regarding—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> action taken under paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> any additional resources (including additional funding for and child care facilities and workers) the Secretary determines necessary to increase access described in paragraph (1).”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida916f292-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Enhancing Military Childcare Programs and Activities of the Department of Defense</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tV/s558">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title V, § 558</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1405">131 Stat. 1405</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tV/s558">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Hours of Operation of Military Childcare Development Centers</inline>.—</heading><content>Each Secretary of a military department shall ensure, to the extent practicable, that the hours of operation of each childcare development center under the jurisdiction of the Secretary are established and maintained in manner that takes into account the demands and circumstances of members of the Armed Forces, including members of the reserve components, who use such center in facilitation of the performance of their military duties.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Matters to Be Taken Into Account</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The demands and circumstances to be taken into account under subsection (a) for purposes of setting and maintaining the hours of operation of a childcare development center shall include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Mission requirements of units whose members use the childcare development center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The unpredictability of work schedules, and fluctuations in day-to-day work hours, of such members.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The potential for frequent and prolonged absences of such members for training, operations, and deployments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The location of the childcare development center on the military installation concerned, including the location in connection with duty locations of members and applicable military family housing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Such other matters as the Secretary of the military department concerned considers appropriate for purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Childcare Coordinators for Military Installations</inline>.—</heading><content>Each Secretary of a military department may provide for a childcare coordinator at each military installation under the jurisdiction of the Secretary at which are stationed significant numbers of members of the Armed Forces with accompanying dependent children, as determined by the Secretary. The childcare coordinator may work with the commander of the installation to ensure that childcare is available and responsive to the needs of members assigned to the installation.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida916f293-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Reports on Child Development Centers and Financial Assistance for Child Care for Members of the Armed Forces</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/383/dA/tV/s587">Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 587</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4230">124 Stat. 4230</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/383/dA/tV/s587">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports Required</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>], and every two years thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on Department of Defense child development centers and financial assistance for child care provided by the Department of Defense off-installation to members of the Armed Forces.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each report required by subsection (a) shall include the following, current as of the date of such report:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The number of child development centers currently located on military installations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The number of dependents of members of the Armed Forces utilizing such child development centers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The number of dependents of members of the Armed Forces that are unable to utilize such child development centers due to capacity limitations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The types of financial assistance available for child care provided by the Department of Defense off-installation to members of the Armed Forces (including eligible members of the reserve components).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> The extent to which members of the Armed Forces are utilizing such financial assistance for child care off-installation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> The methods by which the Department of Defense reaches out to eligible military families to increase awareness of the availability of such financial assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> The formulas used to calculate the amount of such financial assistance provided to members of the Armed Forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> The funding available for such financial assistance in the Department of Defense and in the military departments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> The barriers to access, if any, to such financial assistance faced by members of the Armed Forces, including whether standards and criteria of the Department of Defense for child care off-installation may affect access to child care.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="10">“(10)</num><content> Any other matters the Secretary considers appropriate in connection with such report, including with respect to the enhancement of access to Department of Defense child care development centers and financial assistance for child care off-installation for members of the Armed Forces.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
