<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida9196302-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1799"><num value="1799">§ 1799.</num><heading> Child care services and youth program services for dependents: participation by children and youth otherwise ineligible</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9196303-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1799/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense may authorize participation in child care or youth programs of the Department of Defense, to the extent of the availability of space and services, by children and youth under the age of 19 who are not dependents of members of the armed forces or of employees of the Department of Defense and are not otherwise eligible for participation in those programs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9196304-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1799/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading><content>Authorization of participation in a program under subsection (a) shall be limited to situations in which that participation promotes the attainment of the objectives set forth in subsection (c), as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9196305-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1799/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Objectives</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The objectives for authorizing participation in a program under subsection (a) are as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9196306-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1799/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> To support the integration of children and youth of military families into civilian communities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9196307-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1799/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> To make more efficient use of Department of Defense facilities and resources.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9196308-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s1799/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> To establish or support a partnership or consortium arrangement with schools and other youth services organizations serving children of members of the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida9196309-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tV/s584/a/1/B">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 584(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/634">113 Stat. 634</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tX/s1041/a/7">Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1041(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2645">116 Stat. 2645</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida919630a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida919630b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida919630c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/107/314">Pub. L. 107–314</ref> struck out heading and text of subsec. (d). Text read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(1) Every two years the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report on the exercise of authority under this section. The report shall include an evaluation of the effectiveness of that authority for achieving the objectives set out under subsection (c). The report may include any recommendations for legislation that the Secretary considers appropriate to enhance the capability of the Department of Defense to attain those objectives.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2) A biennial report under this subsection may be combined with the biennial report under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1798/d">section 1798(d) of this title</ref> into a single report for submission to Congress.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
