<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida783f69c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s194"><num value="194">§ 194.</num><heading> Limitations on personnel</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida783f69d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s194/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cap on Headquarters Management Personnel</inline>.—</heading><content>The total number of members of the armed forces and civilian employees assigned or detailed to permanent duty in the management headquarters activities or management headquarters support activities in the Defense Agencies and Department of Defense Field Activities may not exceed the number that is the number of such members and employees assigned or detailed to such duty on <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida783f69e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s194/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cap on Other Personnel</inline>.—</heading><content>The total number of members of the armed forces and civilian employees assigned or detailed to permanent duty in the Defense Agencies and Department of Defense Field Activities, other than members and employees assigned to management headquarters activities or management headquarters support activities, may not exceed the number that is the number of such members and employees assigned or detailed to such duty on <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida783f69f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s194/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition Against Certain Actions to Exceed Limitations</inline>.—</heading><content>The limitations in subsections (a) and (b) may not be exceeded by re­categorizing or redefining duties, functions, offices, or organizations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida783f6a0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s194/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exclusion of NSA</inline>.—</heading><content>The National Security Agency shall be excluded in computing and maintaining the limitations required by this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida783f6a1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s194/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The limitations in this section do not apply—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida783f6a2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s194/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> in time of war; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida783f6a3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s194/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> during a national emergency declared by the President or Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida783f6a4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s194/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the terms “management headquarters activities” and “management headquarters support activities” have the meanings given those terms in Department of Defense Instruction 5100.73, titled “Major DoD Headquarters Activities”.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida783f6a5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/99/433/tIII/s301/a/2">Pub. L. 99–433, title III, § 301(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1021">100 Stat. 1021</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/180/dA/tXIII/s1314/b/3">Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title XIII, § 1314(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1175">101 Stat. 1175</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tXVI/s1622/h/1">Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1622(h)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1605">103 Stat. 1605</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tIX/s906">Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title IX, § 906</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/818">127 Stat. 818</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida783f6a6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida783f6a7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida783f6a8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66">Pub. L. 113–66</ref> substituted “Instruction 5100.73, titled ‘Major DoD Headquarters Activities’.” for “Directive 5100.73, entitled ‘Department of Defense Management Headquarters and Headquarters Support Activities’ and dated <date date="1985-01-07">January 7, 1985</date>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsecs. (a), (b). <ref href="/us/pl/101/189">Pub. L. 101–189</ref> substituted “The” for “After <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>, the”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/180">Pub. L. 100–180</ref> inserted “the President or” after “declared by”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida783f6a9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida783f6aa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Exceptions and Adjustments to Limitations on Personnel</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Baseline personnel limitations in this section inapplicable to certain acquisition personnel and personnel hired pursuant to a shortage category designation for fiscal year 2009 and fiscal years thereafter, and Secretary of Defense or a secretary of a military department authorized to adjust such limitations for fiscal year 2009 and fiscal years thereafter, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/417/s1111">section 1111 of Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s143">section 143 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida783f6ab-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Reductions in Defense Intelligence Agency Personnel</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101/b/tVIII/s8122">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 8122]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1329-43">101 Stat. 1329–43</ref>, 1329–85, provided that nothing in <ref href="/us/pl/100/178/s102d/1">section 102d(1) of Public Law 100–178</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1010">101 Stat. 1010</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/99/433/s601/b/2/A">section 601(b)(2)(A) of Public Law 99–433</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1065">100 Stat. 1065</ref> [set out below], or <ref href="/us/pl/99/433/s601/d">section 601(d) of Public Law 99–433</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1065">100 Stat. 1065</ref> [set out below], shall be construed as requiring or suggesting that the Secretary of Defense avoid allocating personnel reductions to the Defense Intelligence Agency, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/100/456/dA/tXII/s1213">Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XII, § 1213</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2053">102 Stat. 2053</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida783f6ac-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Reduction in Personnel Assigned to Management Headquarters Activities and Certain Other Activities</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/433/tVI/s601">Pub. L. 99–433, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1064">100 Stat. 1064</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/180/dA/tXIII/s1312">Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title XIII, § 1312</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1174">101 Stat. 1174</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tXVI/s1622/h/2">Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1622(h)(2)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1606">103 Stat. 1606</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tXVI/s1622/h/2">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Military Departments and Combatant Commands</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The total number of members of the Armed Forces and civilian employees assigned or detailed to duty described in paragraph (2) may not exceed the number equal to 90 percent of the total number of such members and employees assigned or detailed to such duty on <date date="1986-09-30">September 30, 1986</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Duty referred to in paragraph (1) is permanent duty in the military departments and in the unified and specified combatant commands to perform management headquarters activities or management headquarters support activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> In computing and implementing the limitation in paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense shall exclude members and employees who are assigned or detailed to permanent duty to perform management headquarters activities or management headquarters support activities in the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The Office of the Secretary of the Army and the Army Staff.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The Office of the Secretary of the Navy, the Office of the Chief of Naval Operations, and the Headquarters, Marine Corps.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> The Office of the Secretary of the Air Force and the Air Staff.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> The immediate headquarters staff of the commander of each unified or specified combatant command.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> If the Secretary of Defense applies any reduction in personnel required by the limitation in paragraph (1) to a unified or specified combatant command, the commander of that command, after consulting with his directly subordinate commanders, shall determine the manner in which the reduction shall be accomplished.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Defense Agencies and DOD Field Activities</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Not later than <date date="1988-09-30">September 30, 1988</date>, the Secretary of Defense shall reduce the total number of members of the Armed Forces and civilian employees assigned or detailed to permanent duty in the management headquarters activities and management headquarters support activities in the Defense Agencies and Department of Defense Field Activities by a number that is at least 5 percent of the total number of such members and employees assigned or detailed to such duty on <date date="1986-09-30">September 30, 1986</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Not later than <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>, the Secretary shall carry out an additional reduction in such members and employees of not less than 10 percent of the number of such members and employees assigned or detailed to such duty on <date date="1988-09-30">September 30, 1988</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> If the number of members and employees reduced under subparagraph (A) or (B) is in excess of the reduction required to be made by that subparagraph, such excess number may be applied to the number required to be reduced under paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Not later than <date date="1988-09-30">September 30, 1988</date>, the Secretary of Defense shall reduce the total number of members of the Armed Forces and civilian employees assigned or detailed to permanent duty in the Defense Agencies and Department of Defense Field Activities, other than members and employees assigned or detailed to duty in management headquarters activities or management headquarters support activities, by a number that is at least 5 percent of the total number of such members and employees assigned or detailed to such duty on <date date="1986-09-30">September 30, 1986</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Not later than <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>, the Secretary shall carry out an additional reduction in such members and employees of not less than 5 percent of the number of such members and employees assigned or detailed to such duty on <date date="1988-09-30">September 30, 1988</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> If after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>] and before <date date="1988-10-01">October 1, 1988</date>, the total number of members and employees described in paragraph (1)(A) or (2)(A) is reduced by a number that is in excess of the number required to be reduced under that paragraph, the Secretary may, in meeting the additional reduction required by paragraph (1)(B) or (2)(B), as the case may be, offset such additional reduction by that excess number.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The National Security Agency shall be excluded in computing and making reductions under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition Against Certain Actions To Achieve Reductions</inline>.—</heading><content>Compliance with the limitations and reductions required by subsections (a) and (b) may not be accomplished by recategorizing or redefining duties, functions, offices, or organizations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Allocations To Be Made by Secretary of Defense</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall allocate the reductions required to comply with the limitations in subsections (a) and (b) in a manner consistent with the efficient operation of the Department of Defense. If the Secretary determines that national security requirements dictate that a reduction (or any portion of a reduction) required by subsection (b) not be made from the Defense Agencies and Department of Defense Field Activities, the Secretary may allocate such reduction (or any portion of such reduction) (A) to personnel assigned or detailed to permanent duty in management headquarters activities or management headquarters support activities, or (B) to personnel assigned or detailed to permanent duty in other than management headquarters activities or management headquarters support activities, as the case may be, of the Department of Defense other than the Defense Agencies and Department of Defense Field Activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Among the actions that are taken to carry out the reductions required by subsections (a) and (b), the Secretary shall consolidate and eliminate unnecessary management headquarters activities and management headquarters support activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Total Reductions</inline>.—</heading><content>Reductions in personnel required to be made under this section are in addition to any reductions required to be made under other provisions of this Act or any amendment made by this Act [see Short Title of 1986 Amendment note set out under section 111 of the title].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exclusion</inline>.—</heading><content>In computing and making reductions under this section, there shall be excluded not more than 1,600 personnel transferred during fiscal year 1988 from the General Services Administration to the Department of Defense for the purpose of having the Department of Defense assume responsibility for the management, operation, and administration of certain real property under the jurisdiction of that Department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this section, the terms ‘management headquarters activities’ and ‘management headquarters support activities’ have the meanings given those terms in Department of Defense Directive 5100.73, entitled ‘Department of Defense Management Headquarters and Headquarters Support Activities’ and dated <date date="1985-01-07">January 7, 1985</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
