<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida92ee77d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2142"><num value="2142">§ 2142.</num><heading> Educational assistance program: eligibility</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida92ee77e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2142/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida92ee77f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2142/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A program of educational assistance established under this chapter shall provide that any person enlisting or reenlisting in an armed force under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the military department concerned who meets the eligibility requirements established by the Secretary in accordance with subsection (b) shall, subject to paragraph (3), become entitled to educational assistance under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2143">section 2143 of this title</ref> at the time of such enlistment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida92ee780-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2142/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The period of educational assistance to which such a person becomes entitled is one standard academic year (or the equivalent) for each year of the enlistment of such person, up to a maximum of four years. However, if the person is discharged or otherwise released from active duty after completing two years of the term of such enlistment but before completing the full term of such enlistment (or before completing four years of such term, in the case of an enlistment of more than four years), then the period of educational assistance to which the person is entitled is one standard academic year (or the equivalent) for each year of active service of such person during such term. For the purposes of the preceding sentence, a portion of a year of active service shall be rounded to the nearest month and shall be prorated to a standard academic year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida92ee781-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2142/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida92ee782-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2142/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A member who is discharged or otherwise released from active duty before completing two years of active service of an enlistment which is the basis for entitlement to educational assistance under this chapter or who is discharged or otherwise released from active duty under other than honorable conditions is not entitled to educational assistance under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida92ee783-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2142/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Entitlement to educational assistance under this chapter may not be used until a member has completed two years of active service of the enlistment which is the basis for entitlement to such educational assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida92ee784-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2142/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> In establishing requirements for eligibility for an educational assistance program under this chapter, the Secretary concerned shall limit eligibility to persons who—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida92ee785-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2142/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> enlist or reenlist for service on active duty as a member of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps after <date date="1980-09-30">September 30, 1980</date>, and before <date date="1981-10-01">October 1, 1981</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida92ee786-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2142/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> are graduates from a secondary school; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida92ee787-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2142/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> meet such other requirements as the Secretary may consider appropriate for the purposes of this chapter and the needs of the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida92ee788-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/96/342/tIX/s901/a">Pub. L. 96–342, title IX, § 901(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-09-08">Sept. 8, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1111">94 Stat. 1111</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
