<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida9550ce4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2229"><num value="2229">§ 2229.</num><heading> Strategic policy on prepositioning of materiel and equipment</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9550ce5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2229/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Policy Required.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9550ce6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2229/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall maintain a strategic policy on the programs of the Department of Defense for prepositioned materiel and equipment. Such policy shall take into account national security threats, strategic mobility, service requirements, support for crisis response elements, and the requirements of the combatant commands, and shall address how the Department’s prepositioning programs, both ground and afloat, align with national defense strategies and departmental priorities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9550ce7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2229/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The strategic policy required under paragraph (1) shall include the following elements:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9550ce8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2229/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Overarching strategic guidance concerning planning and resource priorities that link the Department of Defense’s current and future needs for prepositioned stocks, such as desired responsiveness, to evolving national defense objectives.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9550ce9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2229/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A description of the Department’s vision for prepositioning programs and the desired end state.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9550cea-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2229/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Specific interim goals demonstrating how the vision and end state will be achieved.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9550ceb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2229/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> A description of the strategic environment, requirements for, and challenges associated with, prepositioning.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9550cec-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2229/a/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Metrics for how the Department will evaluate the extent to which prepositioned assets are achieving defense objectives.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9550ced-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2229/a/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> A framework for joint departmental oversight that reviews and synchronizes the military services’ prepositioning strategies to minimize potentially duplicative efforts and maximize efficiencies in prepositioned materiel and equipment across the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9550cee-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2229/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Joint oversight</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish joint oversight of the military services’ prepositioning efforts to maximize efficiencies across the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9550cef-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2229/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation of Diversion of Prepositioned Materiel</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of a military department may not divert materiel or equipment from prepositioned stocks except—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9550cf0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2229/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> in accordance with a change made by the Secretary of Defense to the policy maintained under subsection (a); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9550cf1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2229/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> for the purpose of directly supporting a contingency operation or providing humanitarian assistance under chapter 20 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9550cf2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2229/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Congressional Notification</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense may not implement or change the policy required under subsection (a) until the Secretary submits to the congressional defense committees a report describing the policy or change to the policy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9550cf3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2229/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Certification</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9550cf4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2229/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not later than the date of the submission of the President’s budget request for a fiscal year under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105">section 1105 of title 31</ref>, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a certification in writing that the prepositioned stocks of each of the military departments meet all operations plans, in both fill and readiness, that are in effect as of the date of the submission of the certification.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9550cf5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2229/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If, for any year, the Secretary cannot certify that any of the prepositioned stocks meet such operations plans, the Secretary shall include with the certification for that year a list of the operations plans affected, a description of any measures that have been taken to mitigate any risk associated with prepositioned stock shortfalls, and an anticipated timeframe for the replenishment of the stocks.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9550cf6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2229/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A certification under this subsection shall be in an unclassified form but may have a classified annex.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida9550cf7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tIII/s351/a">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title III, § 351(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2160">120 Stat. 2160</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/dA/tIII/s341/a">Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 341(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1369">125 Stat. 1369</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tIII/s321/a">Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title III, § 321(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/730">127 Stat. 730</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tIII/s322">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title III, § 322</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3343">128 Stat. 3343</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/92/dA/tX/s1081/a/8">Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1001">129 Stat. 1001</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida9550cf8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida9550cf9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida9550cfa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/114/92">Pub. L. 114–92</ref> substituted “a certification in writing” for “certification in writing”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/113/291">Pub. L. 113–291</ref> inserted “support for crisis response elements,” after “service requirements,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66">Pub. L. 113–66</ref> amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Secretary of Defense shall maintain a strategic policy on the programs of the Department of Defense for the prepositioning of materiel and equipment. Such policy shall take into account national security threats, strategic mobility, service requirements, and the requirements of the combatant commands.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/112/81">Pub. L. 112–81</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida9550cfb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9550cfc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2021-12-31">Dec. 31, 2021</date>, of provisions in subsec. (d) of this section requiring submittal of annual report to Congress, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1061">section 1061 of Pub. L. 114–328</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s111">section 111 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9550cfd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plans Regarding Condition and Maintenance of Prepositioned Stockpiles of Navy, Marine Corps, and Air Force</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tIII/s333">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title III, § 333</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1855">138 Stat. 1855</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tIII/s333">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Plan Required.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>], the Secretary of the Navy and the Secretary of the Air Force shall each develop a plan to improve the required inspection procedures for the prepositioned stockpiles of the Armed Force concerned, for the purpose of identifying deficiencies and conducting maintenance repairs at levels necessary to ensure such prepositioned stockpiles are mission capable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional requirements for navy and marine corps plan</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The plan of the Secretary of the Navy required under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> an analysis of the readiness of ships of the Navy and Marine Corps that hold or facilitate the off-loading of prepositioned stockpiles; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> suggestions for improving inspection procedures of such ships.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary concerned completes the development of a plan under subsection (a), and not less frequently than twice each year thereafter for the three-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary concerned shall inspect the prepositioned stockpiles of the Armed Force concerned in accordance with the procedures under such plan.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefings.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefing on plan</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, each Secretary concerned shall provide to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] a briefing on the plan of the Secretary developed under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefings on status of prepositioned stockpiles</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter for the three-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, each Secretary concerned shall provide to the congressional defense committees a briefing on the status and condition of the prepositioned stockpiles of the Armed Force concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> The term ‘Armed Force concerned’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Navy and the Marine Corps, with respect to the Secretary of the Navy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Air Force, with respect to the Secretary of the Air Force.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> The term ‘Secretary concerned’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Secretary of the Navy, with respect to matters concerning the Navy and the Marine Corps; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Secretary of the Air Force, with respect to matters concerning the Air Force.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9550cfe-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pre-Positioned Stocks of Finished Defense Textile Articles</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tIII/s336">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title III, § 336</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1856">138 Stat. 1856</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tIII/s336">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense may establish pre-positioned stocks of finished defense textile articles, such as uniforms and protective gear, to support the rapid mobilization and sustainment of members of the Armed Forces during a contingency operation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Plan to Reduce Delays</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall develop a plan for phasing in and targeting policy changes relating to defense textile articles to reduce delinquencies and mitigate delays between policy decisions that may result in the miscalculation of stockpiling in order to ensure ample finished textiles are available to prevent a scenario in which the demand for certain articles is ramping down by the time the supply chain can ramp up to meet the need.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9550cff-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plan Regarding Condition and Maintenance of Prepositioned Stockpiles of the Army</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tIII/s349">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title III, § 349</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/228">137 Stat. 228</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tIII/s349">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Plan Required</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>], the Secretary of the Army shall develop a plan to improve the required inspection procedures for the prepositioned stockpiles of the Army, for the purpose of identifying deficiencies and conducting maintenance repairs at levels necessary to ensure such prepositioned stockpiles are mission-capable.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary completes the development of the plan under subsection (a), and not less frequently than twice each year thereafter for the three-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall inspect the prepositioned stockpiles of the Army in accordance with the procedures under such plan.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefings.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefing on plan</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Army shall provide to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] a briefing on the plan developed under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefings on status of prepositioned stockpiles</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter for the three-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Army shall provide to the congressional defense committees a briefing on the status and condition of the prepositioned stockpiles of the Army.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9550d00-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Implementation Plan and Report</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tIII/s321/b">Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title III, § 321(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/731">127 Stat. 731</ref>, 732, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tIII/s324">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title III, § 324</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3343">128 Stat. 3343</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tIII/s324">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation Plan.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] a plan for implementation of the prepositioning strategic policy required under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2229/a">section 2229(a) of title 10</ref>, United States Code, as amended by subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The implementation plan required under paragraph (1) shall include the following elements:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Detailed guidance for how the Department of Defense will achieve the vision, end state, and goals outlined in the strategic policy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> A comprehensive list of the Department’s prepositioned materiel and equipment programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> A detailed description of how the plan will be implemented.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> A schedule with milestones for the implementation of the plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> An assignment of roles and responsibilities for the implementation of the plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> A description of the resources required to implement the plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> A description of how the plan will be reviewed and assessed to monitor progress.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Comptroller General Report</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Initial report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall review the implementation plan submitted under subsection (b) and the prepositioning strategic policy required under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2229/a">section 2229(a) of title 10</ref>, United States Code, as amended by subsection (a), and submit to the congressional defense committees a report describing the findings of such review and including any additional information relating to the propositioning strategic policy and plan that the Comptroller General determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Progress reports</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than one year after submitting the report required under paragraph (1), and annually thereafter for two years, the Comptroller General shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report assessing the progress of the Department of Defense in implementing its strategic policy and plan for its prepositioned stocks and including any additional information related to the Department’s management of its prepositioned stocks that the Comptroller General determines appropriate.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9550d01-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Deadline for Establishment of Policy</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tIII/s351/c">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title III, § 351(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2160">120 Stat. 2160</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tIII/s351/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deadline</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall establish the strategic policy on the programs of the Department of Defense for the prepositioning of materiel and equipment required under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2229">section 2229 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on diversion of prepositioned materiel</inline>.—</heading><content>During the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>] and ending on the date on which the Secretary of Defense submits the report required under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2229/c">section 2229(c) of title 10</ref>, United States Code, on the policy referred to in paragraph (1), the Secretary of a military department may not divert materiel or equipment from prepositioned stocks except for the purpose of directly supporting a contingency operation or providing humanitarian assistance under chapter 20 of that title.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9550d02-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Improving Department of Defense Support for Civil Authorities</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tIII/s359">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title III, § 359</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2164">120 Stat. 2164</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tIII/s359">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading><content>In the development of concept plans for the Department of Defense for providing support to civil authorities, the Secretary of Defense may consult with the Secretary of Homeland Security and State governments.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prepositioning of Department of Defense Assets</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense may provide for the prepositioning of prepackaged or preidentified basic response assets, such as medical supplies, food and water, and communications equipment, in order to improve the ability of the Department of Defense to rapidly provide support to civil authorities. The prepositioning of basic response assets shall be carried out in a manner consistent with Department of Defense concept plans for providing support to civil authorities and <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2229">section 2229 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, as added by section 351.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement</inline>.—</heading><content>To the extent required by <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1535">section 1535 of title 31</ref>, United States Code, or other applicable law, the Secretary of Defense shall require that the Department of Defense be reimbursed for costs incurred by the Department in the prepositioning of basic response assets under subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Military Readiness</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the prepositioning of basic response assets under subsection (b) does not adversely affect the military preparedness of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Procedures and Guidelines</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may develop procedures and guidelines applicable to the prepositioning of basic response assets under subsection (b).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
