<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida965ae72-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2285"><num value="2285">§ 2285.</num><heading> Department of Defense Climate Resilience Infrastructure Initiative</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida965ae73-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2285/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading><content>The programs, practices, and activities carried out pursuant to this section shall be known collectively as the “Climate Resilience Infrastructure Initiative of the Department of Defense”.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida965ae74-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2285/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Hardening and Quick Recovery</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out military installation resilience plans pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2864">section 2864 of this title</ref>, the Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the development by the Department of Defense of requirements for backup utilities, communications, and transportation to ensure that the critical infrastructure of Department facilities is hardened, developed, and constructed for quick recovery from natural disasters and the impacts of extreme weather.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida965ae75-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2285/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sustainment and Modernization</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall develop sustainment and modernization requirements for facilities of the Department in connection with climate resilience.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida965ae76-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2285/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Collaboration in Planning With Local Communities</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall develop, within existing frameworks for collaborative activities between military installations and State and local communities, and in addition to the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2864/c">section 2864(c) of this title</ref>, a framework that authorizes and directs installation commanders to engage with State, regional, and local agencies, and with local communities, on planning for climate resilience, to enhance efficient response to impacts of extreme weather and secure collaborative investment in infrastructure that is resilient to the current and projected impacts of extreme weather.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida965ae77-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2285/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Testing and Training Range Lands.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida965ae78-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2285/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Practices for sustainment of lands</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall develop and implement practices to sustain the lands of the military testing and training ranges of the Department, and the lands of testing and training ranges on State-owned National Guard installations, through the adaptation and resilience of such lands to the current and projected impacts of extreme weather to ensure the ongoing availability of such lands to military personnel, weapon systems, and equipment for testing and training purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida965ae79-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2285/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Training and education on sustainment of lands</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall develop a program of training and education for members of the Armed Forces (including the reserve components) on the importance of the sustainment of the lands of the military testing and training ranges as described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida965ae7a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2285/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Investment in resilience of lands</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall use existing programs of the Department, including the Readiness and Environmental Protection Integration Program of the Department (or such successor program), to provide for investments determined appropriate by the Secretary in the lands of the military testing and training ranges, to increase the resilience and adaptation of such lands to the current and projected impacts of extreme weather for testing and training purposes in connection with current and projected testing and training requirements in the short- and long-term.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida965ae7b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2285/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Certain Technologies</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall take appropriate actions to increase the use of low emission, emission-free, and net-zero-emission energy technologies in the operations, programs, projects, and activities of the Department, provided the use is cost effective over the life-cycle of the investment.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida965ae7c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tIII/s332/a">Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title III, § 332(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1637">135 Stat. 1637</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tXVII/s1701/a/28">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(a)(28)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2204">138 Stat. 2204</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida965ae7d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida965ae7e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida965ae7f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsecs. (b) to (f). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159">Pub. L. 118–159</ref> redesignated subsecs. (d) to (f) as (c) to (e), respectively, and the second subsec. (b), relating to use of certain technologies, as (f).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
