<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida9681f34-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2341"><num value="2341">§ 2341.</num><heading> Authority to acquire logistic support, supplies, and services for elements of the armed forces deployed outside the United States</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2343">section 2343 of this title</ref> and subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary of Defense may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9681f35-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2341/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> acquire from the Governments of North Atlantic Treaty Organization countries, from North Atlantic Treaty Organization subsidiary bodies, and from the United Nations Organization or any regional international organization logistic support, supplies, and services for elements of the armed forces deployed outside the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9681f36-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2341/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> acquire from any government not a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization logistic support, supplies, and services for elements of the armed forces deployed (or to be deployed) outside the United States if that country—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9681f37-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2341/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> has a defense alliance with the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9681f38-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2341/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> permits the stationing of members of the armed forces in such country or the homeporting of naval vessels of the United States in such country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9681f39-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2341/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> has agreed to preposition materiel of the United States in such country; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9681f3a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2341/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> serves as the host country to military exercises which include elements of the armed forces or permits other military operations by the armed forces in such country.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="ida9681f3b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/96/323/s2/a">Pub. L. 96–323, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1016">94 Stat. 1016</ref>, § 2321; renumbered § 2341 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/99/145/tXIII/s1304/a/1">Pub. L. 99–145, title XIII, § 1304(a)(1)</ref>, (4), <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/741">99 Stat. 741</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/661/dA/tXI/s1104/a">Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XI, § 1104(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3963">100 Stat. 3963</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dA/tXIII/s1312/a">Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title XIII, § 1312(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2547">106 Stat. 2547</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tXIII/s1317/a">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XIII, § 1317(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2899">108 Stat. 2899</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tXII/s1204">Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title XII, § 1204</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3456">119 Stat. 3456</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida9681f3c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida9681f3d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida9681f3e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Par. (1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/163">Pub. L. 109–163</ref> struck out “of which the United States is a member” before “logistic support”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Par. (1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/337">Pub. L. 103–337</ref> substituted a comma for “and” after “countries” and inserted “, and from the United Nations Organization or any regional international organization of which the United States is a member” after “subsidiary bodies”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Par. (1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s1312/a/1">Pub. L. 102–484, § 1312(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “outside the United States” for “in Europe and adjacent waters”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s1312/a/2">Pub. L. 102–484, § 1312(a)(2)</ref>, in introductory provisions, struck out “in which elements of the armed forces are deployed (or are to be deployed)” after “North Atlantic Treaty Organization” and substituted “outside the United States” for “in such country or in the military region in which such country is located”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—<ref href="/us/pl/99/661">Pub. L. 99–661</ref> substituted “elements of the armed forces deployed outside the United States” for “United States armed forces in Europe” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/661">Pub. L. 99–661</ref> amended section generally, restating existing provisions into introductory text and par. (1) and adding par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—<ref href="/us/pl/99/145">Pub. L. 99–145</ref> renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2321">section 2321 of this title</ref> as this section and substituted “section 2343” for “section 2323”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida9681f3f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida9681f40-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tXIII/s1317/j">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XIII, § 1317(j)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2902">108 Stat. 2902</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tXIII/s1317/j">“The amendments made by this section [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2349a">section 2349a of this title</ref> and amending this section and sections 2342 to 2347 and 2350 of this title] shall apply with regard to any acquisition or transfer of logistic support, supplies, and services under the authority of subchapter I of chapter 138 of title 10, United States Code, that is initiated after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida9681f41-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dA/tXIII/s1312/c">Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title XIII, § 1312(c)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2548">106 Stat. 2548</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/484/dA/tXIII/s1312/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2347">section 2347 of this title</ref>] shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>] and shall apply to acquisitions of logistics support, supplies, and services under chapter 138 of title 10, United States Code, that are initiated on or after the date of enactment of this Act.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="ida9681f42-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/323/s1">Pub. L. 96–323, § 1</ref>, <date date="1980-08-04">Aug. 4, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1016">94 Stat. 1016</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/323/s1">“That this Act [enacting this chapter] may be cited as the ‘North Atlantic Treaty Organization Mutual Support Act of 1979’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9681f43-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Demonstration and Prototyping Program To Advance International Product Support Capabilities in a Contested Logistics Environment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tVIII/s842">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title VIII, § 842</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/340">137 Stat. 340</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tVIII/s821">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 821</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1983">138 Stat. 1983</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tVIII">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 871, 872, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1002">139 Stat. 1002</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tVIII">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contested Logistics Demonstration and Prototyping Program Required</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a contested logistics demonstration and prototyping program to identify, develop, demonstrate, and field capabilities for product support in order to reduce or mitigate the risks associated with operations in a contested logistics environment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In carrying out the Program, the Secretary shall do the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Identify ways to capitalize on the inherent interoperability, commonality, and interchangeability of platforms and information systems operated by the United States and one or more covered nations, including to enable effective maintenance and repair activities in a contested logistics environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> Determine, develop, or establish best practices to reduce time needed to return repaired equipment to service, including the use of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> commercial best practices for rapid supply support;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> advanced manufacturing (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4841/f">section 4841(f) of title 10</ref>, United States Code) facilities for rapid, distributed production of parts closer to the point of use; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> common or shared parts pools.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Explore opportunities to expand the ability to preposition or store materials needed to enable rapid surge capability or to support operations in a contested logistics environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Identify, develop, demonstrate, and field effective and efficient means of conducting repairs of equipment away from permanent repair facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Explore flexible approaches to contracting and use of partnership agreements to enable use or development of the capabilities of covered product support providers to effectively, efficiently, and timely satisfy the product support requirements of a combat commander and any applicable covered nation in a contested logistics environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> Identify the resources, including any additional authorizations, required by the Secretary of Defense to reduce or mitigate the risks associated with operations in a contested logistics environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> Identify and document impediments to the performance of product support by covered product support providers in a contested logistics environment, including impediments created by statute, regulation, policy, agency guidance, or limitations on expenditure, transfer, or receipt of funds for product support in contested logistics environments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><chapeau> Identify and document any statutory or regulatory waivers or exemptions that may be applicable or necessary to enable the United States and covered nations to jointly carry out product support activities in contested logistics environments located outside of the United States, including, for each such waiver and exemption—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the person responsible for requesting such waiver or exemption;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the criteria for approval of such waiver or exemption; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the person responsible for approving such waiver or exemption.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Advance Planning and Preparation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may establish a product support arrangement, including an agreement for prepositioning or storage of materials, with a covered product support provider to enable a rapid response in a contingency operation (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101/a">section 101(a) of title 10</ref>, United States Code) to the product support requirements of such contingency operation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorities</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out the Program, the Secretary may, in accordance with section 3 of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2753">22 U.S.C. 2753</ref>), use the authorities under sections 2342, 2474, 3601, 4021, and 4022 of title 10, United States Code.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 24 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>], the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report summarizing Program activities, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> any recommendations to reduce impediments to meeting the requirements of a combatant command or covered nation for product support in a contested logistics environment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> a summary of impediments identified under subsection (b)(7) and specific recommendations for necessary changes to statutory, regulatory, policy, agency guidance, or current limitations on expenditure, transfer, or receipt of funds to carry out the product support activities under this pilot indefinitely;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> a summary of waivers or exemptions identified under subsection (b)(8), along with any recommendations for changes to the processes for obtaining such waivers or exemptions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> recommendations for improving the Program, including whether to extend or make the Program permanent.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Development and Promulgation of Department of Defense Guidance</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue guidance implementing the Program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sunset</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority under this section shall terminate <date date="2030-12-31">December 31, 2030</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contested Logistics Exercise Requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2027-09-30">September 30, 2027</date>, and biannually thereafter until the termination date in subsection (g), the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the senior official responsible for integration of global logistics (as designated in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2229b">section 2229b of this title</ref>), shall incorporate the requirements of the Program into a joint exercise that focuses on the contested logistics environment.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contested logistics environment</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘contested logistics environment’ has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2926">section 2926 of title 10</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered nations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘covered nation’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Australia;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Canada;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Japan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> New Zealand;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> the Republic of Korea;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> other nations as designated as a covered nation for the purposes of this Program by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered product support provider</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘covered product support provider’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a product support provider that includes an entity within the government of a covered nation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a private sector product support provider; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> a product support integrator domiciled in the United States or a covered nation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Product support; product support integrator; product support provider</inline>.—</heading><content>The terms ‘product support’, ‘product support integrator’, and ‘product support provider’ have the meanings given, respectively, in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4324">section 4324 of title 10</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Product support arrangement</inline>.—</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘product support arrangement’ means a contract, task order, or any other type of agreement or arrangement, between the United States and a covered product support provider, for the performance of the functions described in subparagraph (B) with respect to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> a platform or information system operated by the United States and the covered nation of such covered product support provider; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> a subsystem or components of such a platform or information system.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Functions described</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The functions described in this subparagraph, with respect to a platform, information system, subsystem, or component described in subparagraph (A), are the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> Performance-based logistics.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> Sustainment support.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> Contractor logistics support.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> Life-cycle product support.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="v">“(v)</num><content> Weapon system product support.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Program’ means the demonstration and prototyping program established under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Secretary’ means the Secretary of Defense.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9681f44-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Acceptance of Real Property, Services, and Commodities From Foreign Countries by Agencies of Department of Defense</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/165/tIX/s9008">Pub. L. 101–165, title IX, § 9008</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1130">103 Stat. 1130</ref>, which authorized agencies of Department of Defense to accept use of real property from foreign countries for United States in accordance with mutual defense agreements or occupational arrangements and to accept services furnished by foreign countries as reciprocal international courtesies or as services customarily made available without charge and to use same for support of United States forces in such areas without specific appropriation therefor, was repealed and restated in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2350g">section 2350g of this title</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXIV/s1451/b/1">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1451(b)(1)</ref>, (c), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1692">104 Stat. 1692</ref>, 1693.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9681f45-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Overseas Workload Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXIV/s1465">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1465</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1700">104 Stat. 1700</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/dA/tX/s1085">Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1085</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1483">105 Stat. 1483</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dA/tXIII/s1353">Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title XIII, § 1353</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2559">106 Stat. 2559</ref>, which related to eligibility of a firm of any member nation of North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) or of any major non-NATO ally to bid on any contract for maintenance, repair, or overhaul of equipment of the Department of Defense to be awarded under competitive procedures as part of the Overseas Workload Program, was repealed and restated in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2349">section 2349 of this title</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tXIV/s1431/a/1">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XIV, § 1431(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1832">107 Stat. 1832</ref>, 1833. Similar provisions were contained in the following authorization or appropriation acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/396/tIX/s9130">Pub. L. 102–396, title IX, § 9130</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1935">106 Stat. 1935</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tXIV/s1431/b/2">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XIV, § 1431(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1833">107 Stat. 1833</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/172/tVIII/s8122">Pub. L. 102–172, title VIII, § 8122</ref>, <date date="1991-11-26">Nov. 26, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1205">105 Stat. 1205</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/511/tVIII/s8003">Pub. L. 101–511, title VIII, § 8003</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1873">104 Stat. 1873</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/180/dA/tX/s1021">Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title X, § 1021</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1143">101 Stat. 1143</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
