<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida96cda34-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350c"><num value="2350c">§ 2350c.</num><heading> Cooperative military airlift agreements: allied countries</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida96cda35-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350c/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> Subject to the availability of appropriations, and after consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense may enter into cooperative military airlift agreements with the government of any allied country for the transportation of the personnel and cargo of the military forces of that country on aircraft operated by or for the military forces of the United States in return for the reciprocal transportation of the personnel and cargo of the military forces of the United States on aircraft operated by or for the military forces of that allied country. Any such agreement shall include the following terms:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida96cda36-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350c/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The rate of reimbursement for transportation provided shall be the same for each party and shall be not less than the rate charged to military forces of the United States, as determined by the Secretary of Defense under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2208/h">section 2208(h) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida96cda37-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350c/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Credits and liabilities accrued as a result of providing or receiving transportation shall be liquidated as agreed upon by the parties. Liquidation shall be either by direct payment to the country that has provided the greater amount of transportation or by the providing of in-kind transportation services to that country. The liquidation shall occur on a regular basis, but not less often than once every 12 months.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida96cda38-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350c/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> During peacetime, the only military airlift capacity that may be used to provide transportation is that capacity that (A) is not needed to meet the transportation requirements of the military forces of the country providing the transportation, and (B) was not created solely to accommodate the requirements of the military forces of the country receiving the transportation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida96cda39-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350c/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Defense articles purchased by an allied country from the United States under the Arms Export Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.) or from a commercial source under the export controls of the Arms Export Control Act may not be transported (for the purpose of delivery incident to the purchase of the defense articles) to the purchasing allied country on aircraft operated by or for the military forces of the United States except at a rate of reimbursement that is equal to the full cost of transportation of the defense articles, as required by section 21(a)(3) of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2761/a/3">22 U.S.C. 2761(a)(3)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida96cda3a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350c/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Subject to the availability of appropriations, and after consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense may enter into nonreciprocal military airlift agreements with North Atlantic Treaty Organization subsidiary bodies for the transportation of the personnel and cargo of such subsidiary bodies on aircraft operated by or for the military forces of the United States. Any such agreement shall be subject to such terms as the Secretary of Defense considers appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida96cda3b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350c/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> Any amount received by the United States as a result of an agreement entered into under this section shall be credited to applicable appropriations, accounts, and funds of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida96cda3c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350c/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><chapeau> In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida96cda3d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350c/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The term “allied country” means any of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida96cda3e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350c/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A country that is a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida96cda3f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350c/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Australia, New Zealand, Japan, and the Republic of Korea.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida96cda40-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350c/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Any other country designated as an allied country for the purposes of this section by the Secretary of Defense with the concurrence of the Secretary of State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida96cda41-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350c/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “North Atlantic Treaty Organization subsidiary bodies” has the meaning given to it by <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2350">section 2350 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida96cda42-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/97/252/tXI/s1125/a">Pub. L. 97–252, title XI, § 1125(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-08">Sept. 8, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/757">96 Stat. 757</ref>, § 2213; amended <ref href="/us/pl/99/145/tXIII/s1304/b">Pub. L. 99–145, title XIII, § 1304(b)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/742">99 Stat. 742</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/26/s7/k/2">Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(k)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/284">101 Stat. 284</ref>; renumbered § 2350c and amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tIX/s931/b/2">Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title IX, § 931(b)(2)</ref>, (e)(4), <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1534">103 Stat. 1534</ref>, 1535; <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dA/tXIII/s1311">Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title XIII, § 1311</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2547">106 Stat. 2547</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title XII, § 1222], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–328.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida96cda43-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida96cda44-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="ida96cda45-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Arms Export Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.), referred to in subsec. (a)(4), is <ref href="/us/pl/90/629">Pub. L. 90–629</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1320">82 Stat. 1320</ref>, as amended, which is classified principally to chapter 39 (§ 2751 et seq.) of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of Title 22</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida96cda46-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/106/398">Pub. L. 106–398</ref> redesignated subsec. (e) as (d) and struck out former subsec. (d) which read as follows: “Notwithstanding subchapter I, the Secretary of Defense may enter into military airlift agreements with allied countries only under the authority of this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s1311/a">Pub. L. 102–484, § 1311(a)</ref>, substituted “as agreed upon by the parties. Liquidation shall be either by direct payment to the country that has provided the greater amount of transportation or by the providing of in-kind transportation services to that country. The liquidation shall occur on a regular basis, but not less often than once every 12 months.” for “not less often than once every 3 months by direct payment to the country that has provided the greater amount of transportation.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s1311/b">Pub. L. 102–484, § 1311(b)</ref>, substituted “, New Zealand, Japan, and the Republic of Korea” for “or New Zealand”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—<ref href="/us/pl/101/189">Pub. L. 101–189</ref> renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2213">section 2213 of this title</ref> as this section and inserted “: allied countries” after “airlift agreements” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/s931/b/2">Pub. L. 101–189, § 931(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “subchapter I” for “chapter 138 of this title”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/100/26">Pub. L. 100–26</ref> inserted “The term” after each par. designation and substituted “allied” for “Allied” in par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/145">Pub. L. 99–145</ref> substituted “section 2350” for “section 2331”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida96cda47-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida96cda48-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Department of Defense Participation in European Program on Multilateral Exchange of Air Transportation and Air Refueling Services</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dA/tXII/s1276">Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XII, § 1276</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2029">126 Stat. 2029</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tX/s1051/r/9">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1051(r)(9)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1565">131 Stat. 1565</ref>, which related to participation of the United States in the Air Transport, Air-to-Air Refueling and other Exchanges of Services (ATARES) program of the Movement Coordination Centre Europe, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXII/s1203/c">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1203(c)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3911">134 Stat. 3911</ref>. See section 2350<i>o</i> of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida96cda49-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Department of Defense Participation in Strategic Airlift Capability Partnership</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/181/dA/tX/s1032">Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title X, § 1032</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/306">122 Stat. 306</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/181/dA/tX/s1032">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority To Participate in Partnership.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Memorandum of understanding</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may enter into a multilateral memorandum of understanding authorizing the Strategic Airlift Capability Partnership to conduct activities necessary to accomplish its purpose, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the acquisition, equipping, ownership, and operation of strategic airlift aircraft; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the acquisition or transfer of airlift and airlift-related services and supplies among members of the Strategic Airlift Capability Partnership, or between the Partnership and non-member countries or international organizations, on a reimbursable basis or by replacement-in-kind or exchange of airlift or airlift-related services of an equal value.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Payments</inline>.—</heading><content>From funds available to the Department of Defense for such purpose, the Secretary of Defense may pay the United States equitable share of the recurring and non-recurring costs of the activities and operations of the Strategic Airlift Capability Partnership, including costs associated with procurement of aircraft components and spare parts, maintenance, facilities, and training, and the costs of claims.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorities Under Partnership</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In carrying out the memorandum of understanding entered into under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense may do the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> Waive reimbursement of the United States for the cost of the following functions performed by Department of Defense personnel with respect to the Strategic Airlift Capability Partnership:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Auditing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Quality assurance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Inspection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Contract administration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> Acceptance testing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> Certification services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> Planning, programming, and management services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Waive the imposition of any surcharge for administrative services provided by the United States that would otherwise be chargeable against the Strategic Airlift Capability Partnership.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Pay the salaries, travel, lodging, and subsistence expenses of Department of Defense personnel assigned for duty to the Strategic Airlift Capability Partnership without seeking reimbursement or cost-sharing for such expenses.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Crediting of Receipts</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Any amount received by the United States in carrying out the memorandum of understanding entered into under subsection (a) shall be credited, as elected by the Secretary of Defense, to the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The appropriation, fund, or account used in incurring the obligation for which such amount is received.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> An appropriation, fund, or account currently providing funds for the purposes for which such obligation was made.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority To Transfer Aircraft.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transfer authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense may transfer one strategic airlift aircraft to the Strategic Airlift Capability Partnership in accordance with the terms and conditions of the memorandum of understanding entered into under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 30 days before the date on which the Secretary transfers a strategic airlift aircraft under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] a report on the strategic airlift aircraft to be transferred, including the type of strategic airlift aircraft to be transferred and the tail registration or serial number of such aircraft.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Strategic Airlift Capability Partnership Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section the term ‘Strategic Airlift Capability Partnership’ means the strategic airlift capability consortium established by the United States and other participating countries.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
