<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida96cda7a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350f"><num value="2350f">§ 2350f.</num><heading> Procurement of communications support and related supplies and services</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida96cda7b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350f/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> As an alternative means of obtaining communications support and related supplies and services, the Secretary of Defense, subject to the approval of the Secretary of State, may enter into a bilateral arrangement with any allied country or allied international organization or may enter into a multilateral arrangement with allied countries and allied international organizations, under which, in return for being provided communications support and related supplies and services, the United States would agree to provide to the allied country or countries or allied international organization or allied international organizations, as the case may be, an equivalent value of communications support and related supplies and services. The term of an arrangement entered into under this subsection may not exceed five years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida96cda7c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350f/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida96cda7d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350f/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any arrangement entered into under this section shall require that any accrued credits and liabilities resulting from an unequal exchange of communications support and related supplies and services during the term of such arrangement would be liquidated by direct payment to the party having provided the greater amount of communications support and related supplies and services. Liquidations may be made at such times as the parties in an arrangement may agree upon, but in no case may final liquidation in the case of an arrangement be made later than 30 days after the end of the term for which the arrangement was entered into.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida96cda7e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350f/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Parties to an arrangement entered into under this section shall annually reconcile accrued credits and liabilities accruing under such agreement. Any liability of the United States resulting from a reconciliation shall be charged against the applicable appropriation available to the Department of Defense (at the time of the reconciliation) for obligation for communications support and related supplies and services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida96cda7f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350f/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Payments received by the United States shall be credited to the appropriation from which such communications support and related supplies and services have been provided.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" status="repealed" id="ida96cda80-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350f/c"><num value="c">[(c)</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tX/s1041/a/10">Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1041(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2645">116 Stat. 2645</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida96cda81-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350f/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><chapeau> In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida96cda82-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350f/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The term “allied country” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida96cda83-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350f/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a country that is a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida96cda84-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350f/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Australia, New Zealand, Japan, or the Republic of Korea; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida96cda85-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350f/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> any other country designated as an allied country for purposes of this section by the Secretary of Defense with the concurrence of the Secretary of State.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida96cda86-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350f/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “allied international organization” means the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) or any other international organization designated as an allied international organization for the purposes of this section by the Secretary of Defense with the concurrence of the Secretary of State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida96cda87-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/98/525/tX/s1005/a">Pub. L. 98–525, title X, § 1005(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2578">98 Stat. 2578</ref>, § 2401a; amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/26/s7/k/3">Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(k)(3)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/284">101 Stat. 284</ref>; renumbered § 2350f and amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tIX/s933/a">Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title IX, § 933(a)</ref>–(d), <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1537">103 Stat. 1537</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXIV/s1484/k/8">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1484(k)(8)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1719">104 Stat. 1719</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tXV/s1502/a/2">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/502">110 Stat. 502</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tX/s1067/1">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/774">113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tX/s1041/a/10">Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1041(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2645">116 Stat. 2645</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida96cda88-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida96cda89-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida96cda8a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/107/314">Pub. L. 107–314</ref> struck out subsec. (c) which read as follows: “The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives copies of all documents evidencing an arrangement entered into under subsection (a) not later than 45 days after entering into such an arrangement.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/106/65">Pub. L. 106–65</ref> substituted “and the Committee on Armed Services” for “and the Committee on National Security”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106">Pub. L. 104–106</ref> substituted “Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on National Security of the House of Representatives” for “Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (d)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510">Pub. L. 101–510</ref> substituted a semicolon for “, or” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—<ref href="/us/pl/101/189/s933/a">Pub. L. 101–189, § 933(a)</ref>, renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2401a">section 2401a of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/s933/b">Pub. L. 101–189, § 933(b)</ref>, substituted “a bilateral arrangement with any allied country or allied international organization or may enter into a multilateral arrangement with allied countries and allied international organizations” for “an arrangement with the Minister of Defense or other appropriate official of any allied country or with the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO),” and “the allied country or countries or allied international organization or allied international organizations, as the case may be,” for “such country or NATO” and inserted “The term of an arrangement entered into under this subsection may not exceed five years.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/s933/c">Pub. L. 101–189, § 933(c)</ref>, designated first sentence as par. (1), inserted “Liquidations may be made at such times as the parties in an arrangement may agree upon, but in no case may final liquidation in the case of an arrangement be made later than 30 days after the end of the term for which the arrangement was entered into.” after “supplies and services.”, added par. (2), and designated second sentence as par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/s933/d/1">Pub. L. 101–189, § 933(d)(1)</ref>, (2), substituted “In this section:” and par. (1) for “In this section, the term ‘allied country’ means—” and redesignated former cls. (1) and (2) as cls. (A) and (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/s933/d/3">Pub. L. 101–189, § 933(d)(3)</ref>, which directed amendment of cl. (A) by substituting a semicolon for “; or” at end, could not be executed because “; or” did not appear.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/s933/d/4">Pub. L. 101–189, § 933(d)(4)</ref>, substituted “; or” for period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(C), (2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/s933/d/5">Pub. L. 101–189, § 933(d)(5)</ref>, added cl. (C) and par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/100/26">Pub. L. 100–26</ref> inserted “the term” after “In this section,”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
