<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida96cda4a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350d"><num value="2350d">§ 2350d.</num><heading> Cooperative acquisition and logistics support agreements: NATO countries</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida96cda4b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350d/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">General Authority</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida96cda4c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350d/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may enter into bilateral or multilateral agreements known as Support or Procurement Partnership Agreements with one or more governments of other member countries of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) participating in the operation of the NATO Support and Procurement Organization and its executive agencies. Any such agreement shall be for the purpose of providing cooperative acquisition and logistics support for the armed forces of the countries which are parties to the agreement. Any such agreement—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida96cda4d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350d/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall be entered into pursuant to the terms of the charter of the NATO Support and Procurement Organization and its executive agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida96cda4e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350d/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall provide for the common acquisition and logistics support of activities common to the participating countries.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida96cda4f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350d/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Such an agreement may provide for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida96cda50-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350d/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the transfer of logistics support, supplies, and services by the United States to the NATO Support and Procurement Organization and its executive agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida96cda51-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350d/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the acquisition of armaments and logistics support, supplies, and services by the United States from that Organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida96cda52-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350d/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority of Secretary</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Under the terms of a Support or Procurement Partnership Agreement or Arrangement, the Secretary of Defense—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida96cda53-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350d/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> may agree that the NATO Support and Procurement Organization and its executive agencies may enter into contracts for supply, services, support, and acquisition, including armaments for requirements of the United States, to the extent the Secretary determines that the procedures of such Organization governing such supply, services, support, and acquisition are appropriate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida96cda54-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350d/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> may share the costs of set-up charges of facilities for use by the NATO Support and Procurement Organization and its executive agencies to provide cooperative acquisition and logistics support and in the costs of establishing a revolving fund for initial acquisition and replenishment of supply stocks to be used by the NATO Support and Procurement Organization and its executive agencies to provide cooperative acquisition and logistics support.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida96cda55-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350d/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sharing of Administrative Expenses</inline>.—</heading><content>Each Support or Procurement Partnership Agreement shall provide for joint management by the participating countries and for the equitable sharing of the administrative costs and costs of claims incident to the agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida96cda56-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350d/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Application of Chapter</inline> 137.—</heading><content>Except as otherwise provided in this section, the provisions of chapter 137 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002087">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002087"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title apply to a contract entered into by the Secretary of Defense for the acquisition of logistics support under a Support or Procurement Partnership Agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida96cda57-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350d/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Application of Arms Export Control Act</inline>.—</heading><content>Any transfer of defense articles or defense services to a member country of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization or to the NATO Support and Procurement Organization and its executive agencies for the purposes of a Support or Procurement Partnership Agreement shall be carried out in accordance with this chapter and the Arms Export Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida96cda58-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2350d/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Supplemental Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority of the Secretary of Defense under this section is in addition to the authority of the Secretary under subchapter I and any other provision of law.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida96cda59-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added and amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tIX">Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title IX</ref>, §§ 931(c), 938(c), <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1534">103 Stat. 1534</ref>, 1539; <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dA/tVIII/s843/b/2">Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title VIII, § 843(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2469">106 Stat. 2469</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tXII/s1250/a">Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title XII, § 1250(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/926">127 Stat. 926</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tXII/s1279/a">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1279(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/2072">132 Stat. 2072</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tXII/s1244/b">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XII, § 1244(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2845">136 Stat. 2845</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida96cda5a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida96cda5b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="ida96cda5c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Chapter 137 of this title, referred to in subsec. (d), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXVIII/s1881/a">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1881(a)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4293">134 Stat. 4293</ref>, effective <date date="2022-01-01">Jan. 1, 2022</date>, in conjunction with the transfer and reorganization of acquisition provisions in this title by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXVIII">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII</ref>, <date date="2022-01-01">Jan. 1, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4149">134 Stat. 4149</ref>. For definition of “chapter 137 legacy provisions”, see <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3016">section 3016 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Arms Export Control Act, referred to in subsec. (e), is <ref href="/us/pl/90/629">Pub. L. 90–629</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1320">82 Stat. 1320</ref>, as amended, which is classified principally to chapter 39 (§ 2751 et seq.) of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of Title 22</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="ida96cda5d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in <ref href="/us/pl/99/661/dA/tXI/s1102">Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XI, § 1102</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3961">100 Stat. 3961</ref>, which was set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2407">section 2407 of this title</ref>, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/s931/d/2">Pub. L. 101–189, § 931(d)(2)</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida96cda5e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—<ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s1244/b/1">Pub. L. 117–263, § 1244(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “acquisition and logistics support” for “logistic support” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s1244/b/2/A/i">Pub. L. 117–263, § 1244(b)(2)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “acquisition and logistics support” for “logistics support” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s1244/b/2/A/ii">Pub. L. 117–263, § 1244(b)(2)(A)(ii)</ref>, substituted “acquisition and logistics support” for “logistic support”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s1244/b/2/B">Pub. L. 117–263, § 1244(b)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “armaments and logistics support” for “logistics support”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s1244/b/3/A">Pub. L. 117–263, § 1244(b)(3)(A)</ref>, substituted “Partnership Agreement or Arrangement” for “Partnership Agreement” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s1244/b/3/B">Pub. L. 117–263, § 1244(b)(3)(B)</ref>, substituted “supply, services, support, and acquisition, including armaments for requirements” for “supply and acquisition of logistics support in Europe for requirements” and “supply, services, support, and acquisition are appropriate” for “supply and acquisition are appropriate”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s1244/b/3/C">Pub. L. 117–263, § 1244(b)(3)(C)</ref>, substituted “acquisition and logistics support” for “logistics support” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s1279/a/1">Pub. L. 115–232, § 1279(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “NATO Support and Procurement Organization” for “NATO Support Organization” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s1279/a/3">Pub. L. 115–232, § 1279(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “Support or Procurement Partnership Agreements” for “Support Partnership Agreements” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s1279/a/1">Pub. L. 115–232, § 1279(a)(1)</ref>, (2), substituted “Support or Procurement Partnership Agreement” for “Support Partnership Agreement” in introductory provisions and “NATO Support and Procurement Organization” for “NATO Support Organization” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s1279/a/2">Pub. L. 115–232, § 1279(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “Support or Procurement Partnership Agreement” for “Support Partnership Agreement”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s1279/a/1">Pub. L. 115–232, § 1279(a)(1)</ref>, (2), substituted “NATO Support and Procurement Organization” for “NATO Support Organization” and “Support or Procurement Partnership Agreement” for “Support Partnership Agreement”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s1250/a/1">Pub. L. 113–66, § 1250(a)(1)</ref>, (2)(A), in introductory provisions, substituted “Support Partnership Agreements” for “Weapon System Partnership Agreements” and “NATO Support Organization and its executive agencies” for “NATO Maintenance and Supply Organization”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s1250/a/1">Pub. L. 113–66, § 1250(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “NATO Support Organization and its executive agencies” for “NATO Maintenance and Supply Organization”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s1250/a/2/B">Pub. L. 113–66, § 1250(a)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “activities” for “a specific weapon system”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s1250/a/1">Pub. L. 113–66, § 1250(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “NATO Support Organization and its executive agencies” for “NATO Maintenance and Supply Organization”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s1250/a/3">Pub. L. 113–66, § 1250(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “Support Partnership Agreement” for “Weapon System Partnership Agreement” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s1250/a/1">Pub. L. 113–66, § 1250(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “NATO Support Organization and its executive agencies” for “NATO Maintenance and Supply Organization” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s1250/a/3">Pub. L. 113–66, § 1250(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “Support Partnership Agreement” for “Weapon System Partnership Agreement”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s1250/a/1">Pub. L. 113–66, § 1250(a)(1)</ref>, (3), substituted “NATO Support Organization and its executive agencies” for “NATO Maintenance and Supply Organization” and “Support Partnership Agreement” for “Weapon System Partnership Agreement”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484">Pub. L. 102–484</ref> inserted “and costs of claims” after “administrative costs”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/s938/c">Pub. L. 101–189, § 938(c)</ref>, inserted “this chapter and” after “in accordance with”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
