<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida974064d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391"><num value="2391">§ 2391.</num><heading> Military base reuse studies and community planning assistance</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida974064e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reuse Studies</inline>.—</heading><content>Whenever the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of the military department concerned publicly announces that a military installation is a candidate for closure or that a final decision has been made to close a military installation and the Secretary of Defense determines, because of the location, facilities, or other particular characteristics of the installation, that the installation may be suitable for some specific Federal, State, or local use potentially beneficial to the Nation, the Secretary of Defense may conduct such studies, including the preparation of an environmental impact statement in accordance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.), in connection with such installation and such potential use as may be necessary to provide information sufficient to make sound conclusions and recommendations regarding the possible use of the installation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida974064f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Adjustment and Diversification Assistance</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9740650-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense may make grants, conclude cooperative agreements, and supplement funds available under Federal programs administered by agencies other than the Department of Defense in order to assist State and local governments in planning community adjustments and economic diversification required (A) by the proposed or actual establishment, realignment, or closure of a military installation, (B) by the cancellation or termination of a Department of Defense contract or the failure to proceed with an approved major weapon system program, (C) by a publicly announced planned major reduction in Department of Defense spending that would directly and adversely affect a community, (D) by the encroachment of a civilian community on a military installation, (E) by threats to military installation resilience, (F) by the closure or the significantly reduced operations of a defense facility as the result of the merger, acquisition, or consolidation of the defense contractor operating the defense facility, or (G) by any action of the Department of Defense that negatively affects a covered depot (as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2476/f">section 2476(f) of this title</ref>), if the Secretary determines that an action described in clause (A), (B), (C), (F), or (G) is likely to have a direct and significantly adverse consequence on the affected community or, in the case of an action described in clause (D) or (E), if the Secretary determines that either the encroachment of the civilian community or threats to military installation resilience is likely to impair the continued operational utility of the military installation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9740651-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In the case of the establishment or expansion of a military installation, assistance may be made under paragraph (1) only if (A) community impact assistance or special impact assistance is not otherwise available, and (B) the establishment or expansion involves the assignment to the installation of (i) more than 2,000 military, civilian, and contractor Department of Defense personnel, or (ii) more military, civilian, and contractor Department of Defense personnel than the number equal to 10 percent of the number of persons employed in counties or independent municipalities within fifteen miles of the installation, whichever is lesser.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9740652-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In the case of a publicly announced planned reduction in Department of Defense spending, the closure or realignment of a military installation, the cancellation or termination of a Department of Defense contract, or the failure to proceed with a previously approved major defense acquisition program, assistance may be made under paragraph (1) only if the reduction, closure or realignment, cancellation or termination, or failure will have a direct and significant adverse impact on a community or its residents.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9740653-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9740654-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In the case of a State or local government eligible for assistance under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense may also make grants, conclude cooperative agreements, and supplement other Federal funds in order to assist the State or local government to carry out a community adjustment and economic diversification program (including State industrial extension or modernization efforts to facilitate the economic diversification of defense contractors and subcontractors) in addition to planning such a program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9740655-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall establish criteria for the selection of community adjustment and economic diversification programs to receive assistance under subparagraph (A). Such criteria shall include a requirement that the State or local government agree—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9740656-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to provide not less than 10 percent of the funding for the program from non-Federal sources;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9740657-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to provide business planning and market exploration services under the program to defense contractors and subcontractors that seek modernization or diversification assistance; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9740658-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/4/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> to provide training, counseling, and placement services for members of the armed forces and dislocated defense workers.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9740659-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Secretary shall carry out this paragraph in coordination with the Secretary of Commerce.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida974065a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida974065b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense may also make grants, conclude cooperative agreements, and supplement other Federal funds in order to assist a State or local government in planning community adjustments and economic diversification even though the State or local government is not currently eligible for assistance under paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines that a substantial portion of the economic activity or population of the geographic area to be subject to the advance planning is dependent on defense expenditures.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida974065c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may also make grants, conclude cooperative agreements, and supplement other Federal funds in order to assist a State or local government in enhancing its capacities—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida974065d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/5/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to assist communities, businesses, and workers adversely affected by an action described in paragraph (1);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida974065e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/5/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to support local adjustment and diversification initiatives;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida974065f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/5/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> to stimulate cooperation between statewide and local adjustment and diversification efforts; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9740660-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/5/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> to support public infrastructure projects and services (including health care, housing, and defense critical infrastructure projects and services) that enhance the capabilities and resilience of the defense industrial base, defense industrial base workers, and military installations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9740661-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense may also make grants, conclude cooperative agreements, and supplement other Federal funds in order to assist a State or local government in enhancing the capabilities of the government to support efforts of the Department of Defense to privatize, contract for, or diversify the performance of military family support services in cases in which the capability of the Department to provide such services is adversely affected by an action described in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9740662-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense may also make grants, conclude cooperative agreements, and supplement other Federal funds, in order to assist a State or local government in planning, enhancing infrastructure, and implementing measures and projects (to include resilience measures and projects involving the protection, restoration, and maintenance of natural features) that, as determined by the Secretary of Defense, will contribute to maintaining or improving military installation resilience or will prevent or mitigate encroachment that could affect operations of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9740663-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Funds provided to State and local governments and regional organizations under this section may be used as part or all of any required non-Federal contribution to a Federal grant-in-aid program for the purposes stated in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9740664-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><chapeau> To the extent practicable, the Secretary of Defense shall inform a State or local government applying for assistance under this subsection of the approval or rejection by the Secretary of the application for such assistance as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9740665-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Before the end of the 7-day period beginning on the date on which the Secretary receives the application, in the case of an application for a planning grant.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9740666-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Before the end of the 30-day period beginning on such date, in the case of an application for assistance to carry out a community adjustments and economic diversifications program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9740667-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9740668-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In attempting to complete consideration of applications within the time period specified in paragraph (7), the Secretary of Defense shall give priority to those applications requesting assistance for a community described in subsection (f)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9740669-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> If an application under paragraph (7) is rejected by the Secretary, the Secretary shall promptly inform the State or local government of the reasons for the rejection of the application.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida974066a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Research and Technical Assistance</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense may make grants to, or conclude cooperative agreements or enter into contracts with, another Federal agency, a State or local government, or any private entity to conduct research and provide technical assistance in support of activities under this section or Executive Order 12788 (57 Fed. Reg. 2213), as amended by section 33 of Executive Order 13286 (68 Fed. Reg. 10625) and Executive Order 13378 (70 Fed. Reg. 28413).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida974066b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Defense Community Infrastructure Program</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida974066c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida974066d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense may make grants, conclude cooperative agreements, and supplement funds available under Federal programs administered by agencies other than the Department of Defense to assist State governments, local governments, and not-for-profit, member-owned utility services to address deficiencies in community infrastructure supportive of a military installation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida974066e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall establish criteria for the selection of community infrastructure projects to receive assistance under this subsection for each of the following categories:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida974066f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/d/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Projects that will enhance the readiness of a military department or mission assurance at a military installation.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9740670-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/d/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Projects that will enhance military family quality of life at a military installation, taking into consideration subsection (e)(4)(C).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9740671-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/d/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Projects that will enhance military installation resilience, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9740672-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/d/1/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> Projects that will contribute to the training of cadets enrolled in an independent Reserve Officer Training Corps program at a covered educational institution.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9740673-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9740674-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The criteria established for the selection of community infrastructure projects to receive assistance under this subsection shall include a requirement that, except as provided in subparagraph (B), the recipient of such assistance agrees to contribute not less than 30 percent of the funding for the community infrastructure project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9740675-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> If a proposed community infrastructure project will be carried out in a rural area or the Secretary of Defense determines that a proposed community infrastructure project is advantageous for reasons related to national security, the Secretary—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9740676-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/d/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> shall not penalize a State or local government for offering to make a contribution of 30 percent or less of the funding for the community infrastructure project; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9740677-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/d/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> may reduce the requirement for a State or local government contribution to 30 percent or less or waive the cost-sharing requirement entirely.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9740678-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In selecting community infrastructure projects to receive assistance under this subsection, the Secretary shall consider infrastructure improvements identified in the report on strategic seaports required by section 3515 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Public Law 116–92</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/133/1985">133 Stat. 1985</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9740679-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Amounts appropriated or otherwise made available for assistance under paragraph (1) may remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida974067a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida974067b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The terms “military installation” and “realignment” have the meanings given those terms in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2687">section 2687 of this title</ref>. For purposes of paragraphs (1)(D) and (E) and (5)(D) of subsection (b) and subsection (d), the term “military installation” includes a military facility owned and operated by any of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or the Virgin Islands, even though the facility is not under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense, if the Secretary of Defense determines that the military facility is subject to significant use for training by the armed forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida974067c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “defense facility” means any private facility producing goods or services pursuant to a defense contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida974067d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The terms “community adjustment” and “economic diversification” include the development of feasibility studies and business plans for market diversification within a community adversely affected by an action described in clause (A), (B), (C), or (E) of subsection (b)(1) by adversely affected businesses and labor organizations located in the community.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida974067e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida974067f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/e/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> The term “community infrastructure” means a project or facility described in subparagraph (B) that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9740680-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/e/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> is located off of a military installation or on property under the jurisdiction of a Secretary of a military department that is subject to a real estate agreement (including a lease or easement); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9740681-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/e/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> is—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="ida9740682-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/e/4/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> owned by a State or local government; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="ida9740683-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/e/4/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> a not-for-profit, member-owned utility service.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9740684-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/e/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> A project or facility described in this subparagraph is any of the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9740685-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/e/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Any transportation project.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9740686-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/e/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> A school, hospital, police, fire, emergency response, or other community support facility.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9740687-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/e/4/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> A water, waste-water, telecommunications, electric, gas, or other utility infrastructure project.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9740688-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/e/4/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> A demolition project.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9740689-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/e/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> For the purposes of determining whether proposed community infrastructure will enhance quality of life, the Secretary of Defense shall consider the impact of the community infrastructure on alleviating installation commuter workforce issues and the benefit of schools or other local infrastructure located off of a military installation that will support members of the armed forces and their dependents residing in the community.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida974068a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The term “rural area” means a city, town, or unincorporated area that has a population of not more than 100,000 inhabitants.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida974068b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/e/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> The term “covered educational institution” means a college or university that is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida974068c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/e/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a part B institution, as defined in section 322 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1061">20 U.S.C. 1061</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida974068d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/e/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> an 1890 Institution, as defined in section 2 of the Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reform Act of 1998 (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s7601">7 U.S.C. 7601</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida974068e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/e/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> not affiliated with a consortium; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida974068f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/e/6/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> located at least 40 miles from a major military installation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9740690-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2391/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assistance Subject to Appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority of the Secretary of Defense to make grants under this section in any fiscal year is subject to the availability of appropriations for that purpose.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida9740691-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/97/86/tIX/s912/a/1">Pub. L. 97–86, title IX, § 912(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1122">95 Stat. 1122</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/98/115/tVIII/s808">Pub. L. 98–115, title VIII, § 808</ref>, <date date="1983-10-11">Oct. 11, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/789">97 Stat. 789</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/26/s7/k/3">Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(k)(3)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/284">101 Stat. 284</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/456/dB/tXXVIII/s2805">Pub. L. 100–456, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2805</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2116">102 Stat. 2116</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dD/tXLI/s4102/b">Pub. L. 101–510, div. D, title XLI, § 4102(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1851">104 Stat. 1851</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/25/tVII/s701/j/3">Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 701(j)(3)</ref>, <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/116">105 Stat. 116</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dA/tX/s1052/28">Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1052(28)</ref>, div. D, title XLIII, § 4301(a)–(c), <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2500">106 Stat. 2500</ref>, 2696, 2697; <ref href="/us/pl/103/35/tII/s202/a/15">Pub. L. 103–35, title II, § 202(a)(15)</ref>, <date date="1993-05-31">May 31, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/101">107 Stat. 101</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dB/tXXIX/s2913">Pub. L. 103–160, div. B, title XXIX, § 2913</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1925">107 Stat. 1925</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tXI">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XI</ref>, §§ 1122(a), 1123(a), (b), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2870">108 Stat. 2870</ref>, 2871; <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tXV/s1502/a/1">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/502">110 Stat. 502</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dB/tXXVIII/s2814">Pub. L. 104–201, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2814</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2790">110 Stat. 2790</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dB/tXXVIII/s2822">Pub. L. 105–85, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2822</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1997">111 Stat. 1997</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tX/s1067/1">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/774">113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tX/s1041/a/13">Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1041(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2645">116 Stat. 2645</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dB/tXXVIII/s2832">Pub. L. 109–163, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2832</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3520">119 Stat. 3520</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dB/tXXVIII">Pub. L. 109–364, div. B, title XXVIII</ref>, §§ 2861, 2862, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2498">120 Stat. 2498</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/417/dB/tXXVIII/s2823/b">Pub. L. 110–417, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2823(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4730">122 Stat. 4730</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dB/tXXVII/s2712/c/1">Pub. L. 112–239, div. B, title XXVII, § 2712(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2145">126 Stat. 2145</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dB/tXXVIII">Pub. L. 115–232, div. B, title XXVIII</ref>, §§ 2805(f), 2861, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/2263">132 Stat. 2263</ref>, 2282; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dB/tXXVIII/s2862">Pub. L. 116–92, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2862</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1899">133 Stat. 1899</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dB/tXXVIII/s2882">Pub. L. 116–283, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2882</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4369">134 Stat. 4369</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tIII/s313">Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title III, § 313</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1629">135 Stat. 1629</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dB/tXXVIII">Pub. L. 117–263, div. B, title XXVIII</ref>, §§ 2862–2864, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3010">136 Stat. 3010</ref>, 3011; <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dB/tXXVIII/s2801">Pub. L. 118–31, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2801</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/743">137 Stat. 743</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dB/tXXVIII">Pub. L. 118–159, div. B, title XXVIII</ref>, §§ 2802, 2842, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2247">138 Stat. 2247</ref>, 2263; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tIII/s371/a">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title III, § 371(a)</ref>, div. B, title XXVIII, §§ 2805, 2806(a), 2807, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/836">139 Stat. 836</ref>, 1298.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida9740692-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida9740693-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="ida9740694-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/91/190">Pub. L. 91–190</ref>, <date date="1970-01-01">Jan. 1, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/852">83 Stat. 852</ref>, as amended, which is classified generally to chapter 55 (§ 4321 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">section 4321 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order 12788, referred to in subsec. (c), is set out below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The amendment made by section 3002 of the Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2002, referred to in subsec. (d)(1)(B)(i), is the amendment made by <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dB/tXXX/s3002">section 3002 of title XXX of div. B of Pub. L. 107–107</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1344">115 Stat. 1344</ref>, which amended the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 (<ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dB/tXXIX">Pub. L. 101–510, div. B, title XXIX</ref>, part A [§ 2901 et seq.], <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1808">104 Stat. 1808</ref>, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2687">section 2687 of this title</ref>) by adding section 2912 of such Act.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida9740695-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s371/a">Pub. L. 119–60, § 371(a)</ref>, struck out “or” after “military installation resilience,”, inserted “or (G) by any action of the Department of Defense that negatively affects a covered depot (as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2476/f">section 2476(f) of this title</ref>),” after “the defense facility,”, and substituted “(C), (F), or (G)” for “(C), or (F)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5)(B)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s2805">Pub. L. 119–60, § 2805</ref>, inserted “(including health care, housing, and defense critical infrastructure projects and services)” after “projects and services” and substituted “the defense industrial base, defense industrial base workers, and military installations” for “the defense industrial base workers, if the Secretary determines such support will improve operations of the Department of Defense”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s2806/a/1">Pub. L. 119–60, § 2806(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “for each of the following categories” for “, including selection of community infrastructure projects in the following order of priority” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s2806/a/2">Pub. L. 119–60, § 2806(a)(2)</ref>, which directed substitution of “the readiness of a military department or mission assurance at a military installation.” for “ ‘military value’ and all that follows through the period”, was executed by striking out “military value at a military installation, taking into consideration the military value criteria originally developed by the Secretary in compliance with the amendment made by section 3002 of the Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2002 (division B of <ref href="/us/pl/107/107">Public Law 107–107</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/115/1344">115 Stat. 1344</ref>).”, beginning with “military value” where first appearing, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(B)(ii), (iv). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s2806/a/3">Pub. L. 119–60, § 2806(a)(3)</ref>, redesignated cls. (ii) and (iv) as (iv) and (ii), respectively, and reordered cls. accordingly.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(4)(B)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s2807">Pub. L. 119–60, § 2807</ref>, added cl. (iv).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (b)(5)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s2842/1">Pub. L. 118–159, § 2842(1)</ref>, inserted “or local government” after “a State” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5)(B)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s2842/2">Pub. L. 118–159, § 2842(2)</ref>–(4), added cl. (iv).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s2802/a/1">Pub. L. 118–159, § 2802(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “State governments, local governments, and not-for-profit, member-owned utility services” for “State and local governments”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s2802/b">Pub. L. 118–159, § 2802(b)</ref>, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101/e/8">section 101(e)(8) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s2802/a/2">Pub. L. 118–159, § 2802(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “the recipient of such assistance agrees” for “the State or local government agree”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2023—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s2801/1">Pub. L. 118–31, § 2801(1)</ref>, struck out “Pilot” before “Program” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s2801/2">Pub. L. 118–31, § 2801(2)</ref>, struck out par. (5) which read as follows: “The authority under this subsection shall expire on <date date="2028-09-30">September 30, 2028</date>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (d)(1)(B)(ii) to (iv). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s2862/1">Pub. L. 117–263, § 2862(1)</ref>, added cl. (ii) and redesignated former cls. (ii) and (iii) as (iii) and (iv), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3) to (5). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s2863">Pub. L. 117–263, § 2863</ref>, added par. (3) and redesignated former pars. (3) and (4) as (4) and (5), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(4)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s2864">Pub. L. 117–263, § 2864</ref>, inserted “or on property under the jurisdiction of a Secretary of a military department that is subject to a real estate agreement (including a lease or easement)” after “installation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s2862/2">Pub. L. 117–263, § 2862(2)</ref>, added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (b)(5)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s313/1">Pub. L. 117–81, § 313(1)</ref>, added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s2882/a">Pub. L. 116–283, § 2882(a)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A), struck out “, if the Secretary determines that such assistance will enhance the military value, resilience, or military family quality of life at such military installation” after “supportive of a military installation”, and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s2882/b">Pub. L. 116–283, § 2882(b)</ref>, amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “The Secretary shall establish criteria for the selection of community infrastructure projects to receive assistance under paragraph (1). The criteria shall include a requirement that the State or local government agree to contribute not less than 30 percent of the funding for the community infrastructure project, unless the community infrastructure project is located in a rural area, or for reasons related to national security, in which case the Secretary may waive the requirement for a State or local government contribution.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s2882/c">Pub. L. 116–283, § 2882(c)</ref>, substituted “on <date date="2028-09-30">September 30, 2028</date>” for “upon the expiration of the 10-year period which begins on the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s313/2">Pub. L. 117–81, § 313(2)</ref>, substituted “paragraphs (1)(D) and (E) and (5)(D) of subsection (b) and subsection (d)” for “subsection (b)(1)(D)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(4)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s2882/d">Pub. L. 116–283, § 2882(d)</ref>, added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s2882/e">Pub. L. 116–283, § 2882(e)</ref>, substituted “100,000 inhabitants” for “50,000 inhabitants”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (e)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Pub. L. 116–92</ref> amended par. (4) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The term ‘community infrastructure’ means any transportation project; school, hospital, police, fire, emergency response, or other community support facility; or water, waste-water, telecommunications, electric, gas, or other utility infrastructure project that is located off of a military installation and owned by a State or local government.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s2805/f">Pub. L. 115–232, § 2805(f)</ref>, substituted “, (E) by threats to military installation resilience, or (F) by the closure” for “, or (E) by the closure”, “(A), (B), (C), or (F)” for “(A), (B), (C), or (E)”, and “action described in clause (D) or (E), if the Secretary determines that either the encroachment of the civilian community or threats to military installation resilience” for “action described in clause (D), if the Secretary determines that the encroachment of the civilian community”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s2861/1">Pub. L. 115–232, § 2861(1)</ref>, (2), added subsec. (d) and redesignated former subsec. (d) as (e). Former subsec. (e) redesignated (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s2861/3">Pub. L. 115–232, § 2861(3)</ref>, added pars. (4) and (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s2861/1">Pub. L. 115–232, § 2861(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (e) as (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239">Pub. L. 112–239</ref> substituted “section 2687” for “section 2687(e)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/110/417">Pub. L. 110–417</ref> inserted “the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands,” after “Guam,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/s2832/a">Pub. L. 109–163, § 2832(a)</ref>, substituted “realignment of a military installation” for “significantly reduced operations of a defense facility”, “closure or realignment, cancellation or” for “cancellation,”, and “community or its residents.” for “community and will result in the loss of—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) 2,500 or more employee positions, in the case of a Metropolitan Statistical Area or similar area (as defined by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget);</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) 1,000 or more employee positions, in the case of a labor market area outside of a Metropolitan Statistical Area; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) one percent of the total number of civilian jobs in that area.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s2861">Pub. L. 109–364, § 2861</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s2862">Pub. L. 109–364, § 2862</ref>, inserted at end “For purposes of subsection (b)(1)(D), the term ‘military installation’ includes a military facility owned and operated by any of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, Guam, or the Virgin Islands, even though the facility is not under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense, if the Secretary of Defense determines that the military facility is subject to significant use for training by the armed forces.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/163/s2832/b">Pub. L. 109–163, § 2832(b)</ref>, amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “The term ‘military installation’ means any camp, post, station, base, yard, or other installation under the jurisdiction of a military department that is located within any of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or Guam.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/107/314">Pub. L. 107–314</ref> struck out heading and text of subsec. (c). Text read as follows: “The Secretary of Defense shall submit a report not later than December 1 of each year to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives concerning the operation of this section during the preceding fiscal year. Each such report shall identify each State, unit of local government, and regional organization that received a grant under this section during such fiscal year and the total amount granted under this section during such year to each such State, unit of local government, and regional organization.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/106/65">Pub. L. 106–65</ref> substituted “and the Committee on Armed Services” for “and the Committee on National Security”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (b)(5)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85">Pub. L. 105–85</ref> added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/104/201">Pub. L. 104–201</ref> designated existing provisions as subpar. (A) and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106">Pub. L. 104–106</ref> substituted “Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on National Security of the House of Representatives” for “Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b)(5) to (7). <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s1123/a">Pub. L. 103–337, § 1123(a)</ref>, added par. (5) and redesignated former pars. (5) and (6) as (6) and (7), respectively. Former par. (7) redesignated (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s1123/a/1">Pub. L. 103–337, § 1123(a)(1)</ref>, (b), redesignated par. (7) as (8) and substituted “paragraph (7)” for “paragraph (6)” in subpars. (A) and (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s1122/a">Pub. L. 103–337, § 1122(a)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/35">Pub. L. 103–35</ref> made technical amendment to directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s4301/b/1/C">Pub. L. 102–484, § 4301(b)(1)(C)</ref>. See 1992 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6), (7). <ref href="/us/pl/103/160">Pub. L. 103–160</ref> added pars. (6) and (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s4301/c/1">Pub. L. 102–484, § 4301(c)(1)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s4301/c/2">Pub. L. 102–484, § 4301(c)(2)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s4301/b/1">Pub. L. 102–484, § 4301(b)(1)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/103/35">Pub. L. 103–35</ref>, substituted “, (D)” for “, or (D)”, substituted “(C), or (E)” for “or (C)”, and inserted cl. (E) before first reference to “if the Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s1052/28">Pub. L. 102–484, § 1052(28)</ref>, substituted “publicly announced” for “publicly-announced”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s4301/b/2">Pub. L. 102–484, § 4301(b)(2)</ref>, inserted “the closure or significantly reduced operations of a defense facility,” after “Defense spending,” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s4301/a/1">Pub. L. 102–484, § 4301(a)(1)</ref>, (2), added par. (4) and redesignated former par. (4) as (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s4301/c/3">Pub. L. 102–484, § 4301(c)(3)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s4301/b/3">Pub. L. 102–484, § 4301(b)(3)</ref>, amended subsec. (d) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (d) read as follows: “In this section, the term ‘military installation’ means any camp, post, station, base, yard, or other installation under the jurisdiction of a military department that is located within any of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or Guam.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s4301/c/4">Pub. L. 102–484, § 4301(c)(4)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/102/25">Pub. L. 102–25</ref> substituted “publicly announced” for “publicly-announced” and inserted a comma after “only if the reduction”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (b)(3) to (6). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510">Pub. L. 101–510</ref> added par. (3), redesignated par. (5) as (4), and struck out former pars. (3), (4), and (6), which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(3) In the case of the cancellation or termination of a Department of Defense contract or the failure to proceed with an approved major weapon system program, assistance may be made under paragraph (1) only if the cancellation, termination, or failure to proceed involves the loss of 2,500 or more full-time Department of Defense and contractor employee positions in the locality of the affected community.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(4) In the case of a publicly-announced planned major reduction in Department of Defense spending that will directly and adversely affect a community, assistance may be made under paragraph (1) only if the publicly-announced planned major reduction will result in the loss of 1,000 or more full-time Department of Defense and contractor employee positions over a five-year period in the locality of the affected community.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(6) Not more than $2,000,000 in assistance may be provided under this subsection in any fiscal year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/456/s2805/a">Pub. L. 100–456, § 2805(a)</ref>, amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “The Secretary of Defense may make grants, conclude cooperative agreements, and supplement funds made available under Federal programs administered by agencies other than the Department of Defense in order to assist State and local governments, and regional organizations composed of State and local governments, in planning community adjustments required (A) by the proposed or actual establishment, realignment, or closure of a military installation, or (B) by the cancellation or termination of a Department of Defense contract or the failure to proceed with an approved major weapon system program, if the Secretary of Defense determines that the action is likely to impose a significant impact on the affected community.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4) to (6). <ref href="/us/pl/100/456/s2805/b">Pub. L. 100–456, § 2805(b)</ref>, added par. (4) and redesignated former pars. (4) and (5) as (5) and (6), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/100/26">Pub. L. 100–26</ref> inserted “the term” after “In this section,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/115">Pub. L. 98–115</ref> substituted “2,000” for “2,500”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida9740696-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida9740697-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1993 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/35">Pub. L. 103–35</ref> applicable as if included in the enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/102/484">Pub. L. 102–484</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/35/s202/b">section 202(b) of Pub. L. 103–35</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s155">section 155 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida9740698-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/456/dB/tXXVII/s2702">Pub. L. 100–456, div. B, title XXVII, § 2702</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2115">102 Stat. 2115</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/456/dB/tXXVII/s2702">“Except as otherwise specifically provided, this division [amending this section and sections 2662, 2672, 2809, and 2828 of this title and enacting provisions set out as a note under this section] shall take effect on <date date="1988-10-01">October 1, 1988</date>, or the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>], whichever is later.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida9740699-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1983 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/115/tVIII/s808">Pub. L. 98–115, title VIII, § 808</ref>, <date date="1983-10-11">Oct. 11, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/789">97 Stat. 789</ref>, provided that the amendment made by that section is effective <date date="1983-10-01">Oct. 1, 1983</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida974069a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Temporary Priority and Allocation of Funds Under Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dB/tXXVIII/s2806/b">Pub. L. 119–60, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2806(b)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1298">139 Stat. 1298</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dB/tXXVIII/s2806/b">
<inline>“During the two-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> give priority under the Defense Community Infrastructure Program under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2391/d">section 2391(d) of title 10</ref>, United States Code, to projects under subparagraph (B)(ii) of such section (as amended by subsection (a)), for which an application has been previously made for assistance under that program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> allocate not less than two-thirds of the amounts appropriated or otherwise made available for such program equally among projects under subparagraphs (B)(i) and (B)(ii) of such program (as amended by subsection (a)).”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida974069b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Restrictions on Use of Funds for Development of Public Infrastructure in Commonwealth of Northern Mariana Islands</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dB/tXXVIII/s2863">Pub. L. 115–232, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2863</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/2284">132 Stat. 2284</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/232/dB/tXXVIII/s2863">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Restriction</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If the Secretary of Defense determines that any grant, cooperative agreement, transfer of funds to another Federal agency, or supplement of funds available under Federal programs administered by agencies other than the Department of Defense will result in the development (including repair, replacement, renovation, conversion, improvement, expansion, acquisition, or construction) of public infrastructure in the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands (hereafter in this section referred to as the ‘Commonwealth’), the Secretary of Defense may not carry out such grant, transfer, cooperative agreement, or supplemental funding unless such grant, transfer, cooperative agreement, or supplemental funding—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> is specifically authorized by law; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> will be used to carry out a public infrastructure project included in the report submitted under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report of Economic Adjustment Committee.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Convening of committee</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>], the Secretary of Defense, as the chair of the Economic Adjustment Committee established in Executive Order No. 127887 [probably should be Executive Order No. 12788] (<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2391">10 U.S.C. 2391</ref> note), shall convene the Economic Adjustment Committee to consider assistance, including assistance to support public infrastructure projects, necessary to support changes in Department of Defense activities in the Commonwealth.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after convening the Economic Adjustment Committee under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] a report—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> describing the results of the Economic Adjustment Committee deliberations required by paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> containing a description of any assistance the Committee determines to be necessary to support changes in Department of Defense activities in the Commonwealth, including any public infrastructure projects the Committee determines should be carried out with such assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Public Infrastructure Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘public infrastructure’ means any utility, method of transportation, item of equipment, or facility under the control of a public entity or State or local government that is used by, or constructed for the benefit of, the general public.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida974069c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Advance Adjustment Planning</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dD/tXLIII/s4301/d">Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLIII, § 4301(d)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2697">106 Stat. 2697</ref>, authorized Secretary of Defense, during fiscal year 1993, to make grants and other assistance available under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b">10 U.S.C. 2391(b)</ref> to assist a State or local government in planning community adjustments and economic diversification even though the State or local government currently failed to meet the criteria for assistance under such section if the Secretary determined that a substantial portion of the economic activity or population of the geographic area to be subjected to the adjustment or diversification planning was dependent on Department of Defense expenditures.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida974069d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effect of 1992 Amendments on Efforts of Economic Development Administration</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dD/tXLIII/s4301/f">Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLIII, § 4301(f)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2698">106 Stat. 2698</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/484/dD/tXLIII/s4301/f">“Nothing in this section [amending this section and enacting provisions set out as a note above] is intended to replace the efforts of the economic development program administered by the Economic Development Administration of the Department of Commerce.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida974069e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pilot Project To Improve Economic Adjustment Planning</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dD/tXLIII/s4302">Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLIII, § 4302</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2698">106 Stat. 2698</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tXIII/s1323/a">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XIII, § 1323(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1790">107 Stat. 1790</ref>, authorized Secretary of Defense, during fiscal years 1993 and 1994, to conduct a pilot project to examine methods to improve the provision of economic adjustment and diversification assistance under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b/1">10 U.S.C. 2391(b)(1)</ref> to State and local governments adversely affected by the closure of military installations, the cancellation or completion of defense contracts, or reductions in defense spending.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida974069f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Donation of Real Property to Nonprofit Entities Providing Support to Children With Life-Threatening Diseases</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/172/tVIII/s8149">Pub. L. 102–172, title VIII, § 8149</ref>, <date date="1991-11-26">Nov. 26, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1214">105 Stat. 1214</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/172/tVIII/s8149">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense, during the current fiscal year or at any time thereafter, may make a donation to an entity described in subsection (b) of a parcel of real property (including structures on such property) under the jurisdiction of the Secretary that is not currently required for the needs of the Department and that the Secretary determines is needed and appropriate for the activities of that entity.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> A donation under subsection (a) may be made to a nonprofit entity which provides medical, educational, and emotional support in a recreational setting to children with life-threatening diseases and their families.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida97406a0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Defense Economic Adjustment, Diversification, Conversion, and Stabilization</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dD">Pub. L. 101–510, div. D</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1848">104 Stat. 1848</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/dA/tX/s1062/c">Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1062(c)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1475">105 Stat. 1475</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dD/tXLII/s4212/b">Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLII, § 4212(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2664">106 Stat. 2664</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tVIII/s825">Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title VIII, § 825</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2611">110 Stat. 2611</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dA/s101/f/tVIII/s405/d/6">Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(d)(6)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-337">112 Stat. 2681–337</ref>, 2681–419; <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tIX/s932">Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 932</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1581">117 Stat. 1581</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/dB/tXXVIII/s2841">Pub. L. 113–66, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2841</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/1024">127 Stat. 1024</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/66/dB/tXXVIII/s2841">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="4001">“SEC. 4001.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This division may be cited as the ‘Defense Economic Adjustment, Diversification, Conversion, and Stabilization Act of 1990’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="4002">“SEC. 4002.</num><heading> FINDINGS AND POLICY</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> There are likely to be significant reductions in the programs, projects, and activities of the Department of Defense during the first several fiscal years following fiscal year 1990.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Such reductions will adversely affect the economies of many communities in the United States and small businesses and civilian workers throughout the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Policy</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In view of the findings expressed in subsection (a), it is the policy of the United States that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> assistance be provided under existing planning assistance programs and economic adjustment assistance programs of the Federal Government to substantially and seriously affected communities, businesses, and workers to the extent necessary to facilitate an orderly transition for such communities, small businesses, and workers from economic reliance on Department of Defense spending to economic reliance on other sources of business, employment, and revenue; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> funding for such programs be increased by amounts necessary to meet the needs of such communities, small businesses, and workers without reducing the funding that would otherwise be available under those programs by reason of causes unrelated to the reductions referred to in subsection (a)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="4003">“SEC. 4003.</num><heading> DEFINITIONS</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“For purposes of this division:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> The term ‘major defense contract or subcontract’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> any defense contract in an amount not less than $5,000,000 (without regard to the date on which the contract was awarded); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> any subcontract which—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> is entered into in connection with a contract (without regard to the effective date of the subcontract); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> involves not less than $500,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘Economic Adjustment Committee’ or ‘Committee’ means the Economic Adjustment Committee established in Executive Order 12049 (<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s111">10 U.S.C. 111</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The term ‘defense facility’ means any private or government facility producing goods or services pursuant to a defense contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The term ‘military installation’ means a base, camp, post, station, yard, center, or homeport facility for any ship in the United States, or any other facility under the jurisdiction of a military department located in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><chapeau> The term ‘substantially and seriously affected’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> when such term is used in conjunction with the term ‘community’, a community—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> which has within its administrative and political jurisdiction one or more military installations or defense facilities or which is economically affected by proximity to a military installation or defense facility;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><chapeau> in which the actual or threatened curtailment, completion, elimination, or realignment of a defense contract results in a workforce reduction of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> 2,500 or more employee positions, in the case of a Metropolitan Statistical Area or similar area (as defined by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget);</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> 1,000 or more employee positions, in the case of a labor market area outside of a Metropolitan Statistical Area; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="III">     “(III)</num><content> one percent of the total number of civilian jobs in that area; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> which establishes, by evidence, that any workforce reduction referred to in clause (ii) occurred as a direct result of changes in Department of Defense requirements or programs;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> when such term is used in conjunction with the term ‘businesses’ any business which—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> holds a major defense contract or subcontract (or held such contract or subcontract before a reduction in the defense budget);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><chapeau> experiences a reduction, or the threat of a reduction, of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> 25 percent or more in sales or production; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> 80 percent or more of the workforce of such business in any division of such business or at any plant or other facility of such business; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> establishes, by evidence, that the reductions referred to in clause (ii) occurred as a direct result of a reduction in the defense budget; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> when such term is used in conjunction with the term ‘group of workers’, any group of 100 or more workers at a defense facility who are (or who are threatened to be), eligible to participate in the defense conversion adjustment program under section 325 of the Job Training Partnership Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1662d">29 U.S.C. 1662d</ref>] (as added by section 4202 of this division), as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 [<date date="1998-08-07">Aug. 7, 1998</date>].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="4004">“SEC. 4004.</num><heading> CONTINUATION OF ECONOMIC ADJUSTMENT COMMITTEE</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination or Alteration Prohibited</inline>.—</heading><content>The Economic Adjustment Committee established in Executive Order 12049 (<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s111">10 U.S.C. 111</ref> note) may not be terminated and the duties of the Committee may not be significantly altered unless specifically authorized by a law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Chairman</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall be the chairman of the Committee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Executive Council</inline>.—</heading><content>Until <date date="1997-10-01">October 1, 1997</date>, the National Defense Technology and Industrial Base Council shall function as an Executive Council of the Committee. Under the direction of the chairman of the Committee, the Executive Council shall develop policies and procedures to ensure that communities, businesses, and workers substantially and seriously affected by reductions in defense expenditures are advised of the assistance available to such communities, businesses, and workers under programs administered by the departments and agency comprising the Council.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Duties of Committee</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Economic Adjustment Committee shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> coordinate and facilitate cooperative efforts among Federal agencies represented on the Committee to implement defense economic adjustment programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> serve as an information clearinghouse for and between Federal, State, and local entities regarding their defense economic adjustment efforts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<title style="-uslm-lc:I71"><num value="XLI">“TITLE XLI—</num><heading>ECONOMIC ADJUSTMENT PLANNING</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I580467" status="repealed"><num value="4101">“[SEC. 4101.</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tVIII/s825">Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title VIII, § 825</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2611">110 Stat. 2611</ref>.]</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="4102">“SEC. 4102.</num><heading> ECONOMIC ADJUSTMENT PLANNING ASSISTANCE THROUGH THE DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Any substantially and seriously affected community shall be eligible for economic adjustment planning assistance through the Office of Economic Adjustment in the Department of Defense under subsection (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2391">section 2391 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, subject to subsection (e) of such section. Such assistance shall be provided in accordance with the standards, procedures, and priorities established by the Committee under this division.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> [Amended <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b">section 2391(b) of this title</ref>.]</heading><content />
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="4103">“SEC. 4103.</num><heading> COMMUNITY ECONOMIC ADJUSTMENT ASSISTANCE THROUGH THE ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT ADMINISTRATION</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>A community that has been determined by the Economic Development Administration of the Department of Commerce or the Office of Economic Adjustment of the Department of Defense, in accordance with the standards and procedures established by the Economic Adjustment Committee, to be a substantially and seriously affected community shall be eligible for economic adjustment assistance authorized under title IX of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3241">42 U.S.C. 3241</ref> et seq.], subject to the availability of appropriations for such purpose and subject to meeting the eligibility requirements of such title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Defense for fiscal year 1991 $50,000,000 for purposes of carrying out subsection (a). Any amount appropriated pursuant to this subsection shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</title>
<title style="-uslm-lc:I71"><num value="XLII">“TITLE XLII—</num><heading>ADJUSTMENT ASSISTANCE FOR EMPLOYEES</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I580467" status="repealed"><num value="4201">“[SEC. 4201.</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tVIII/s825">Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title VIII, § 825</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2611">110 Stat. 2611</ref>.]</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="4202">“SEC. 4202.</num><heading> DEFENSE CONVERSION ADJUSTMENT PROGRAM</heading><note topic="miscellaneous" style="-uslm-lc:I21" id="ida97676a1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<p class="indent0">“[Enacted <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1662d">section 1662d of Title 29</ref>, Labor.]</p></note>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="4203">“SEC. 4203.</num><heading> AUTHORIZATION OF APPROPRIATIONS</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization</inline>.—</heading><content>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Defense $150,000,000 for fiscal year 1991 to carry out section 4201 and the amendment made by section 4202. Amounts appropriated pursuant to this subsection shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Administrative Expenses</inline>.—</heading><content>Of amounts appropriated pursuant to this section, not more than five percent may be retained by the Secretary of Labor for the administration of the activities authorized by the amendment made by section 4202.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</title>
<title style="-uslm-lc:I71"><num value="XLIII">“TITLE XLIII—</num><heading>EXPANSION OF BUSINESS CAPITAL ASSISTANCE PROGRAMS</heading><section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="4301">“SEC. 4301.</num><heading> EXPANSION OF SMALL BUSINESS LOAN PROGRAM</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>], the President, acting with the assistance of the Committee and after consulting experts in government and the private sector, shall transmit to the Congress recommendations regarding ways that assistance provided pursuant to the business loan program under section 7(a) of the Small Business Act of 1958 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s636/a">15 U.S.C. 636(a)</ref>] may be used to respond to the consequences of defense budget reductions.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="4302">“SEC. 4302.</num><heading> ECONOMIC PLANNING ASSISTANCE FOR EXCEPTIONAL PROJECTS</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assistance Authorized</inline>.—</heading><content>The Economic Development Administration, in the case of assistance under title IX of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3241">42 U.S.C. 3241</ref> et seq.], and the Office of Economic Adjustment, in the case of planning assistance under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2391/b">section 2391(b) of title 10</ref>, United States Code, may award planning assistance under those programs to any substantially and seriously affected community, on behalf of a business, group of businesses, or group of workers, if such planning funds are determined by the agency concerned to be necessary and appropriate as a catalyst for projects which the agency determines, on a case-by-case basis, have exceptional promise for achieving the objectives of this division.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Conditions on Assistance</inline>.—</heading><content>Awards under this section shall be subject to the availability of appropriations for such purpose and shall be made in accordance with any other applicable provisions of law.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="4303">“SEC. 4303.</num><heading> EXPANSION OF EXPORT FINANCING FOR GOODS AND SERVICES PRODUCED BY FIRMS AND EMPLOYEES FORMERLY ENGAGED IN DEFENSE PRODUCTION</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Export-Import Bank.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sense of congress on plan for expansion</inline>.—</heading><content>It is the sense of Congress that the United States businesses undergoing transition from defense production to nondefense production will need assistance in seizing export markets overseas. Therefore, in order to provide financial support for such businesses, as well as meeting other normal demands on its resources, the annual direct lending authority of the Export-Import Bank of the United States should be increased by at least 150 percent from the fiscal year 1990 level over the five-year period beginning <date date="1990-10-01">October 1, 1990</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report of feasibility</inline>.—</heading><content>Before <date date="1990-09-30">September 30, 1990</date>, the President, acting with the assistance of the Committee and after consulting the Board of Directors of the Export-Import Bank of the United States and other experts in government and the private sector, shall transmit to the Congress a report assessing the feasibility and desirability of a program for increasing the amount of direct loan authority in the manner described in paragraph (1) and the factors considered in making such assessment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transition to nondefense production required to be considered</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In determining whether to provide financial support for an export transaction, the Export-Import Bank of the United States shall take into account, to the extent feasible and in accordance with applicable standards and procedures established by the bank in consultation with the Committee, the fact that the product or service is produced or provided by any business or group of workers which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> was substantially and seriously affected by defense budget reductions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> is in transition from defense to nondefense production.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">SBA Use of Authority for Export Financing Assistance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In determining whether to provide financial or other assistance under the Small Business Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s631">15 U.S.C. 631</ref> et seq.], title VIII of the Omnibus Trade and Competitiveness Act of 1988 [<ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref>, see Short Title of 1988 Amendments note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s631">section 631 of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade], or any program referred to in section 4301 to any small business involved in, or attempting to become involved in, the export of any product or service, the Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall take into account the fact that such product or service is produced or provided by any business or group of workers which—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> has been substantially and seriously affected by defense budget reductions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> is in transition from defense to nondefense production.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coordination and Integration of Activities and Assistance with Other Agencies</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In providing additional financial assistance pursuant to any increase in loan authority under this division—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Federal agencies concerned with international trade shall participate in the process of coordination conducted by the Committee pursuant to section 4004(c)(1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> such Federal agencies shall attempt, to the maximum extent practicable, to coordinate and integrate the activities and assistance of the agencies in support of exports, including financial assistance in the form of direct loans, loan guarantees, and insurance, general trade promotion, marketing assistance, and marketing and commercial information, in a manner consistent with the purposes of this division (and the amendments made by this division to other provisions of law).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reporting</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The annual reports made by the Export-Import Bank of the United States and the Administrator of the Small Business Administration and the annual economic stabilization and adjustment report under section 4004(c)(3) of this division shall include a description of the extent to which the bank and the Administrator are—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> providing financing described in subsections (a)(2) and (b), respectively, to businesses or groups of workers which were substantially and seriously affected by defense budget reductions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> coordinating and integrating export support and financing activities with other Federal agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="4304">“SEC. 4304.</num><heading> BENEFIT INFORMATION FOR BUSINESSES</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Information Required To Be Provided</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Commerce and the Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall provide any business affected by defense budget reductions with a complete description of available programs which provide any business, whether on an industrywide or an individual basis, with any planning assistance, financial, technical, or managerial assistance, worker retraining assistance, or other assistance authorized under this division.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effective Notification System</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Commerce and the Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall take such action as may be appropriate to ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that each business affected by defense budget reductions receives the information required to be provided under subsection (a) on a timely basis.”</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</title>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida97676a2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Commission on Alternative Utilization of Military Facilities</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/456/s2819">Section 2819 of Pub. L. 100–456</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dB/tXXIX/s2922/a">Pub. L. 101–510, div. B, title XXIX, § 2922(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1820">104 Stat. 1820</ref>, established Commission on Alternative Utilization of Military Facilities and required Commission to submit reports to President and Congress not later than Sept. 1 of every second year through fiscal year 1996, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/105/261/dA/tX/s1031/b">Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title X, § 1031(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2123">112 Stat. 2123</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida97676a3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Submission Date for First Report</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/97/86/tIX/s912/c">Pub. L. 97–86, title IX, § 912(c)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1123">95 Stat. 1123</ref>, required the first report under subsec. (c) of this section to be submitted not later than <date date="1982-12-01">Dec. 1, 1982</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="ida97676a4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="ida97676a5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 12682. Commission on Alternative Utilization of Military Facilities</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 12682, <date date="1989-07-07">July 7, 1989</date>, 54 F.R. 29315, provided:</p>
<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and laws of the United States of America, including section 2819 of the Military Construction Authorization Act, 1989 (<ref href="/us/pl/100/456">Public Law 100–456</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2391">10 U.S.C. 2391</ref> note], it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. (a) I hereby establish the Commission on Alternative Utilization of Military Facilities (“Commission”).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Commission shall consist of a representative of the Department of Defense designated by the Secretary of Defense, a representative of the Federal Bureau of Prisons designated by the Attorney General, a representative of the National Institute on Drug Abuse designated by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, a representative of the General Services Administration designated by the Administrator of General Services, a representative of the Department of Housing and Urban Development designated by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, and a representative of the Office of National Drug Control Policy designated by the Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy. The representative of the Department of Defense shall chair the Commission.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The Secretary of Defense shall provide such personnel and support to the Commission as the Secretary determines is necessary to accomplish its mission.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. (a) Subject to subsection (b), the Secretary of Defense shall prepare and submit to the Commission reports listing active and nonactive military facilities that are underutilized in whole or in part or otherwise excess to the needs of the Department of Defense.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The first such report shall be prepared and submitted as soon as possible for inclusion in the first report of the Commission. The second report shall be prepared and submitted on <date date="1990-01-30">January 30, 1990</date>, and succeeding reports shall be prepared and submitted every other year commencing on <date date="1992-01-30">January 30, 1992</date>, and continuing until <date date="1996-01-30">January 30, 1996</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. (a) Subject to subsection (b), the Commission shall submit a report to the President and then to the Congress that identifies those facilities, or parts of facilities, from the list submitted by the Secretary of Defense under Section 2 that could be effectively utilized or renovated to serve as:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(1) minimum security facilities for nonviolent prisoners,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) drug treatment facilities for nonviolent drug abusers, and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(3) facilities to assist the homeless.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The first report of the Commission shall be submitted to the President and then to the Congress by <date date="1989-09-01">September 1, 1989</date>. The second, and succeeding reports of the Commission, shall be submitted to the President and then to the Congress no later than <date date="1990-09-01">September 1, 1990</date>, and every second year through <date date="1996-09-01">September 1, 1996</date>.</p>
<signature>
<name>George Bush.</name>
</signature>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="ida97676a6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 12788. Defense Economic Adjustment Program</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 12788, <date date="1992-01-15">Jan. 15, 1992</date>, 57 F.R. 2213, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 13286, § 33, <date date="2003-02-28">Feb. 28, 2003</date>, 68 F.R. 10625; Ex. Ord. No. 13378, <date date="2005-05-12">May 12, 2005</date>, 70 F.R. 28413, provided:</p>
<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2391">10 U.S.C. 2391</ref> and the Defense Economic Adjustment, Diversification, Conversion, and Stabilization Act of 1990, enacted as Division D, section 4001 <i>et seq</i>., of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1991, <ref href="/us/pl/101/510">Public Law 101–510</ref> [set out above], and to provide coordinated Federal economic adjustment assistance necessitated by changes in Department of Defense activities, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Function of the Secretary of Defense</i>. The Secretary of Defense shall, through the Economic Adjustment Committee, design and establish a Defense Economic Adjustment Program.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. <i>Purpose of the Defense Economic Adjustment Program</i>. The Defense Economic Adjustment Program shall (1) assist substantially and seriously affected communities, businesses, and workers from the effects of major Defense base closures, realignments, and Defense contract-related adjustments, and (2) assist State and local governments in preventing the encroachment of civilian communities from impairing the operational utility of military installations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. <i>Functions of the Defense Economic Adjustment Program</i>. The Defense Economic Adjustment Program shall:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) Identify problems of States, regions, metropolitan areas, or communities that result from major Defense base closures, realignments, and Defense contract-related adjustments, and the encroachment of the civilian community on the mission of military installations and that require Federal assistance;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Use and maintain a uniform socioeconomic impact analysis to justify the use of Federal economic adjustment resources, prior to particular realignments;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) Apply consistent policies, practices, and procedures in the administration of Federal programs that are used to assist Defense-affected States, regions, metropolitan areas, communities, and businesses;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) Identify and strengthen existing agency mechanisms to coordinate employment opportunities for displaced agency personnel;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) Identify and strengthen existing agency mechanisms to improve reemployment opportunities for dislocated Defense industry personnel;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(f) Assure timely consultation and cooperation with Federal, State, regional, metropolitan, and community officials concerning Defense-related impacts on Defense-affected communities’ problems;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(g) Assure coordinated interagency and intergovernmental adjustment assistance concerning Defense impact problems;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(h) Prepare, facilitate, and implement cost-effective strategies and action plans to coordinate interagency and intergovernmental economic adjustment efforts;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) Encourage effective Federal, State, regional, metropolitan, and community cooperation and concerted involvement of public interest groups and private sector organizations in Defense economic adjustment activities;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(j) Serve as a clearinghouse to exchange information among Federal, State, regional, metropolitan, and community officials involved in the resolution of community economic adjustment problems. Such information may include, for example, previous studies, technical information, and sources of public and private financing;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(k) Assist in the diversification of local economies to lessen dependence on Defense activities;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(<i>l</i>) Encourage and facilitate private sector interim use of lands and buildings to generate jobs as military activities diminish;, [sic]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(m) Develop ways to streamline property disposal procedures to enable Defense-impacted communities to acquire base property to generate jobs as military activities diminish; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(n) Encourage resolution of regulatory issues that impede encroachment prevention and local economic adjustment efforts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 4. <i>Economic Adjustment Committee.</i></p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) <i>Membership</i>. The Economic Adjustment Committee (“Committee”) shall be composed of the following individuals, or a designated principal deputy of these individuals, and such other individuals from the executive branch as the President may designate. Such individuals shall include the:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(1) Secretary of Agriculture;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) Attorney General;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(3) Secretary of Commerce;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(4) Secretary of Defense;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(5) Secretary of Education;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(6) Secretary of Energy;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(7) Secretary of Health and Human Services;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(8) Secretary of Housing and Urban Development;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(9) Secretary of the Interior;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(10) Secretary of Labor;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(11) Secretary of State;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(12) Secretary of Transportation;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(13) Secretary of the Treasury;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(14) Secretary of Veterans Affairs;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(15) Secretary of Homeland Security;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(16) Chairman, Council of Economic Advisers;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(17) Director of the Office of Management and Budget;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(18) Director of the Office of Personnel Management;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(19) Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(20) Administrator of General Services;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(21) Administrator of the Small Business Administration; and,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(22) Postmaster General.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) <i>Chairman</i>. The Secretary of Defense, or the Secretary’s designee, shall chair the Committee.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) <i>Vice Chairman</i>. The Secretaries of Labor and Commerce shall serve as Vice Chairmen of the Committee. The Vice Chairmen shall co-chair the Committee in the absence of both the Chairman and the Chairman’s designee and may also preside over meetings of designated representatives of the concerned executive agencies.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) <i>Executive Director</i>. The head of the Department of Defense’s Office of Economic Adjustment shall provide all necessary policy and administrative support for the Committee and shall be responsible for coordinating the application of the Defense Economic Adjustment Program to Department of Defense activities.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) <i>Duties</i>. The Committee shall:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(1) Advise, assist, and support the Defense Economic Adjustment Program;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) Develop procedures for ensuring that State, regional, and community officials and representatives of organized labor in those States, municipalities, localities, or labor organizations that are substantially and seriously affected by changes in Defense expenditures, realignments or closures, or cancellation or curtailment of major Defense contracts, are notified of available Federal economic adjustment programs; and,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(3) Report annually to the President and then to the Congress on the work of the Economic Adjustment Committee during the preceding fiscal year.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 5. <i>Responsibilities of Executive Agencies.</i></p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) The head of each agency represented on the Committee shall designate an agency representative to:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(1) Serve as a liaison with the Secretary of Defense’s economic adjustment staff;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) Coordinate agency support and participation in economic adjustment assistance projects; and,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(3) Assist in resolving Defense-related impacts on Defense-affected communities.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) All executive agencies shall:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(1) Support, to the extent permitted by law, the economic adjustment assistance activities of the Secretary of Defense. Such support may include the use and application of personnel, technical expertise, legal authorities, and available financial resources. This support may be used, to the extent permitted by law, to provide a coordinated Federal response to the needs of individual States, regions, municipalities, and communities adversely affected by necessary Defense changes;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) Afford priority consideration to requests from Defense-affected communities for Federal technical assistance, financial resources, excess or surplus property, or other requirements, that are part of a comprehensive plan used by the Committee.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 6. <i>Judicial Review</i>. This order shall not be interpreted to create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law by a party against the United States, its agencies, its officers, its agents, or any person.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 7. <i>Construction</i>. (a) Nothing in this order shall be construed as subjecting any function vested by law in, or assigned pursuant to law to, any agency or head thereof to the authority of any other agency or officer or as abrogating or restricting any such function in any manner.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) This order shall be effective immediately and shall supersede Executive Order No. 12049.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Amendment by Ex. Ord. 13378 directing insertion of “and” after “diminish;” in section 3(m) of Ex. Ord. 12788, was executed by substituting “; and” for the comma after “diminish”.]</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
