<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida97fed5e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2475"><num value="2475">§ 2475.</num><heading> Consolidation, restructuring, or reengineering of organizations, functions, or activities: notification requirements</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida97fed5f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2475/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Strategic Sourcing Plan of Action Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term “Strategic Sourcing Plan of Action” means a Strategic Sourcing Plan of Action for the Department of Defense (as identified in the Department of Defense Interim Guidance dated <date date="2000-02-29">February 29, 2000</date>, or any successor Department of Defense guidance or directive) in effect for a fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida97fed60-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2475/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notification of Decision To Execute Plan</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If a decision is made to consolidate, restructure, or reengineer an organization, function, or activity of the Department of Defense pursuant to a Strategic Sourcing Plan of Action described in subsection (a), and such consolidation, restructuring, or reengineering would result in a manpower reduction affecting 50 or more personnel of the Department of Defense (including military and civilian personnel)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida97fed61-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2475/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report describing that decision, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida97fed62-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2475/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a projection of the savings that will be realized as a result of the consolidation, restructuring, or reengineering, compared with the cost incurred by the Department of Defense to perform the function or to operate the organization or activity prior to such proposed consolidation, restructuring, or reengineering;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida97fed63-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2475/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a description of all missions, duties, or military requirements that will be affected as a result of the decision to consolidate, restructure, or reengineer the organization, function, or activity that was analyzed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida97fed64-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2475/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the Secretary’s certification that the consolidation, restructuring, or reengineering will not result in any diminution of military readiness;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida97fed65-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2475/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> a schedule for performing the consolidation, restructuring, or reengineering; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida97fed66-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2475/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the Secretary’s certification that the entire analysis for the consolidation, restructuring, or reengineering is available for examination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida97fed67-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2475/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the head of the Defense Agency or the Secretary of the military department concerned may not implement the plan until 30 days after the date that the agency head or Secretary submits notification to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives of the intent to carry out such plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida97fed68-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title III, § 353(a)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–72; amended <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tX/s1051/a/17">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1051(a)(17)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1561">131 Stat. 1561</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida97fed69-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida97fed6a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida97fed6b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91">Pub. L. 115–91</ref> amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) required the Secretary of Defense to submit the Strategic Sourcing Plan of Action to Congress annually.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
