<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida984a83e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485"><num value="2485">§ 2485.</num><heading> Commissary stores: operation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a83f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Private Operation</inline>.—</heading><content>Under such regulations as the Secretary of Defense may approve, private persons may operate selected commissary store functions, except that such functions may not include functions relating to the procurement of products to be sold in a commissary store or functions relating to the overall management of a commissary system or the management of a commissary store. Such functions shall be carried out by personnel of the Department of Defense under regulations approved by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a840-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contracts With Other Agencies and Instrumentalities</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a841-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Defense Commissary Agency, and any other agency of the Department of Defense that supports the operation of the commissary system, may enter into a contract or other agreement with another element of the Department of Defense or with another Federal department, agency, or instrumentality to provide or obtain services beneficial to the efficient management and operation of the commissary system. However, the Defense Commissary Agency may not pay for any such service provided by the United States Transportation Command any amount that exceeds the price at which the service could be procured through full and open competition, as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s107">section 107 of title 41</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a842-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A commissary store operated by a nonappropriated fund instrumentality of the Department of Defense shall be operated in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2483">section 2483 of this title</ref>. Subject to such section, the Secretary of Defense may authorize a transfer of goods, supplies, and facilities of, and funds appropriated for, the Defense Commissary Agency or any other agency of the Department of Defense that supports the operation of the commissary system to a nonappropriated fund instrumentality for the operation of a commissary store.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a843-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Governing Board</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a844-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s192/d">section 192(d) of this title</ref>, the Secretary of Defense shall establish a governing board for the commissary system to provide advice to the Secretary regarding the prudent operation of the commissary system and to assist in the overall supervision of the Defense Commissary Agency. The Secretary may authorize the board to have such supervisory authority as the Secretary considers appropriate to permit the board to carry out its responsibilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a845-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall determine the membership of the governing board, which shall include, at a minimum, appropriate representatives from each military department. The chairman of the governing board shall be a commissioned officer or member of the senior executive service who has demonstrated experience or knowledge relevant to the management of the defense commissary system. In selecting other members of the governing board, the Secretary shall give priority to persons with experience related to logistics, military personnel, military entitlements or other experiences of value of management of commissaries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a846-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The governing board shall be accountable only to the Secretary of Defense and to the civilian officer of the Department of Defense who is assigned the responsibility for the overall supervision of the Defense Commissary Agency pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s192/a">section 192(a) of this title</ref>. The Director of the Defense Commissary Agency shall be accountable to and report to the board.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a847-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assignment of Active Duty Members</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a848-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), members of the armed forces on active duty may not be assigned to the operation of a commissary store.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a849-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a84a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense may assign an officer on the active-duty list to serve as the Director of the Defense Commissary Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a84b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Not more than 18 members (in addition to the officer referred to in subparagraph (A)) of the armed forces on active duty may be assigned to the Defense Commissary Agency. Members who may be assigned under this subparagraph to regional headquarters of the agency shall be limited to enlisted members assigned to duty as advisers in the regional headquarters responsible for overseas commissaries and to veterinary specialists.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a84c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reimbursement for Use of Commissary Facilities by Military Departments</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a84d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of a military department shall pay the Defense Commissary Agency the amount determined under paragraph (2) for any use of a commissary facility by the military department for a purpose other than commissary sales or operations in support of commissary sales.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a84e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The amount payable under paragraph (1) for use of a commissary facility by a military department shall be equal to the share of depreciation of the facility that is attributable to that use, as determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a84f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Director of the Defense Commissary Agency shall credit amounts paid under paragraph (1) for use of a facility to an appropriate account to which proceeds of a surcharge applied under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2484/d">section 2484(d) of this title</ref> are credited.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a850-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> This subsection applies with respect to a commissary facility that is acquired, constructed, converted, expanded, installed, or otherwise improved (in whole or in part) with the proceeds of a surcharge applied under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2484/d">section 2484(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a851-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Donation of Unusable Food</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a852-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may donate food described in paragraph (2) to any of the following entities:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida984a853-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A charitable nonprofit food bank that is designated by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Health and Human Services as authorized to receive such donations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida984a854-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A State or local agency that is designated by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Health and Human Services as authorized to receive such donations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida984a855-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/f/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> A chapter or other local unit of a recognized national veterans organization that provides services to persons without adequate shelter and is designated by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs as authorized to receive such donations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida984a856-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/f/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> A not-for-profit organization that provides care for homeless veterans and is designated by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs as authorized to receive such donations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a857-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Food that may be donated under this subsection is commissary store food, mess food, meals ready-to-eat (MREs), rations known as humanitarian daily rations (HDRs), and other food available to the Secretary of Defense that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida984a858-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is certified as edible by appropriate food inspection technicians;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida984a859-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> would otherwise be destroyed as unusable; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida984a85a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/f/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> in the case of commissary store food, is unmarketable and unsaleable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a85b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In the case of commissary store food, a donation under this subsection shall take place at the site of the commissary store that is donating the food.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a85c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> This subsection does not authorize any service (including transportation) to be provided in connection with a donation under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a85d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Collection of Dishonored Checks</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a85e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense may impose a charge for the collection of a check accepted at a commissary store that is not honored by the financial institution on which the check is drawn. The imposition and amounts of charges shall be consistent with practices of commercial grocery stores regarding dishonored checks.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a85f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a860-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/g/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> The following persons are liable to the United States for the amount of a check referred to in paragraph (1) that is returned unpaid to the United States, together with any charge imposed under that paragraph:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida984a861-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/g/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The person who presented the check.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida984a862-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/g/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Any person whose status and relationship to the person who presented the check provide the basis for that person’s eligibility to make purchases at a commissary store.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a863-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/g/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any amount for which a person is liable under subparagraph (A) may be collected by deducting and withholding such amount from any amounts payable to that person by the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a864-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Amounts collected as charges imposed under paragraph (1) shall be credited to the commissary trust revolving fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a865-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Appropriated funds may be used to pay any costs incurred in the collection of checks and charges referred to in paragraph (1). An appropriation account charged a cost under the preceding sentence shall be reimbursed the amount of that cost out of funds in the commissary trust revolving fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a866-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/g/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> In this subsection, the term “commissary trust revolving fund” means the trust revolving fund maintained by the Department of Defense for surcharge collections and proceeds of sales of commissary stores.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a867-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Release of Certain Commercially Valuable Information to Public</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a868-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense may limit the release to the public of any information described in paragraph (2) if the Secretary determines that it is in the best interest of the Department of Defense to limit the release of such information. If the Secretary determines to limit the release of any such information, the Secretary may provide for limited release of such information in accordance with paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a869-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Paragraph (1) applies to the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida984a86a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Information contained in the computerized business systems of commissary stores or the Defense Commissary Agency that is collected through or in connection with the use of electronic scanners in commissary stores, including the following information:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida984a86b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/h/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Data relating to sales of goods or services.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida984a86c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/h/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Demographic information on customers.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida984a86d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/h/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Any other information pertaining to commissary transactions and operations.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida984a86e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Business programs, systems, and applications (including software) relating to commissary operations that were developed with funding derived from commissary surcharges.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a86f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a870-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/h/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense may, using competitive procedures, enter into a contract to sell information described in paragraph (2).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a871-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/h/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense may release, without charge, information on an item sold in commissary stores to the manufacturer or producer of that item or an agent of the manufacturer or producer.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a872-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/h/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall establish performance benchmarks and shall submit information on customer satisfaction and performance data to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a873-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/h/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense may, by contract entered into with a business, grant to the business a license to use business programs referred to in paragraph (2)(B), including software used in or comprising any such program. The fee charged for the license shall be based on the costs of similar programs developed and marketed by businesses in the private sector, determined by means of surveys.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a874-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/h/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Each contract entered into under this paragraph shall specify the amount to be paid for information released or a license granted under the contract, as the case may be.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a875-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/h/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Information described in paragraph (2) may not be released, under paragraph (3) or otherwise, in a form that identifies any customer or that provides information making it possible to identify any customer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a876-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/h/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Amounts received by the Secretary under this section shall be credited to funds derived from commissary surcharges applied under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2484/e">section 2484(e) of this title</ref>, shall be merged with those funds, and shall be available for the same purposes as the funds with which merged.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a877-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2485/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Expert Commercial Advice</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense may enter into a contract with an entity to obtain expert commercial advice, commercial assistance, or other similar services not otherwise carried out by the Defense Commissary Agency, to implement section 2481(c), subsections (i) and (j) of section 2484, and <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2487/c">section 2487(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida984a878-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(<ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041">Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/141">70A Stat. 141</ref>, § 2482; <ref href="/us/pl/100/456/dA/tIII/s321">Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1952">102 Stat. 1952</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tIII/s331/a">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title III, § 331(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/260">110 Stat. 260</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tIII/s341/b">Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title III, § 341(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2489">110 Stat. 2489</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/261/dA/tIII">Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title III</ref>, §§ 361(b), 363(a), <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1984">112 Stat. 1984</ref>, 1985; <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tVI/s653">Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title VI, § 653</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1522">117 Stat. 1522</ref>; renumbered § 2485 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/dA/tVI/s651/a/2">Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title VI, § 651(a)(2)</ref>, (6), (7), <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1964">118 Stat. 1964</ref>, 1968; <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tVI/s672">Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title VI, § 672</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3319">119 Stat. 3319</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s5/b/35">Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(b)(35)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3845">124 Stat. 3845</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/dA/tX/s1061/16">Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title X, § 1061(16)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1583">125 Stat. 1583</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tVI/s661/e">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VI, § 661(e)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2172">130 Stat. 2172</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida984a879-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note topic="historicalAndRevision" id="ida984a87a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<html:table class="HNR" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc: c3,L2,tp7,s10,xls80,xs80,tp7,s10,xls80,xs80; " id="ida984a87b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 38pt;" />
<html:col style="width:84pt ; max-width:84pt;" />
<html:col style="width:84pt ; max-width:84pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style=""><html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Historical and Revision Notes</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="min-width: 38.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Revised section</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:84.0pt ; max-width:84.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (U.S. Code)</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:84.0pt ; max-width:84.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (Statutes at Large)</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>2482</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">[Uncodified].</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:a href="/us/act/1953-08-01/ch305/s624">Aug. 1, 1953, ch. 305, § 624</html:a> (last proviso), <html:a href="/us/stat/67/353">67 Stat. 353</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section is codified as permanent law on the basis of an opinion of the Assistant General Counsel (Fiscal Matters), Department of Defense, dated <date date="1954-09-28">September 28, 1954</date>. The words “and privately owned organizations” are omitted as surplusage since under <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s1">1 U.S.C. 1</ref> “person” includes such an organization.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida984a87c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="ida984a87d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 2485, added <ref href="/us/pl/99/145/tXIV/s1460/a">Pub. L. 99–145, title XIV, § 1460(a)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/764">99 Stat. 764</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tIII/s324/a">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title III, § 324(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1530">104 Stat. 1530</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tIII/s365">Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title III, § 365</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2494">110 Stat. 2494</ref>, related to donation of unusable food from commissary stores and other activities, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/dA/tVI/s651/a/1">Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title VI, § 651(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1964">118 Stat. 1964</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 2486 was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2484">section 2484 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida984a87e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328">Pub. L. 114–328</ref> added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/112/81">Pub. L. 112–81</ref> struck out par. (1) designation before “Under such regulations” and struck out par. (2) which read as follows: “Any change to private operation of a commissary store function that is being performed by more than 10 Department of Defense civilian employees shall not take effect until the end of the 75-day period beginning on the date on which the Secretary of Defense submits to Congress written notice of the change. Until <date date="2008-12-31">December 31, 2008</date>, the Defense Commissary Agency is not required to conduct any cost-comparison study under the policies and procedures of Office of Management and Budget Circular A–76 relating to the possible contracting out of commissary store functions.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/350">Pub. L. 111–350</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s107">section 107 of title 41</ref>” for “section 4(6) of the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s403/6">41 U.S.C. 403(6)</ref>)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/109/163">Pub. L. 109–163</ref> inserted at end “Until <date date="2008-12-31">December 31, 2008</date>, the Defense Commissary Agency is not required to conduct any cost-comparison study under the policies and procedures of Office of Management and Budget Circular A–76 relating to the possible contracting out of commissary store functions.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—<ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s651/a/2">Pub. L. 108–375, § 651(a)(2)</ref>, (6), renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2482">section 2482 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s651/a/7/A">Pub. L. 108–375, § 651(a)(7)(A)</ref>, substituted “section 2483” for “section 2484”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s651/a/7/B">Pub. L. 108–375, § 651(a)(7)(B)</ref>, inserted at end “The chairman of the governing board shall be a commissioned officer or member of the senior executive service who has demonstrated experience or knowledge relevant to the management of the defense commissary system. In selecting other members of the governing board, the Secretary shall give priority to persons with experience related to logistics, military personnel, military entitlements or other experiences of value of management of commissaries.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d) to (h). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s651/a/7/C">Pub. L. 108–375, § 651(a)(7)(C)</ref>, added subsecs. (d) to (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136">Pub. L. 108–136</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted first sentence, added par. (2), and struck out former first and second sentences which read as follows: “Private persons may operate commissary stores under such regulations as the Secretary of Defense may approve. A contract with a private person for the operation of any commissary store may not require or permit the contractor to carry out functions for the procurement of products to be sold in the store or to engage in functions relating to the overall management of a commissary system or the management of any such store.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/261/s363/a">Pub. L. 105–261, § 363(a)</ref>, inserted at end “However, the Defense Commissary Agency may not pay for any such service provided by the United States Transportation Command any amount that exceeds the price at which the service could be procured through full and open competition, as such term is defined in section 4(6) of the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s403/6">41 U.S.C. 403(6)</ref>).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/105/261/s361/b">Pub. L. 105–261, § 361(b)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—<ref href="/us/pl/104/106">Pub. L. 104–106</ref> struck out “private” after “stores:” in section catchline, designated existing text as subsec. (a), inserted heading, and added subsec. (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/201">Pub. L. 104–201</ref> substituted “another element of the Department of Defense or with another Federal department, agency, or instrumentality to provide or obtain services” for “another department, agency, or instrumentality of the Department of Defense or another Federal agency to provide services”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/456">Pub. L. 100–456</ref> inserted at end “A contract with a private person for the operation of any commissary store may not require or permit the contractor to carry out functions for the procurement of products to be sold in the store or to engage in functions relating to the overall management of a commissary system or the management of any such store. Such functions shall be carried out by personnel of the Department of Defense under regulations approved by the Secretary of Defense.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida984a87f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida984a880-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/261/dA/tIII/s363/b">Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title III, § 363(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1986">112 Stat. 1986</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/261/dA/tIII/s363/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to services provided or obtained on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida984a881-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Acceptance of Military Star Card at Commissaries</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tVI/s662">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VI, § 662</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2172">130 Stat. 2172</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tVI/s662">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> commissary stores accept as payment the Military Star Card; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> any financial liability of the United States relating to such acceptance as payment be assumed by the Army and Air Force Exchange Service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Military Star Card Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘Military Star Card’ means a credit card administered under the Exchange Credit Program by the Army and Air Force Exchange Service.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida984a882-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Demonstration Program for Operation of Certain Commissary Stores by Nonappropriated Fund Instrumentalities</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dA/tIII/s363">Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title III, § 363</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2380">106 Stat. 2380</ref>, required the Secretary of Defense to establish a demonstration program to determine the feasibility of having nonappropriated fund instrumentalities operate commissary stores at military installations and provided for termination of the program and submission of a report on its implementation, not later than the expiration of the one-year period beginning on <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
