<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida984a8c5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2491"><num value="2491">§ 2491.</num><heading> Uniform funding and management of morale, welfare, and recreation programs</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a8c6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2491/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority for Uniform Funding and Management</inline>.—</heading><content>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, funds appropriated to the Department of Defense and available for morale, welfare, and recreation programs may be treated as nonappropriated funds and expended in accordance with laws applicable to the expenditures of nonappropriated funds. When made available for morale, welfare, and recreation programs under such regulations, appropriated funds shall be considered to be nonappropriated funds for all purposes and shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a8c7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2491/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Conditions on Availability</inline>.—</heading><content>Funds appropriated to the Department of Defense may be made available to support a morale, welfare, or recreation program only if the program is authorized to receive appropriated fund support and only in the amounts the program is authorized to receive.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a8c8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2491/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Conversion of Employment Positions</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a8c9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2491/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense may identify positions of employees in morale, welfare, and recreation programs within the Department of Defense who are paid with appropriated funds whose status may be converted from the status of an employee paid with appropriated funds to the status of an employee of a nonappropriated fund instrumentality.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a8ca-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2491/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The status of an employee in a position identified by the Secretary under paragraph (1) may, with the consent of the employee, be converted to the status of an employee of a nonappropriated fund instrumentality. An employee who does not consent to the conversion may not be removed from the position because of the failure to provide such consent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a8cb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2491/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The conversion of an employee from the status of an employee paid by appropriated funds to the status of an employee of a nonappropriated fund instrumentality shall be without a break in service for the concerned employee. The conversion shall not entitle an employee to severance pay, back pay or separation pay under subchapter IX of chapter 55 of title 5, or be considered an involuntary separation or other adverse personnel action entitling an employee to any right or benefit under such title or any other provision of law or regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida984a8cc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2491/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> In this subsection, the term “an employee of a nonappropriated fund instrumentality” means an employee described in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2105/c">section 2105(c) of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida984a8cd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tIII/s323/a">Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title III, § 323(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2510">116 Stat. 2510</ref>, § 2494; renumbered § 2491, <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/dA/tVI/s651/c/2">Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title VI, § 651(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1972">118 Stat. 1972</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida984a8ce-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida984a8cf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="ida984a8d0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 2491 was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4801">section 4801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida984a8d1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—<ref href="/us/pl/108/375">Pub. L. 108–375</ref> renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2494">section 2494 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
