<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida9b92634-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2692"><num value="2692">§ 2692.</num><heading> Storage, treatment, and disposal of nondefense toxic and hazardous materials</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9b92635-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2692/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9b92636-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2692/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as otherwise provided in this section, the Secretary of Defense may not permit the use of an installation of the Department of Defense for the storage, treatment, or disposal of any material that is a toxic or hazardous material and that is not owned either by the Department of Defense or by a member of the armed forces (or a dependent of the member) assigned to or provided military housing on the installation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9b92637-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2692/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall define by regulation what materials are hazardous or toxic materials for the purposes of this section, including specification of the quantity of a material that serves to make it hazardous or toxic for the purposes of this section. The definition shall include materials referred to in section 101(14) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601/14">42 U.S.C. 9601(14)</ref>) and materials designated under section 102 of that Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9602">42 U.S.C. 9602</ref>) and shall include materials that are of an explosive, flammable, or pyrotechnic nature.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9b92638-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2692/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> Subsection (a) does not apply to the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9b92639-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2692/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The storage, treatment, or disposal of materials that will be or have been used in connection with an activity of the Department of Defense or in connection with a service to be performed on an installation of the Department for the benefit of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9b9263a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2692/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The storage of strategic and critical materials in the National Defense Stockpile under an agreement for such storage with the Administrator of General Services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9b9263b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2692/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The temporary storage or disposal of explosives in order to protect the public or to assist agencies responsible for Federal, State, or local law enforcement in storing or disposing of explosives when no alternative solution is available, if such storage or disposal is made in accordance with an agreement between the Secretary of Defense and the head of the Federal, State, or local agency concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9b9263c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2692/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The temporary storage or disposal of explosives in order to provide emergency lifesaving assistance to civil authorities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9b9263d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2692/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The disposal of excess explosives produced under a Department of Defense contract, if the head of the military department concerned determines, in each case, that an alternative feasible means of disposal is not available to the contractor, taking into consideration public safety, available resources of the contractor, and national defense production requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9b9263e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2692/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The temporary storage of nuclear materials or nonnuclear classified materials in accordance with an agreement with the Secretary of Energy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9b9263f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2692/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The storage of materials that constitute military resources intended to be used during peacetime civil emergencies in accordance with applicable Department of Defense regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9b92640-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2692/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> The temporary storage of materials of other Federal agencies in order to provide assistance and refuge for commercial carriers of such material during a transportation emergency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bb9641-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2692/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> The storage of any material that is not owned by the Department of Defense if the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that the material is required or generated in connection with the authorized and compatible use of a facility of the Department of Defense, including the use of such a facility for testing material or training personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bb9642-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2692/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><chapeau> The treatment and disposal of any material that is not owned by the Department of Defense if the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that the material is required or generated in connection with the authorized and compatible use of a facility of that military department and the Secretary enters into a contract or agreement with the prospective user that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9bb9643-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2692/b/10/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is consistent with the best interest of national defense and environmental security; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9bb9644-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2692/b/10/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provides for the prospective user’s continued financial and environmental responsibility and liability with regard to the material.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bb9645-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2692/b/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> The storage of any material that is not owned by the Department of Defense if the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that the material is required or generated in connection with the use of a space launch facility located on an installation of the Department of Defense or on other land controlled by the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9bb9646-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2692/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense may grant exceptions to subsection (a) when essential to protect the health and safety of the public from imminent danger if the Secretary otherwise determines the exception is essential and if the storage or disposal authorized does not compete with private enterprise.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9bb9647-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2692/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9bb9648-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2692/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary may assess a charge for any storage or disposal provided under this section. Any such charge shall be on a reimbursable cost basis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9bb9649-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2692/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In the case of storage under this section authorized because of an imminent danger, the storage provided shall be temporary and shall cease once the imminent danger no longer exists. In all other cases of storage or disposal authorized under this section, the storage or disposal authorized shall be terminated as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida9bb964a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/98/407/tVIII/s805/a">Pub. L. 98–407, title VIII, § 805(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-08-28">Aug. 28, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1520">98 Stat. 1520</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dB/tXXVIII/s2852">Pub. L. 102–484, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2852</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2625">106 Stat. 2625</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tIII/s325">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title III, § 325</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2711">108 Stat. 2711</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tIII/s343/a">Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title III, § 343(a)</ref>–(g)(2), <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1686">111 Stat. 1686</ref>, 1687; <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tX/s1066/a/25">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1066(a)(25)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/772">113 Stat. 772</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tX/s1071/a/21">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1071(a)(21)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2399">120 Stat. 2399</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida9bb964b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida9bb964c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida9bb964d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (b)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364">Pub. L. 109–364</ref> substituted “testing material” for “testing materiel”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/106/65">Pub. L. 106–65</ref> substituted “apply to the following:” for “apply to—” in introductory provisions, “The” for “the” at the beginning of each of pars. (1) to (11), a period for the semicolon at the end of each of pars. (1) to (9), and a period for “; and” at the end of par. (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—<ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s343/g/2">Pub. L. 105–85, § 343(g)(2)</ref>, substituted “Storage, treatment, and” for “Storage and” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s343/g/1">Pub. L. 105–85, § 343(g)(1)</ref>, substituted “storage, treatment, or disposal” for “storage or disposal”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s343/a">Pub. L. 105–85, § 343(a)</ref>, substituted “either by the Department of Defense or by a member of the armed forces (or a dependent of the member) assigned to or provided military housing on the installation” for “by the Department of Defense”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1), (2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s343/b">Pub. L. 105–85, § 343(b)</ref>, added par. (1) and redesignated former par. (1) as (2). Former par. (2) redesignated (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s343/b/1">Pub. L. 105–85, § 343(b)(1)</ref>, (c), redesignated par. (2) as (3) and substituted “Federal, State, or local law enforcement” for “Federal law enforcement” and “Federal, State, or local agency” for “Federal agency”. Former par. (3) redesignated (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4) to (8). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s343/b/1">Pub. L. 105–85, § 343(b)(1)</ref>, redesignated pars. (3) to (7) as (4) to (8), respectively. Former par. (8) redesignated (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s343/b/1">Pub. L. 105–85, § 343(b)(1)</ref>, (d), redesignated par. (8) as (9) and substituted “in connection with the authorized and compatible use of a” for “by a private person in connection with the authorized and compatible use by that person of an industrial-type” and “, including the use of such a facility for testing materiel or training personnel;” for “; and”. Former par. (9) redesignated (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s343/b/1">Pub. L. 105–85, § 343(b)(1)</ref>, (e), redesignated par. (9) as (10) and substituted “in connection with the authorized and compatible use of a” for “by a private person in connection with the authorized and compatible commercial use by that person of an industrial-type”, “or agreement with the prospective user” for “with that person”, “for the prospective user’s” for “for that person’s”, and “; and” for period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s343/f">Pub. L. 105–85, § 343(f)</ref>, added par. (11).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/103/337">Pub. L. 103–337</ref> added par. (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484">Pub. L. 102–484</ref> added par. (8).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida9bb964e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="savings" id="ida9bb964f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Savings Provision</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tIII/s343/h">Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title III, § 343(h)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1688">111 Stat. 1688</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tIII/s343/h">“Nothing in the amendments made by this section [amending this section] is intended to modify environmental laws or laws relating to the siting of facilities.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
