<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida9bde005-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701"><num value="2701">§ 2701.</num><heading> Environmental restoration program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9bde006-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Environmental Restoration Program.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bde007-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall carry out a program of environmental restoration at facilities under the jurisdiction of the Secretary and at National Guard facilities. The program shall be known as the “Defense Environmental Restoration Program”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bde008-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Application of section 120 of cercla</inline>.—</heading><content>Activities of the program described in subsection (b)(1) shall be carried out subject to, and in a manner consistent with, section 120 (relating to Federal facilities) of CERCLA (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9620">42 U.S.C. 9620</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bde009-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation with epa</inline>.—</heading><content>The program shall be carried out in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bde00a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Administrative office within osd</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall identify an office within the Office of the Secretary which shall have responsibility for carrying out the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9bde00b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program Goals</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Goals of the program shall include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bde00c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The identification, investigation, research and development, and cleanup of contamination from a hazardous substance or pollutant or contaminant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bde00d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Correction of other environmental damage (such as detection and disposal of unexploded ordnance) which creates an imminent and substantial endangerment to the public health or welfare or to the environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bde00e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Demolition and removal of unsafe buildings and structures, including buildings and structures of the Department of Defense at sites formerly used by or under the jurisdiction of the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9bde00f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Responsibility for Response Actions.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bde010-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Basic responsibility</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall carry out (in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and CERCLA) all response actions with respect to releases of hazardous substances or pollutants or contaminants from each of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9bde011-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Each facility or site owned by, leased to, or otherwise possessed by the United States and under the jurisdiction of the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9bde012-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Each facility or site which was under the jurisdiction of the Secretary and owned by, leased to, or otherwise possessed by the United States at the time of actions leading to contamination by hazardous substances or pollutants or contaminants.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9bde013-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Each vessel owned or operated by the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9bde014-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/c/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Each National Guard facility being used for training the National Guard pursuant to chapter 5 of title 32 with funds provided by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department at the time of actions leading to contamination by hazardous substances or pollutants or contaminants.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bde015-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other responsible parties</inline>.—</heading><content>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to a removal or remedial action if the Administrator has provided for response action by a potentially responsible person in accordance with section 122 (relating to settlements) of CERCLA (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9622">42 U.S.C. 9622</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bde016-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State fees and charges</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall pay fees and charges imposed by State authorities for permit services for the disposal of hazardous substances or pollutants or contaminants on lands which are under the jurisdiction of the Secretary to the same extent that nongovernmental entities are required to pay fees and charges imposed by State authorities for permit services. The preceding sentence shall not apply with respect to a payment that is the responsibility of a lessee, contractor, or other private person.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9bde017-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Services of Other Entities.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bde018-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to paragraph (3), the Secretary may enter into agreements on a reimbursable or other basis with any other Federal agency, any State or local government agency, any Indian tribe, any owner of covenant property, or any nonprofit conservation organization to obtain the services of the agency, Indian tribe, owner, or organization to assist the Secretary in carrying out any of the Secretary’s responsibilities under this section. Services which may be obtained under this subsection include the identification, investigation, and cleanup of any off-site contamination resulting from the release of a hazardous substance or waste at a facility under the Secretary’s jurisdiction or at a National Guard facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bde019-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cross-fiscal year agreements</inline>.—</heading><content>An agreement with an agency under paragraph (1) may be for a period that begins in one fiscal year and ends in another fiscal year so long as the period of the agreement does not exceed two years. This two-year limitation does not apply to an agreement funded using amounts in the Department of Defense Base Closure Account established by section 2906 of the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 (part A of title XXIX of <ref href="/us/pl/101/510">Public Law 101–510</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2687">10 U.S.C. 2687</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bde01a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on reimbursable agreements</inline>.—</heading><content>An agreement with an agency under paragraph (1) may not provide for reimbursement of the agency for regulatory enforcement activities. An agreement under such paragraph with respect to a site also may not change the cleanup standards selected for the site pursuant to law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bde01b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subsection:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9bde01c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/d/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given such term in section 101(36) of CERCLA (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601/36">42 U.S.C. 9601(36)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9bde01d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/d/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The term “nonprofit conservation organization” means any non-governmental nonprofit organization whose primary purpose is conservation of open space or natural resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9bde01e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/d/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The term “owner of covenant property” means an owner of property subject to a covenant provided by the United States in accordance with the requirements of paragraphs (3) and (4) of section 120(h) of CERCLA (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9620/h">42 U.S.C. 9620(h)</ref>), so long as the covenant property is the site at which the services procured under paragraph (1) are to be performed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bde01f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Savings clause</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this subsection affects the applicability of section 120 of CERCLA (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9620">42 U.S.C. 9620</ref>) to the Department of Defense or the obligations and responsibilities of the Department of Defense under subsection (h) of such section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9bde020-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Response Action Contractors</inline>.—</heading><content>The provisions of section 119 of CERCLA (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9619">42 U.S.C. 9619</ref>) apply to response action contractors (as defined in that section) who carry out response actions under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9bde021-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Appropriated Funds at Former DOD Sites</inline>.—</heading><content>Appropriations available to the Department of Defense may be used at sites formerly used by the Department of Defense for removal of unsafe buildings or debris of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9bde022-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Removal of Unsafe Buildings and Debris Before Release From Federal Control</inline>.—</heading><content>In the case of property formerly used by the Department of Defense which is to be released from Federal Government control and at which there are unsafe buildings or debris of the Department of Defense, all actions necessary to comply with regulations of the General Services Administration on the transfer of property in a safe condition shall be completed before the property is released from Federal Government control, except in the case of property to be conveyed to an entity of State or local government or to a native corporation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9bde023-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Surety-Contractor Relationship</inline>.—</heading><content>Any surety which provides a bid, performance, or payment bond in connection with any direct Federal procurement for a response action contract under the Defense Environmental Restoration Program and begins activities to meet its obligations under such bond, shall, in connection with such activities or obligations, be entitled to any indemnification and the same standard of liability to which its principal was entitled under the contract or under any applicable law or regulation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9bde024-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Surety Bonds.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bde025-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability of sections 3131 and 3133 of title 40</inline>.—</heading><content>If under sections 3131 and 3133 of title 40 surety bonds are required for any direct Federal procurement of any response action contract under the Defense Environmental Restoration Program and are not waived pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s3134">section 3134 of title 40</ref>, the surety bonds shall be issued in accordance with sections 3131 and 3133.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bde026-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation of accrual of rights of action under bonds</inline>.—</heading><content>If, under applicable Federal law, surety bonds are required for any direct Federal procurement of any response action contract under the Defense Environmental Restoration Program, no right of action shall accrue on the performance bond issued on such contract to or for the use of any person other than an obligee named in the bond.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bde027-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Liability of sureties under bonds</inline>.—</heading><content>If, under applicable Federal law, surety bonds are required for any direct Federal procurement of any response action contract under the Defense Environmental Restoration Program, unless otherwise provided for by the Secretary in the bond, in the event of a default, the surety’s liability on a performance bond shall be only for the cost of completion of the contract work in accordance with the plans and specifications of the contract less the balance of funds remaining to be paid under the contract, up to the penal sum of the bond. The surety shall in no event be liable on bonds to indemnify or compensate the obligee for loss or liability arising from personal injury or property damage whether or not caused by a breach of the bonded contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bde028-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/i/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Nonpreemption</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this section shall be construed as preempting, limiting, superseding, affecting, applying to, or modifying any State laws, regulations, requirements, rules, practices, or procedures. Nothing in this section shall be construed as affecting, applying to, modifying, limiting, superseding, or preempting any rights, authorities, liabilities, demands, actions, causes of action, losses, judgment, claims, statutes of limitation, or obligations under Federal or State law, which do not arise on or under the bond.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9bde029-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9bde02a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Subsections (h) and (i) shall not apply to bonds executed before <date date="1991-12-05">December 5, 1991</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9bde02b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Subsections (h) and (i) shall not apply to bonds to which section 119(g) of CERCLA (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9619/g">42 U.S.C. 9619(g)</ref>) applies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9bde02c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><heading> UXO <inline class="small-caps">Program Manager</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9bde02d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/k/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall designate a program manager who shall serve as the single point of contact in the Department of Defense for policy and budgeting issues involving the characterization, research, remediation, and management of explosive and related risks with respect to unexploded ordnance, discarded military munitions, and munitions constituents at defense sites (as such terms are defined in section 2710 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002090">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002090"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title) that pose a threat to human health or safety.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9bde02e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/k/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The position of program manager shall be filled by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bde02f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/k/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an employee in a position that is equivalent to pay grade O–6 or above; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9bde030-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/k/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a member of the armed forces who is serving in the grade of colonel or, in the case of the Navy, captain, or in a higher grade.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9bde031-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/k/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The program manager shall report to the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Energy, Installations, and Environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9bde032-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2701/k/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The program manager may establish an independent advisory and review panel that may include representatives of the National Academy of Sciences, nongovernmental organizations with expertise regarding unexploded ordnance, discarded military munitions, or munitions constituents, the Environmental Protection Agency, States (as defined in section 2710 <sup>1</sup> of this title), and tribal governments. If established, the panel shall report annually to Congress on progress made by the Department of Defense to address unexploded ordnance, discarded military munitions, or munitions constituents at defense sites and make such recommendations as the panel considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida9bde033-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/99/499/tII/s211/a/1/B">Pub. L. 99–499, title II, § 211(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1719">100 Stat. 1719</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXIV/s1481/i/1">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1481(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1708">104 Stat. 1708</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/dA/tIII/s336/a">Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title III, § 336(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1342">105 Stat. 1342</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dA/tIII/s331/b">Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title III, § 331(b)</ref>, title X, § 1052(35), <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2373">106 Stat. 2373</ref>, 2501; <ref href="/us/pl/103/35/tII/s201/d/6">Pub. L. 103–35, title II, § 201(d)(6)</ref>, <date date="1993-05-31">May 31, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/99">107 Stat. 99</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tIII">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title III</ref>, §§ 322, 323, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2711">108 Stat. 2711</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tIII/s321/a/1">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title III, § 321(a)(1)</ref>, title XV, § 1504(a)(1), div. D, title XLIII, § 4321(b)(22), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/251">110 Stat. 251</ref>, 513, 673; <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tIII/s329">Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title III, § 329</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2483">110 Stat. 2483</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tIII/s314">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title III, § 314</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1053">115 Stat. 1053</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s3/b/17">Pub. L. 107–217, § 3(b)(17)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1296">116 Stat. 1296</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tIII">Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title III</ref>, §§ 311, 312, 313(c)(2), div. B, title XXVIII, § 2812(c), <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2506">116 Stat. 2506</ref>, 2508, 2709; <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/dA/tX/s1084/d/24">Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title X, § 1084(d)(24)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/2062">118 Stat. 2062</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tIII/s312/a">Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title III, § 312(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3190">119 Stat. 3190</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/284/s2">Pub. L. 109–284, § 2</ref>, <date date="2006-09-27">Sept. 27, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1211">120 Stat. 1211</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tIII">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title III</ref>, §§ 311, 312, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2137">120 Stat. 2137</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/dA/tX/s1073/a/28">Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(28)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2474">123 Stat. 2474</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/dA/tX/s1075/b/46/B">Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(46)(B)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4371">124 Stat. 4371</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dB/tXXVII/s2711/c/4/A">Pub. L. 112–239, div. B, title XXVII, § 2711(c)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2144">126 Stat. 2144</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tIX/s901/n/2">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title IX, § 901(n)(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3469">128 Stat. 3469</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tIII/s316/c">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title III, § 316(c)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1304">133 Stat. 1304</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tIII/s313/b">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title III, § 313(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2503">136 Stat. 2503</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tIII/s312/b">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title III, § 312(b)</ref>–(d), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/215">137 Stat. 215</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida9bde034-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida9bde035-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="ida9bde036-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2710">Section 2710 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (k), was subsequently amended, and no longer defines the term “unexploded ordnance”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="ida9bde037-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in subsecs. (f) and (g) of this section were contained in <ref href="/us/pl/101/165/tIX/s9038">Pub. L. 101–165, title IX, § 9038</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1137">103 Stat. 1137</ref>, which was set out below, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s1481/i/2">Pub. L. 101–510, § 1481(i)(2)</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 2701 was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2721">section 2721 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida9bde038-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2023—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s312/b">Pub. L. 118–31, § 312(b)</ref>, struck out “State-owned” before “National Guard”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s312/c">Pub. L. 118–31, § 312(c)</ref>, struck out “State-owned” before “National Guard”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s312/d">Pub. L. 118–31, § 312(d)</ref>, inserted “or at a National Guard facility” after “the Secretary’s jurisdiction”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s313/b">Pub. L. 117–263, § 313(b)</ref>, inserted “and at State-owned National Guard facilities” after “jurisdiction of the Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s313/c">Pub. L. 117–263, § 313(c)</ref>, added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Pub. L. 116–92</ref> inserted “or pollutants or contaminants” after “hazardous substances” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239">Pub. L. 112–239</ref> substituted “Department of Defense Base Closure Account established by section 2906” for “Department of Defense Base Closure Account 1990 or the Department of Defense Base Closure Account 2005 established under sections 2906 and 2906A”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383">Pub. L. 111–383</ref> substituted “a hazardous substance or pollutant or contaminant” for “hazardous substances, pollutants, and contaminants”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (d)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/111/84">Pub. L. 111–84</ref> substituted “9620)” for “6920)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/s312/a/1">Pub. L. 109–163, § 312(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “any owner of covenant property,” after “any Indian tribe,” and “owner,” after “, Indian tribe,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s312">Pub. L. 109–364, § 312</ref>, inserted at end “This two-year limitation does not apply to an agreement funded using amounts in the Department of Defense Base Closure Account 1990 or the Department of Defense Base Closure Account 2005 established under sections 2906 and 2906A of the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 (part A of title XXIX of <ref href="/us/pl/101/510">Public Law 101–510</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2687">10 U.S.C. 2687</ref> note).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/s312/a/2">Pub. L. 109–163, § 312(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “An agreement under such paragraph with respect to a site also may not change the cleanup standards selected for the site pursuant to law.” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(4)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/s312/a/3">Pub. L. 109–163, § 312(a)(3)</ref>, added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/s312/a/4">Pub. L. 109–163, § 312(a)(4)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/284">Pub. L. 109–284</ref> substituted “sections 3131 and 3133 of title 40” for “miller act” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s311/1">Pub. L. 109–364, § 311(1)</ref>, substituted “designate” for “establish” and inserted “research,” after “characterization,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(2) to (4). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s311/2">Pub. L. 109–364, § 311(2)</ref>, (3), added pars. (2) and (3), redesignated former par. (3) as (4), and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows: “The authority to establish the program manager may be delegated to the Secretary of a military department, who may delegate the authority to the Under Secretary of that military department. The authority may not be further delegated.”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s1084/d/24/A">Pub. L. 108–375, § 1084(d)(24)(A)</ref>, inserted “(<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9620">42 U.S.C. 9620</ref>)” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s1084/d/24/B">Pub. L. 108–375, § 1084(d)(24)(B)</ref>, substituted “(relating to settlements) of CERCLA (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9622">42 U.S.C. 9622</ref>)” for “of CERCLA (relating to settlements)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s1084/d/24/C">Pub. L. 108–375, § 1084(d)(24)(C)</ref>, inserted “(<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9619">42 U.S.C. 9619</ref>)” after “CERCLA”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s1084/d/24/D">Pub. L. 108–375, § 1084(d)(24)(D)</ref>, substituted “CERCLA” for “the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s313/c/2">Pub. L. 107–314, § 313(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “CERCLA” for “the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (hereinafter in this chapter referred to as ‘CERCLA’) (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601">42 U.S.C. 9601</ref> et seq.)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s2812/c/1">Pub. L. 107–314, § 2812(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “Entities” for “Agencies” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/314">Pub. L. 107–314</ref>, §§ 311(1), 2812(c)(2), substituted “paragraph (3)” for “paragraph (2)”, “any State or local government agency, any Indian tribe, or any nonprofit conservation organization” for “with any State or local government agency, or with any Indian tribe,”, and “the agency, Indian tribe, or organization” for “the agency”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s311/2">Pub. L. 107–314, § 311(2)</ref>, (3), added par. (2) and redesignated former par. (2) as (3). Former par. (3) redesignated (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s2812/c/3">Pub. L. 107–314, § 2812(c)(3)</ref>, added par. (4) and struck out heading and text of former par. (4). Text read as follows: “In this subsection, the term ‘Indian tribe’ has the meaning given such term in section 101(36) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601/36">42 U.S.C. 9601(36)</ref>).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s311/2">Pub. L. 107–314, § 311(2)</ref>, redesignated par. (3) as (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/217">Pub. L. 107–217</ref> substituted “sections 3131 and 3133 of title 40” for “the Miller Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s270a">40 U.S.C. 270a</ref> et seq.)”, “<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s3134">section 3134 of title 40</ref>” for “the Act of <date date="1941-04-29">April 29, 1941</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s270e–270f">40 U.S.C. 270e–270f</ref>)”, and “sections 3131 and 3133” for “the Miller Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s312">Pub. L. 107–314, § 312</ref>, added subsec. (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (j)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/107">Pub. L. 107–107</ref> struck out “, or after <date date="1999-12-31">December 31, 1999</date>” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/104/201">Pub. L. 104–201</ref> substituted “, with any State or local government agency, or with any Indian tribe,” for “, or with any State or local government agency,” in par. (1) and added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1504/a/1">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1504(a)(1)</ref>, made technical correction to directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s322/1">Pub. L. 103–337, § 322(1)</ref>. See 1994 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s321/a/1">Pub. L. 104–106, § 321(a)(1)</ref>, amended subsec. (d) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (d) read as follows: “<inline class="small-caps">Services of Other Agencies.—</inline></p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—The Secretary may enter into agreements on a reimbursable basis with any other Federal agency, and on a reimbursable or other basis with any State or local government agency or any Indian tribe, to obtain the services of that agency to assist the Secretary in carrying out any of the Secretary’s responsibilities under this section. Services which may be obtained under this subsection include the identification, investigation, and cleanup of any off-site contamination possibly resulting from the release of a hazardous substance or waste at a facility under the Secretary’s jurisdiction.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) <inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—In this subsection, the term ‘Indian tribe’ has the meaning given such term in section 101(36) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601/36">42 U.S.C. 9601(36)</ref>).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s4321/b/22">Pub. L. 104–106, § 4321(b)(22)</ref>, substituted “Miller Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s270a">40 U.S.C. 270a</ref> et seq.)” for “Act of <date date="1935-08-24">August 24, 1935</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s270a–270d">40 U.S.C. 270a–270d</ref>), commonly referred to as the ‘Miller Act’,” and “the Miller Act” for “such Act of <date date="1935-08-24">August 24, 1935</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s322/1">Pub. L. 103–337, § 322(1)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1504/a/1">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1504(a)(1)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and inserted par. (1) heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s322/2">Pub. L. 103–337, § 322(2)</ref>, inserted “or any Indian tribe” after “any State or local government agency”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s322/3">Pub. L. 103–337, § 322(3)</ref>, added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s323">Pub. L. 103–337, § 323</ref>, substituted “<date date="1999-12-31">December 31, 1999</date>” for “<date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (j)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/35">Pub. L. 103–35</ref> substituted “(<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9619/g">42 U.S.C. 9619(g)</ref>) applies” for “applies (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9619/g">42 U.S.C. 9619(g)</ref>)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s1052/35">Pub. L. 102–484, § 1052(35)</ref>, substituted “<date date="1991-12-05">December 5, 1991</date>,” for “the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Years 1992 and 1993” in par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s331/b">Pub. L. 102–484, § 331(b)</ref>, substituted “<date date="1995-12-31">December 31, 1995</date>” for “<date date="1992-12-31">December 31, 1992</date>”, designated existing provisions as par. (1), and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsecs. (h) to (j). <ref href="/us/pl/102/190">Pub. L. 102–190</ref> added subsecs. (h) to (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsecs. (f), (g). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510">Pub. L. 101–510</ref> added subsecs. (f) and (g).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida9bde039-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="ida9bde03a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Assistant Secretary of Defense for Energy, Installations, and Environment” substituted for “Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Installations and Environment” in subsec. (k)(3) on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/s901/n/2">section 901(n)(2) of Pub. L. 113–291</ref>, set out as a References note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s131">section 131 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida9bde03b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2013 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dB/tXXVII/s2711/d">Pub. L. 112–239, div. B, title XXVII, § 2711(d)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2144">126 Stat. 2144</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/239/dB/tXXVII/s2711/d">
<inline>“This section and the amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 2703, 2705, and 2883 of this title and enacting and amending provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2687">section 2687 of this title</ref>] shall take effect on the later of—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> <date date="2013-10-01">October 1, 2013</date>; and [sic]</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the date of the enactment of an Act authorizing funds for military construction for fiscal year 2014 [div. J of <ref href="/us/pl/113/76">Pub. L. 113–76</ref>, approved <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>].”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida9bde03c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tXV/s1504/a">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1504(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/513">110 Stat. 513</ref>, provided that the amendment made by that section is effective as of <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, and as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/103/337">Pub. L. 103–337</ref> as enacted.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date and applicability of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s4321/b/22">section 4321(b)(22) of Pub. L. 104–106</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s4401">section 4401 of Pub. L. 104–106</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2220">section 2220 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="savings" id="ida9bde03d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Savings Clause</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Nothing in amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s316">section 316 of Pub. L. 116–92</ref> to affect any requirement or authority under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601">42 U.S.C. 9601</ref> et seq.), see <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s316/d">section 316(d) of Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2700">section 2700 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9bde03e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Provision of Alternative Drinking Water to Households Whose Private Drinking Water is Contaminated With Perfluorooctanesulfonic Acid and Perfluorooctanoic Acid Substances From Department of Defense Activities</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tIII/s317">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title III, § 317</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/806">139 Stat. 806</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tIII/s317">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Subject to subsections (b) and (c), on and after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall offer alternative drinking water to a household if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the household is downgradient from a military installation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the household receives water from one or more private drinking water wells where contamination from detections of perfluorooctanesulfonic acid and perfluorooctanoic acid substances resulting solely from activities of the Department of Defense, as determined by the Secretary, carried out at such military installation has, at one point in time, exceeded the maximum contaminant level for such substances established by the Environmental Protection Agency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> as of the date of the enactment of this Act, another household located in the same community was eligible for alternative drinking water provided by the Secretary by reason of contamination from detections of perfluorooctanesulfonic acid and perfluorooctanoic acid substances resulting from activities of the Department carried out at the same military installation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coordination With Other Authorities</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall carry out this section in a manner that is consistent with the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601">42 U.S.C. 9601</ref> et seq.) and the authorities of the Secretary under environmental law, including by prioritizing and coordinating the efforts of the Secretary under subsection (a) with other efforts to address releases of perfluorooctanesulfonic acid and perfluorooctanoic acid.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary is not required to offer or provide alternative drinking water to a household under subsection (a) if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the household is part of a community, as determined by the Secretary, where all the households in the community that have been affected by contamination from detections of perfluorooctanesulfonic acid and perfluorooctanoic acid substances resulting from activities of the Department have been connected to a municipal drinking water distribution system; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Secretary has otherwise taken action under the Comprehensive, [sic] Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601">42 U.S.C. 9601</ref> et seq.) to reduce drinking water exposures, including by meeting the relevant Federal or State drinking water standards for perfluorooctanesulfonic acid and perfluorooctanoic acid substances.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> The term ‘alternative drinking water’ includes—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> provision of bottled water;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> connection to public water systems for members of the public using private wells; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> provision of filtration systems for private residences.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘Federal drinking water standard’ means an enforceable Federal standard for drinking water, as described in section 121(d)(2)(A)(i) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9621/d/2/A/i">42 U.S.C. 9621(d)(2)(A)(i)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The terms ‘maximum contaminant level’ and ‘public water system’ have the meanings given those terms in section 1401 of the Safe Drinking Water Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300f">42 U.S.C. 300f</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The term ‘private drinking water well’ means a drinking water well that is not a public water system and is not connected to a public water system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> The term ‘State drinking water standard’ means an enforceable State standard, in effect in that State, for drinking water, as described in section 121(d)(2)(A)(ii) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9621/d/2/A/ii">42 U.S.C. 9621(d)(2)(A)(ii)</ref>).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9bde03f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Strategy To Accelerate Remediation of Contamination From Perfluoroalkyl Substances and Polyfluoroalkyl Substances</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tIII/s322">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title III, § 322</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/814">139 Stat. 814</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tIII/s322">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Strategy</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] a strategy to accelerate the response efforts of the Department of Defense with respect to releases of perfluoroalkyl substances or polyfluoroalkyl substances from the activities of the Department. Consistent with CERCLA, the strategy shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> criteria that the Department uses to prioritize response actions on military installations and National Guard facilities based on relative risk to human health and the environment, including concentrations of releases of perfluoroalkyl substances or polyfluoroalkyl substances, migration pathways, and proximity to receptors;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> timelines for completing each phase of the cleanup process under CERCLA with respect to such releases for each such military installation or National Guard facility;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> a plan for deploying additional technologies, personnel, or other resources to reduce delays to remediation efforts, including an identification of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the number of laboratories accredited by the environmental laboratory accreditation program of the Department to test for the presence of perfluoroalkyl substances and polyfluoroalkyl substances; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the number of laboratories in the process of being so accredited; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> benchmarks for evaluating the performance of each military department or Defense Agency in reducing the relative risk with respect to response efforts to address releases of perfluoroalkyl substances and polyfluoroalkyl substances.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Public Dashboard</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall publish on a publicly accessible website of the Department, an online dashboard that provides information on the actions of the Department, including each military department, addressing releases of perfluoroalkyl substances and polyfluoroalkyl substances from activities of the Department. The dashboard shall be updated on a semiannual basis and shall include a summary of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> funding that has been obligated or expended address such releases, dissagregated by each military installation or National Guard facility with respect to which efforts are planned or underway;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the status of response efforts to address such releases under the applicable phase of the cleanup process under CERCLA, including the status of any interim removal actions, at each such site;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> projected and actual timelines for the completion of response actions with respect to such releases at each such site; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> points of contact for community engagement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The terms ‘CERCLA’, ‘National Guard facility’, ‘removal’, and ‘response’ have the meanings given those terms in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2700">section 2700 of title 10</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘Defense Agency’ has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101/a">section 101(a) of title 10</ref>, United States Code.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9bde040-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Authority To Use Certain Technologies To Destroy or Dispose of Perfluoroalkyl or Polyfluoroalkyl Substances</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tIII/s324">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title III, § 324</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/815">139 Stat. 815</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tIII/s324">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may use technologies for the destruction or disposal of a perfluoroalkyl or polyfluoroalkyl substance that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> are cost effective; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> are permitted or otherwise approved by a Federal or State agency that regulates the destruction or disposal of such a substance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guidance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> issue guidance implementing the authority under subsection (a), including by setting forth technologies that the Secretary determines meet the criteria specified in paragraphs (1) and (2) of such subsection; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> periodically review and revise such guidance, taking into account the development of new technologies.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9bde041-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Use of Expeditionary Solid Waste Disposal Systems by Department of Defense</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tIII/s380">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title III, § 380</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/844">139 Stat. 844</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tIII/s380">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Expeditionary Solid Waste Disposal Systems.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorized use</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense may use expeditionary solid waste disposal systems for the destruction of covered materials.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Equipping and availability of systems</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Expeditionary solid waste disposal systems units deployed for use in accordance with paragraph (1) shall be—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> equipped to support operations relating to border security and the elimination of contraband; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> made available with respect to military installations, forward operating bases, and the security forces of allies and partners of the United States as necessary to assist in countering infiltration and the unauthorized use of military assets of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Use of Open-air Burn Pits to Dispose of Covered Material</inline>.—</heading><content>In addition to the prohibition on the disposal of certain wastes in open-air burn pits under section 317 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2010 (<ref href="/us/pl/111/84">Public Law 111–84</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2701">10 U.S.C. 2701</ref> note), the Secretary of Defense may not use open-air burn pits for the disposal of any covered material.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered Material Defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term ‘covered material’ means the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Contraband or other property that is illegal to possess, including seized counterfeit materials and unauthorized military equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Classified equipment or materials.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9bde042-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Guidance and Target Goal Relating to Formerly Used Defense Sites Programs</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tIII/s326">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title III, § 326</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2518">136 Stat. 2518</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tIII/s326">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guidance Relating to Site Prioritization</inline>.—</heading><content>The Assistant Secretary of Defense for Energy, Installations, and Environment shall issue guidance setting forth how, in prioritizing sites for activities funded under the ‘Environmental Restoration Account, Formerly Used Defense Sites’ account established under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2703/a/5">section 2703(a)(5) of title 10</ref>, United States Code, the Assistant Secretary shall weigh the relative risk or other factors between Installation Restoration Program sites and Military Munitions Response Program sites.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Target Goal for Military Munitions Response Program</inline>.—</heading><content>The Assistant Secretary of Defense for Energy, Installations, and Environment shall establish a target goal for the completion of the cleanup of all Military Munitions Response Program sites.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9bde043-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Annual Briefings on Department of Defense Procurement of Covered Items Containing PFOS or PFOA</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tIII/s347/b">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title III, § 347(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2532">136 Stat. 2532</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tIII/s347/b">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Briefings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall provide to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate a briefing that includes a description of each of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Steps taken to identify covered items procured by the Department of Defense that contain perfluorooctane sulfonate (PFOS) or perfluorooctanoic acid (PFOA).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Steps taken to identify products and vendors of covered items that do not contain PFOS or PFOA.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Steps taken to limit the procurement by the Department of covered items that contain PFOS or PFOA.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Steps the Secretary intends to take to limit the procurement of covered items that contain PFOS or PFOA.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered Item Defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term ‘covered item’ means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> nonstick cookware or cooking utensils for use in galleys or dining facilities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> upholstered furniture, carpets, and rugs that have been treated with stain-resistant coatings.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9bde044-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Temporary Moratorium on Incineration by Department of Defense of Perfluoroalkyl Substances, Polyfluoroalkyl Substances, and Aqueous Film Forming Foam</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tIII/s343">Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title III, § 343</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1643">135 Stat. 1643</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tIII/s335">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title III, § 335</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/222">137 Stat. 222</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tIII/s335">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Temporary Moratorium</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (c), beginning not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall prohibit the incineration of covered materials until the earlier of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> The date on which the Secretary issues guidance implementing—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the interim guidance on the destruction and disposal of PFAS and materials containing PFAS published by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency under section 7361 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s8961">15 U.S.C. 8961</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> section 330 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Public Law 116–92</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2701">10 U.S.C. 2701</ref> note).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The date on which the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency publishes in the Federal Register a final rule regarding the destruction and disposal of such materials pursuant to such section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Required Adoption of Final Rule</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon publication of the final rule specified in subsection (a)(2), the Secretary shall adopt such final rule, regardless of whether the Secretary previously implemented the interim guidance specified in subsection (a)(1)(A).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Certain Materials</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding subsection (a), until the date on which the Secretary adopts the final rule pursuant to subsection (b), the Secretary may treat covered materials, including soils that have been contaminated with PFAS, through the use of any remediation or disposal technology that is approved by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than one year after the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for three years, the Secretary shall submit to the Administrator and the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on all incineration by the Department of Defense of covered materials during the year covered by the report, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the total amount of covered materials incinerated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the temperature range specified in the permit where the covered materials were incinerated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the locations and facilities where the covered materials were incinerated;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> details on actions taken by the Department of Defense to implement section 330 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> recommendations for the safe storage of PFAS and PFAS-containing materials prior to destruction and disposal.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Scope</inline>.—</heading><content>The prohibition in subsection (a) and reporting requirements in subsection (d) shall apply not only to materials sent directly by the Department of Defense to an incinerator, but also to materials sent to another entity or entities, including any waste processing facility, subcontractor, or fuel blending facility, prior to incineration.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The term ‘AFFF’ means aqueous film forming foam.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> The term ‘covered material’ means any AFFF formulation containing PFAS, material contaminated by AFFF release, or spent filter or other PFAS-contaminated material resulting from site remediation or water filtration that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> has been used by the Department of Defense or a military department;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> is being discarded for disposal by the Department of Defense or a military department; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> is being removed from sites or facilities owned or operated by the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The term ‘PFAS’ means per- or polyfluoroalkyl substances.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9bde045-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Review and Guidance Relating to Prevention and Mitigation of Spills of Aqueous Film-Forming Foam</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tIII/s344">Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title III, § 344</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1644">135 Stat. 1644</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tIII/s344">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Review Required</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days of after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall complete a review of the efforts of the Department of Defense to prevent or mitigate spills of aqueous film-forming foam (in this section referred to as ‘AFFF’). Such review shall assess the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The preventative maintenance guidelines for fire trucks of the Department and fire suppression systems in buildings of the Department, to mitigate the risk of equipment failure that may result in a spill of AFFF.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Any requirements for the use of personal protective equipment by personnel when conducting a material transfer or maintenance activity of the Department that may result in a spill of AFFF, or when conducting remediation activities for such a spill, including requirements for side-shield safety glasses, latex gloves, and respiratory protection equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The methods by which the Secretary ensures compliance with guidance specified in material safety data sheets with respect to the use of such personal protective equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guidance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 90 days after the date on which the Secretary completes the review under subsection (a), the Secretary shall issue guidance on the prevention and mitigation of spills of AFFF based on the results of such review that includes, at a minimum, best practices and recommended requirements to ensure the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The supervision by personnel trained in responding to spills of AFFF of each material transfer or maintenance activity of the Department of Defense that may result in such a spill.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The use of containment berms and the covering of storm drains and catch basins by personnel performing maintenance activities for the Department in the vicinity of such drains or basins.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The storage of materials for the cleanup and containment of AFFF in close proximity to fire suppression systems in buildings of the Department and the presence of such materials during any transfer or activity specified in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefing</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary issues the guidance under subsection (b), the Secretary shall provide to the congressional defense committees [Committee on Armed Services and Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and House of Representatives] a briefing that summarizes the results of the review conducted under subsection (a) and the guidance issued under subsection (b).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9bde046-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Notification to Agricultural Operations Located in Areas Exposed to Department of Defense PFAS Use</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tIII/s335">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title III, § 335</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3532">134 Stat. 3532</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tIII/s335">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notification Required</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>], the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, shall provide a notification described in subsection (b) to any agricultural operation located within one mile down gradient of a military installation or National Guard facility where covered PFAS—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> has been detected in groundwater;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> has been hydrologically linked to a local agricultural or drinking water source, including a water well; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> is suspected to be, or known to be, the result of the use of PFAS at an installation of the Department of Defense located in the United States or State-owned facility of the National Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notification Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The notification required under subsection (a) shall include the following information:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The name of the Department of Defense installation or National Guard facility from which the covered PFAS in groundwater originated.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The specific covered PFAS detected in groundwater.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The levels of the covered PFAS detected.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Relevant governmental information regarding the health and safety of the covered PFAS detected, including relevant Federal or State standards for PFAS in groundwater, livestock, food commodities and drinking water, and any known restrictions for sale of agricultural products that have been irrigated or watered with water containing PFAS.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional Testing Results</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall provide to an agricultural operation that receives a notice under subsection (a) any pertinent updated information, including any results of new elevated testing, by not later than 15 days after receiving validated test results.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives a report on the status of providing notice under subsection (a). Such report shall include, for the period covered by the report—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the approximate locations of such operations relative to installations of the Department of Defense located in the United States and State-owned facilities of the National Guard;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the covered PFAS detected in groundwater; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the levels of covered PFAS detected.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> The term ‘covered PFAS’ means each of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Perfluorooctanoic acid (commonly referred to as ‘PFOA’) (Chemical Abstracts Service No. 335–67–1) detected in groundwater above 70 parts per trillion, individually or in combination with PFOS.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Perfluorooctane sulfonic acid (commonly referred to as ‘PFOS’) (Chemical Abstracts Service No. 1763–23–1) detected in groundwater above 70 parts per trillion, individually or in combination with PFOA.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Perfluorobutanesulfonic acid (commonly referred to as ‘PFBS’) (Chemical Abstracts Service No. 375–73–5) detected in groundwater above 40 parts per billion.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘PFAS’ means a perfluoroalkyl or polyfluoroalkyl substance with at least one fully fluorinated carbon atom, including the chemical GenX.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9bde047-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Contamination by Perfluoroalkyl or Polyfluoroalkyl Substances</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tIII/s321/b">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title III, § 321(b)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/221">137 Stat. 221</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tIII/s321/b">“Beginning not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall publish on the publicly available website established under section 331(b) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Public Law 116–92</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2701">10 U.S.C. 2701</ref> note) timely and regularly updated information on the status of cleanup at sites for which the Secretary has obligated funds for environmental restoration activities.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tIII/s341/a">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title III, § 341(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2528">136 Stat. 2528</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tIII/s341/a">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Beginning not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], [the] Secretary of Defense shall publish on the publicly available website established under section 331(b) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Public Law 116–92</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2701">10 U.S.C. 2701</ref> note) timely and regularly updated information on the research efforts of the Department of Defense relating to perfluoroalkyl substances or polyfluoroalkyl substances, which shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> A description of any research collaboration or data sharing by the Department with the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry, or any other agency (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s551">section 551 of title 5</ref>, United States Code), State, academic institution, nongovernmental organization, or other entity.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Regularly updated information on research projects supported or conducted by the Department of Defense pertaining to the development, testing, and evaluation of a fluorine-free firefighting foam or any other alternative to aqueous film forming foam that contains perfluoroalkyl substances or polyfluoroalkyl substances, excluding any proprietary information that is business confidential.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Regularly updated information on research projects supported or conducted by the Department pertaining to the health effects of perfluoroalkyl substances or polyfluoroalkyl substances, including information relating to the impact of such substances on firefighters, veterans, and military families, and excluding any personally identifiable information.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Regularly updated information on research projects supported or conducted by the Department pertaining to treatment options for drinking water, surface water, ground water, and the safe disposal of perfluoroalkyl substances or polyfluoroalkyl substances.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> Budget information, including specific spending information for the research projects relating to perfluoroalkyl substances or polyfluoroalkyl substances that are supported or conducted by the Department.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> Such other matters as may be relevant to ongoing research projects supported or conducted by the Department to address the use of perfluoroalkyl substances or polyfluoroalkyl substances and the health effects of the use of such substances.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Format</inline>.—</heading><content>The information published under paragraph (1) shall be made available in a downloadable, machine-readable, open, and user-friendly format.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subsection:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The term ‘military installation’ includes active, inactive, and former military installations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The term ‘perfluoroalkyl substance’ means a man-made chemical of which all of the carbon atoms are fully fluorinated carbon atoms.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> The term ‘polyfluoroalkyl substance’ means a man-made chemical containing a mix of fully fluorinated carbon atoms, partially fluorinated carbon atoms, and nonfluorinated carbon atoms.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tIII">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title III</ref>, §§ 329–332, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1312">133 Stat. 1312</ref>, 1313, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tIII">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="329">“SEC. 329.</num><heading> PROHIBITION ON PERFLUOROALKYL SUBSTANCES AND POLYFLUOROALKYL SUBSTANCES IN MEALS READY-TO-EAT FOOD PACKAGING.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2021-10-01">October 1, 2021</date>, the Director of the Defense Logistics Agency shall ensure that any food contact substances that are used to assemble and package meals ready-to-eat (MREs) procured by the Defense Logistics Agency do not contain any perfluoroalkyl substances or polyfluoroalkyl substances.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Perfluoroalkyl substance</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘perfluoroalkyl substance’ means a man-made chemical of which all of the carbon atoms are fully fluorinated carbon atoms.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Polyfluoroalkyl substance</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘polyfluoroalkyl substance’ means a man-made chemical containing a mix of fully fluorinated carbon atoms, partially fluorinated carbon atoms, and nonfluorinated carbon atoms.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="330">“SEC. 330.</num><heading> DISPOSAL OF MATERIALS CONTAINING PER- AND POLYFLUOROALKYL SUBSTANCES OR AQUEOUS FILM-FORMING FOAM.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that when materials containing per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances (referred to in this section as ‘PFAS’) or aqueous film forming foam (referred to in this section as ‘AFFF’) are disposed—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> all incineration is conducted at a temperature range adequate to break down PFAS chemicals while also ensuring the maximum degree of reduction in emission of PFAS, including elimination of such emissions where achievable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> all incineration is conducted in accordance with the requirements of the Clean Air Act (42 USC 7401 et seq.), including controlling hydrogen fluoride;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> any materials containing PFAS that are designated for disposal are stored in accordance with the requirement under part 264 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> all incineration is conducted at a facility that has been permitted to receive waste regulated under subtitle C of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (42 USC 6921 et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Scope of Application</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The requirements in subsection (a) only apply to all legacy AFFF formulations containing PFAS, materials contaminated by AFFF release, and spent filters or other PFAS contaminated materials resulting from site remediation or water filtration that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> have been used by the Department of Defense or a military department; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> are being discarded for disposal by means of incineration by the Department of Defense or a military department; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> are being removed from sites or facilities owned or operated by the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="331">“SEC. 331.</num><heading> AGREEMENTS TO SHARE MONITORING DATA RELATING TO PERFLUOROALKYL AND POLYFLUOROALKYL SUBSTANCES AND OTHER CONTAMINANTS OF CONCERN.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall seek to enter into agreements with municipalities or municipal drinking water utilities located adjacent to military installations under which both the Secretary and the municipalities and utilities would share monitoring data relating to perfluoroalkyl substances, polyfluoroalkyl substances, and other emerging contaminants of concern collected at the military installation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Publicly Available Website</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall maintain a publicly available website that provides a clearinghouse for information about the exposure of members of the Armed Forces, their families, and their communities to per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances. The information provided on the website shall include information on testing, clean-up, and recommended available treatment methodologies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Public Communication</inline>.—</heading><content>An agreement under subsection (a) does not negate the responsibility of the Secretary to communicate with the public about drinking water contamination from perfluoroalkyl substances, polyfluoroalkyl substances, and other contaminants.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Military Installation Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘military installation’ has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2801/c">section 2801(c) of title 10</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="332">“SEC. 332.</num><heading> COOPERATIVE AGREEMENTS WITH STATES TO ADDRESS CONTAMINATION BY PERFLUOROALKYL AND POLYFLUOROALKYL SUBSTANCES.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cooperative Agreements.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon request from the Governor or chief executive of a State, the Secretary of Defense shall work expeditiously, pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2701/d">section 2701(d) of title 10</ref>, United States Code, to finalize a cooperative agreement, or amend an existing cooperative agreement to address testing, monitoring, removal, and remedial actions relating to the contamination or suspected contamination of drinking, surface, or ground water from PFAS originating from activities of the Department of Defense by providing the mechanism and funding for the expedited review and approval of documents of the Department related to PFAS investigations and remedial actions from an active or decommissioned military installation, including a facility of the National Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Minimum standards</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A cooperative agreement finalized or amended under paragraph (1) shall meet or exceed the most stringent of the following standards for PFAS in any environmental media:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> An enforceable State standard, in effect in that State, for drinking, surface, or ground water, as described in section 121(d)(2)(A)(ii) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9621/d/2/A/ii">42 U.S.C. 9621(d)(2)(A)(ii)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> An enforceable Federal standard for drinking, surface, or ground water, as described in section 121(d)(2)(A)(i) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9621/d/2/A/i">42 U.S.C. 9621(d)(2)(A)(i)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> A health advisory under section 1412(b)(1)(F) of the Safe Drinking Water Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300g–1/b/1/F">42 U.S.C. 300g–1(b)(1)(F)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other authority</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In addition to the requirements for a cooperative agreement under paragraph (1), when otherwise authorized to expend funds for the purpose of addressing ground or surface water contaminated by a perfluorinated compound, the Secretary of Defense may, to expend those funds, enter into a grant agreement, cooperative agreement, or contract with—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> the local water authority with jurisdiction over the contamination site, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> a public water system (as defined in section 1401 of the Safe Drinking Water Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300f">42 U.S.C. 300f</ref>)); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> a publicly owned treatment works (as defined in section 212 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s1292">33 U.S.C. 1292</ref>)); or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a State, local, or Tribal government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Beginning on <date date="2020-02-01">February 1, 2020</date>, if a cooperative agreement is not finalized or amended under subsection (a) within one year after the request from the Governor or chief executive under that subsection, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees and Members of Congress a report—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> explaining why the agreement has not been finalized or amended, as the case may be; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> setting forth a projected timeline for finalizing or amending the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate committees and members of congress</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘appropriate committees and Members of Congress’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Senators who represent a State impacted by PFAS contamination described in subsection (a)(1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the Members of the House of Representatives who represent a district impacted by such contamination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Fully fluorinated carbon atom</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘fully fluorinated carbon atom’ means a carbon atom on which all the hydrogen substituents have been replaced by fluorine.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">PFAS</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘PFAS’ means perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances that are man-made chemicals with at least one fully fluorinated carbon atom.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘State’ has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601">42 U.S.C. 9601</ref>).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c05148-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Treatment of Contaminated Water Near Military Installations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tIII">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title III</ref>, subtitle C, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1317">133 Stat. 1317</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tIII">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="341">“SEC. 341.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This subtitle may be cited as the ‘Prompt and Fast Action to Stop Damages Act of 2019’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="342">“SEC. 342.</num><heading> DEFINITIONS.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“In this subtitle:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">PFOA</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘PFOA’ means perfluorooctanoic acid.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">PFOS</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘PFOS’ means perfluorooctane sulfonate.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="343">“SEC. 343.</num><heading> PROVISION OF WATER UNCONTAMINATED WITH PERFLUOROOCTANOIC ACID (PFOA) AND PERFLUOROOCTANE SULFONATE (PFOS) FOR AGRICULTURAL PURPOSES.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Using amounts authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for operation and maintenance for the military department concerned, or for operation and maintenance Defense-wide in the case of the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary concerned may provide water sources uncontaminated with perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances, including PFOA and PFOS, or treatment of contaminated waters, for agricultural purposes used to produce products destined for human consumption in an area in which a water source has been determined pursuant to paragraph (2) to be contaminated with such compounds by reason of activities on a military installation under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicable standard</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of paragraph (1), an area is determined to be contaminated with PFOA or PFOS if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the level of contamination is above the Lifetime Health Advisory for contamination with such compounds issued by the Environmental Protection Agency and printed in the Federal Register on <date date="2016-05-25">May 25, 2016</date>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> on or after the date the Food and Drug Administration sets a standard for PFOA and PFOS in raw agricultural commodities and milk, the level of contamination is above such standard.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secretary Concerned Defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term ‘Secretary concerned’ means the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The Secretary of the Army, with respect to the Army.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Secretary of the Navy, with respect to the Navy, the Marine Corps, and the Coast Guard (when it is operating as a service in the Navy).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The Secretary of the Air Force, with respect to the Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense, with respect to the Defense Agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="344">“SEC. 344.</num><heading> ACQUISITION OF REAL PROPERTY BY AIR FORCE.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of the Air Force may acquire one or more parcels of real property within the vicinity of an Air Force base that has shown signs of contamination from PFOA and PFOS due to activities on the base and which would extend the contiguous geographic footprint of the base and increase the force protection standoff near critical infrastructure and runways.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Improvements and personal property</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority under paragraph (1) to acquire real property described in that paragraph shall include the authority to purchase improvements and personal property located on that real property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Relocation expenses</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority under paragraph (1) to acquire real property described in that paragraph shall include the authority to provide Federal financial assistance for moving costs, relocation benefits, and other expenses incurred in accordance with the Uniform Relocation Assistance and Real Property Acquisition Policies Act of 1970 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4601">42 U.S.C. 4601</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Environmental Activities</inline>.—</heading><content>The Air Force shall conduct such activities at a parcel or parcels of real property acquired under subsection (a) as are necessary to remediate contamination from PFOA and PFOS related to activities at the Air Force base.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading><content>Funds for the land acquisitions authorized under subsection (a) shall be derived from amounts authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 2020 for military construction or the unobligated balances of appropriations for military construction that are enacted after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority under this section constitutes authority to carry out land acquisitions for purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2802">section 2802 of title 10</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="345">“SEC. 345.</num><heading> REMEDIATION PLAN.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a remediation plan for cleanup of all water at or adjacent to a military installation that is contaminated with PFOA or PFOS.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study</inline>.—</heading><content>In preparing the remediation plan under subsection (a), the Secretary shall conduct a study on the contamination of water at military installations with PFOA or PFOS.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Budget Amount</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall ensure that each budget of the President submitted to Congress under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105/a">section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, United States Code, requests funding in amounts necessary to address remediation efforts under the remediation plan submitted under subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c05149-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plan, Funding Documents, and Management Review Relating to Explosive Ordnance Disposal</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tIII/s343">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title III, § 343</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2082">130 Stat. 2082</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tIII/s343">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Plan Required.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall develop a plan to establish an explosive ordnance disposal program in the Department of Defense to ensure close and continuous coordination among the military departments on matters relating to explosive ordnance disposal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Roles, responsibilities, and authorities</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The plan under paragraph (1) shall include provisions under which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> the Secretary of Defense shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> assign responsibility for the coordination and integration of explosive ordnance disposal to a joint office or entity in the Office of the Secretary of Defense; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> designate the Secretary of the Navy (or a designee of the Secretary of the Navy) as the executive agent for the Department of Defense to coordinate and integrate research, development, test, and evaluation activities and procurement activities of the military departments relating to explosive ordnance disposal; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Secretary of each military department shall assess the needs of the military department concerned with respect to explosive ordnance disposal and may carry out research, development, test, and evaluation activities and procurement activities to address such needs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Explosive Ordnance Disposal Funding Documents.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress, as a part of the defense budget materials for each fiscal year after fiscal year 2017, a consolidated funding display, in classified and unclassified form, that identifies the funding source for all explosive ordnance disposal activities within the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The funding display under paragraph (1) for a fiscal year shall include a single program element from each military department for each of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Research, development, test, and evaluation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Procurement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Operation and maintenance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Any other program element used to fund explosive ordnance disposal activities (but not including any program element relating to military construction).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Management Review and Assessment.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall review and assess the effectiveness of current management structures in supporting the explosive ordnance disposal needs of the combatant commands and the military departments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The review and assessment under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> A review of the organizational structures and responsibilities within the Office of the Secretary of Defense that provide policy and oversight of the policies, programs, acquisition activities, and personnel of the military departments relating to explosive ordnance disposal.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> A review of the organizational structures and responsibilities within the military departments that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> man, equip, and train explosive ordnance disposal forces; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> support such forces with manpower, technology, equipment, and readiness.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> A review of the organizational structures and responsibilities of the Secretary of the Navy as the executive agent for explosive ordnance disposal technology and training.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Budget displays for each military department that support research, development, test, and evaluation; procurement; and operation and maintenance, relating to explosive ordnance disposal.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> An assessment of the adequacy of the organizational structures and responsibilities and the alignment of funding within the military departments in supporting the needs of the combatant commands and the military departments with respect to explosive ordnance disposal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefing</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than <date date="2017-03-01">March 1, 2017</date>, the Secretary shall provide to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a briefing that includes—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> details of the plan required under subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the results of the review and assessment under subsection (c);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> a description of any measures undertaken to improve joint coordination, oversight, and management of programs relating to explosive ordnance disposal;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> recommendations to the Secretary to improve the capabilities and readiness of explosive ordnance disposal forces; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> an explanation of the advantages and disadvantages of assigning responsibility for the coordination and integration of explosive ordnance disposal to a single joint office or entity in the Office of the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Explosive ordnance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘explosive ordnance’ means any munition containing explosives, nuclear fission or fusion materials, or biological or chemical agents, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> bombs and warheads;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> guided and ballistic missiles;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> artillery, mortar, rocket, and small arms munitions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> mines, torpedoes, and depth charges;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> demolition charges;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> pyrotechnics;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> clusters and dispensers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> cartridge and propellant actuated devices;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> electro-explosive devices; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="J">“(J)</num><content> clandestine and improvised explosive devices.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Disposal</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘disposal’ means, with respect to explosive ordnance, the detection, identification, field evaluation, defeat, disablement, or rendering safe, recovery and exploitation, and final disposition of the ordnance.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c0514a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prohibition on Disposing of Waste in Open-Air Burn Pits</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/84/dA/tIII/s317">Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title III, § 317</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2249">123 Stat. 2249</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/dA/tIII/s316">Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 316</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1358">125 Stat. 1358</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tIII/s314">Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title III, § 314</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/729">127 Stat. 729</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tX/s1071/g/1">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3511">128 Stat. 3511</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tIII/s316">Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title III, § 316</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1630">135 Stat. 1630</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tIII/s316">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations prohibiting the disposal of covered waste in open-air burn pits during contingency operations except in circumstances in which the Secretary determines that no alternative disposal method is feasible. Such regulations shall apply to contingency operations that are ongoing as of the date of the enactment of this Act, including Operation Iraqi Freedom and Operation Enduring Freedom, and to contingency operations that begin after the date of the enactment of this Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In determining that no alternative disposal method is feasible for an open-air burn pit pursuant to regulations prescribed under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> not later than 30 days after such determination is made, submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives notice of such determination, including the circumstances, reasoning, and methodology that led to such determination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> after notice is given under subparagraph (A), for each subsequent 180-day-period during which covered waste is disposed of in the open-air burn pit covered by such notice, submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives the justifications of the Secretary for continuing to operate such open-air burn pit.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exemption authority for certain locations.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may exempt a location from the prohibition under paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines it is in the paramount interest of the United States to do so.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Nondelegation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may not delegate the authority under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reporting requirement for location exemptions.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 30 days after granting an exemption pursuant to paragraph (3)(A) with respect to the use of an open-air burn pit at a location, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a written report that identifies—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the location of the open-air burn pit;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the number of personnel of the United States assigned to the location where the open-air burn pit is being used;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> the size and expected duration of use of the open-air burn pit;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> the personal protective equipment or other health risk mitigation efforts that will be used by members of the armed forces when airborne hazards are present, including how such equipment will be provided when required; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="v">“(v)</num><content> the need for the open-air burn pit and rationale for granting the exemption.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Form</inline>.—</heading><content>A report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>], the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives a report on the use of open-air burn pits by the United States Armed Forces. Such report shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> an explanation of the situations and circumstances under which open-air burn pits are used to dispose of waste during military exercises and operations worldwide;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> a detailed description of the types of waste authorized to be burned in open-air burn pits;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> a plan through which the Secretary intends to develop and implement alternatives to the use of open-air burn pits;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> a copy of the regulations required to be prescribed by subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> the health and environmental compliance standards the Secretary has established for military and contractor operations in Iraq and Afghanistan with regard to solid waste disposal, including an assessment of whether those standards are being met;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> a description of the environmental, health, and operational impacts of open-pit burning of plastics and the feasibility of including plastics in the regulations prescribed pursuant to subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> an assessment of the ability of existing medical surveillance programs to identify and track exposures to toxic substances that result from open-air burn pits, including recommendations for such changes to such programs as would be required to more accurately identify and track such exposures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Health Assessment Reports</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after notice is due under subsection (a)(2), the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives a health assessment report on each open-air burn pit at a location where at least 100 personnel have been employed for 90 consecutive days or more. Each such report shall include each of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> An epidemiological description of the short-term and long-term health risks posed to personnel in the area where the burn pit is located because of exposure to the open-air burn pit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> A copy of the methodology used to determine the health risks described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> A copy of the assessment of the operational risks and health risks when making the determination pursuant to subsection (a) that no alternative disposal method is feasible for the open-air burn pit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The term ‘contingency operation’ has the meaning given that term by <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101/a/13">section 101(a)(13) of title 10</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> The term ‘covered waste’ includes—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> hazardous waste, as defined by section 1004(5) of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6903/5">42 U.S.C. 6903(5)</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> medical waste;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> tires;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> treated wood;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> batteries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> plastics, except insignificant amounts of plastic remaining after a good-faith effort to remove or recover plastic materials from the solid waste stream;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> munitions and explosives, except when disposed of in compliance with guidance on the destruction of munitions and explosives contained in the Department of Defense Ammunition and Explosives Safety Standards, DoD Manual 6055.09-M;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> compressed gas cylinders, unless empty with valves removed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> fuel containers, unless completely evacuated of its contents;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="J">“(J)</num><content> aerosol cans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="K">“(K)</num><content> polychlorinated biphenyls;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="L">“(L)</num><content> petroleum, oils, and lubricants products (other than waste fuel for initial combustion);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="M">“(M)</num><content> asbestos;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="N">“(N)</num><content> mercury;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="O">“(O)</num><content> foam tent material;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="P">“(P)</num><content> any item containing any of the materials referred to in a preceding paragraph; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="Q">“(Q)</num><content> other waste as designated by the Secretary.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c0514b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Purpose of <ref href="/us/pl/109/284">Pub. L. 109–284</ref></heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/284/s1">Pub. L. 109–284, § 1</ref>, <date date="2006-09-27">Sept. 27, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/1211">120 Stat. 1211</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/284/s1">“The purpose of this Act [amending this section, sections 107 and 210 of Title 23, Highways, <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1499">section 1499 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure, sections 2301, 20908, 40103, 70912, 150511, 151303, 153513, 220104, 220501, 220505, 220506, 220509, 220511, 220512, and 220521 of Title 36, Patriotic and National Observances, Ceremonies, and Organizations, and sections 522, 552, 554, 581, 593, 611, 3131, 3133, 3141, 3142, 3701, 3702, 3704, 6111, 8104, 8105, 8501, 8502, 8711, 8712, 8722, 9302, 14308, and 17504 of Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works] is to make technical corrections to the United States Code relating to cross references, typographical errors, and stylistic matters.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c0514c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Formerly Utilized Sites Remedial Action Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dC/tXXXI/s3138">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [div. C, title XXXI, § 3138]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–461, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dC/tXXXI/s3138">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contingent Limitation on Availability of Funds for Certain Travel Expenses</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Effective <date date="2001-11-01">November 1, 2001</date>, but subject to subsection (b), no funds authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available by this or any other Act for the Department of Energy or the Department of the Army may be obligated or expended for travel by—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the Secretary of Energy or any officer or employee of the Office of the Secretary of Energy; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Chief of Engineers.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effective Date</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The limitation in subsection (a) shall not take effect if before <date date="2001-11-01">November 1, 2001</date>, both of the following certifications are submitted to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives]:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> A certification by the Secretary of Energy that the Department of Energy is in compliance with the requirements of section 3131 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2000 (<ref href="/us/pl/106/65">Public Law 106–65</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/113/925">113 Stat. 925</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2701">10 U.S.C. 2701</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> A certification by the Chief of Engineers that the Corps of Engineers is in compliance with the requirements of that section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading><content>If the limitation in subsection (a) takes effect, the limitation shall cease to be in effect when both certifications referred to in subsection (b) have been submitted to the congressional defense committees.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dC/tXXXI/s3131">Pub. L. 106–65, div. C, title XXXI, § 3131</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/925">113 Stat. 925</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/65/dC/tXXXI/s3131">“Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no funds authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available by this Act [see Tables for classification], or by any Act authorizing appropriations for the military activities of the Department of Defense or the defense activities of the Department of Energy for a fiscal year after fiscal year 2000, may be obligated or expended to conduct treatment, storage, or disposal activities at any site designated as a site under the Formerly Utilized Site Remedial Action Program as of the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/106/60/tVI/s611">Pub. L. 106–60, title VI, § 611</ref>, <date date="1999-09-29">Sept. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/502">113 Stat. 502</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/60/tVI/s611">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, in carrying out the program known as the Formerly Utilized Sites Remedial Action Program, shall undertake the following functions and activities to be performed at eligible sites where remediation has not been completed:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Sampling and assessment of contaminated areas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Characterization of site conditions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Determination of the nature and extent of contamination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Selection of the necessary and appropriate response actions as the lead Federal agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Cleanup and closeout of sites.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> Any other functions and activities determined by the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, as necessary for carrying out that program, including the acquisition of real estate interests where necessary, which may be transferred upon completion of remediation to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of Energy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> Any response action under that program by the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, shall be subject to the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9601">42 U.S.C. 9601</ref> et seq.) (in this section referred to as ‘CERCLA’), and the National Oil and Hazardous Substances Pollution Contingency Plan (40 CFR 300).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> Any sums recovered under CERCLA or other authority from a liable party, contractor, insurer, surety, or other person for any expenditures by the Army Corps of Engineers or the Department of Energy for response actions under that program shall be credited to the amounts made available to carry out that program and shall be available until expended for costs of response actions for any eligible site.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><content> The Secretary of Energy may exercise the authority under section 168 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2208">42 U.S.C. 2208</ref>) to make payments in lieu of taxes for federally owned property at which activities under that program are carried out, regardless of which Federal agency has administrative jurisdiction over the property and notwithstanding any reference to ‘the activities of the Commission’ in that section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><content> This section does not alter, curtail, or limit the authorities, functions, or responsibilities of other agencies under CERCLA or, except as stated in this section, under the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2011">42 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><content> This section shall apply to fiscal year 2000 and each succeeding fiscal year.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c0514d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Settlement of Claims of Foreign Governments for Environmental Cleanup of Overseas Sites Formerly Used by Department of Defense</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/261/dA/tIII/s321">Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title III, § 321</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1962">112 Stat. 1962</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/261/dA/tIII/s321">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice of Negotiations</inline>.—</heading><content>The President shall notify Congress before entering into any negotiations for the ex-gratia settlement of the claims of a government of another country against the United States for environmental cleanup of sites in that country that were formerly used by the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization Required for Use of Funds for Payment of Settlement</inline>.—</heading><content>No funds may be used for any payment under an ex-gratia settlement of any claims described in subsection (a) unless the use of the funds for that purpose is specifically authorized by law or international agreement, including a treaty.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c0514e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Recovery and Sharing of Costs of Environmental Restoration at Department of Defense Sites</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tIII/s348">Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title III, § 348</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1689">111 Stat. 1689</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tIII/s348">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="1998-03-01">March 1, 1998</date>, the Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations containing the guidelines and requirements described in subsections (b) and (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guidelines</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The regulations prescribed under subsection (a) shall contain uniform guidelines for the military departments and defense agencies concerning the cost-recovery and cost-sharing activities of those departments and agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall take appropriate actions to ensure the implementation of the guidelines.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The regulations prescribed under subsection (a) shall contain requirements for the Secretaries of the military departments and the heads of defense agencies to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> obtain all data that is relevant for purposes of cost-recovery and cost-sharing activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> identify any negligence or other misconduct that may preclude indemnification or reimbursement by the Department of Defense for the costs of environmental restoration at a Department site or justify the recovery or sharing of costs associated with such restoration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term ‘cost-recovery and cost-sharing activities’ means activities concerning—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the recovery of the costs of environmental restoration at Department of Defense sites from contractors of the Department and other private parties that contribute to environmental contamination at such sites; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the sharing of the costs of such restoration with such contractors and parties.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c0514f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pilot Program for Sale of Air Pollution Emission Reduction Incentives</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tIII/s316/b">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title III, § 316(b)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1053">115 Stat. 1053</ref>, directed the Secretary of Defense to prepare a report concerning the operation of the pilot program for the sale of economic incentives for the reduction of emission of air pollutants attributable to military facilities, as authorized by <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s351">section 351 of Pub. L. 105–85</ref>, formerly set out below, and to submit the report to the Congress not later than <date date="2003-03-01">Mar. 1, 2003</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tIII/s351">Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title III, § 351</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1692">111 Stat. 1692</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tIII/s325">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title III, § 325</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/563">113 Stat. 563</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tIII/s316/a">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title III, § 316(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1053">115 Stat. 1053</ref>, authorized the Secretary of Defense, until <date date="2003-09-30">Sept. 30, 2003</date>, to carry out a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of the sale of economic incentives for the reduction of emission of air pollutants attributable to a facility of a military department.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c05150-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Authority To Develop and Implement Land Use Plans for Defense Environmental Restoration Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tIII/s325">Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title III, § 325</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2481">110 Stat. 2481</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tIII/s325">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense may, to the extent possible and practical, develop and implement, as part of the Defense Environmental Restoration Program provided for in chapter 160 of title 10, United States Code, a land use plan for any defense site selected by the Secretary under subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Selection of Sites</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may select up to 10 defense sites, from among sites where the Secretary is planning or implementing environmental restoration activities, for which land use plans may be developed under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement To Consult With Review Committee or Advisory Board</inline>.—</heading><content>In developing a land use plan under this section, the Secretary shall consult with a technical review committee established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2705/c">section 2705(c) of title 10</ref>, United States Code, a restoration advisory board established pursuant to section 2705(d) of such title, a local land use redevelopment authority, or another appropriate State agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> 50-<inline class="small-caps">Year Planning Period</inline>.—</heading><content>A land use plan developed under this section shall cover a period of at least 50 years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading><content>For each defense site for which the Secretary develops a land use plan under this section, the Secretary shall take into account the land use plan in selecting and implementing, in accordance with applicable law, environmental restoration activities at the site.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deadlines</inline>.—</heading><content>For each defense site for which the Secretary intends to develop a land use plan under this section, the Secretary shall develop a draft land use plan by <date date="1997-10-01">October 1, 1997</date>, and a final land use plan by <date date="1998-03-15">March 15, 1998</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition of Defense Site</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this section, the term ‘defense site’ means (A) any building, structure, installation, equipment, pipe or pipeline (including any pipe into a sewer or publicly owned treatment works), well, pit, pond, lagoon, impoundment, ditch, landfill, storage container, motor vehicle, rolling stock, or aircraft under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense, or (B) any site or area under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense where a hazardous substance has been deposited, stored, disposed of, or placed, or otherwise come to be located; but does not include any consumer product in consumer use or any vessel.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>In the annual report required under [former] <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2706/a">section 2706(a) of title 10</ref>, United States Code, the Secretary shall include information on the land use plans developed under this section and the effect such plans have had on environmental restoration activities at the defense sites where they have been implemented. The annual report submitted in 1999 shall include recommendations on whether such land use plans should be developed and implemented throughout the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Savings Provisions</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Nothing in this section, or in a land use plan developed under this section with respect to a defense site, shall be construed as requiring any modification to a land use plan that was developed before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Nothing in this section may be construed to affect statutory requirements for an environmental restoration or waste management activity or project or to modify or otherwise affect applicable statutory or regulatory environmental restoration and waste management requirements, including substantive standards intended to protect public health and the environment, nor shall anything in this section be construed to preempt or impair any local land use planning or zoning authority or State authority.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c05151-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Fiscal Year 1996 Restrictions on Reimbursements Under Agreements for Services of Other Agencies</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tIII/s321/a/2">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title III, § 321(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/251">110 Stat. 251</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tX/s1073/d/1/A">Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(d)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1905">111 Stat. 1905</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tX/s1073/d/1/A">
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the total amount of funds available for reimbursements under agreements entered into under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2701/d">section 2701(d) of title 10</ref>, United States Code, as amended by paragraph (1), in fiscal year 1996 may not exceed $10,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may pay in fiscal year 1996 an amount for reimbursements under agreements referred to in subparagraph (A) in excess of the amount specified in that subparagraph for that fiscal year if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the Secretary certifies to Congress that the payment of the amount under this subparagraph is essential for the management of the Defense Environmental Restoration Program under chapter 160 of title 10, United States Code; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> a period of 60 days has expired after the date on which the certification is received by Congress.”</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c05152-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Environmental Education and Training Program for Defense Personnel</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tIII/s328">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title III, § 328</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2714">108 Stat. 2714</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tIII/s328">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish and conduct an education and training program for members of the Armed Forces and civilian employees of the Department of Defense whose responsibilities include planning or executing the environmental mission of the Department. The Secretary shall conduct the program to ensure that such members and employees obtain and maintain the knowledge and skill required to comply with existing environmental laws and regulations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Identification of Military Facilities With Environmental Training Expertise</inline>.—</heading><content>As part of the program, the Secretary may identify military facilities that have existing expertise (or the capacity to develop such expertise) in conducting education and training activities in various environmental disciplines. In the case of a military facility identified under this subsection, the Secretary should encourage the use of the facility by members and employees referred to in subsection (a) who are not under the jurisdiction of the military department operating the facility.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c05153-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Grants to Institutions of Higher Education To Provide Education and Training in Environmental Restoration to Dislocated Defense Workers and Young Adults</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tXIII/s1333">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XIII, § 1333</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1798">107 Stat. 1798</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tX/s1070/b/11">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title X, § 1070(b)(11)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2857">108 Stat. 2857</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/244/tI/s102/a/2/D">Pub. L. 105–244, title I, § 102(a)(2)(D)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-07">Oct. 7, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1617">112 Stat. 1617</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dA/s101/f/tVIII/s405/d/8">Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(d)(8), (f)(7)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-337">112 Stat. 2681–337</ref>, 2681–420, 2681–430; <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tX/s1056/a/2">Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1056(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3438">119 Stat. 3438</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tX/s1056/a/2">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Grant Program Authorized</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense may establish a program to provide demonstration grants to institutions of higher education to assist such institutions in providing education and training in environmental restoration and hazardous waste management to eligible dislocated defense workers and young adults described in subsection (d). The Secretary shall award the grants pursuant to a merit-based selection process.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> A grant provided under this subsection may cover a period of not more than three fiscal years, except that the payments under the grant for the second and third fiscal year shall be subject to the approval of the Secretary and to the availability of appropriations to carry out this section in that fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Application</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>To be eligible for a grant under subsection (a), an institution of higher education shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such form, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. The application shall include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> An assurance by the institution of higher education that it will use the grant to supplement and not supplant non-Federal funds that would otherwise be available for the education and training activities funded by the grant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> A proposal by the institution of higher education to provide expertise, training, and education in hazardous materials and waste management and other environmental fields applicable to defense manufacturing sites and Department of Defense and Department of Energy defense facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Grant Funds</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An institution of higher education receiving a grant under subsection (a) shall use the grant to establish a consortium consisting of the institution and one or more of each of the entities described in paragraph (2) for the purpose of establishing and conducting a program to provide education and training in environmental restoration and waste management to eligible individuals described in subsection (d). To the extent practicable, the Secretary shall authorize the consortium to use a military installation closed or selected to be closed under a base closure law in providing on-site basic skills training to participants in the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> The entities referred to in paragraph (1) are the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Appropriate State and local agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> local [sic] workforce investment boards established under [former] section 117 of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 [former <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s2832">29 U.S.C. 2832</ref>].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Community-based organizations (as defined in section 4(5) of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1503/5">29 U.S.C. 1503(5)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Businesses.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> Organized labor.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> Other appropriate educational institutions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible Individuals</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A program established or conducted using funds provided under subsection (a) may provide education and training in environmental restoration and waste management to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> individuals who have been terminated or laid off from employment (or have received notice of termination or lay off) as a consequence of reductions in expenditures by the United States for defense, the cancellation, termination, or completion of a defense contract, or the closure or realignment of a military installation under a base closure law, as determined in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> individuals who have attained the age of 16 but not the age of 25.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements of Education and Training Program</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In establishing or conducting an education and training program using funds provided under subsection (a), the institution of higher education shall meet the following requirements:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> The institution of higher education shall establish and provide a work-based learning system consisting of education and training in environmental restoration—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> which may include basic educational courses, on-site basic skills training, and mentor assistance to individuals described in subsection (d) who are participating in the program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> which may lead to the awarding of a certificate or degree at the institution of higher education.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The institution of higher education shall undertake outreach and recruitment efforts to encourage participation by eligible individuals in the education and training program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The institution of higher education shall select participants for the education and training program from among eligible individuals described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><chapeau> To the extent practicable, in the selection of young adults described in subsection (d)(2) to participate in the education and training program, the institution of higher education shall give priority to those young adults who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> have not attended and are otherwise unlikely to be able to attend an institution of higher education; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> have, or are members of families who have, received a total family income that, in relation to family size, is not in excess of the higher of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the official poverty line (as defined by the Office of Management and Budget, and revised annually in accordance with section 673(2) of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1981 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9902/2">42 U.S.C. 9902(2)</ref>)); or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> 70 percent of the lower living standard income level.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> To the extent practicable, the institution of higher education shall select instructors for the education and training program from institutions of higher education, appropriate community programs, and industry and labor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> To the extent practicable, the institution of higher education shall consult with appropriate Federal, State, and local agencies carrying out environmental restoration programs for the purpose of achieving coordination between such programs and the education and training program conducted by the consortium.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Selection of Grant Recipients</inline>.—</heading><content>To the extent practicable, the Secretary shall provide grants to institutions of higher education under subsection (a) in a manner which will equitably distribute such grants among the various regions of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Amount of Grant to a Single Recipient</inline>.—</heading><content>The amount of a grant under subsection (a) that may be made to a single institution of higher education in a fiscal year may not exceed ⅓ of the amount made available to provide grants under such subsection for that fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reporting Requirements</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary may provide a grant to an institution of higher education under subsection (a) only if the institution agrees to submit to the Secretary, in each fiscal year in which the Secretary makes payments under the grant to the institution, a report containing—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a description and evaluation of the education and training program established by the consortium formed by the institution under subsection (c); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> such other information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>], the Secretary shall submit to the President and Congress an interim report containing—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a compilation of the information contained in the reports received by the Secretary from each institution of higher education under paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> an evaluation of the effectiveness of the demonstration grant program authorized by this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> Not later than <date date="1997-01-01">January 1, 1997</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the President and Congress a final report containing—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a compilation of the information described in the interim report; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a final evaluation of the effectiveness of the demonstration grant program authorized by this section, including a recommendation as to the feasibility of continuing the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Base closure law</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘base closure law’ has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101/a/17">section 101(a)(17) of title 10</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Environmental restoration</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘environmental restoration’ means actions taken consistent with a permanent remedy to prevent or minimize the release of hazardous substances into the environment so that such substances do not migrate to cause substantial danger to present or future public health or welfare or the environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Institution of higher education</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘institution of higher education’ has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 [<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</ref>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Secretary’ means the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="j">“(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Conforming Repeal</inline>.—</heading><content>Section 4452 of the Defense Conversion, Reinvestment, and Transition Assistance Act of 1992 (division D of <ref href="/us/pl/102/484">Public Law 102–484</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2701">10 U.S.C. 2701</ref> note) is repealed.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c05154-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Environmental Education Opportunities Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tXIII/s1334">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XIII, § 1334</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1801">107 Stat. 1801</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/244/tI/s102/a/2/E">Pub. L. 105–244, title I, § 102(a)(2)(E)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-07">Oct. 7, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1617">112 Stat. 1617</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/244/tI/s102/a/2/E">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, may establish a scholarship program in order to enable eligible individuals described in subsection (d) to undertake the educational training or activities relating to environmental engineering, environmental sciences, or environmental project management in fields related to hazardous waste management and cleanup described in subsection (b) at the institutions of higher education described in subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Educational Training or Activities</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The program established under subsection (a) shall be limited to educational training or activities related to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> site remediation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> site characterization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> hazardous waste management;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> hazardous waste reduction;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> recycling;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> process and materials engineering;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> training for positions related to environmental engineering, environmental sciences, or environmental project management (including training for management positions); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> environmental engineering with respect to the construction of facilities to address the items described in subparagraphs (A) through (G).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> The program established under subsection (a) shall be limited to educational training or activities designed to enable individuals to achieve specialization in the following fields:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Earth sciences.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Chemistry.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Chemical Engineering.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Environmental engineering.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> Statistics.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> Toxicology.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> Industrial hygiene.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> Health physics.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> Environmental project management.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible Institutions of Higher Education</inline>.—</heading><content>Scholarship funds awarded under this section shall be used by individuals awarded scholarships to enable such individuals to attend institutions of higher education associated with hazardous substance research centers to enable such individuals to undertake a program of educational training or activities described in subsection (b) that leads to an undergraduate degree, a graduate degree, or a degree or certificate that is supplemental to an academic degree.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible Individuals</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Individuals eligible for scholarships under the program established under subsection (a) are the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> Any member of the Armed Forces who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> was on active duty or full-time National Guard duty on <date date="1990-09-30">September 30, 1990</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> during the 5-year period beginning on that date—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> is involuntarily separated (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1141">section 1141 of title 10</ref>, United States Code) from active duty or full-time National Guard duty; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> is separated from active duty or full-time National Guard duty pursuant to a special separation benefits program under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1174a">section 1174a of title 10</ref>, United States Code, or the voluntary separation incentive program under section 1175 of that title; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> is not entitled to retired or retainer pay incident to that separation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> Any civilian employee of the Department of Energy or the Department of Defense (other than an employee referred to in paragraph (3)) who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> is terminated or laid off from such employment during the five-year period beginning on <date date="1990-09-30">September 30, 1990</date>, as a result of reductions in defense-related spending (as determined by the appropriate Secretary); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> is not entitled to retired or retainer pay incident to that termination or lay off.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Any civilian employee of the Department of Defense whose employment at a military installation approved for closure or realignment under a base closure law is terminated as a result of such closure or realignment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Award of Scholarship</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall award scholarships under this section to such eligible individuals as the Secretary determines appropriate pursuant to regulations or policies promulgated by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> In awarding a scholarship under this section, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> take into consideration the extent to which the qualifications and experience of the individual applying for the scholarship prepared such individual for the educational training or activities to be undertaken; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> award a scholarship only to an eligible individual who has been accepted for enrollment in the institution of higher education described in subsection (c) and providing the educational training or activities for which the scholarship assistance is sought.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall determine the amount of the scholarships awarded under this section, except that the amount of scholarship assistance awarded to any individual under this section may not exceed—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> $10,000 in any 12-month period; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a total of $20,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Application; Period for Submission</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Each individual desiring a scholarship under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary of Defense in such manner and containing or accompanied by such information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> A member of the Armed Forces described in subsection (d)(1) who desires to apply for a scholarship under this section shall submit an application under this subsection not later than 180 days after the date of the separation of the member. In the case of members described in subsection (d)(1) who were separated before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>], the Secretary shall accept applications from these members submitted during the 180-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> A civilian employee described in paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (d) who desires to apply for a scholarship under this section, but who receives no prior notice of such termination or lay off, may submit an application under this subsection at any time after such termination or lay off. A civilian employee described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (d) who receives a notice of termination or lay off shall submit an application not later than 180 days before the effective date of the termination or lay off. In the case of employees described in such paragraphs who were terminated or laid off before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>], the Secretary shall accept applications from these employees submitted during the 180-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Repayment</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any individual receiving scholarship assistance from the Secretary of Defense under this section shall enter into an agreement with the Secretary under which the individual agrees to pay to the United States the total amount of the scholarship assistance provided to the individual by the Secretary under this section, plus interest at the rate prescribed in paragraph (4), if the individual does not complete the educational training or activities for which such assistance is provided.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> If an individual fails to pay to the United States the total amount required pursuant to paragraph (1), including the interest, at the rate prescribed in paragraph (4), the unpaid amount shall be recoverable by the United States from the individual or such individual’s estate by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> in the case of an individual who is an employee of the United States, set off against accrued pay, compensation, amount of retirement credit, or other amount due the employee from the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> such other method as is provided by law for the recovery of amounts owing to the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense may waive in whole or in part a required repayment under this subsection if the Secretary determines that the recovery would be against equity and good conscience or would be contrary to the best interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The total amount of scholarship assistance provided to an individual under this section, for purposes of repayment under this subsection, shall bear interest at the applicable rate of interest under section 427A(c) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1077a/c">20 U.S.C. 1077a(c)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coordination of Benefits</inline>.—</heading><content>Any scholarship assistance provided to an individual under this section shall be taken into account in determining the eligibility of the individual for Federal student financial assistance provided under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070">20 U.S.C. 1070</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="1995-01-01">January 1, 1995</date>, the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall submit to the Congress a report describing the activities undertaken under the program authorized by subsection (a) and containing recommendations for future activities under the program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="j">“(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> To carry out the scholarship program authorized by subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense may use the unobligated balance of funds made available pursuant to section 4451(k) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1993 (<ref href="/us/pl/102/484">Public Law 102–484</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2701">10 U.S.C. 2701</ref> note) for fiscal year 1993 for environmental scholarship and fellowship programs for the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The cost of carrying out the program authorized by subsection (a) may not exceed $8,000,000 in any fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="k">“(k)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> The term ‘base closure law’ means the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Title II of the Defense Authorization Amendments and Base Closure and Realignment Act (<ref href="/us/pl/100/526">Public Law 100–526</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2687">10 U.S.C. 2687</ref> note).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 (part A of title XXIX of <ref href="/us/pl/101/510">Public Law 101–510</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2687">10 U.S.C. 2687</ref> note).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘hazardous substance research centers’ means the hazardous substance research centers described in section 311(d) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9660/d">42 U.S.C. 9660(d)</ref>). Such term includes the Great Plains and Rocky Mountain Hazardous Substance Research Center, the Northeast Hazardous Substance Research Center, the Great Lakes and Mid-Atlantic Hazardous Substance Research Center, the South and Southwest Hazardous Substance Research Center, and the Western Region Hazardous Substance Research Center.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The term ‘institution of higher education’ has the same meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 [<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</ref>].”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c2c255-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Training and Employment of Department of Defense Employees To Carry Out Environmental Restoration at Military Installations To Be Closed</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tXIII/s1335">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XIII, § 1335</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1804">107 Stat. 1804</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tXIII/s1335">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Training Program</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense may establish a program to provide such training to eligible civilian employees of the Department of Defense as the Secretary considers to be necessary to qualify such employees to carry out environmental assessment, remediation, and restoration activities (including asbestos abatement) at military installations closed or to be closed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Employment of Graduates</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In the case of eligible civilian employees of the Department of Defense who successfully complete the training program established pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> employ such employees to carry out environmental assessment, remediation, and restoration activities at military installations referred to in subsection (a); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> require, as a condition of a contract for the private performance of such activities at such an installation, the contractor to be engaged in carrying out such activities to employ such employees.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible Employees</inline>.—</heading><content>Eligibility for selection to participate in the training program under subsection (a) shall be limited to those civilian employees of the Department of Defense whose employment would be terminated by reason of the closure of a military installation if not for the selection of the employees to participate in the training program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Priority in Training and Employment</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall give priority in providing training and employment under this section to eligible civilian employees employed at a military installation the closure of which will directly result in the termination of the employment of at least 1,000 civilian employees of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effect on Other Environmental Requirements</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to revise or modify any requirement established under Federal or State law relating to environmental assessment, remediation, or restoration activities at military installations closed or to be closed.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c2c256-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Cooperative Agreements and Grants To Implement Legacy Resource Management Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/139/tII">Pub. L. 103–139, title II</ref>, <date date="1993-11-11">Nov. 11, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1422">107 Stat. 1422</ref>, provided in part: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/139/tII">“That notwithstanding the provisions of the Federal Cooperative Grant and Agreement Act of 1977 (<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s6303–630">31 U.S.C. 6303–630</ref>8), the Department of Defense may hereafter negotiate and enter into cooperative agreements and grants with public and private agencies, organizations, institutions, individuals or other entities to implement the purposes of the Legacy Resource Management Program”.</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c2c257-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pilot Program for Expedited Environmental Response Actions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dA/tIII/s323">Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title III, § 323</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2365">106 Stat. 2365</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/484/dA/tIII/s323">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a pilot program to expedite the performance of on-site environmental restoration at—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> military installations scheduled for closure under title II of the Defense Authorization Amendments and Base Closure and Realignment Act (<ref href="/us/pl/100/526">Public Law 100–526</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2687">10 U.S.C. 2687</ref> note);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> military installations scheduled for closure under the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 (part A of title XXIX of <ref href="/us/pl/101/510">Public Law 101–510</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2687">10 U.S.C. 2687</ref> note); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> facilities for which the Secretary is responsible under the Defense Environmental Restoration Program established under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2701">section 2701 of title 10</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Selection of Installations and Facilities</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> For participation in the pilot program, the Secretary shall select—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> 2 military installations referred to in subsection (a)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> 4 military installations referred to in subsection (a)(2), consisting of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> 2 military installations scheduled for closure as of the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>]; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> 2 military installations included in the list transmitted by the Secretary no later than <date date="1993-04-15">April 15, 1993</date>, pursuant to section 2903(c)(1) of the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 [<ref href="/us/pl/101/510">Pub. L. 101–510</ref>] (<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2687">10 U.S.C. 2687</ref> note) and recommended in a report transmitted by the President in that year pursuant to section 2903(e) of such Act and for which a joint resolution disapproving such recommendations is not enacted by the deadline set forth in section 2904(b) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2687">10 U.S.C. 2687</ref> note]; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> not less than 4 facilities referred to in subsection (a)(3) with respect to each military department.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the selections under paragraph (1) shall be made not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The selections under paragraph (1) of military installations described in subparagraph (B)(ii) of such paragraph shall be made not later than 60 days after the date on which the deadline (set forth in section 2904(b) of such Act) for enacting a joint resolution of disapproval with respect to the report transmitted by the President has passed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> The installations and facilities selected under paragraph (1) shall be representative of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a variety of the environmental restoration activities required for facilities under the Defense Environmental Restoration Program and for military installations scheduled for closure under the Defense Authorization Amendments and Base Closure and Realignment Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2687">10 U.S.C. 2687</ref> note) [see Short Title of 1988 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2687">10 U.S.C. 2687</ref>] and the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 (<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2687">10 U.S.C. 2687</ref> note); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the different sizes of such environmental restoration activities to provide, to the maximum extent practicable, opportunities for the full range of business sizes to enter into environmental restoration contracts with the Department of Defense and with prime contractors to perform activities under the pilot program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Execution of Program</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Subject to subsection (d), and to the maximum extent possible, the Secretary shall, in order to eliminate redundant tasks and to accelerate environmental restoration at military installations, use the authorities granted in existing law to carry out the pilot program, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the development and use of innovative contracting techniques;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the use of all reasonable and appropriate methods to expedite necessary Federal and State administrative decisions, agreements, and concur­rences; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the use (including any necessary request for the use) of existing authorities to ensure that environmental restoration activities under the pilot program are conducted expeditiously, with particular emphasis on activities that may be conducted in advance of any final plan for environmental restoration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program Principles</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program consistent with the following principles:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Activities of the pilot program shall be carried out subject to and in accordance with all applicable Federal and State laws and regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Competitive procedures shall be used to select the contractors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The experience and ability of the contractors shall be considered, in addition to cost, as a factor to be evaluated in the selection of the contractors.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program Restrictions</inline>.—</heading><content>The pilot program established in this section shall not result in the delay of environmental restoration activities at other military installations and former sites of the Department of Defense.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c2c258-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Overseas Environmental Restoration</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dA/tIII/s324">Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title III, § 324</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2367">106 Stat. 2367</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tX/s1031/d/1">Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1604">117 Stat. 1604</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tX/s1031/d/1">
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“It is the sense of the Congress that in carrying out environmental restoration activities at military installations outside the United States, the President should seek to obtain an equitable division of the costs of environmental restoration with the nation in which the installation is located.”</p>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c2c259-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Environmental Scholarship and Fellowship Programs for Department of Defense</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dD/tXLIV/s4451">Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLIV, § 4451</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2735">106 Stat. 2735</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/244/tI/s102/a/2/F">Pub. L. 105–244, title I, § 102(a)(2)(F)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-07">Oct. 7, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1617">112 Stat. 1617</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/244/tI/s102/a/2/F">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense (hereinafter in this section referred to as the ‘Secretary’) may conduct scholarship and fellowship programs for the purpose of enabling individuals to qualify for employment in the field of environmental restoration or other environmental programs in the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligibility</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>To be eligible to participate in the scholarship or fellowship program, an individual must—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> be accepted for enrollment or be currently enrolled as a full-time student at an institution of higher education (as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 [<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</ref>]);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> be pursuing a program of education that leads to an appropriate higher education degree in engineering, biology, chemistry, or another qualifying field related to environmental activities, as determined by the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> sign an agreement described in subsection (c);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> be a citizen or national of the United States or be an alien lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> meet any other requirements prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Agreement</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An agreement between the Secretary and an individual participating in a scholarship or fellowship established in subsection (a) shall be in writing, shall be signed by the individual, and shall include the following provisions:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The agreement of the Secretary to provide the individual with educational assistance for a specified number of school years (not to exceed 5 years) during which the individual is pursuing a course of education in a qualifying field. The assistance may include payment of tuition, fees, books, laboratory expenses, and (in the case of a fellowship) a stipend.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> The agreement of the individual to perform the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Accept such educational assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Maintain enrollment and attendance in the educational program until completed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Maintain, while enrolled in the educational program, satisfactory academic progress as prescribed by the institution of higher education in which the individual is enrolled.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Serve, upon completion of the educational program and selection by the Secretary under subsection (e), as a full-time employee in an environmental restoration or other environmental position in the Department of Defense for the applicable period of service specified in subsection (d).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Period of Service</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The period of service required under subsection (c)(2)(D) is as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> For an individual who completes a bachelor’s degree under a scholarship program established under subsection (a), a period of 12 months for each school year or part thereof for which the individual is provided a scholarship under the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> For an individual who completes a master’s degree or other post-graduate degree under a fellowship program established under subsection (a), a period of 24 months for each school year or part thereof for which the individual is provided a fellowship under the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Selection for Service</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall annually review the number and performance under the agreement of individuals who complete educational programs during the preceding year under any scholarship and fellowship programs conducted pursuant to subsection (a). From among such individuals, the Secretary shall select individuals for environmental positions in the Department of Defense, based on the type and availability of such positions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Repayment</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Any individual participating in a scholarship or fellowship program under this section shall agree to pay to the United States the total amount of educational assistance provided to the individual under the program, plus interest at the rate prescribed in paragraph (4), if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the individual does not complete the educational program as agreed to pursuant to subsection (c)(2)(B), or is selected by the Secretary under subsection (e) but declines to serve, or fails to complete the service, in a position in the Department of Defense as agreed to pursuant to subsection (c)(2)(D); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the individual is involuntarily separated for cause from the Department of Defense before the end of the period for which the individual has agreed to continue in the service of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> If an individual fails to fulfill the agreement of the individual to pay to the United States the total amount of educational assistance provided under a program established under subsection (a), plus interest at the rate prescribed in paragraph (4), a sum equal to the amount of the educational assistance (plus such interest, if applicable) shall be recoverable by the United States from the individual or his estate by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> in the case of an individual who is an employee of the Department of Defense or other Federal agency, set off against accrued pay, compensation, amount of retirement credit, or other amount due the employee from the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> such other method provided by law for the recovery of amounts owing to the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The Secretary may waive in whole or in part a required repayment under this subsection if the Secretary determines the recovery would be against equity and good conscience or would be contrary to the best interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The total amount of educational assistance provided to an individual under a program established under subsection (a) shall, for purposes of repayment under this section, bear interest at the applicable rate of interest under section 427A(c) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1077a/c">20 U.S.C. 1077a(c)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Preference</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In evaluating applicants for the award of a scholarship or fellowship under a program established under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give a preference to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> individuals who are, or have been, employed by the Department of Defense or its contractors and subcontractors who have been engaged in defense-related activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> individuals who are or have been members of the Armed Forces.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coordination of Benefits</inline>.—</heading><content>A scholarship or fellowship awarded under this section shall be taken into account in determining the eligibility of the individual for Federal student financial assistance provided under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070">20 U.S.C. 1070</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Award of Scholarships and Fellowships</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may award to qualified applicants not more than 100 scholarships (for undergraduate students) and not more than 30 fellowships (for graduate students) in fiscal year 1993.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="j">“(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="1994-01-01">January 1, 1994</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a report on activities undertaken under the programs established under subsection (a) and recommendations for future activities under the programs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="k">“(k)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Funding for Fiscal Year</inline> 1993.—</heading><chapeau>Of the amount authorized to be appropriated in section 301(5) [<ref href="/us/stat/106/2360">106 Stat. 2360</ref>]—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> $7,000,000 shall be available to carry out the scholarship and fellowship programs established in subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> $3,000,000 shall be available to provide training to Department of Defense personnel to obtain the skills required to comply with existing environmental statutory and regulatory requirements.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c2c25a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Grants to Institutions of Higher Education To Provide Training in Environmental Restoration and Hazardous Waste Management</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dD/tXLIV/s4452">Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLIV, § 4452</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2738">106 Stat. 2738</ref>, authorized the Secretary of Defense to establish a program to assist institutions of higher education, as defined in former <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1141/a">section 1141(a) of Title 20</ref>, Education, to provide education and training in environmental restoration and hazardous waste management and to award grants to such institutions, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tXIII/s1333/j">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XIII, § 1333(j)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1800">107 Stat. 1800</ref>. See <ref href="/us/pl/103/160/s1333">section 1333 of Pub. L. 103–160</ref>, set out above.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c2c25b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Policies and Report on Overseas Environmental Compliance</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tIII/s342/b">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title III, § 342(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1537">104 Stat. 1537</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tIII/s342/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall develop a policy for determining applicable environmental requirements for military installations located outside the United States. In developing the policy, the Secretary shall ensure that the policy gives consideration to adequately protecting the health and safety of military and civilian personnel assigned to such installations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall develop a policy for determining the responsibilities of the Department of Defense with respect to cleaning up environmental contamination that may be present at military installations located outside the United States. In developing the policy, the Secretary shall take into account applicable international agreements (such as Status of Forces agreements), multinational or joint use and operation of such installations, relative share of the collective defense burden, and negotiated accommodations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall develop a policy and strategy to ensure adequate oversight of compliance with applicable environmental requirements and responsibilities of the Department of Defense determined under the policies developed under paragraphs (1) and (2). In developing the policy, the Secretary shall consider using the Inspector General of the Department of Defense to ensure active and forceful oversight.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> At the same time the President submits to Congress his budget for fiscal year 1993 pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105">section 1105 of title 31</ref>, United States Code, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report describing the policies developed under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3). The report also shall include a discussion of the role of the Inspector General of the Department of Defense in overseeing environmental compliance at military installations outside the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> For purposes of this subsection, the term ‘military installation’ means a base, camp, post, station, yard, center, or other activity under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of a military department which is located outside the United States and outside any territory, commonwealth, or possession of the United States.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c2c25c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Environmental Education Program for Department of Defense Personnel</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tIII/s344">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title III, § 344</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1538">104 Stat. 1538</ref>, directed Secretary of Defense to establish a program for the purpose of educating Department of Defense personnel in environmental management and, not later than date on which President submits budget for FY 1992 to Congress pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105/a">31 U.S.C. 1105(a)</ref>, to submit to Congress recommendations regarding whether program should be continued after <date date="1991-09-30">Sept. 30, 1991</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c2c25d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Use of Ozone Depleting Substances Within Department of Defense</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dA/tIII/s325">Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title III, § 325</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2367">106 Stat. 2367</ref>, required the Director of the Defense Logistics Agency to evaluate the use of class I and class II substances, listed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7671a">42 U.S.C. 7671a</ref>, by the military departments and Defense Agencies for the years 1992 to 1995 and to submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the status of the evaluation in 1993.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tIII/s345">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title III, § 345</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1538">104 Stat. 1538</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tIII/s345">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">DOD Requirements for Ozone Depleting Chemicals Other Than CFC</inline>s.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In addition to the functions of the advisory committee established pursuant to section 356(c) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Years 1990 and 1991 [<ref href="/us/pl/101/189">Pub. L. 101–189</ref>] (<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2701">10 U.S.C. 2701</ref> note), it shall be the function of the Committee to study (A) the use of methyl chloroform, hydrochlorofluorcarbons (HCFCs), and carbon tetrachloride by the Department of Defense and by contractors in the performance of contracts for the Department of Defense, and (B) the costs and feasibility of using alternative compounds or technologies for methyl chloroform, HCFCs, and carbon tetrachloride.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Within 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>], the Secretary shall provide the Committee with a list of all military specifications, standards, and other requirements that specify the use of methyl chloroform, HCFCs, or carbon tetrachloride.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Within 150 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall provide the Committee with a list of all military specifications, standards, and other requirements that do not specify use of methyl chloroform, HCFCs, or carbon tetrachloride but cannot be met without the use of one or more of such substances.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>In preparing the report required by section 356(d) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Years 1990 and 1991 [<ref href="/us/pl/101/189">Pub. L. 101–189</ref>, set out below] and the report required by subsection (d) of this section, the Committee shall work closely with the Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program Council and shall provide to such Council such reports.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Extension of Reporting Deadline for CFC</inline>s.—</heading><content>The deadline for submitting to Congress the report required by section 356(d) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Years 1990 and 1991 concerning the uses of CFCs is hereby extended to <date date="1991-06-30">June 30, 1991</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reporting Deadline for Methyl Chloroform, HCFC</inline>s, <inline class="small-caps">and Carbon Tetrachloride</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="1991-09-30">September 30, 1991</date>, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report containing the results of the study by the Committee required by subsection (a)(1) of this section.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c2c25e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Requirement for Development of Environmental Data Base</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tIII/s352">Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title III, § 352</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1423">103 Stat. 1423</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tIII/s352">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Environmental Data Base</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall develop and maintain a comprehensive data base on environmental activities carried out by the Department of Defense pursuant to, and environmental compliance obligations to which the Department is subject under, chapter 160 of title 10, United States Code, and all other applicable Federal and State environmental laws. At a minimum, the information in the data base shall include all the fines and penalties assessed against the Department of Defense pursuant to environmental laws and paid by the Department, all notices of violations of environmental laws received by the Department, and all obligations of the Department for compliance with environmental laws. The Secretary may include any other information he considers appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives a report on the progress in development of the data base required under subsection (a). The report shall include a summary of the information collected for the data base with respect to environmental activities during 1989.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c2c25f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Funding for Waste Minimization Programs for Certain Industrial-Type Activities of Department of Defense</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tIII/s354">Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title III, § 354</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1424">103 Stat. 1424</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/dA/tIII/s332">Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title III, § 332</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1340">105 Stat. 1340</ref>, directed the Secretary of Defense to require the Secretary of each military department to establish a program for fiscal years 1992, 1993, and 1994 to reduce the volume of solid and hazardous wastes disposed of, and hazardous materials used by, each industrial-type activity within the department that was a depot maintenance installation and for which a working-capital fund had been established under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2208">section 2208 of this title</ref>, and to submit to Congress, not later than 90 days after <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, the name of each industrial-type or commercial-type activity of each military department which was not covered by the waste minimization program because the activity did not carry out depot maintenance installation functions.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c2c260-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Use of Chlorofluorocarbons and Halons in Department of Defense</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tIII/s356">Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title III, § 356</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1425">103 Stat. 1425</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tIX/s904/f">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title IX, § 904(f)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1729">107 Stat. 1729</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tIX/s911/a/1">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title IX, § 911(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/717">113 Stat. 717</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tIX/s911/a/1">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Chlorofluorocarbons Emission Reduction</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall formulate and carry out, through the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics a program to reduce the unnecessary release of chlorofluorocarbons (hereinafter in this section referred to as ‘CFCs’) and halons into the atmosphere in connection with maintenance operations and training and testing practices of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives a report describing the program the Secretary proposes to carry out pursuant to subsection (a). The Secretary shall specify in the report the reduction goals that are attainable on the basis of known technology, including the use of refrigerant recovery systems currently available. The Secretary shall include in the report a schedule for meeting those goals. The Secretary shall also include in such report reduction goals that can be achieved only with the use of new technology and assess the technologies and investment that will be required to attain those goals within a five-year period.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Before the report required under paragraph (1) is submitted to the committees named in such paragraph, the Secretary shall transmit a copy of the report to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency for comment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">DOD Requirements for CFCs</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>], the Secretary shall establish an advisory committee to be known as the ‘CFC Advisory Committee’ (hereinafter in this section referred to as the ‘Committee’). The Committee shall be composed of not more than 15 members, with an equal number of representatives from the Department of Defense, the Environmental Protection Agency, and defense contractors. Members representing defense contractors shall be contractors that supply the Department of Defense with products or equipment that require the use of CFCs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> It shall be the function of the Committee to study (A) the use of CFCs by the Department of Defense and by contractors in the performance of contracts for the Department of Defense, and (B) the cost and feasibility of using alternative compounds for CFCs or using alternative technologies that do not require the use of CFCs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Within 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall provide the Committee with a list of all military specifications, standards, and other requirements that specify the use of CFCs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Within 150 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall provide the Committee with a list of all military specifications, standards, and other requirements that do not specify use of CFCs but cannot be met without the use of CFCs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than <date date="1990-09-30">September 30, 1990</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the committees named in subsection (b) a report containing the results of the study by the Committee. The report shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> identify cases in which the Committee found that substitutes for CFCs could be made most expeditiously;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> identify the feasibility and cost of substituting compounds or technologies for CFC uses referred to in subsection (c)(3) and estimate the time necessary for completing the substitution;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> identify CFC uses referred to in subsection (c)(4) for which substitutes are not currently available and indicate the reasons substitutes are not available;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> describe the types of research programs that should be undertaken to identify substitute compounds or technologies for CFC uses referred to in paragraphs (3) and (4) of subsection (c) and estimate the cost of the program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> recommend procedures to expedite the use of substitute compounds and technologies offered by contractors to replace CFC uses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> estimate the earliest date on which CFCs will no longer be required for military applications; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> estimate the cost of revising military specifications for the use of substitutes for CFCs, the additional costs resulting from modification of Department of Defense contracts to provide for the use of substitutes for CFCs, and the cost of purchasing new equipment and reverification necessitated by the use of substitutes for CFCs.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c2c261-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report on Environmental Requirements and Priorities</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tIII/s358">Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title III, § 358</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1427">103 Stat. 1427</ref>, directed Secretary of Defense, not later than two years after <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, to submit to Congress a comprehensive report on the long-range environmental challenges and goals of the Department of Defense.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c2c262-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study of Waste Recycling</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tIII/s361">Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title III, § 361</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1429">103 Stat. 1429</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tIII/s343">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title III, § 343</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1538">104 Stat. 1538</ref>, required the Secretary of Defense to conduct a study of current practices and future plans for managing postconsumer waste at facilities of the Department of Defense at which such waste was generated and the feasibility of such Department of Defense facilities participating in programs at military installations or in local communities to recycle the postconsumer waste generated at the facilities, and to submit to Congress a report describing the findings and conclusions of the Secretary resulting from the study not later than <date date="1991-03-01">Mar. 1, 1991</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9c2c263-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Use of Department of Defense Appropriations for Removal of Unsafe Buildings or Debris</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/165/tIX/s9038">Pub. L. 101–165, title IX, § 9038</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1137">103 Stat. 1137</ref>, which authorized appropriations available to the Department of Defense to be used at sites formerly used by the Department for removal of unsafe buildings or debris of the Department and required that removal be completed before the property is released from Federal Government control, was repealed and restated in subsecs. (f) and (g) of this section by <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXIV/s1481/i">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1481(i)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1708">104 Stat. 1708</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
