<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida9cc3898-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2737"><num value="2737">§ 2737.</num><heading> Property loss; personal injury or death: incident to use of property of the United States and not cognizable under other law</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9cc3899-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2737/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> Under such regulations as the Secretary concerned may prescribe, he or his designee may settle and pay, in an amount not more than $1,000, a claim against the United States, not cognizable under any other provision of law, for—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9cc389a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2737/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> damage to, or loss of, property; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9cc389b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2737/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> personal injury or death;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">caused by a civilian official or employee of a military department or the Coast Guard, or a member of the armed forces, incident to the use of a vehicle of the United States at any place, or any other property of the United States on a Government installation.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9cc389c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2737/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> Under such regulations as the Secretary of Defense may prescribe, he or his designee has the same authority as the Secretary of a military department with respect to a claim, not cognizable under any other provision of law, for—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9cc389d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2737/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> damage to, or loss of, property; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9cc389e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2737/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> personal injury or death;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">caused by a civilian official or employee of the Department of Defense not covered by subsection (a), incident to the use of a vehicle of the United States at any place, or any other property of the United States on a Government installation.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9cc389f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2737/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> A claim may not be allowed under subsection (a) or (b) if the damage to, or loss of, property, or the personal injury or death was caused wholly or partly by a negligent or wrongful act of the claimant, his agent, or his employee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9cc38a0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2737/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> A claim for personal injury or death under this section may not be allowed for more than the cost of reasonable medical, hospital, and burial expenses actually incurred, and not otherwise furnished or paid by the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9cc38a1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2737/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> No claim may be allowed under this section unless it is presented in writing within two years after it accrues.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9cc38a2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2737/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> A claim may not be paid under subsection (a) or (b) unless the amount tendered is accepted by the claimant in full satisfaction.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9cc38a3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2737/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> No claim or any part thereof, the amount of which is legally recoverable by the claimant under an indemnifying law or indemnity contract, may be paid under this section. No subrogated claim may be paid under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9cc38a4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2737/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content> So far as practicable, regulations prescribed under this section shall be uniform. Regulations prescribed under this section by the Secretaries of the military departments must be approved by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida9cc38a5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/87/769/s1/1/A">Pub. L. 87–769, § 1(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-09">Oct. 9, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/767">76 Stat. 767</ref>, § 2736; renumbered § 2737, <ref href="/us/pl/89/718/s21/a">Pub. L. 89–718, § 21(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-02">Nov. 2, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1118">80 Stat. 1118</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida9cc38a6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida9cc38a7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="ida9cc38a8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
