<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida9e4061b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853"><num value="2853">§ 2853.</num><heading> Authorized cost and scope of work variations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e4061c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cost Variations Authorized; Limitation</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subsection (c), (d), or (e), the cost authorized for a military construction project or for the construction, improvement, and acquisition of a military family housing project may be increased or decreased by not more than 25 percent of the total authorized cost of the project or 200 percent of the minor construction project ceiling specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2805/a">section 2805(a) of this title</ref>, whichever is less, if the Secretary concerned determines that such revised cost is required for the sole purpose of meeting unusual variations in cost and that such variations in cost could not have reasonably been anticipated at the time the project was authorized by Congress.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e4061d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Scope of Work Variations Authorized; Limitation</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e4061e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in subsection (c), the scope of work for a military construction project or for the construction, improvement, and acquisition of a military family housing project may be reduced by not more than 25 percent from the amount specified for that project, construction, improvement, or acquisition in the justification data provided to Congress as part of the request for authorization of the project, construction, improvement, or acquisition. Any reduction in scope of work for a military construction project shall not result in a facility or item of infrastructure that is not complete and useable or does not fully meet the mission requirement contained in the justification data provided to Congress as part of the request for authorization of the project, construction, improvement, or acquisition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e4061f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Except as provided in subsection (d), the scope of work for a military construction project or for the construction, improvement, and acquisition of a military family housing project may not be increased above the amount specified for that project, construction, improvement, or acquisition in the justification data provided to Congress as part of the request for authorization of the project, construction, improvement, or acquisition.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e40620-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In this subsection, the term “scope of work” refers to the function, size, or quantity of a facility or item of complete and useable infrastructure contained in the justification data provided to Congress as part of the request for authorization of the project, construction, improvement, or acquisition.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e40621-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions to Limitation on Cost Variations and Scope of Work Reductions</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e40622-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e40623-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Except as provided in subparagraph (D), the Secretary concerned may waive the percentage or dollar cost limitation applicable to a military construction project or a military family housing project under subsection (a) and approve an increase in the cost authorized for the project in excess of that limitation if the Secretary concerned notifies the appropriate committees of Congress of the cost increase in the manner provided in this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e40624-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> The notification required by subparagraph (A) shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9e40625-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/c/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> identify the amount of the cost increase and the reasons for the increase;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9e40626-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/c/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> certify that the cost increase is sufficient to meet the mission requirement identified in the justification data provided to Congress as part of the request for authorization of the project; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9e40627-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/c/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> describe the funds proposed to be used to finance the cost increase.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e40628-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> A waiver and approval by the Secretary concerned under subparagraph (A) shall take effect only after the end of the 14-day period beginning on the date on which the notification required by such subparagraph is received by the appropriate committees of Congress in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s480">section 480 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e40629-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/c/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The Secretary concerned may not use the authority provided by subparagraph (A) to waive the cost limitation applicable to a military construction project with a total authorized cost greater than $500,000,000 or a military family housing project with a total authorized cost greater than $500,000,000 if that waiver would increase the project cost by more than 50 percent of the total authorized cost of the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e4062a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/c/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> In addition to the notification required by this paragraph, subsection (f) applies whenever a military construction project or military family housing project with a total authorized cost greater than $40,000,000 will have a cost increase of 25 percent or more. Subsection (f) may not be construed to authorize a cost increase in excess of the limitation imposed by subparagraph (D).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e4062b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e4062c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary concerned may waive the percentage or dollar cost limitation applicable to a military construction project or a military family housing project under subsection (a) and approve a decrease in the cost authorized for the project in excess of that limitation if the Secretary concerned notifies the appropriate committees of Congress of the cost decrease not later than 14 days after the date funds are obligated in connection with the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e4062d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The notification required by subparagraph (A) shall be provided in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s480">section 480 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e4062e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e4062f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary concerned may waive the limitation on a reduction in the scope of work applicable to a military construction project or a military family housing project under subsection (b)(1) and approve a scope of work reduction for the project in excess of that limitation if the Secretary concerned notifies the appropriate committees of Congress of the reduction in the manner provided in this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e40630-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> The notification required by subparagraph (A) shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9e40631-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/c/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> describe the reduction in the scope of work and the reasons for the decrease; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9e40632-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/c/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> certify that the mission requirement identified in the justification data provided to Congress can still be met with the reduced scope.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e40633-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> A waiver and approval by the Secretary concerned under subparagraph (A) shall take effect only after the end of the 14-day period beginning on the date on which the notification required by such subparagraph is received by the appropriate committees of Congress in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s480">section 480 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e40634-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions to Limitation on Scope of Work Increases</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e40635-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (4), the Secretary concerned may waive the limitation on an increase in the scope of work applicable to a military construction project or a military family housing project under subsection (b)(1) and approve an increase in the scope of work for the project in excess of that limitation if the Secretary concerned notifies the appropriate committees of Congress of the reduction in the manner provided in this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e40636-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The notification required by paragraph (1) shall describe the increase in the scope of work and the reasons for the increase.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e40637-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A waiver and approval by the Secretary concerned under paragraph (1) shall take effect only after the end of the 14-day period beginning on the date on which the notification required by such paragraph is received by the appropriate committees of Congress in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s480">section 480 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e40638-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Secretary concerned may not use the authority provided by paragraph (1) to waive the limitation on an increase in the scope of work applicable to a military construction project or a military family housing project and approve an increase in the scope of work for the project that would increase the scope of work by more than 10 percent of the amount specified for the project in the justification data provided to Congress as part of the request for authorization of the project.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e40639-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional Cost Variation Exceptions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The limitation on cost variations in subsection (a) does not apply to the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9e4063a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The settlement of a contractor claim under a contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9e4063b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The costs associated with the required remediation of an environmental hazard in connection with a military construction project or military family housing project, such as asbestos removal, radon abatement, lead-based paint removal or abatement, or any other legally required environmental hazard remediation, if the required remediation could not have reasonably been anticipated at the time the project was approved originally by Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e4063c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional Reporting Requirement for Certain Cost Increases</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e4063d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In addition to the notification sent under paragraph (1) of subsection (c) of a cost increase with respect to a project, the Secretary concerned shall provide an additional report notifying the congressional defense committees of any military construction project or military family housing project with a total authorized cost greater than $40,000,000 that has a cost increase of 25 percent or more.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e4063e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The report under paragraph (1) shall include the following—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9e4063f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A description of the specific reasons for the cost increase and the specific organizations and individuals responsible.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9e40640-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A description of any ongoing or completed proceedings or investigation into a government employee, prime contractor, subcontractor, or non-governmental organization that may be responsible for the cost increase, and the status of such proceeding or investigation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9e40641-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/f/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> If any proceeding or investigation identified in subparagraph (B) resulted in final judicial or administrative action, the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9e40642-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/f/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> In the case of a judicial or administrative action taken against a government employee, the report shall identify the individual’s organization, position within the organization, and the action taken against the individual, but shall exclude personally identifiable information about the individual.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9e40643-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/f/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> In the case of a judicial or administrative action taken against a prime contractor, subcontractor, or non-governmental organization, the report shall identify the prime contractor, subcontractor, or non-governmental organization and the action taken against the prime contractor, subcontractor, or non-governmental organization.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9e40644-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/f/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> A summary of any changes the Secretary concerned believes may be required to the organizational structure, project management and oversight practices, policy, or authorities of a government organization involved in military construction projects as a result of problems identified and lessons learned from the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e40645-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If any proceeding or investigation described in paragraph (2)(C) is still ongoing at the time the Secretary concerned submits the report under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall provide a supplemental report to the congressional defense committees not later than 30 days after such proceeding or investigation has been completed. If such proceeding or investigation resulted in final judicial or administrative action against a government employee, prime contractor, subcontractor, or non-governmental organization, the Secretary shall include in the supplemental report the information required by paragraph (2)(C).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e40646-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Each report under this subsection shall be cosigned by the senior engineer authorized to supervise military construction projects and military family housing projects under section 2851(a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e40647-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/f/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The Secretary shall send the report required under paragraph (1) with respect to a project not later than 180 days after the Secretary sends to the appropriate committees of Congress the notification under paragraph (1) of subsection (c) of a cost increase with respect to the project.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e40648-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2853/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Relation to Other Law</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding the authority under subsections (a) through (f), the Secretary concerned shall ensure compliance of contracts for military construction projects and for the construction, improvement, and acquisition of military family housing projects with <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1341">section 1341 of title 31</ref> (commonly referred to as the “Anti-Deficiency Act”).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida9e40649-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/97/214/s2/a">Pub. L. 97–214, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-07-12">July 12, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/164">96 Stat. 164</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/98/407/tVIII/s807">Pub. L. 98–407, title VIII, § 807</ref>, <date date="1984-08-28">Aug. 28, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1521">98 Stat. 1521</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/26/s7/f/2">Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(f)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/281">101 Stat. 281</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/180/dB">Pub. L. 100–180, div. B</ref>, subdiv. 3, title I, §§ 2312, 2313, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1217">101 Stat. 1217</ref>, 1218; <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/dB/tXXVIII/s2808">Pub. L. 101–189, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2808</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1648">103 Stat. 1648</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dB/tXXVIII/s2817">Pub. L. 104–106, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2817</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/553">110 Stat. 553</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dB/tXXVIII/s2802">Pub. L. 107–107, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2802</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1305">115 Stat. 1305</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/dB/tXXVIII/s2803">Pub. L. 108–375, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2803</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/2121">118 Stat. 2121</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dB/tXXVIII/s2804/a">Pub. L. 109–163, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2804(a)</ref>–(c)(1), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3506">119 Stat. 3506</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dB/tXXVIII/s2806">Pub. L. 109–364, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2806</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2468">120 Stat. 2468</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/dB/tXXVIII/s2803">Pub. L. 111–84, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2803</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2661">123 Stat. 2661</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/dB/tXXVIII/s2802/c/2">Pub. L. 112–81, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2802(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1685">125 Stat. 1685</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dB/tXXVIII/s2801">Pub. L. 112–239, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2801</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2146">126 Stat. 2146</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tX/s1071/f/24">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(f)(24)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3511">128 Stat. 3511</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dB/tXXVIII/s2803">Pub. L. 114–328, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2803</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2712">130 Stat. 2712</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dB/tXXVIII">Pub. L. 115–91, div. B, title XXVIII</ref>, §§ 2801(c)(1), 2821, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1843">131 Stat. 1843</ref>, 1853; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dB/tXXVIII/s2803/a">Pub. L. 116–283, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2803(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4319">134 Stat. 4319</ref>, 4320; <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dB/tXXVIII/s2802">Pub. L. 117–81, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2802</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/2184">135 Stat. 2184</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dB/tXXVIII/s2808">Pub. L. 117–263, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2808</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2996">136 Stat. 2996</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida9e4064a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida9e4064b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida9e4064c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (c)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Pub. L. 117–263</ref> amended subpar. (D) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (D) read as follows: “The Secretary concerned may not use the authority provided by subparagraph (A)—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) to waive the cost limitation applicable to a military construction project with a total authorized cost greater than $500,000,000 or a military family housing project with a total authorized cost greater than $500,000,000; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) to approve an increase in the cost authorized for the project that would increase the project cost by more than 50 percent of the total authorized cost of the project.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s2802/b">Pub. L. 117–81, § 2802(b)</ref>, (c)(1), inserted heading and substituted “the total authorized cost of the project” for “the amount appropriated for such project” in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s2802/c/2">Pub. L. 117–81, § 2802(c)(2)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s2802/a">Pub. L. 117–81, § 2802(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (c) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (c) related to situations where limitation on cost variations or the limitation on scope reduction did not apply.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s2803/b">Pub. L. 116–283, § 2803(b)</ref>, inserted “(subject to subsection (f))” after “cost increase” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s2802/a">Pub. L. 117–81, § 2802(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (d) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (d) related to situations where the limitation on an increase in the scope of work did not apply.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s2802/c/3">Pub. L. 117–81, § 2802(c)(3)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s2802/c/4">Pub. L. 117–81, § 2802(c)(4)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s2803/a/1">Pub. L. 116–283, § 2803(a)(1)</ref>, struck out “and the Comptroller General of the United States” after “congressional defense committees”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s2803/a/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 2803(a)(2)</ref>, struck out par. (6) which read as follows: “The Comptroller General of the United States shall review each report submitted under this subsection and validate or correct as necessary the information provided.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s2802/c/5">Pub. L. 117–81, § 2802(c)(5)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—Subsec. (c)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s2801/c/1/A">Pub. L. 115–91, § 2801(c)(1)(A)</ref>, struck out “in writing” after “committees of Congress”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s2801/c/1/B">Pub. L. 115–91, § 2801(c)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “14-day period” for “period of 21 days” and struck out “or, if over sooner, a period of 14 days has elapsed after the date on which a copy of the notification is provided” after “received by the committees”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s2801/c/1/A">Pub. L. 115–91, § 2801(c)(1)(A)</ref>, (C), inserted “, using an electronic medium pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s480">section 480 of this title</ref>,” after “notifies” and struck out “in writing” after “committees of Congress”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s2821/2">Pub. L. 115–91, § 2821(2)</ref>, added subsec. (f). Former subsec. (f) redesignated (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s2821/1">Pub. L. 115–91, § 2821(1)</ref>, (3), redesignated subsec. (f) as (g) and substituted “subsections (a) through (f)” for “subsections (a) through (e)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s2803/c">Pub. L. 114–328, § 2803(c)</ref>, inserted “of this title” after “section 2805(a)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s2803/b/1">Pub. L. 114–328, § 2803(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “subsection (c), (d), or (e)” for “subsection (c) or (d)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s2803/a/1">Pub. L. 114–328, § 2803(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Except as provided in subsection (d), the scope of work” for “The scope of work”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s2803/a/3">Pub. L. 114–328, § 2803(a)(3)</ref>, added subsec. (d). Former subsec. (d) redesignated (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s2803/a/2">Pub. L. 114–328, § 2803(a)(2)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (d) as (e). Former subsec. (e) redesignated (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s2803/a/2">Pub. L. 114–328, § 2803(a)(2)</ref>, (b)(2), redesignated subsec. (e) as (f) and substituted “through (e)” for “through (d)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (c)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/113/291">Pub. L. 113–291</ref> substituted “can still be” for “can be still be”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s2801/1">Pub. L. 112–239, § 2801(1)</ref>, substituted “was authorized” for “was approved originally”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s2801/2/A">Pub. L. 112–239, § 2801(2)(A)</ref>, inserted at end “Any reduction in scope of work for a military construction project shall not result in a facility or item of infrastructure that is not complete and useable or does not fully meet the mission requirement contained in the justification data provided to Congress as part of the request for authorization of the project, construction, improvement, or acquisition.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s2801/2/B">Pub. L. 112–239, § 2801(2)(B)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s2801/3">Pub. L. 112–239, § 2801(3)</ref>, substituted “, the reasons therefor, a certification that the mission requirement identified in the justification data provided to Congress can be still be met with the reduced scope, and a description” for “and the reasons therefor, including a description”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s2801/4">Pub. L. 112–239, § 2801(4)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/112/81">Pub. L. 112–81</ref> substituted “section 2805(a)” for “section 2805(a)(1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/s2803/1">Pub. L. 111–84, § 2803(1)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), substituted “may be reduced by not more than 25 percent from the amount specified for that project, construction, improvement, or acquisition in the justification data provided to Congress as part of the request for authorization of the project, construction, improvement, or acquisition.” for “may be reduced by not more than 25 percent from the amount approved for that project, construction, improvement, or acquisition by Congress.”, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/s2803/2">Pub. L. 111–84, § 2803(2)</ref>, substituted “subsection (b)(1)” for “subsection (b)” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—<ref href="/us/pl/109/163/s2804/c/1">Pub. L. 109–163, § 2804(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “Authorized cost and scope of work variations” for “Authorized cost variations” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/s2804/a/1">Pub. L. 109–163, § 2804(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “may be increased or decreased by not more than 25 percent” for “may be increased by not more than 25 percent” and “if the Secretary concerned determines that such revised cost is required” for “if the Secretary concerned determines that such an increase in cost is required”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364">Pub. L. 109–364</ref> substituted “if the variation in cost or reduction in the scope of work is approved by the Secretary concerned and—” for “if—” in introductory provisions, added pars. (1) and (2), and struck out former pars. (1) to (3) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(1) the variation in cost or reduction in scope is approved by the Secretary concerned;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2) the Secretary concerned notifies the appropriate committees of Congress in writing of the variation or reduction and the reasons therefor, including a description of the funds proposed to be used to finance any increased costs; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(3) a period of 21 days has elapsed after the date on which the notification is received by the committees or, if over sooner, a period of 14 days has elapsed after the date on which a copy of the notification is provided in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s480">section 480 of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/163/s2804/a/2">Pub. L. 109–163, § 2804(a)(2)</ref>, (b), substituted “limitation on cost variations” for “limitation on cost increase” in introductory provisions, “the variation” for “the increase” in pars. (1) and (2), and inserted “, including a description of the funds proposed to be used to finance any increased costs” after “the reasons therefor” in par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/s2804/a/3">Pub. L. 109–163, § 2804(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “limitation on cost variations” for “limitation on cost increases” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375">Pub. L. 108–375</ref> inserted before period at end “or, if over sooner, a period of 14 days has elapsed after the date on which a copy of the notification is provided in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s480">section 480 of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/107/107">Pub. L. 107–107</ref> amended subsec. (d) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (d) read as follows: “The limitation on cost increases in subsection (a) does not apply to the settlement of a contractor claim under a contract.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106">Pub. L. 104–106</ref> amended subsec. (d) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (d) read as follows: “The limitation on cost increases in subsection (a) does not apply to a within-scope modification to a contract or to the settlement of a contractor claim under a contract if the increase in cost is approved by the Secretary concerned, and the Secretary concerned promptly submits written notification of the facts relating to the proposed increase in cost to the appropriate committees of Congress.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—<ref href="/us/pl/101/189">Pub. L. 101–189</ref> amended section generally, substituting subsecs. (a) to (d) for former subsecs. (a) to (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/180/s2312">Pub. L. 100–180, § 2312</ref>, substituted “Except as provided in paragraph (2), the total cost authorized for military construction projects at an installation (including each project the cost of which is included in such total authorized cost and is less than the minor project ceiling) may be increased by not more than 25 percent of the total amount appropriated for such projects” for “Except as provided in paragraph (2), the cost authorized for a military construction project (other than a project for which the approved amount is less than the minor project ceiling (as defined in subsection (f))) may be increased by not more than 25 percent of the amount appropriated for the project”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/26/s7/f/2/A">Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(f)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “the minor project ceiling (as defined in subsection (f))” for “the amount specified by law as the maximum amount for a minor military construction project”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/26/s7/f/2/B">Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(f)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “the minor project ceiling” for “the amount specified by law as the maximum amount for a minor military construction project”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/26/s7/f/2/B">Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(f)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “the minor project ceiling” for “the amount specified by law as the maximum amount for a minor military construction project” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/26/s7/f/2/B">Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(f)(2)(B)</ref>, (C), substituted “the minor project ceiling” for “the amount specified by law as the maximum amount for a minor military construction project” and “the amount of such ceiling” for “such maximum amount” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/100/180/s2313">Pub. L. 100–180, § 2313</ref>, substituted “construction, improvement,” for “construction”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/100/26/s7/f/2/B">Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(f)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “the minor project ceiling” for “the amount specified by law as the maximum amount for a minor military construction project”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/100/26/s7/f/2/D">Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(f)(2)(D)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/98/407">Pub. L. 98–407</ref> inserted “is more than the amount specified by law as the maximum amount for a minor military construction project and”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida9e4064d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="ida9e4064e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date and applicability of section, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/214/s12/a">section 12(a) of Pub. L. 97–214</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2801">section 2801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
