<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida9e8e8e7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869"><num value="2869">§ 2869.</num><heading> Exchange of property at military installations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e8e8e8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exchange Authorized</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e8e8e9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary concerned may enter into an agreement to convey real property, including any improvements thereon, described in paragraph (2) to any person who agrees, in exchange for the real property, to transfer to the United States all right, title, and interest of the person in and to a parcel of real property, including any improvements thereon under the person’s control, or to carry out a land acquisition, including the acquisition of all right, title, and interest or a lesser interest in real property under an agreement entered into under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2684a">section 2684a of this title</ref> to limit encroachments and other constraints on military training, testing, and operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e8e8ea-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Paragraph (1) applies with respect to real property under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9e8e8eb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> that is located on a military installation that is closed or realigned under a base closure law; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9e8e8ec-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> that is located on a military installation not covered by subparagraph (A) and for which the Secretary concerned makes a determination that the conveyance under paragraph (1) is advantageous to the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e8e8ed-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e8e8ee-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall establish a pilot program under which the Secretary concerned, during the term of the pilot program, may use the authority provided by paragraph (1) to also convey real property, including any improvements thereon, described in paragraph (2) to any person who agrees, in exchange for the real property, to provide—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9e8e8ef-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/a/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> installation-support services (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2679/f">section 2679(f) of this title</ref>); or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9e8e8f0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/a/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a new facility or improvements to an existing facility.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e8e8f1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The acquisition of a facility or improvements to an existing facility using the authority provided by subparagraph (A) shall not be treated as a military construction project for which an authorization is required by <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2802">section 2802 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e8e8f2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The expanded conveyance authority provided by subparagraph (A) applies only during the eight-year period beginning on the date on which the Secretary of Defense issues guidance regarding the use by the Secretaries concerned of such authority.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e8e8f3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Conditions on Conveyance Authority</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e8e8f4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The fair market value of the real property, installation-support services, or facility or improvements to an existing facility obtained by the Secretary concerned under subsection (a) in exchange for the conveyance of real property by the Secretary under such subsection shall be at least equal to the fair market value of the conveyed real property, as determined by the Secretary. If the fair market value of the real property conveyed by the Secretary concerned exceeds the fair market value of the real property, installation-support services, or facility or improvements received by the Secretary, the recipient of the property shall pay to the United States an amount equal to the difference in the fair market values.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e8e8f5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> In the case of a conveyance of real property to a political subdivision of a State, the value of the real property to be conveyed by the Secretary concerned under subsection (a) may exceed the fair market value of the land to be obtained, as determined under paragraph (1), by an amount not to exceed the reduction in value of the land which is attributable to voluntary zoning actions taken by such political subdivision to limit encroachment on a military installation, but only if the notice required by subsection (d)(2) contains—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9e8e8f6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a certification by the Secretary concerned that the military value to the United States of the land to be acquired justifies a payment in excess of the fair market value; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9e8e8f7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a description of the military value to be obtained.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e8e8f8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The Secretary concerned may agree to accept a facility or improvements to an existing facility under subsection (a)(3) only if the Secretary concerned determines that the facility or improvements—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9e8e8f9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> are completed and usable, fully functional, and ready for occupancy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9e8e8fa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> satisfy all operational requirements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9e8e8fb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> meet all Federal, State, and local requirements applicable to the facility relating to health, safety, and the environment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e8e8fc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Use of Conveyance Authority at Installations Closed Under Base Closure Laws</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority under subsection (a)(2)(A) to convey property located on a military installation may only be used to the extent the conveyance is consistent with an approved redevelopment plan for such installation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e8e8fd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Advance Notice of Use of Authority</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e8e8fe-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notice of the proposed use of the conveyance authority provided by subsection (a) shall be provided in such manner as the Secretary of Defense may prescribe, including publication in the Federal Register and otherwise. When real property located at a military installation is proposed for conveyance by means of a public sale, the Secretary concerned may notify prospective purchasers that consideration for the property may be provided in the manner authorized by such subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e8e8ff-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Secretary concerned may not enter into an agreement under subsection (a) for the conveyance of real property until—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9e8e900-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> the Secretary submits to Congress notice of the conveyance, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9e8e901-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/d/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a description of the real property to be conveyed by the Secretary under the agreement;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9e8e902-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/d/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a description of the land acquisition to be carried out under the agreement in exchange for the conveyance of the property; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9e8e903-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/d/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the amount of any payment to be made under subsection (b) or under section 2684a(d) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002101">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002101"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title to equalize the fair market values of the property to be conveyed and the land acquisition to be carried out under the agreement in exchange for the conveyance of the property; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9e8e904-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the waiting period applicable to that notice under paragraph (3) expires.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9e8e905-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If the notice submitted under paragraph (2) deals with the conveyance of real property located on a military installation that is closed or realigned under a base closure law or the conveyance of real property under an agreement entered into under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2684a">section 2684a of this title</ref>, the Secretary concerned may enter into the agreement under subsection (a) for the conveyance of the property after the end of the 14-day period beginning on the date of the submission of the notice in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s480">section 480 of this title</ref>. In the case of other real property to be conveyed under subsection (a), the Secretary concerned may enter into the agreement only after the end of the 45-day period beginning on the date of the submission of the notice in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s480">section 480 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9eb31f6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deposit and Use of Funds</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary concerned shall deposit funds received under subsection (b) in the appropriation “Foreign Currency Fluctuations, Construction, Defense”. The funds deposited shall be available, in such amounts as provided in appropriation Acts, for the purpose of paying increased costs of overseas military construction and family housing construction or improvement associated with unfavorable fluctuations in currency exchange rates. The use of such funds for this purpose does not relieve the Secretary concerned from the duty to provide advance notice to Congress under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2853/c">section 2853(c) of this title</ref> whenever the Secretary approves an increase in the cost of an overseas project under such section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9eb31f7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Description of Property</inline>.—</heading><content>The exact acreage and legal description of real property conveyed under subsection (a) shall be determined by surveys satisfactory to the Secretary concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9eb31f8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2869/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional Terms and Conditions</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary concerned may require such additional terms and conditions in connection with a conveyance under subsection (a) as the Secretary considers appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida9eb31f9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dB/tXXVIII/s2805/a/1">Pub. L. 108–136, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2805(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1719">117 Stat. 1719</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dB/tXXVIII/s2811/a">Pub. L. 109–364, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2811(a)</ref>–(f)(1), <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2471-2473">120 Stat. 2471–2473</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/dB/tXXVIII/s2804/a">Pub. L. 111–84, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2804(a)</ref>–(d)(1), <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2661">123 Stat. 2661</ref>, 2662; <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/dB/tXXVIII/s2815/a">Pub. L. 112–81, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2815(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1688">125 Stat. 1688</ref>, 1689; <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dB/tXXVIII/s2811">Pub. L. 112–239, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2811</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2150">126 Stat. 2150</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dB/tXXVIII">Pub. L. 115–91, div. B, title XXVIII</ref>, §§ 2801(c)(6), 2815, 2816, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1844">131 Stat. 1844</ref>, 1850; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dB/tXXVIII/s2862/a">Pub. L. 116–283, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2862(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4357">134 Stat. 4357</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dB/tXXVIII/s2851">Pub. L. 118–159, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2851</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2269">138 Stat. 2269</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida9eb31fa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="ida9eb31fb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2684a/d">Section 2684a(d) of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (d)(2)(A)(iii), was redesignated <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2684a/e">section 2684a(e) of this title</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tIII/s314/1">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title III, § 314(1)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/216">137 Stat. 216</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida9eb31fc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida9eb31fd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (a)(3)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s2851/b">Pub. L. 118–159, § 2851(b)</ref>, substituted “section 2679(f)” for “2679(e)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s2851/a">Pub. L. 118–159, § 2851(a)</ref>, substituted “eight-year period” for “five-year period”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s2862/a">Pub. L. 116–283, § 2862(a)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s2862/b/1">Pub. L. 116–283, § 2862(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “of the real property, installation-support services, or facility or improvements to an existing facility” for “of the land to be” and “of the real property conveyed by the Secretary concerned exceeds the fair market value of the real property, installation-support services, or facility or improvements received by the Secretary” for “of the land is less than the fair market value of the real property to be conveyed”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s2862/b/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 2862(b)(2)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s2815">Pub. L. 115–91, § 2815</ref>, amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “Paragraph (1) applies with respect to real property under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned that—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) is located on a military installation that is closed or realigned under a base closure law; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) is located on a military installation not covered by subparagraph (A) and is determined to be excess to the needs of the Department of Defense.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s2816">Pub. L. 115–91, § 2816</ref>, amended subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The fair market value of the land to be obtained by the Secretary concerned under subsection (a) in exchange for the conveyance of real property by the Secretary under such subsection shall be at least equal to the fair market value of the conveyed real property, as determined by the Secretary. If the fair market value of the land is less than the fair market value of the real property to be conveyed, the recipient of the property shall pay to the United States an amount equal to the difference in the fair market values.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s2801/c/6">Pub. L. 115–91, § 2801(c)(6)</ref>, substituted “after the end of the 14-day period beginning on the date of the submission of the notice in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s480">section 480 of this title</ref>.” for “after a period of 21 days has elapsed from the date of receipt of the notice or, if over sooner, a period of 14 days has elapsed from the date on which a copy of the notice is provided in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s480">section 480 of this title</ref>.” and “only after the end of the 45-day period beginning on the date of the submission of the notice in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s480">section 480 of this title</ref>.” for “only after a period of 60 days has elapsed from the date of receipt of the notice or, if over sooner, a period of 45 days has elapsed from the date on which the electronic copy is provided.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239">Pub. L. 112–239</ref> substituted “any person” for “any eligible entity”, “the person” for “the entity”, and “the person’s control” for “their control”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—<ref href="/us/pl/112/81/s2815/a/1">Pub. L. 112–81, § 2815(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Exchange of property at military installations” for “Conveyance of property at military installations to limit encroachment” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/s2815/a/2/A">Pub. L. 112–81, § 2815(a)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “Exchange Authorized” for “Conveyance Authorized; Consideration” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/s2815/a/2/B">Pub. L. 112–81, § 2815(a)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “to any eligible entity who agrees, in exchange for the real property, to transfer to the United States all right, title, and interest of the entity in and to a parcel of real property, including any improvements thereon under their control, or to carry out a land acquisition” for “to any person who agrees, in exchange for the real property, to carry out a land acquisition”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (f) to (h). <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/s2815/b">Pub. L. 112–81, § 2815(b)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (g) and (h) as (f) and (g), respectively, and struck out former subsec. (f), which provided that authority to enter into an agreement under this section would expire on <date date="2013-09-30">September 30, 2013</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—<ref href="/us/pl/111/84/s2804/d/1">Pub. L. 111–84, § 2804(d)(1)</ref>, amended section catchline generally. Prior to amendment, catchline read as follows: “Conveyance of property at military installations to support military construction or limit encroachment”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/s2804/a/1/A">Pub. L. 111–84, § 2804(a)(1)(A)</ref>, struck out subpar. (A) designation before “to carry out”, substituted “real property,” for “real property—”, “ to carry out a land acquisition” for “to carry out a military construction project or land acquisition”, and a period for “; or”, and struck out subpar. (B) which read as follows: “to transfer to the Secretary concerned housing that is constructed or provided by the person and located at or near a military installation at which there is a shortage of suitable military family housing, military unaccompanied housing, or both.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/s2804/a/1/B">Pub. L. 111–84, § 2804(a)(1)(B)</ref>, struck out par. (3) which read as follows: “Subparagraph (B) of paragraph (2) shall apply only during the period beginning on the date of the enactment of the John Warner National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2007 and ending on <date date="2008-09-30">September 30, 2008</date>. Any conveyance of real property described in such subparagraph for which the Secretary concerned has provided the advance public notice required by subsection (d)(1) before the expiration date may be completed after that date.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/s2804/a/2">Pub. L. 111–84, § 2804(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “fair market value of the land” for “fair market value of the military construction, military family housing, or military unaccompanied housing” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/s2804/a/3">Pub. L. 111–84, § 2804(a)(3)</ref>, added subsec. (c) and struck out former subsec. (c) which related to pilot program for use of conveyance authority.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(A)(ii), (iii). <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/s2804/a/4">Pub. L. 111–84, § 2804(a)(4)</ref>, substituted “land acquisition” for “military construction project, land acquisition, military family housing, or military unaccompanied housing”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/s2804/b">Pub. L. 111–84, § 2804(b)</ref>, designated par. (3) as entire subsec., substituted “The Secretary concerned shall deposit funds received under subsection (b) in the appropriation ‘Foreign Currency Fluctuations, Construction, Defense’. The funds deposited shall be available” for “The funds deposited under paragraph (2) shall be available”, and struck out pars. (1) and (2), which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary concerned may deposit funds received under subsection (b) in the Department of Defense housing funds established under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2883/a">section 2883(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2) During the period specified in paragraph (3) of subsection (a), the Secretary concerned shall deposit funds received under subsection (b) in the appropriation ‘Foreign Currency Fluctuations, Construction, Defense’.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/s2804/c">Pub. L. 111–84, § 2804(c)</ref>, amended subsec. (f) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (f) related to annual reports on conveyances and effect of failure to submit report.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—<ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s2811/f/1">Pub. L. 109–364, § 2811(f)(1)</ref>, substituted “to support military construction or limit encroachment” for “closed or realigned to support military construction” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s2811/a">Pub. L. 109–364, § 2811(a)</ref>, (b), designated existing provisions as par. (1), in introductory provisions substituted “described in paragraph (2)” for “located on a military installation that is closed or realigned under a base closure law”, redesignated former pars. (1) and (2) as subpars. (A) and (B), respectively, in subpar. (A) substituted “land acquisition, including the acquisition of all right, title, and interest or a lesser interest in real property under an agreement entered into under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2684a">section 2684a of this title</ref> to limit encroachments and other constraints on military training, testing, and operations” for “land acquisition”, and added pars. (2) and (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s2811/c/1">Pub. L. 109–364, § 2811(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “is proposed for conveyance” for “closed or realigned under the base closure laws is to be conveyed”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s2811/c/2">Pub. L. 109–364, § 2811(c)(2)</ref>, added pars. (2) and (3) and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows: “The Secretary concerned may not enter into an agreement under subsection (a) for the conveyance of real property until—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) the Secretary submits to Congress notice of the conveyance, including the military construction activities, military family housing, or military unaccompanied housing to be obtained in exchange for the conveyance; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) a period of 14 days expires beginning on the date on which the notice is submitted.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s2811/d">Pub. L. 109–364, § 2811(d)</ref>, amended heading and text of subsec. (e) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Secretary concerned may deposit funds received under subsection (b) in the Department of Defense housing funds established under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2883/a">section 2883(a) of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s2811/e">Pub. L. 109–364, § 2811(e)</ref>, in heading substituted “Annual Reports; Effect of Failure to Submit” for “Annual Report”, designated existing provisions as par. (1), in introductory provisions substituted “Not later than March 15 of each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report detailing the following:” for “In the budget materials submitted to Congress in connection with the submission of the budget for a fiscal year pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105">section 1105 of title 31</ref>, the Secretary of Defense shall include a report detailing the following:”, redesignated former pars. (1) to (3) as subpars. (A) to (C), respectively, in subpar. (C) inserted “and of excess real property at military installations” before period at end, and added par. (2).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida9eb31fe-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9eb31ff-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Issuance of Guidance</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dB/tXXVIII/s2862/c">Pub. L. 116–283, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2862(c)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4358">134 Stat. 4358</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/283/dB/tXXVIII/s2862/c">“Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall issue guidance providing for the implementation of the pilot program required by <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2869/a/3">section 2869(a)(3) of title 10</ref>, United States Code, as added by this section.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
