<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida9efed55-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890"><num value="2890">§ 2890.</num><heading> Rights and responsibilities of tenants of housing units</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efed56-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Development of Tenant Bill of Rights and Tenant Responsibilities Documents</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efed57-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall develop two separate documents, to be known as the Military Housing Privatization Initiative Tenant Bill of Rights and the Military Housing Privatization Initiative Tenant Responsibilities, for tenants of housing units.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efed58-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary of each military department shall ensure that the housing documents are attached to each lease agreement for a housing unit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efed59-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The rights and responsibilities contained in the housing documents are not intended to be exclusive. The omission of a tenant right or responsibility shall not be construed to deny the existence of such a right or responsibility for tenants.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efed5a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Each contract between the Secretary concerned and a landlord shall incorporate the housing documents and guarantee the rights and responsibilities of tenants who reside in housing units covered by the contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efed5b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall develop the housing documents in coordination with the Secretaries of the military departments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efed5c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements of Tenant Bill of Rights</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>At a minimum, the Military Housing Privatization Initiative Tenant Bill of Rights shall address the following rights of tenants of housing units:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed5d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The right to reside in a housing unit and community that meets applicable health and environmental standards.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed5e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The right to reside in a housing unit that has working fixtures, appliances, and utilities and to reside in a community with well-maintained common areas and amenity spaces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed5f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The right to be provided with a maintenance history of the prospective housing unit before signing a lease, as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2892a">section 2892a of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed60-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The right to a written lease with clearly defined rental terms to establish tenancy in a housing unit, including any addendums and other regulations imposed by the landlord regarding occupancy of the housing unit and use of common areas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed61-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The right to a plain-language briefing, before signing a lease and 30 days after move-in, by the installation housing office on all rights and responsibilities associated with tenancy of the housing unit, including information regarding the existence of any additional fees authorized by the lease, any utilities payments, the procedures for submitting and tracking work orders, the identity of the military tenant advocate, and the dispute resolution process.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed62-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The right to have sufficient time and opportunity to prepare and be present for move-in and move-out inspections, including an opportunity to obtain and complete necessary paperwork.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed63-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><chapeau> The right to report inadequate housing standards or deficits in habitability of the housing unit to the landlord, the chain of command, and housing management office without fear of reprisal or retaliation, as provided in subsection (e), including reprisal or retaliation in the following forms:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9efed64-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Unlawful recovery of, or attempt to recover, possession of the housing unit.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9efed65-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Unlawfully increasing the rent, decreasing services, or increasing the obligations of a tenant.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9efed66-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Interference with a tenant’s right to privacy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9efed67-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/7/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Harassment of a tenant.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9efed68-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/7/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Refusal to honor the terms of the lease.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9efed69-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/7/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> Interference with the career of a tenant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed6a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> The right of access to a military tenant advocate, as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2894/b/4">section 2894(b)(4) of this title</ref>, through the housing management office of the installation of the Department at which the housing unit is located.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed6b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> The right to receive property management services provided by a landlord that meet or exceed industry standards and that are performed by professionally and appropriately trained, responsive, and courteous customer service and maintenance staff.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed6c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> The right to have multiple, convenient methods to communicate directly with the landlord maintenance staff, and to receive consistently honest, accurate, straightforward, and responsive communications.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed6d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> The right to have access to an electronic work order system through which a tenant may request maintenance or repairs of a housing unit and track the progress of the work.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed6e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><chapeau> With respect to maintenance and repairs to a housing unit, the right to the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9efed6f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/12/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Prompt and professional maintenance and repair.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9efed70-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/12/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> To be informed of the required time frame for maintenance or repairs when a maintenance request is submitted.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9efed71-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/12/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> In the case of maintenance or repairs necessary to ensure habitability of a housing unit, to prompt relocation into suitable lodging or other housing at no cost to the tenant until the maintenance or repairs are completed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed72-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> The right to receive advice from military legal assistance on procedures involving mechanisms for resolving disputes with the property management company or property manager to include mediation, arbitration, and filing claims against a landlord.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed73-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> The right to enter into a dispute resolution process, as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2894">section 2894 of this title</ref>, should all other methods be exhausted and, in which case, a decision in favor of the tenant may include a reduction in rent or an amount to be reimbursed or credited to the tenant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed74-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content> The right to have the tenant’s basic allowance housing payments segregated, with approval of a designated commander, and not used by the property owner, property manager, or landlord pending completion of the dispute resolution process.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed75-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/16"><num value="16">(16)</num><content> The right to have reasonable, advance notice of any entrance by a landlord, installation housing staff, or chain of command into the housing unit, except in the case of an emergency or abandonment of the housing unit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed76-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/17"><num value="17">(17)</num><content> The right to not pay non-refundable fees or have application of rent credits arbitrarily held.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed77-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/b/18"><num value="18">(18)</num><content> The right to expect common documents, forms, and processes for housing units will be the same for all installations of the Department, to the maximum extent applicable without violating local, State, and Federal regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efed78-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements of Tenant Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>At a minimum, the Military Housing Privatization Initiative Tenant Responsibilities shall address the following responsibilities of tenants of housing units:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed79-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The responsibility to report in a timely manner any apparent environmental, safety, or health hazards of the housing unit to the landlord and any defective, broken, damaged, or malfunctioning building systems, fixtures, appliances, or other parts of the housing unit, the common areas, or related facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed7a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The responsibility to maintain standard upkeep of the housing unit as instructed by the housing management office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed7b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The responsibility to conduct oneself as a tenant in a manner that will not disturb neighbors, and to assume responsibility for one’s actions and those of a family member or guest in the housing unit or common areas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed7c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The responsibility not to engage in any inappropriate, unauthorized, or criminal activity in the housing unit or common areas.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed7d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The responsibility to allow the landlord reasonable access to the rental home in accordance with the terms of the tenant lease agreement to allow the landlord to make necessary repairs in a timely manner.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed7e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The responsibility to read all lease-related materials provided by the landlord and to comply with the terms of the lease agreement, lease addenda, and any associated rules and guidelines.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efed7f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission to Congress and Public Availability</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efed80-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> As part of the budget submission for fiscal year 2021, and biennially thereafter, each Secretary of a military department shall submit the then-current housing documents to the congressional defense committees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efed81-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any change made to a housing document must be submitted to Congress at least 30 days before the change takes effect.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efed82-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Upon submission of a housing document under paragraph (1) or (2), each Secretary of a military department shall publish the housing document on a publicly available Internet website of the military department under the jurisdiction of such Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efed83-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Investigation of Reports of Reprisals</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efed84-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Inspector General of the Department of Defense shall investigate all reports of reprisal against a tenant for reporting an issue relating to a housing unit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efed85-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> If the Inspector General determines under paragraph (1) that a landlord has retaliated against a tenant for reporting an issue relating to a housing unit, the Inspector General shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed86-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> provide initial notice to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives as soon as practicable after making that determination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed87-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> following that initial notice, provide an update to such committees every 30 days thereafter until such time as the Inspector General has taken final action with respect to the retaliation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efed88-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Inspector General of the Department of Defense shall carry out this subsection in coordination with the Inspector General of the military department concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efed89-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Use of Nondisclosure Agreements</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efed8a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A tenant or prospective tenant of a housing unit may not be required to sign a nondisclosure agreement in connection with entering into, continuing, or terminating a lease for the housing unit. Any such agreement against the interests of the tenant is invalid.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efed8b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Paragraph (1) shall not apply to a nondisclosure agreement executed—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed8c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> as part of the settlement of litigation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efed8d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to avoid litigation if the tenant has retained legal counsel or has sought military legal assistance under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1044">section 1044 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efed8e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2890/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A party presenting a proposed nondisclosure agreement to a tenant shall notify such tenant that such tenant may, not later than 10 business days after such presentation, seek legal counsel with respect to the terms of and implications of entering into such agreement. A tenant may not be required to sign such agreement before the end of such 10-day period.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida9efed8f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added and amended <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dB/tXXX">Pub. L. 116–92, div. B, title XXX</ref>, §§ 3011(b), 3023, 3024(a), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1917">133 Stat. 1917</ref>, 1935; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dB/tXXVIII/s2811/b">Pub. L. 116–283, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2811(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4323">134 Stat. 4323</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dB/tXXVIII">Pub. L. 118–31, div. B, title XXVIII</ref>, §§ 2822(b), 2823, 2839(e), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/751">137 Stat. 751</ref>, 752, 761.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida9efed90-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida9efed91-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida9efed92-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2023—Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s2839/e/1">Pub. L. 118–31, § 2839(e)(1)</ref>, substituted “each Secretary of a military department” for “the Secretary of Defense”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s2839/e">Pub. L. 118–31, § 2839(e)</ref>, substituted “each Secretary of a military department” for “the Secretary of Defense” and “the military department under the jurisdiction of such Secretary” for “the Department of Defense”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s2822/b/1">Pub. L. 118–31, § 2822(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Inspector General of the Department of Defense” for “Assistant Secretary of Defense for Sustainment” and “tenant” for “member of the armed forces”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s2822/b/2/A">Pub. L. 118–31, § 2822(b)(2)(A)</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted “Inspector General determines” for “Assistant Secretary of Defense for Sustainment determines”, “tenant” for “member of the armed forces”, and “Inspector General shall” for “Assistant Secretary shall”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s2822/b/2/B">Pub. L. 118–31, § 2822(b)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “Inspector General” for “Assistant Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s2822/b/3">Pub. L. 118–31, § 2822(b)(3)</ref>, substituted “Inspector General of the Department of Defense” for “Assistant Secretary of Defense for Sustainment” and “Inspector General of the military department concerned” for “Secretary of the military department concerned”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s2823">Pub. L. 118–31, § 2823</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (b)(15). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s2811/b/1">Pub. L. 116–283, § 2811(b)(1)</ref>, struck out “and held in escrow” after “payments segregated”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s2811/b/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 2811(b)(2)</ref>, inserted “a” before “landlord” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s2811/b/3">Pub. L. 116–283, § 2811(b)(3)</ref>, added par. (2) and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows: “Paragraph (1) shall not apply to a nondisclosure agreement executed as part of the settlement of litigation.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s3023">Pub. L. 116–92, § 3023</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s3024/a">Pub. L. 116–92, § 3024(a)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida9efed93-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida9efed94-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2019 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dB/tXXX/s3024/c">Pub. L. 116–92, div. B, title XXX, § 3024(c)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1935">133 Stat. 1935</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/92/dB/tXXX/s3024/c">“Subsection (f) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2890">section 2890 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall apply with respect to any nondisclosure agreement covered by the terms of such subsection (f) regardless of the date on which the agreement was executed.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9efed95-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dB/tXXX/s3024/b">Pub. L. 116–92, div. B, title XXX, § 3024(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1935">133 Stat. 1935</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/92/dB/tXXX/s3024/b">“The Secretary of Defense and the Secretaries of the military departments shall promulgate such regulations as may be necessary to give full force and effect to subsection (f) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2890">section 2890 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9efed96-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Implementation of Comptroller General Recommendations Relating to Strengthening Oversight of Privatized Military Housing</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dB/tXXVIII/s2825">Pub. L. 118–31, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2825</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/752">137 Stat. 752</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/31/dB/tXXVIII/s2825">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall implement each recommendation of the Comptroller General of the United States contained in the report titled ‘DOD Can Further Strengthen Oversight of Its Privatized Housing Program’ (GAO–23–105377), dated <date date="2023-04-06">April 6, 2023</date>, and reissued with revisions on <date date="2023-04-20">April 20, 2023</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Non-implementation Reporting Requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Secretary elects not to implement any such recommendation, the Secretary shall, not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report that includes a justification for such election.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9efed97-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Requirements Relating to Move-In, Move-Out, and Maintenance of Privatized Military Housing</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dB/tXXX/s3056">Pub. L. 116–92, div. B, title XXX, § 3056</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1944">133 Stat. 1944</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/92/dB/tXXX/s3056">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Move-in and Move-out Checklist.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Checklist required</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall develop a uniform move-in and move-out checklist for use by landlords providing privatized military housing and by tenants of such housing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Required move-in element</inline>.—</heading><content>A tenant who will occupy a unit of privatized military housing is entitled to be present for an inspection of the housing unit before accepting occupancy of the housing unit to ensure that the unit is habitable and that facilities and common areas of the building are in good repair.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Required move-out element</inline>.—</heading><content>A tenant of a unit of privatized military housing is entitled to be present for the move-out inspection of the housing unit and must be given sufficient time to address any concerns related to the tenant’s occupancy of the housing unit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Maintenance Checklist</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> develop a uniform checklist to be used by housing management offices to validate the completion of all maintenance work related to health and safety issues at privatized military housing; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> require that all maintenance issues and work orders related to health and safety issues at privatized military housing be reported to the commander of the installation for which the housing is provided.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall carry out this section in consultation with the Secretaries of the military departments.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deadline</inline>.—</heading><content>The uniform checklists required by this section shall be completed not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>].”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “landlord”, “privatized military housing”, and “tenant” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s3056">section 3056 of Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s3001/a">section 3001(a) of Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2821">section 2821 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9efed98-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Standardized Documentation, Templates, and Forms for Privatized Military Housing</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dB/tXXX/s3057">Pub. L. 116–92, div. B, title XXX, § 3057</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1945">133 Stat. 1945</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/92/dB/tXXX/s3057">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Development Required.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall develop standardized documentation, templates, and forms for use throughout the Department of Defense with respect to privatized military housing. In developing such documentation, templates, and forms, the Secretary shall ensure that, to the maximum extent practicable, the documentation, templates, and forms do not conflict with applicable State and local housing regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Initial guidance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall issue guidance for the development of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Policies and standard operating procedures of the Department for privatized military housing.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> A universal lease agreement for privatized military housing that includes—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the documents developed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2890">section 2890 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, as added by section 3011, entitled Military Housing Privatization Initiative Tenant Bill of Rights and Military Housing Privatization Initiative Tenant Responsibilities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> any lease addendum required by the law of the State in which the unit of privatized military housing is located.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall carry out this subsection in consultation with the Secretaries of the military departments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Military Department Plans</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2020-02-01">February 1, 2020</date>, the Secretary of each military department shall submit to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] a plan for the implementation of this section by that military department.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definition of “privatized military housing” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s3057">section 3057 of Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s3001/a">section 3001(a) of Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2821">section 2821 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
