<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida9efedc2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a"><num value="2891a">§ 2891a.</num><heading> Requirements relating to management of housing units</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efedc3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that each contract between the Secretary concerned and a landlord regarding the management of housing units for an installation of the Department of Defense includes the requirements set forth in this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efedc4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements for Installation Commanders</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efedc5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The installation commander shall be responsible for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efedc6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> reviewing, on an annual basis, the mold mitigation plan and pest control plan of each landlord managing housing units for the installation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efedc7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> notifying the landlord and the major subordinate command of any deficiencies found in either plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efedc8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In response to a request by the head of the housing management office of an installation, the installation commander shall use the assigned bio-environmental personnel or contractor equivalent at the installation to test housing units for mold, unsafe water conditions, and other health and safety conditions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efedc9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements for Housing Management Office</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efedca-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The head of the housing management office of an installation shall be responsible for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efedcb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> conducting a physical inspection of, and approving the habitability of, a vacant housing unit for the installation before the landlord managing the housing unit is authorized to offer the housing unit available for occupancy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efedcc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> conducting a physical inspection of the housing unit upon tenant move-out; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efedcd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> maintaining all test results relating to the health, environmental, and safety condition of the housing unit and the results of any inspection conducted by the housing management office, landlord, or third-party contractor for the life of the contract relating to that housing unit.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efedce-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The head of the installation housing management office shall be provided a list of any move-out charges that a landlord seeks to collect from an outgoing tenant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efedcf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The head of the installation housing management office shall initiate contact with a tenant regarding the satisfaction of the tenant with the housing unit of the tenant not later than—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efedd0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> 15 days after move-in; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efedd1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> 60 days after move-in.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efedd2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements for Landlords</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efedd3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The landlord providing a housing unit shall disclose to the Secretary of Defense any bonus structures offered for community managers and regional executives and any bonus structures relating to maintenance of housing units, in order to minimize the impact of those incentives on the operating budget of the installation for which the housing units are provided.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efedd4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> With respect to test results relating to the health and safety condition of a housing unit, the landlord providing the housing unit shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efedd5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> not later than three days after receiving the test results, share the results with the tenant of the housing unit and submit the results to the head of the installation housing management office; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efedd6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> include with any environmental hazard test results a simple guide explaining those results, preferably citing standards set forth by the Federal Government relating to environmental hazards.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efedd7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Before a prospective tenant signs a lease to occupy a housing unit, the landlord providing the housing unit shall conduct a walkthrough inspection of the housing unit—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efedd8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> for the prospective tenant; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efedd9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if the prospective tenant is not able to be present for the inspection, with an official of the housing management office designated by the prospective tenant to conduct the inspection on the tenant’s behalf.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efedda-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> In the event that the installation housing management office determines that a housing unit does not meet minimum health, safety, and welfare standards set forth in Federal, State, and local law as a result of a walkthrough inspection or an inspection conducted under subsection (c), the landlord providing the housing unit shall remediate any issues and make any appropriate repairs to the satisfaction of the housing management office and subject to another inspection by the housing management office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efeddb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> A landlord providing a housing unit may not conduct any promotional events to encourage tenants to fill out maintenance comment cards or satisfaction surveys of any kind, without the approval of the chief of the housing management office.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efeddc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> A landlord providing a housing unit may not award an installation of the Department of Defense or an officer or employee of the Department a “Partner of the Year award” or similar award.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efeddd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><chapeau> A landlord providing a housing unit may not enter into any form of settlement, nondisclosure, or release of liability agreement with a tenant without—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efedde-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> first notifying the tenant of the tenant’s right to assistance from the legal assistance office at the installation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efeddf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> not later than five days before entering into such settlement, nondisclosure, or release of liability agreement, providing a copy of the agreement and terms to the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Sustainment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efede0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> A landlord providing a housing unit may not change the position of a prospective tenant on a waiting list for a housing unit or remove a prospective tenant from the waiting list in response to the prospective tenant turning down an offer for a housing unit, if the housing unit is determined unsatisfactory by the prospective tenant and the determination is confirmed by the housing management office and the installation commander.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efede1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><chapeau> A landlord providing a housing unit shall allow employees of the housing management office and other officers and employees of the Department to conduct—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efede2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d/9/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> with the permission of the tenant of the housing unit as appropriate, physical inspections of the housing unit; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efede3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d/9/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> physical inspections of any common areas maintained by the landlord.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efede4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> A landlord providing a housing unit shall agree to participate in the dispute resolution and payment-withholding processes established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2894">section 2894 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efede5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> Upon request by a prospective tenant, a landlord providing a housing unit shall ensure that the needs of enrollees in the Exceptional Family Member Program, or any successor program, are considered in assigning the prospective tenant to a housing unit provided by the landlord.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efede6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> A landlord providing a housing unit shall maintain an electronic work order system that enables access by the tenant to view work order history, status, and other relevant information, as required by <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2892">section 2892 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efede7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><chapeau> A landlord providing a housing unit shall agree to have any agreements or forms to be used by the landlord approved by the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Sustainment, including the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efede8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d/13/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A common lease agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efede9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/d/13/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any disclosure or nondisclosure forms that could be given to a tenant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efedea-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements for Secretary Concerned</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary concerned shall be responsible for—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efedeb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> providing for a mold inspection of each vacant housing unit before any new tenant moves into the unit; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efedec-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> providing to the new tenant the results of the inspection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efeded-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition Against Collection of Amounts in Addition to Rent</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efedee-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A landlord providing a housing unit may not impose on a tenant of the housing unit a supplemental payment, such as an out-of-pocket fee, in addition to the amount of rent the landlord charges for a unit of similar size and composition to the housing unit, without regard to whether or not the amount of the basic allowance for housing under <ref href="/us/usc/t37/s403">section 403 of title 37</ref> the tenant may receive as a member of the armed forces is less than the amount of the rent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efedef-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Nothing in paragraph (1) shall be construed—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efedf0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> to prohibit a landlord from imposing an additional payment—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9efedf1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/f/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> for optional services provided to military tenants, such as access to a gym or a parking space;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9efedf2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/f/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> for non-essential utility services, as determined in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary concerned; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9efedf3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/f/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> to recover damages associated with tenant negligence, consistent with subsection (c)(2); or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9efedf4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to limit or otherwise affect the authority of the Secretary concerned to enter into rental guarantee agreements under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2876">section 2876 of this title</ref> or to make differential lease payments under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2877">section 2877 of this title</ref>, so long as such agreements or payments do not require a tenant to pay an out-of-pocket fee or payment in addition to the amount of any basic allowance for housing under <ref href="/us/usc/t37/s403">section 403 of title 37</ref> the tenant may receive as a member of the armed forces.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efedf5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efedf6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/f/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Costs incurred to reasonably modify or upgrade a housing unit to comply with standards addressing discrimination against an individual with a disability established pursuant to the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12101">42 U.S.C. 12101</ref> et seq.), or to meet the reasonable modification and accommodation requirements of section 804 of the Fair Housing Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3604">42 U.S.C. 3604</ref>) and in order to facilitate occupancy of a housing unit by an individual with a disability, may not be considered optional services under paragraph (2)(A)(i) or another exception to the prohibition in paragraph (1) against collection from tenants of housing units of amounts in addition to rent.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9efedf7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2891a/f/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In subparagraph (A), the term “disability” has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12102">42 U.S.C. 12102</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida9efedf8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dB/tXXX/s3014/a">Pub. L. 116–92, div. B, title XXX, § 3014(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1924">133 Stat. 1924</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dB/tXXVIII/s2811/d">Pub. L. 116–283, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2811(d)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4324">134 Stat. 4324</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tX/s1081/a/31">Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(31)</ref>, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2813(b)(1), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1921">135 Stat. 1921</ref>, 2192; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dB/tXXVIII/s2824">Pub. L. 117–263, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2824</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3001">136 Stat. 3001</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida9efedf9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida9efedfa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="ida9efedfb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, referred to in subsec. (e)(3)(A), is <ref href="/us/pl/101/336">Pub. L. 101–336</ref>, <date date="1990-07-26">July 26, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/327">104 Stat. 327</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 126 (§ 12101 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12101">section 12101 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida9efedfc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsecs. (e), (f). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Pub. L. 117–263</ref> added subsec. (e) and redesignated former subsec. (e) as (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s2811/d/1">Pub. L. 116–283, § 2811(d)(1)</ref>, inserted period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s2811/d/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 2811(d)(2)</ref>, added par. (11) and struck out former par. (11) which read as follows: “A landlord providing a housing unit shall ensure that the needs of enrollees in the Exceptional Family Member Program, or any successor program, are considered in assigning prospective tenants to housing units provided by the landlord.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s1081/a/31">Pub. L. 117–81, § 1081(a)(31)</ref>, substituted “the basic allowance” for “the any basic allowance”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s2811/d/3">Pub. L. 116–283, § 2811(d)(3)</ref>, substituted “any” for “the any”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s2813/b/1">Pub. L. 117–81, § 2813(b)(1)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida9efedfd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida9efedfe-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dB/tXXVIII/s2813/b/2">Pub. L. 117–81, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2813(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/2192">135 Stat. 2192</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/81/dB/tXXVIII/s2813/b/2">“Subsection (e)(3) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2891a">section 2891a of title 10</ref>, United States Code [now <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2891e/f/3">10 U.S.C. 2891e(f)(3)</ref>], as added by paragraph (1), shall apply to contracts described in subsection (a) of such section entered into on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida9efedff-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2019 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dB/tXXX/s3014/c">Pub. L. 116–92, div. B, title XXX, § 3014(c)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1926">133 Stat. 1926</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/92/dB/tXXX/s3014/c">“The requirements set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2891a">section 2891a of title 10</ref>, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall apply to appropriate legal documents entered into or renewed on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>] between the Secretary of a military department and a landlord regarding privatized military housing.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “landlord” and “privatized military housing” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s3014/c">section 3014(c) of Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s3001/a">section 3001(a) of Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2821">section 2821 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9efee00-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Implementation of Recommendations From Audit of Medical Conditions of Residents in Privatized Military Housing</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dB/tXXVIII/s2825">Pub. L. 117–263, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2825</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3001">136 Stat. 3001</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dB/tXXVIII/s2825">“Not later than <date date="2023-03-01">March 1, 2023</date>, the Secretary of Defense shall implement the recommendations contained in the report of the Inspector General of the Department of Defense published on <date date="2022-04-01">April 1, 2022</date>, and titled ‘Audit of Medical Conditions of Residents in Privatized Military Housing’ (DODIG–2022–078).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9efee01-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Military Department Implementation Plans</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dB/tXXX/s3014/b">Pub. L. 116–92, div. B, title XXX, § 3014(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1926">133 Stat. 1926</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/92/dB/tXXX/s3014/b">“Not later than <date date="2020-02-01">February 1, 2020</date>, the Secretary of each military department shall submit to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] a plan for the implementation by that military department of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2891a">section 2891a of title 10</ref>, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9efee02-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Retroactive Landlord Agreements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dB/tXXX/s3014/e">Pub. L. 116–92, div. B, title XXX, § 3014(e)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1926">133 Stat. 1926</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/92/dB/tXXX/s3014/e">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2020-02-01">February 1, 2020</date>, the Secretary of Defense shall seek agreement from all landlords to accept the application of the requirements set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2891a">section 2891a of title 10</ref>, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), to appropriate legal documents entered into or renewed before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>] between the Secretary of a military department and a landlord regarding privatized military housing [sic]</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submittal of list to congress</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2020-03-01">March 1, 2020</date>, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] a list of any landlords that did not agree under paragraph (1) to accept the requirements set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2891a">section 2891a of title 10</ref>, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consideration of lack of agreement in future contracts</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretaries of the military departments shall include any lack of agreement under paragraph (1) as past performance considered under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2891b">section 2891b of title 10</ref>, United States Code, as added by section 3015, with respect to entering into or renewing any future contracts regarding privatized military housing.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “landlord” and “privatized military housing” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s3014/e">section 3014(e) of Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s3001/a">section 3001(a) of Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2821">section 2821 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
