<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida9f25e42-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2892a"><num value="2892a">§ 2892a.</num><heading> Access by tenants to historical maintenance information</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f25e43-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2892a/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Maintenance Information for Prospective Tenants</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary concerned shall require each eligible entity or subsequent landlord that offers for lease a housing unit to provide to a prospective tenant of the housing unit—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25e44-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2892a/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> not later than five business days before the prospective tenant is asked to sign the lease, a summary of maintenance conducted with respect to that housing unit for the previous seven years; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25e45-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2892a/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> not later than two business days after the prospective tenant requests additional information regarding maintenance conducted with respect to that housing unit during such period, all information possessed by the eligible entity or subsequent landlord regarding such maintenance conducted during such period.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f25e46-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2892a/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Maintenance Information for Existing Tenants</inline>.—</heading><content>A tenant of a housing unit who did not receive maintenance information described in subsection (a) regarding that housing unit while a prospective tenant may request such maintenance information and shall receive such maintenance information not later than five business days after the making the request.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f25e47-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2892a/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Maintenance Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In the section, the term “maintenance” includes any renovations of the housing unit during the period specified in subsection (a)(1).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida9f25e48-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dB/tXXX/s3019">Pub. L. 116–92, div. B, title XXX, § 3019</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1931">133 Stat. 1931</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dB/tXXVIII/s2811/e">Pub. L. 116–283, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2811(e)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4324">134 Stat. 4324</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida9f25e49-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida9f25e4a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida9f25e4b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—<ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> added section text and struck out former text which read as follows: “The Secretary concerned shall require each eligible entity or subsequent landlord that offers for lease a housing unit to provide to a prospective tenant of the housing unit, before the prospective tenant moves into the housing unit as a tenant, all information regarding maintenance conducted with respect to that housing unit for the previous seven years. In this section, the term ‘maintenance’ includes any renovations of the housing unit during such period.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
