<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida9f25eb1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902"><num value="2902">§ 2902.</num><heading> Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program Council</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f25eb2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> There is a Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program Council (hereinafter in this chapter referred to as the “Council”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f25eb3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> The Council is composed of 12 members as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25eb4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The official within the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering who is responsible for science and technology.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25eb5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25eb6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The official within the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment who is responsible for environmental security.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25eb7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Assistant Secretary of Energy for Defense programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25eb8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The Assistant Secretary of Energy responsible for environmental restoration and waste management.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25eb9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The Director of the Department of Energy Office of Science.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25eba-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25ebb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> One representative from each of the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Coast Guard.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25ebc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> The Executive Director of the Council (appointed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2903">section 2903 of this title</ref>), who shall be a nonvoting member.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f25ebd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall designate a member of the Council as chairman for each odd numbered fiscal year. The Secretary of Energy shall designate a member of the Council as chairman for each even-numbered fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f25ebe-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><chapeau> The Council shall have the following responsibilities:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25ebf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> To prescribe policies and procedures to implement the Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25ec0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> To enter into contracts, grants, and other financial arrangements, in accordance with other applicable law, to carry out the purposes of the Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25ec1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> To prepare an annual report that contains the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9f25ec2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A description of activities of the strategic environmental research and development program carried out during the fiscal year before the fiscal year in which the report is prepared.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9f25ec3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A general outline of the activities planned for the program during the fiscal year in which the report is prepared.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9f25ec4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/d/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> A summary of projects continued from the fiscal year before the fiscal year in which the report is prepared and projects expected to be started during the fiscal year in which the report is prepared and during the following fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9f25ec5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/d/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> A summary of the actions of the Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program Scientific Advisory Board during the year preceding the year in which the report is submitted and any recommendations, including recommendations on program direction and legislation, that the Advisory Board considers appropriate regarding the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25ec6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> To promote the maximum exchange of information, and to minimize duplication, regarding environmentally related research, development, and demonstration activities through close coordination with the military departments and Defense Agencies, the Department of Energy, the Environmental Protection Agency, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, other departments and agencies of the Federal Government or any State and local governments, including the National Science and Technology Council, and other organizations engaged in such activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25ec7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> To ensure that research and development activities under the Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program do not duplicate other ongoing activities sponsored by the Department of Defense, the Department of Energy, the Environmental Protection Agency, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, or any other department or agency of the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25ec8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> To ensure that the research and development programs identified for support pursuant to policies and procedures prescribed by the council utilize, to the maximum extent possible, the talents, skills, and abilities residing at the Federal laboratories, including the Department of Energy multiprogram and defense laboratories, the Department of Defense laboratories, and Federal contract research centers. To utilize the research capabilities of institutions of higher education and private industry to the extent practicable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f25ec9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><chapeau> In carrying out subsection (d)(1), the Council shall prescribe policies and procedures that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25eca-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> provide for appropriate access by Federal Government personnel, State and local government personnel, college and university personnel, industry personnel, and the general public to data under the control of, or otherwise available to, the Department of Defense that is relevant to environmental matters by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9f25ecb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> identifying the sources of such data;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9f25ecc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> publicizing the availability and sources of such data by appropriately-targeted dissemination of information to such personnel and the general public, and by other means; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9f25ecd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> providing for review of classified data relevant to environmental matters with a view to declassifying or preparing unclassified summaries of such data;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25ece-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> provide governmental and nongovernmental entities with analytic assistance, consistent with national defense missions, including access to military platforms for sensor deployment and access to computer capabilities, in order to facilitate environmental research;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25ecf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> provide for the identification of energy technologies developed for national defense purposes (including electricity generation systems, energy storage systems, alternative fuels, biomass energy technology, and applied materials technology) that might have environmentally sound, energy efficient applications for other programs of the Department of Defense and the Department of Energy national security programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25ed0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> provide for the identification and support of programs of basic and applied research, development, and demonstration in technologies useful—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9f25ed1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/e/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to facilitate environmental compliance, remediation, and restoration activities of the Department of Defense and at Department of Energy defense facilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9f25ed2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/e/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to minimize waste generation, including reduction at the source, by such departments; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9f25ed3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/e/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> to substitute use of nonhazardous, nontoxic, nonpolluting, and other environmentally sound materials and substances for use of hazardous, toxic, and polluting materials and substances by such departments;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25ed4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> provide for the identification and support of research, development, and application of other technologies developed for national defense purposes which not only are directly useful for programs, projects, and activities of such departments, but also have useful applications for solutions to such national and international environmental problems as climate change and ozone depletion;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25ed5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/e/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> provide for the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Energy, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, in cooperation with other Federal and State agencies, as appropriate, to conduct joint research, development, and demonstration projects relating to innovative technologies, management practices, and other approaches for purposes of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9f25ed6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/e/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> preventing pollution from all sources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9f25ed7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/e/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> minimizing hazardous and solid waste, including recycling; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida9f25ed8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/e/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> treating hazardous and solid waste, including the use of thermal, chemical, and biological treatment technologies;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25ed9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/e/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> encourage transfer of technologies referred to in clauses (2) through (6) to the private sector under the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3701">15 U.S.C. 3701</ref> et seq.) and other applicable laws;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25eda-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/e/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> provide for the identification of, and planning for the demonstration and use of, existing environmentally sound, energy-efficient technologies developed by the private sector that could be used directly by the Department of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25edb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/e/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> provide for the identification of military specifications that prevent or limit the use of environmentally beneficial technologies, materials, and substances in the performance of Department of Defense contracts and recommend changes to such specifications; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25edc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/e/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> to ensure that the research and development programs identified for support pursuant to the policies and procedures prescribed by the Council are closely coordinated with, and do not duplicate, ongoing activities sponsored by the Department of Defense, the Department of Energy, the Environmental Protection Agency, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, or other Federal agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f25edd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> The Council shall be subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of Defense in prescribing policies and procedures under subsection (d)(1).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f25ede-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2902/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> Not later than February 1 of each year, the Council shall submit to the Secretary of Defense the annual report prepared pursuant to subsection (d)(3).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida9f25edf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXVIII/s1801/a/1">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XVIII, § 1801(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1751">104 Stat. 1751</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/dA/tII/s257/a">Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title II, § 257(a)</ref>, title X, § 1061(a)(19), <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1331">105 Stat. 1331</ref>, 1473; <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dA/tX/s1052/38">Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1052(38)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2501">106 Stat. 2501</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tII/s265/a">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title II, § 265(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1611">107 Stat. 1611</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tII/s203/a">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title II, § 203(a)</ref>–(b)(2), (c), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/217">110 Stat. 217</ref>, 218; <ref href="/us/pl/105/245/tIII/s309/b/2/B">Pub. L. 105–245, title III, § 309(b)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-07">Oct. 7, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1853">112 Stat. 1853</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tIII/s324">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title III, § 324</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/563">113 Stat. 563</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title III, § 313(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–55; <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tX/s1031/a/52">Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(52)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1603">117 Stat. 1603</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/dA/tIX/s901/j/5">Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title IX, § 901(j)(5)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4324">124 Stat. 4324</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tIX/s902/80">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(80)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1553">133 Stat. 1553</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida9f25ee0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida9f25ee1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="ida9f25ee2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980, referred to in subsec. (e)(7), is <ref href="/us/pl/96/480">Pub. L. 96–480</ref>, <date date="1980-10-21">Oct. 21, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2311">94 Stat. 2311</ref>, as amended, which is classified generally to chapter 63 (§ 3701 et seq.) of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3701">section 3701 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida9f25ee3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s902/80/A">Pub. L. 116–92, § 902(80)(A)</ref>, substituted “Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering” for “Office of the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s902/80/B">Pub. L. 116–92, § 902(80)(B)</ref>, substituted “Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment” for “Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s901/j/5/A">Pub. L. 111–383, § 901(j)(5)(A)</ref>, substituted “official within the Office of the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering who is responsible for science and technology” for “Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Science and Technology”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s901/j/5/B">Pub. L. 111–383, § 901(j)(5)(B)</ref>, substituted “official within the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics who is” for “Deputy Under Secretary of Defense”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136">Pub. L. 108–136</ref> struck out designation for par. (1) before “Not later than February” and struck out par. (2) which read as follows: “Not later than March 15 of each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit such annual report to Congress, along with such comments as the Secretary considers appropriate.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (d)(3)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/106/398">Pub. L. 106–398</ref> added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/106/65">Pub. L. 106–65</ref> substituted “Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Science and Technology” for “Director of Defense Research and Engineering”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (b)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/105/245">Pub. L. 105–245</ref> substituted “Science” for “Energy Research”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s203/a/1">Pub. L. 104–106, § 203(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “12” for “thirteen” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3) to (7). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s203/a/2">Pub. L. 104–106, § 203(a)(2)</ref>, (3), redesignated pars. (4) to (8) as (3) to (7), respectively, and struck out former par. (3) which read as follows: “The Assistant Secretary of the Air Force responsible for matters relating to space.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s203/a/3">Pub. L. 104–106, § 203(a)(3)</ref>, (4), redesignated par. (9) as (8) and struck out “, who shall be nonvoting members” after “Coast Guard”. Former par. (8) redesignated (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9), (10). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s203/a/3">Pub. L. 104–106, § 203(a)(3)</ref>, redesignated pars. (9) and (10) as (8) and (9), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s203/b/1/A">Pub. L. 104–106, § 203(b)(1)(A)</ref>, added par. (3) and struck out former par. (3) which read as follows: “To prepare an annual five-year strategic environmental research and development plan that shall cover the fiscal year in which the plan is prepared and the four fiscal years following such fiscal year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s203/b/1/B">Pub. L. 104–106, § 203(b)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “National Science and Technology Council” for “Federal Coordinating Council on Science, Engineering, and Technology”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s203/c">Pub. L. 104–106, § 203(c)</ref>, substituted “national security programs” for “national security programs, particularly technologies that have the potential for industrial, commercial, and other governmental applications, and to support programs of research in and development of such applications”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (f), (g). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s203/b/2">Pub. L. 104–106, § 203(b)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (g), redesignated former subsec. (g) as (f), and struck out former subsec. (f) which authorized Secretaries of Defense and Energy to submit to the Council proposals for conducting environmental research under this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s203/b/2/A">Pub. L. 104–106, § 203(b)(2)(A)</ref>, struck out subsec. (h) which required Council to submit to Secretary of Defense and to Congress an annual report on annual five-year strategic environmental research and development plan.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (b)(1) to (4). <ref href="/us/pl/103/160/s265/a/1">Pub. L. 103–160, § 265(a)(1)</ref>–(3), redesignated pars. (2) to (4) as (1) to (3), respectively, added par. (4), and struck out former par. (1) which read as follows: “The Assistant Secretary of Defense responsible for matters relating to production and logistics.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/103/160/s265/a/4">Pub. L. 103–160, § 265(a)(4)</ref>, added par. (6) and struck out former par. (6) which read as follows: “The Director of the Department of Energy Office of Environmental Restoration and Waste Management.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (b)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484">Pub. L. 102–484</ref> substituted “nonvoting” for “non-voting”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/s257/a/1">Pub. L. 102–190, § 257(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “thirteen” for “nine” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9), (10). <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/s257/a/2">Pub. L. 102–190, § 257(a)(2)</ref>, (3), added par. (9) and redesignated former par. (9) as (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/s1061/a/19">Pub. L. 102–190, § 1061(a)(19)</ref>, substituted “department’s” for “Department’s”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida9f25ee4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida9f25ee5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2011 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/383">Pub. L. 111–383</ref> effective <date date="2011-01-01">Jan. 1, 2011</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s901/p">section 901(p) of Pub. L. 111–383</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s131">section 131 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida9f25ee6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tII/s203/b/3">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title II, § 203(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/218">110 Stat. 218</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tII/s203/b/3">“The amendments made by this subsection [amending this section] shall apply with respect to the annual report prepared during fiscal year 1997 and each fiscal year thereafter.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="ida9f25ee7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9f25ee8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">First Annual Report of Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program Council</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXVIII/s1801/c">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XVIII, § 1801(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1758">104 Stat. 1758</ref>, provided that the first annual report required by former subsec. (h) of this section be submitted to Secretary of Defense, Secretary of Energy, and Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency not later than <date date="1992-02-01">Feb. 1, 1992</date>, that the Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program Council conduct and include as part of report an assessment of advisability of, and various alternatives to, charging fees for information released, as required pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2901/b/3">section 2901(b)(3) of this title</ref> and subsecs. (e)(1), (2), and (g)(2)(I) [now (f)(2)(I)] of this section, to private sector entities operating for a profit, and that Secretary of Defense, Secretary of Energy, and Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency submit to Congress any recommendations for changes in structure or personnel of Council that Secretaries and Administrator consider necessary to carry out environmental activities of strategic environmental research and development program.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
