<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida9f25ef6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2904"><num value="2904">§ 2904.</num><heading> Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program Scientific Advisory Board</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f25ef7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2904/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall jointly appoint a Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program Scientific Advisory Board (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Advisory Board”) consisting of not less than six and not more than 14 members.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f25ef8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2904/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f25ef9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2904/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The following persons shall be permanent members of the Advisory Board:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25efa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2904/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Science Advisor to the President, or his designee.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25efb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2904/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, or his designee.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f25efc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2904/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Other members of the Advisory Board shall be appointed from among persons eminent in the fields of basic sciences, engineering, ocean and environmental sciences, education, research management, international and security affairs, health physics, health sciences, or social sciences, with due regard given to the equitable representation of scientists and engineers who are women or who represent minority groups. At least one member of the Advisory Board shall be a representative of environmental public interest groups and one member shall be a representative of the interests of State governments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f25efd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2904/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall request—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25efe-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2904/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> that the head of the National Academy of Sciences, in consultation with the head of the National Academy of Engineering and the head of the Institutes of Medicine of the National Academy of Sciences, nominate persons for appointment to the Advisory Board;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25eff-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2904/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> that the Council on Environmental Quality nominate for appointment to the Advisory Board at least one person who is a representative of environmental public interest groups; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f25f00-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2904/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> that the National Association of Governors nominate for appointment to the Advisory Board at least one person who is representative of the interests of State governments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f25f01-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2904/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Members of the Advisory Board shall be appointed for terms of not less than two and not more than four years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f25f02-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2904/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> A member of the Advisory Board who is not otherwise employed by the Federal Government shall not be considered to be a Federal employee, except for the purposes of chapter 81 of title 5 (relating to compensation for work-related injuries) and chapter 171 of title 28 (relating to tort claims).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f25f03-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2904/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> The Advisory Board shall prescribe procedures for carrying out its responsibilities. Such procedures shall define a quorum as a majority of the members, provide for annual election of the Chairman by the members of the Advisory Board, and require at least four meetings of the Advisory Board each year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f25f04-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2904/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> The Council shall refer to the Advisory Board, and the Advisory Board shall review, each proposed research project including its estimated cost, for research in and development of technologies related to environmental activities in excess of $1,000,000. The Advisory Board shall make any recommendations to the Council that the Advisory Board considers appropriate regarding such project or proposal.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f25f05-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2904/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> The Advisory Board may make recommendations to the Council regarding technologies, research, projects, programs, activities, and, if appropriate, funding within the scope of the Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f25f06-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2904/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> The Advisory Board shall assist and advise the Council in identifying the environmental data and analytical assistance activities that should be covered by the policies and procedures prescribed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2902/d/1">section 2902(d)(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f25f07-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2904/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content> Each member of the Advisory Board shall be required to file a financial disclosure report under subchapter I of chapter 131 of title 5.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida9f25f08-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXVIII/s1801/a/1">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XVIII, § 1801(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1756">104 Stat. 1756</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/dA/tII/s257/b">Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title II, § 257(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1331">105 Stat. 1331</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tIII/s341">Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title III, § 341</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1686">111 Stat. 1686</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title III, § 313(a)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–55; <ref href="/us/pl/117/286/s4/c/21">Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(c)(21)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4356">136 Stat. 4356</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida9f25f09-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida9f25f0a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida9f25f0b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/117/286">Pub. L. 117–286</ref> substituted “subchapter I of chapter 131 of title 5.” for “title I of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsecs. (h), (i). <ref href="/us/pl/106/398">Pub. L. 106–398</ref> redesignated subsec. (i) as (h) and struck out former subsec. (h) which read as follows: “Not later than March 15 of each year, the Advisory Board shall submit to the Congress an annual report setting forth its actions during the year preceding the year in which the report is submitted and any recommendations, including recommendations on projects, programs, and information exchange and recommendations for legislation, that the Advisory Board considers appropriate regarding the Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85">Pub. L. 105–85</ref> substituted “not less than two and not more than four” for “three years”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/s257/b/1">Pub. L. 102–190, § 257(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “14 members” for “13 members”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/s257/b/2">Pub. L. 102–190, § 257(b)(2)</ref>, added par. (1) and struck out former par. (1) which read as follows: “The Science Advisor to the President, or his designee, shall be a permanent member of the Advisory Board.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida9f25f0c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9f25f0d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Initial Appointments of Advisory Board Members</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXVIII/s1801/b">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XVIII, § 1801(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1757">104 Stat. 1757</ref>, directed Secretary of Defense and Secretary of Energy to make the appointments required by <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2904/a">10 U.S.C. 2904(a)</ref> not later than 60 days after <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, and provided that up to one-half of the members originally appointed to the Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program Scientific Advisory Board could be appointed for terms of not more than six and not less than two years in order to provide for staggered expiration of the terms of members.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9f25f0e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">First Annual Report of Advisory Board</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXVIII/s1801/d">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XVIII, § 1801(d)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1758">104 Stat. 1758</ref>, directed that first annual report of the Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program Scientific Advisory Board be submitted not later than <date date="1992-03-15">Mar. 15, 1992</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida9f25f0f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Advisory Boards</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Advisory boards established after <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on the date of their establishment, unless, in the case of a board established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such board is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a board established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided for by law. See sections 1001(2) and 1013 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
