<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida9f989de-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2915"><num value="2915">§ 2915.</num><heading> Facilities: use of renewable forms of energy and energy efficient products</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f989df-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2915/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Renewable Forms of Energy Encouraged</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall encourage the use of energy systems using solar energy or other renewable forms of energy as a source of energy for military construction projects (including military family housing projects) and facility repairs and renovations where use of such form of energy is consistent with the energy performance goals and energy performance master plan for the Department of Defense developed under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2911">section 2911 of this title</ref> and supported by the special considerations specified in subsection (e) of such section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f989e0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2915/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consideration During Design Phase of Projects</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f989e1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2915/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary concerned shall require that the design for the construction, repair, or renovation of facilities (including family housing and back-up power generation facilities) requires consideration of energy systems using solar energy or other renewable forms of energy when use of a renewable form of energy—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f989e2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2915/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is consistent with the energy performance goals and energy performance master plan for the Department of Defense developed under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2911">section 2911 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f989e3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2915/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> supported by the special considerations specified in subsection (e) of such section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f989e4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2915/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary concerned shall require that contracts for construction resulting from such design include a requirement that energy systems using solar energy or other renewable forms of energy be installed if such systems can be shown to be cost effective.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f989e5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2915/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Determination of Cost Effectiveness</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f989e6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2915/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> For the purposes of this section, an energy system using solar energy or other renewable forms of energy for a facility shall be considered to be cost effective if the difference between (A) the original investment cost of the energy system for the facility with such a system, and (B) the original investment cost of the energy system for the facility without such a system can be recovered over the expected life of the facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f989e7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2915/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A determination under paragraph (1) concerning whether a cost-differential can be recovered over the expected life of a facility shall be made using the life-cycle cost methods and procedures established pursuant to section 544(a) of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8254/a">42 U.S.C. 8254(a)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f989e8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2915/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception to Square Feet and Cost Per Square Foot Limitations</inline>.—</heading><content>In order to equip a military construction project (including a military family housing project) with heating equipment, cooling equipment, or both heating and cooling equipment using solar energy or other renewable forms of energy or with a passive energy system using solar energy or other renewable forms of energy, the Secretary concerned may authorize an increase in any otherwise applicable limitation with respect to the number of square feet or the cost per square foot of the project by such amount as may be necessary for such purpose. Any such increase under this subsection shall be in addition to any other administrative increase in cost per square foot or variation in floor area authorized by law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f989e9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2915/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Energy Efficient Products in Facilities</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f989ea-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2915/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that energy efficient products meeting the requirements of the Department of Defense are used in construction, repair, or renovation of facilities by or for the Department carried out under chapter 169 of this title if such products are readily available and their use is consistent with the energy performance goals and energy performance master plan for the Department developed under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2911">section 2911 of this title</ref> and supported by the special considerations specified in subsection (e) of such section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f989eb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2915/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f989ec-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2915/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe a definition of the term “energy-efficient product” for purposes of this subsection and establish and maintain a list of products satisfying the definition. The definition and list shall be developed in consultation with the Secretary of Energy to ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, consistency with definitions of the term used by other Federal agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f989ed-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2915/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary shall modify the definition and list of energy-efficient products as necessary to account for emerging or changing technologies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f989ee-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2915/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The list of energy-efficient products shall be included as part of the energy performance master plan developed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2911/d/2">section 2911(d)(2) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida9f989ef-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2915/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> In determining the energy efficiency of products, the Secretary shall consider products that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f989f0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2915/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> meet or exceed Energy Star specifications; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida9f989f1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s2915/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> are listed on the Federal Energy Management Program Product Energy Efficiency Recommendations product list of the Department of Energy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida9f989f2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/97/214/s2/a">Pub. L. 97–214, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-07-12">July 12, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/166">96 Stat. 166</ref>, § 2857; amended <ref href="/us/pl/97/321/tVIII/s801/b/1">Pub. L. 97–321, title VIII, § 801(b)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1982-10-15">Oct. 15, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1571">96 Stat. 1571</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/525/tXIV/s1405/45/A">Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1405(45)(A)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2625">98 Stat. 2625</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/218/s8/b">Pub. L. 101–218, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-11">Dec. 11, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1868">103 Stat. 1868</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dB/tXXVIII/s2852/b">Pub. L. 101–510, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2852(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1804">104 Stat. 1804</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/25/tVII/s701/g/2">Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 701(g)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/115">105 Stat. 115</ref>; renumbered § 2915 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dB/tXXVIII">Pub. L. 109–364, div. B, title XXVIII</ref>, §§ 2851(b)(1), (3)(A), 2854, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2494">120 Stat. 2494</ref>, 2497; <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/dB/tXXVIII/s2832/b">Pub. L. 111–383, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2832(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4468">124 Stat. 4468</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/dB/tXXVIII/s2825/a">Pub. L. 112–81, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2825(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1693">125 Stat. 1693</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dB/tXXVIII/s2831/c/2">Pub. L. 115–91, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2831(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1857">131 Stat. 1857</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida9f989f3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida9f989f4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida9f989f5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—Subsecs. (a), (b)(1)(B), (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s2831/c/2/A">Pub. L. 115–91, § 2831(c)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “subsection (e)” for “subsection (c)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s2831/c/2/B">Pub. L. 115–91, § 2831(c)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “2911(d)(2)” for “2911(b)(2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—<ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s2832/b/4">Pub. L. 111–383, § 2832(b)(4)</ref>, substituted “Facilities: use of renewable forms of energy and energy efficient products” for “New construction: use of renewable forms of energy and energy efficient products” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s2832/b/1">Pub. L. 111–383, § 2832(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “and facility repairs and renovations” after “military family housing projects)” and substituted “energy performance master plan” for “energy performance plan”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s2832/b/2">Pub. L. 111–383, § 2832(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “the design for the construction, repair, or renovation of facilities (including family housing and back-up power generation facilities) requires consideration of energy systems using solar energy or other renewable forms of energy when use of a renewable form of energy—” for “the design of all new facilities (including family housing) shall include consideration of energy systems using solar energy or other renewable forms of energy.” and added subpars. (A) and (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s2832/b/3/A">Pub. L. 111–383, § 2832(b)(3)(A)</ref>, substituted “Use of Energy Efficient Products in Facilities” for “Use of Energy Efficiency Products in New Construction” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s2832/b/3/B">Pub. L. 111–383, § 2832(b)(3)(B)</ref>, substituted “construction, repair, or renovation of facilities” for “new facility construction” and “energy performance master plan” for “energy performance plan”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/112/81">Pub. L. 112–81</ref> added par. (2) and struck out former par. (2), which related to energy efficient products and provided examples of technologies, consistent with the products specified in paragraph (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s2832/b/3/D">Pub. L. 111–383, § 2832(b)(3)(D)</ref>, added par. (2). Former par. (2) redesignated (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s2832/b/3/C">Pub. L. 111–383, § 2832(b)(3)(C)</ref>, redesignated par. (2) as (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—<ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s2854/b/1">Pub. L. 109–364, § 2854(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “New construction: use of renewable forms of energy and energy efficient products” for “Use of renewable forms of energy in new facilities” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s2851/b/1">Pub. L. 109–364, § 2851(b)(1)</ref>, renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2857">section 2857 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s2854/b/2">Pub. L. 109–364, § 2854(b)(2)</ref>,(3)(A)(i), inserted heading and substituted “is consistent with the energy performance goals and energy performance plan for the Department of Defense developed under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2911">section 2911 of this title</ref> and supported by the special considerations specified in subsection (c) of such section” for “would be practical and economically feasible”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s2854/b/3">Pub. L. 109–364, § 2854(b)(3)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s2851/b/3/A/ii">Pub. L. 109–364, § 2851(b)(3)(A)(ii)</ref>, struck out “in those cases in which use of such forms of energy has the potential for reduced energy costs” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s2854/b/4">Pub. L. 109–364, § 2854(b)(4)</ref>, (5) inserted headings.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s2854/a">Pub. L. 109–364, § 2854(a)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/25">Pub. L. 102–25</ref> inserted “(<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s8254/a">42 U.S.C. 8254(a)</ref>)” after “Policy Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (c)(2), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510">Pub. L. 101–510</ref> added par. (2) and struck out former pars. (2) and (3) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2) A determination under paragraph (1) of whether a cost-differential can be recovered over the expected life of a facility shall be made using accepted life-cycle costing procedures and shall include—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) the use of all capital expenses and all operating and maintenance expenses associated with the energy system with and without an energy system using solar energy or other renewable forms of energy over the expected life of the facility or during a period of 25 years, whichever is shorter;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) the use of fossil fuel costs (and a rate of cost growth for fossil fuel costs) as determined by the Secretary of Defense; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) the use of a discount rate of 7 percent per year for all expenses of the energy system.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(3) For the purpose of any life-cycle cost analysis under this subsection, the original investment cost of the energy system using solar energy or other renewable forms of energy shall be reduced by 10 percent to reflect an allowance for an investment cost credit.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/218">Pub. L. 101–218</ref> substituted “reduced energy costs” for “significant savings of fossil-fuel-derived energy”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/525">Pub. L. 98–525</ref> substituted “use of such forms of energy has the potential for” for “use of solar energy has the potential for”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—<ref href="/us/pl/97/321/s801/b/2">Pub. L. 97–321, § 801(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “renewable forms of energy in new facilities” for “solar energy systems” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/321/s801/b/1/A">Pub. L. 97–321, § 801(b)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “energy systems using solar energy or other renewable forms of energy” and “such form of energy would” for “solar energy systems” and “solar energy would”, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/97/321/s801/b/1/B">Pub. L. 97–321, § 801(b)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “energy systems using solar energy or other renewable forms of energy” for “solar energy systems” and directed that “such form of energy has” be substituted for “a solar energy has”, but “a solar energy has” did not appear in par. (1). See 1984 Amendment note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/97/321/s801/b/1/B/i">Pub. L. 97–321, § 801(b)(1)(B)(i)</ref>, substituted “energy systems using solar energy or other renewable forms of energy” for “solar energy systems”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/321/s801/b/1/C">Pub. L. 97–321, § 801(b)(1)(C)</ref>–(E), substituted: in par. (1) “an energy system using solar energy or other renewable forms of energy” for “a solar energy system” before “for a facility” and in items (A) and (B) “such a system” for “a solar energy system”; in par. (2)(A) “an energy system using solar energy or other renewable forms of energy” for “a solar energy system”; and in par. (3) “energy system using solar energy or other renewable forms of energy” for “solar energy system”, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/321/s801/b/1/F">Pub. L. 97–321, § 801(b)(1)(F)</ref>, substituted “heating equipment, cooling equipment, or both heating and cooling equipment using solar energy or other renewable forms of energy or with a passive energy energy system using solar energy or other renewable forms of energy” for “solar heating equipment, solar cooling equipment, or both solar heating and solar cooling equipment, or with a passive solar energy system”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida9f989f6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida9f989f7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/525/tXIV/s1405/45/B">Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1405(45)(B)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2625">98 Stat. 2625</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/525/tXIV/s1405/45/B">“The amendment made by subparagraph (A) [amending this section] shall take effect as if it had been included in the amendments made by <ref href="/us/pl/97/321/s801">section 801 of Public Law 97–321</ref>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="ida9f989f8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date and applicability of section, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/214/s12/a">section 12(a) of Pub. L. 97–214</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2801">section 2801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
