<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idaa0c9cfa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3138"><num value="3138">§ 3138.</num><heading> Obligations for contract services: reporting in budget object classes</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa0c9cfb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3138/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Reporting in Miscellaneous Services Object Class</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that, in reporting to the Office of Management and Budget (pursuant to OMB Circular A–11 (relating to preparation and submission of budget estimates)) obligations of the Department of Defense for any period of time for contract services, no more than 15 percent of the total amount of obligations so reported is reported in the miscellaneous services object class.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa0c9cfc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3138/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition of Reporting Categories for Advisory and Assistance Services</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In carrying out <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105/g">section 1105(g) of title 31</ref> for the Department of Defense (and in determining what services are to be reported to the Office of Management and Budget in the advisory and assistance services object class), the Secretary of Defense shall apply to the terms used for the definition of “advisory and assistance services” in paragraph (2)(A) of that section the following meanings (subject to the authorized exemptions):</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa0c9cfd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3138/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Management and professional support services</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “management and professional support services” (used in clause (i) of <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105/g/2/A">section 1105(g)(2)(A) of title 31</ref>) means services that provide engineering or technical support, assistance, advice, or training for the efficient and effective management and operation of organizations, activities, or systems. Those services—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa0c9cfe-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3138/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> are closely related to the basic responsibilities and mission of the using organization; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa0c9cff-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3138/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> include efforts that support or contribute to improved organization or program management, logistics management, project monitoring and reporting, data collection, budgeting, accounting, auditing, and administrative or technical support for conferences and training programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa0c9d00-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3138/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Studies, analyses, and evaluations</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “studies, analyses, and evaluations” (used in clause (ii) of <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105/g/2/A">section 1105(g)(2)(A) of title 31</ref>) means services that provide organized, analytic assessments to understand or evaluate complex issues to improve policy development, decisionmaking, management, or administration and that result in documents containing data or leading to conclusions or recommendations. Those services may include databases, models, methodologies, and related software created in support of a study, analysis, or evaluation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa0c9d01-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3138/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Engineering and technical services</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “engineering and technical services” (used in clause (iii) of <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105/g/2/A">section 1105(g)(2)(A) of title 31</ref>) means services that take the form of advice, assistance, training, or hands-on training necessary to maintain and operate fielded weapon systems, equipment, and components (including software when applicable) at design or required levels of effectiveness.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa0c9d02-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3138/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Proper Classification of Advisory and Assistance Services</inline>.—</heading><content>Before the submission to the Office of Management and Budget of the proposed Department of Defense budget for inclusion in the President’s budget for a fiscal year pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105">section 1105 of title 31</ref>, the Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller), shall conduct a review of Department of Defense services expected to be performed as contract services during the fiscal year for which that budget is to be submitted in order to ensure that those services that are advisory and assistance services (as defined in accordance with subsection (b)) are in fact properly classified, in accordance with that subsection, in the advisory and assistance services object class.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa0c9d03-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3138/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall submit to Congress each year, not later than 30 days after the date on which the budget for the next fiscal year is submitted pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105">section 1105 of title 31</ref>, a report containing the information derived from the review under subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa0c9d04-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3138/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assessment by Comptroller General</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa0c9d05-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3138/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Comptroller General shall conduct a review of the report of the Secretary of Defense under subsection (d) each year and shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa0c9d06-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3138/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> assess the methodology used by the Secretary in obtaining the information submitted to Congress in that report; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa0c9d07-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3138/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> assess the information submitted to Congress in that report.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa0c9d08-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3138/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Not later than 120 days after the date on which the Secretary submits to Congress the report required under subsection (d) for any year, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress the Comptroller General’s report containing the results of the review for that year under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa0c9d09-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3138/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa0c9d0a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3138/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “contract services” means all services that are reported to the Office of Management and Budget pursuant to OMB Circular A–11 (relating to preparation and submission of budget estimates) in budget object classes that are designated in the Object Class 25 series.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa0c9d0b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3138/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “advisory and assistance services object class” means those contract services constituting the budget object class that is denominated “Advisory and Assistance Service” and designated (as of <date date="1998-10-17">October 17, 1998</date>) as Object Class 25.1 (or any similar object class established after <date date="1998-10-17">October 17, 1998</date>, for the reporting of obligations for advisory and assistance contract services).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa0c9d0c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3138/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “miscellaneous services object class” means those contract services constituting the budget object class that is denominated “Other Services (services not otherwise specified in the 25 series)” and designated (as of <date date="1998-10-17">October 17, 1998</date>) as Object Class 25.2 (or any similar object class established after <date date="1998-10-17">October 17, 1998</date>, for the reporting of obligations for miscellaneous or unspecified contract services).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa0c9d0d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3138/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The term “authorized exemptions” means those exemptions authorized (as of <date date="1998-10-17">October 17, 1998</date>) under Department of Defense Directive 4205.2, captioned “Acquiring and Managing Contracted Advisory and Assistance Services (CAAS)” and issued by the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Technology on <date date="1992-02-10">February 10, 1992</date>, such exemptions being set forth in Enclosure 3 to that directive (captioned “CAAS Exemptions”).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idaa0c9d0e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/105/261/dA/tIX/s911/a/1">Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title IX, § 911(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2097">112 Stat. 2097</ref>, § 2212; amended <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tX/s1066/a/17">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1066(a)(17)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/771">113 Stat. 771</ref>; renumbered § 3138, <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXVIII/s1809/i/1">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1809(i)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4162">134 Stat. 4162</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idaa0c9d0f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idaa0c9d10-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idaa0c9d11-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—<ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2212">section 2212 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (f)(2), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/106/65">Pub. L. 106–65</ref> substituted “as of <date date="1998-10-17">October 17, 1998</date>” for “as of the date of the enactment of this section” and “after <date date="1998-10-17">October 17, 1998</date>,” for “after the date of the enactment of this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/s1066/a/17/B">Pub. L. 106–65, § 1066(a)(17)(B)</ref>, substituted “as of <date date="1998-10-17">October 17, 1998</date>” for “as of the date of the enactment of this section”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idaa0c9d12-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idaa0c9d13-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reference to Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Technology deemed to refer to Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics, pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/s911/a/1">section 911(a)(1) of Pub. L. 106–65</ref>, formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s133">section 133 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idaa0c9d14-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> effective <date date="2022-01-01">Jan. 1, 2022</date>, with additional provisions for delayed implementation and applicability of existing law, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1801/d">section 1801(d) of Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
