<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idaa13c877-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3207"><num value="3207">§ 3207.</num><heading> Assessment before contract for acquisition of supplies is entered into</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0"> The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that before a contract for the delivery of supplies to the Department of Defense is entered into—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa13c878-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3207/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> when the appropriate officials of the Department are making an assessment of the most advantageous source for acquisition of the supplies (considering quality, price, delivery, and other factors), there is a review of the availability and cost of each item of supply—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa13c879-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3207/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> through the supply system of the Department of Defense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa13c87a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3207/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> under standard Government supply contracts, if the item is in a category of supplies defined under regulations of the Secretary of Defense as being potentially available under a standard Government supply contract; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa13c87b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3207/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> there is a review of both the procurement history of the item and a description of the item, including, when necessary for an adequate description of the item, a picture, drawing, diagram, or other graphic representation of the item.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idaa13c87c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added and amended <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXVIII/s1811/f">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1811(f)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4173">134 Stat. 4173</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idaa13c87d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idaa13c87e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idaa13c87f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The text of subsec. (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2305">section 2305 of this title</ref>, which was transferred to this section and amended by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1811/f/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1811(f)(2)</ref>, was based on <ref href="/us/pl/98/525/tXII/s1213/a">Pub. L. 98–525, title XII, § 1213(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2591">98 Stat. 2591</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idaa13c880-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 3207, <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041">act Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/173">70A Stat. 173</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/155/tI/s101/5">Pub. L. 85–155, title I, § 101(5)</ref>, <date date="1957-08-21">Aug. 21, 1957</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/71/376">71 Stat. 376</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/130/s1/9/C">Pub. L. 90–130, § 1(9)(C)</ref>, (D), <date date="1967-11-08">Nov. 8, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/375">81 Stat. 375</ref>, prescribed authorized strength of Army Medical Specialist Corps in commissioned officers on active list of Regular Army, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/96/513/tII/s202">Pub. L. 96–513, title II, § 202</ref>, title VII, § 701, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2878">94 Stat. 2878</ref>, 2955, effective <date date="1981-09-15">Sept. 15, 1981</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idaa13c881-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—<ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1811/f/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1811(f)(2)</ref>, transferred subsec. (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2305">section 2305 of this title</ref> to this section and struck out subsec. (c) designation at beginning.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idaa13c882-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idaa13c883-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section and amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> effective <date date="2022-01-01">Jan. 1, 2022</date>, with additional provisions for delayed implementation and applicability of existing law, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1801/d">section 1801(d) of Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2021 Amendment note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idaa13c884-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Establishing Biobased Product Merit Guidance</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tII/s248">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title II, § 248</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/799">139 Stat. 799</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tII/s248">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>], the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering, in coordination with the Secretaries of the military departments, shall develop and make publicly available guidance for private entities on how such entities can effectively demonstrate, validate, and verify that a biobased product of such entity provides capabilities meeting the requirements of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Analysis</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In developing the guidance required by subsection (a), the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering shall conduct an analysis of current military specifications for suitable product categories and make such analysis publicly available for use by private entities, such as in industry or academia. Such analysis shall include:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> Assessment of all current military specifications and identification of those that may—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> have existing biobased products that meet such specifications;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> could be met with biobased products with some modification; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> have no military specification where a new one may be required.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Assessment of current validation and verification processes related to military specifications to determine if modifications to such processes are needed to consider biobased product alternatives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Review of existing acquisition policy and practices related to procurement of materials meeting military specifications to determine if any changes to such processes are recommended to accommodate biobased products.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Biobased Product Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘biobased product’ means a product manufactured, produced, or developed through the application of living organisms to alter living or non-living materials.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idaa13c885-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Process for Enhanced Supply Chain Scrutiny</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tVIII/s807">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VIII, § 807</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1456">131 Stat. 1456</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tVIII/s807">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Process</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall establish a process for enhancing scrutiny of acquisition decisions in order to improve the integration of supply chain risk management into the overall acquisition decision cycle.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The process under subsection (a) shall include the following elements:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Designation of a senior official responsible for overseeing the development and implementation of the process.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Development or integration of tools to support commercial due-diligence, business intelligence, or otherwise analyze and monitor commercial activity to understand business relationships with entities determined to be threats to the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Development of risk profiles of products or services based on commercial due-diligence tools and data services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Development of education and training curricula for the acquisition workforce that supports the process.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Integration, as needed, with intelligence sources to develop threat profiles of entities determined to be threats to the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> Periodic review and assessment of software products and services on computer networks of the Department of Defense to remove prohibited products or services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> Synchronization of the use of current authorities for making supply chain decisions, including <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s806">section 806 of Public Law 111–383</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2304">10 U.S.C. 2304</ref> note) or improved use of suspension and debarment officials.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> Coordination with interagency, industrial, and international partners, as appropriate, to share information, develop Government-wide strategies for dealing with significant entities determined to be significant threats to the United States, and effectively use authorities in other departments and agencies to provide consistent, Government-wide approaches to supply chain threats.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> Other matters as the Secretary considers necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 90 days after establishing the process required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide a written notification to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives that the process has been established. The notification also shall include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Identification of the official designated under subsection (b)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Identification of tools and services currently available to the Department of Defense under subsection (b)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Assessment of additional tools and services available under subsection (b)(2) that the Department of Defense should evaluate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Identification of, or recommendations for, any statutory changes needed to improve the effectiveness of the process.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Projected resource needs for implementing any recommendations made by the Secretary.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
