<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idaa188387-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243"><num value="3243">§ 3243.</num><heading> Encouragement of new competitors: qualification requirement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa188388-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Qualification Requirement Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term “qualification requirement” means a requirement for testing or other quality assurance demonstration that must be completed by an offeror before award of a contract.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa188389-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Actions Before Establishing Qualification Requirement</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (c), the head of the agency shall, before establishing a qualification requirement—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa18838a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> prepare a written justification stating the necessity for establishing the qualification requirement and specify why the qualification requirement must be demonstrated before contract award;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa18838b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> specify in writing and make available to a potential offeror upon request all requirements which a prospective offeror, or its product, must satisfy in order to become qualified, such requirements to be limited to those least restrictive to meet the purposes necessitating the establishment of the qualification requirement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa18838c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> specify an estimate of the costs of testing and evaluation likely to be incurred by a potential offeror in order to become qualified;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa18838d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> ensure that a potential offeror is provided, upon request and on a reimbursable basis, a prompt opportunity to demonstrate its ability to meet the standards specified for qualification using qualified personnel and facilities of the agency concerned or of another agency obtained through interagency agreement, or under contract, or other methods approved by the agency (including use of approved testing and evaluation services not provided under contract to the agency);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa18838e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> if testing and evaluation services are provided under contract to the agency for the purposes of paragraph (4), provide to the extent possible that such services be provided by a contractor who is not expected to benefit from an absence of additional qualified sources and who shall be required in such contract to adhere to any restriction on technical data asserted by the potential offeror seeking qualification; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa1af48f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> ensure that a potential offeror seeking qualification is promptly informed as to whether qualification is attained and, in the event qualification is not attained, is promptly furnished specific information why qualification was not attained.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa1af490-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability, Waiver Authority, and Referral of Offers.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa1af491-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading><content>Subsection (b) does not apply with respect to a qualification requirement established by statute or administrative action before <date date="1984-10-19">October 19, 1984</date>, unless such requirement is a qualified products list.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa1af492-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Waiver Authority.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa1af493-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission of determination of unreasonableness</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subparagraph (C), if it is unreasonable to specify the standards for qualification which a prospective offeror or its product must satisfy, a determination to that effect shall be submitted to the advocate for competition of the procuring activity responsible for the purchase of the item subject to the qualification requirement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa1af494-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority to grant waiver</inline>.—</heading><content>After considering any comments of the advocate for competition reviewing such determination, the head of the purchasing office may waive the requirements of clauses (2) through (6) of subsection (b) for up to two years with respect to the item subject to the qualification requirement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa1af495-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability to qualified products list</inline>.—</heading><content>The waiver authority provided in this paragraph does not apply with respect to a qualified products list.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa1af496-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission and consideration of offer not to be denied in certain cases</inline>.—</heading><content>A potential offeror may not be denied the opportunity to submit and have considered an offer for a contract solely because the potential offeror (A) is not on a qualified bidders list, qualified manufacturers list, or qualified products list, or (B) has not been identified as meeting a qualification requirement established after <date date="1984-10-19">October 19, 1984</date>, if the potential offeror can demonstrate to the satisfaction of the contracting officer (or, in the case of a contract for the procurement of an aviation critical safety item or ship critical safety item, the head of the design control activity for such item) that the potential offeror or its product meets the standards established for qualification or can meet such standards before the date specified for award of the contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa1af497-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Referral to small business administration</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing contained in this subsection requires the referral of an offer to the Small Business Administration pursuant to section 8(b)(7) of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s637/b/7">15 U.S.C. 637(b)(7)</ref>) if the basis for the referral is a challenge by the offeror to either the validity of the qualification requirement or the offeror’s compliance with such requirement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa1af498-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Delay of procurement not required</inline>.—</heading><content>The head of an agency need not delay a proposed procurement in order to comply with subsection (b) or in order to provide a potential offeror with an opportunity to demonstrate its ability to meet the standards specified for qualification.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa1af499-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements before enforcement of certain lists</inline>.—</heading><content>The requirements of subsection (b) also apply before enforcement of any qualified products list, qualified manufacturers list, or qualified bidders list.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa1af49a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Fewer Than</inline> 2 <inline class="small-caps">Actual Manufacturers.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa1af49b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Solicitation and testing of additional sources or products</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If the number of qualified sources or qualified products available to compete actively for an anticipated future requirement is fewer than two actual manufacturers or the products of two actual manufacturers, respectively, the head of the agency concerned shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa1af49c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> periodically publish notice in the Commerce Business Daily soliciting additional sources or products to seek qualification, unless the contracting officer determines that such publication would compromise national security; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa1af49d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> bear the cost of conducting the specified testing and evaluation (excluding the costs associated with producing the item or establishing the production, quality control, or other system to be tested and evaluated) for a small business concern or a product manufactured by a small business concern which has met the standards specified for qualification and which could reasonably be expected to compete for a contract for that requirement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa1af49e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certification required</inline>.—</heading><content>The head of an agency shall require a prospective contractor requesting the United States to bear testing and evaluation costs under paragraph (1)(B) to certify as to its status as a small business concern under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s632">15 U.S.C. 632</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa1af49f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Advanced Manufacturing Crisis Qualification Frameworks</inline>.—</heading><content>The head of the agency shall establish a process to streamline and expedite the qualification of advanced manufacturing sources, processes, or products prior to or during wartime or upon activation of the Civil Reserve Manufacturing Network (as defined in section 1832 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002109">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002109"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2026), that addresses materials, systems, and processes using a risk framework suitable for wartime or during periods in which the CRMN is activated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa1af4a0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Examination and Revalidation of Qualification Requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>Within seven years after the establishment of a qualification requirement under subsection (b) or within seven years following an agency’s enforcement of a qualified products list, qualified manufacturers list, or qualified bidders list, any such qualification requirement shall be examined and revalidated in accordance with the requirements of subsection (b). The preceding sentence does not apply in the case of a qualification requirement for which a waiver is in effect under subsection (c)(2).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa1af4a1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Restriction on Enforcement</inline>.—</heading><content>Except in an emergency as determined by the head of the agency, whenever the head of the agency determines not to enforce a qualification requirement for a solicitation, the agency may not thereafter enforce that qualification requirement unless the agency complies with the requirements of subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa1af4a2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa1af4a3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “aviation critical safety item” means a part, an assembly, installation equipment, launch equipment, recovery equipment, or support equipment for an aircraft or aviation weapon system if the part, assembly, or equipment contains a characteristic any failure, malfunction, or absence of which could cause a catastrophic or critical failure resulting in the loss of or serious damage to the aircraft or weapon system, an unacceptable risk of personal injury or loss of life, or an uncommanded engine shutdown that jeopardizes safety.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa1af4a4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “ship critical safety item” means any ship part, assembly, or support equipment containing a characteristic the failure, malfunction, or absence of which could cause a catastrophic or critical failure resulting in loss of or serious damage to the ship or unacceptable risk of personal injury or loss of life.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa1af4a5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3243/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “design control activity”, with respect to an aviation critical safety item or ship critical safety item, means the systems command of a military department that is specifically responsible for ensuring the airworthiness of an aviation system or equipment, or the seaworthiness of a ship or ship equipment, in which such item is to be used.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idaa1af4a6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/98/525/tXII/s1216/a">Pub. L. 98–525, title XII, § 1216(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2593">98 Stat. 2593</ref>, § 2319; amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/26/s7/d/5">Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(d)(5)</ref>, (i)(4), (k)(3), <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/281">101 Stat. 281</ref>, 282, 284; <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tVIII/s802/d">Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title VIII, § 802(d)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1541">117 Stat. 1541</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tI/s130/d">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title I, § 130(d)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2110">120 Stat. 2110</ref>; renumbered § 3243 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXVIII/s1813/d">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1813(d)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4179">134 Stat. 4179</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tVIII/s812/a/6">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title VIII, § 812(a)(6)</ref>, title XVIII, § 1841(f)(2), <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/952">139 Stat. 952</ref>, 1257.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idaa1af4a7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idaa1af4a8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idaa1af4a9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 1832 of National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2026, referred to in subsec. (e), probably means <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s1841">section 1841 of Pub. L. 119–60</ref>, which relates to the Civil Reserve Manufacturing Network. Subsecs. (a) to (e) of section 1841 are set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4811">section 4811 of this title</ref>. Subsec. (f) of section 1841 amends sections 3243 and 4841 of this title. <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s1832">Section 1832 of Pub. L. 119–60</ref>, which amends sections 4402 and 4403 of this title, relates to modifications to requirements for modular open system approach.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idaa1af4aa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (d)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s812/a/6/A">Pub. L. 119–60, § 812(a)(6)(A)</ref>, struck out “subject to paragraph (2),” before “bear the cost”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s812/a/6/B">Pub. L. 119–60, § 812(a)(6)(B)</ref>, (C), redesignated par. (3) as (2) and struck out par. (2). Text of former par. (2) read as follows: “Costs may be borne under paragraph (1)(B) only if the head of the agency determines that such additional qualified sources or products are likely to result in cost savings from increased competition for future requirements sufficient to amortize the costs incurred by the agency within a reasonable period of time considering the duration and dollar value of anticipated future requirements.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e) to (h). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s1841/f/2">Pub. L. 119–60, § 1841(f)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (e) and redesignated former subsecs. (e) to (g) as (f) to (h), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—<ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1813/d/1">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1813(d)(1)</ref>, substituted “Encouragement of new competitors: qualification requirement” for “Encouragement of new competitors” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1813/d">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1813(d)</ref>, renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2319">section 2319 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1813/d/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1813(d)(2)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1813/d/3/A">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1813(d)(3)(A)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1813/d/3/B">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1813(d)(3)(B)</ref>, substituted “paragraph (4)” for “clause (4)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1813/d/4/A">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1813(d)(4)(A)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1813/d/4/A">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1813(d)(4)(A)</ref>, inserted heading and struck out “of this section” after “Subsection (b)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1813/d/4/C/i">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1813(d)(4)(C)(i)</ref>, inserted heading and realigned margin.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1813/d/4/C/i">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1813(d)(4)(C)(i)</ref>, inserted heading and substituted “Except as provided in subparagraph (C),” for “Except as provided in subparagraph (B),”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1813/d/4/C/iii">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1813(d)(4)(C)(iii)</ref>, (iv), redesignated second sentence of subsec. (c)(2)(A) as (B) and inserted heading. Former subpar. (B) redesignated (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(B), (C). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1813/d/4/C/ii">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1813(d)(4)(C)(ii)</ref>, (v), redesignated subpar. (B) as (C) and inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3) to (6). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1813/d/4/B">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1813(d)(4)(B)</ref>, (D)–(G), inserted headings and realigned margins.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1813/d/5/A">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1813(d)(5)(A)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1813/d/5/A">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1813(d)(5)(A)</ref>, (F), inserted heading and realigned margins of subpars. (A) and (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1813/d/5/C">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1813(d)(5)(C)</ref>, inserted “subject to paragraph (2),” before “bear the cost of” and substituted “that requirement.” for “that requirement, but such costs may be borne”. Remainder of subpar. (B) redesignated par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1813/d/5/D">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1813(d)(5)(D)</ref>, (E), designated text of par. (1)(B) beginning with “only if the head” as (2), inserted heading, and inserted “Costs may be borne under paragraph (1)(B)” at beginning. Former par. (2) redesignated (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1813/d/5/B">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1813(d)(5)(B)</ref>, redesignated par. (2) as (3), inserted heading, and realigned margin.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e), (f). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1813/d/6">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1813(d)(6)</ref>, (7), inserted headings.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s130/d/1">Pub. L. 109–364, § 130(d)(1)</ref>, inserted “or ship critical safety item” after “aviation critical safety item”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s130/d/2">Pub. L. 109–364, § 130(d)(2)</ref>, added par. (2), redesignated former par. (2) as (3), inserted “or ship critical safety item” after “aviation critical safety item” and “, or the seaworthiness of a ship or ship equipment,” after “or equipment”, and substituted “such item” for “the item”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/s802/d/1">Pub. L. 108–136, § 802(d)(1)</ref>, inserted “(or, in the case of a contract for the procurement of an aviation critical safety item, the head of the design control activity for such item)” after “the contracting officer”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/s802/d/2">Pub. L. 108–136, § 802(d)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/26/s7/k/3">Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(k)(3)</ref>, inserted “the term” after “In this section,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/26/s7/i/4">Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(i)(4)</ref>, substituted “<date date="1984-10-19">October 19, 1984</date>,” for “the date of the enactment of the Defense Procurement Reform Act of 1984”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/100/26/s7/d/5/A">Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(d)(5)(A)</ref>, inserted “(<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s637/b/7">15 U.S.C. 637(b)(7)</ref>)” after “Small Business Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/26/s7/d/5/B">Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(d)(5)(B)</ref>, inserted “(<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s632">15 U.S.C. 632</ref>)” after “Small Business Act”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idaa1af4ab-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idaa1af4ac-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> effective <date date="2022-01-01">Jan. 1, 2022</date>, with additional provisions for delayed implementation and applicability of existing law, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1801/d">section 1801(d) of Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idaa1af4ad-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/525/tXII/s1216/c/2">Pub. L. 98–525, title XII, § 1216(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2599">98 Stat. 2599</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/525/tXII/s1216/c/2">“Sections 2319 [now <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3243">10 U.S.C. 3243</ref>], [former] 2320, and [former] 2321 of title 10, United States Code (as added by subsection (a)), shall apply with respect to solicitations issued after the end of the one-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
