<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida79e34c2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333"><num value="333">§ 333.</num><heading> Foreign security forces: authority to build capacity</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida79e34c3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense is authorized to conduct or support a program or programs to provide training and equipment to the national security forces of one or more foreign countries for the purpose of building the capacity of such forces to conduct one or more of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida79e34c4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Counterterrorism operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida79e34c5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Counter-weapons of mass destruction operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida79e34c6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Counter-illicit drug trafficking operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida79e34c7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Counter-transnational organized crime operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida79e34c8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Maritime and border security operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida79e34c9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Military intelligence operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida79e34ca-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Air domain awareness operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida79e34cb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> Operations or activities that contribute to an existing international coalition operation that is determined by the Secretary to be in the national interest of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida79e34cc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> Cyberspace security and defensive cyberspace operations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida79e34cd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Concurrence and Coordination With Secretary of State.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida79e34ce-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Concurrence in conduct of programs</inline>.—</heading><content>The concurrence of the Secretary of State is required to conduct or support any program authorized by subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida79e34cf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Joint development and planning of programs</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of State shall jointly develop and plan any program carried out pursuant to subsection (a). In developing and planning a program to build the capacity of the national security forces of a foreign country under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense and Secretary of State should jointly consider political, social, economic, diplomatic, and historical factors, if any, of the foreign country that may impact the effectiveness of the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida79e34d0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation of programs</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of State shall coordinate the implementation of any program under subsection (a). The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of State shall each designate an individual responsible for program coordination under this paragraph at the lowest appropriate level in the Department concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida79e34d1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coordination in preparation of certain notices</inline>.—</heading><content>Any notice required by this section to be submitted to the appropriate committees of Congress shall be prepared in coordination with the Secretary of State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida79e34d2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Types of Capacity Building.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida79e34d3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorized elements</inline>.—</heading><content>A program under subsection (a) may include the provision and sustainment of defense articles, training, defense services, supplies (including consumables), and small-scale construction supporting security cooperation programs under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida79e34d4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Required elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A program under subsection (a) shall include elements that promote the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida79e34d5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Observance of and respect for the law of armed conflict, human rights and fundamental freedoms, the rule of law, and civilian control of the military.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida79e34d6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Institutional capacity building.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida79e34d7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Observance of and respect for the law of armed conflict, human rights and fundamental freedoms, the rule of law, and civilian control of the military</inline>.—</heading><content>In order to meet the requirement in paragraph (2)(A) with respect to particular national security forces under a program under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall certify, prior to the initiation of the program, that the Department of Defense or the Department of State is already undertaking, or will undertake as part of the security sector assistance provided to the foreign country concerned, training that includes a comprehensive curriculum on the law of armed conflict, human rights and fundamental freedoms, and the rule of law, and that enhances the capacity to exercise responsible civilian control of the military, as applicable, to such national security forces.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida79e34d8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Institutional capacity building</inline>.—</heading><content>In order to meet the requirement in paragraph (2)(B) with respect to a particular foreign country under a program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall certify, prior to the initiation of the program, that the Department of Defense or another department or agency is already undertaking, or will undertake as part of the security sector assistance provided to the foreign country concerned, a program of institutional capacity building with appropriate institutions of such foreign country to enhance the capacity of such foreign country to organize, administer, employ, manage, maintain, sustain, or oversee the national security forces of such foreign country.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida79e34d9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitations.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida79e34da-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assistance otherwise prohibited by law</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense may not use the authority in subsection (a) to provide any type of assistance described in subsection (c) that is otherwise prohibited by any provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida79e34db-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on assistance to units that have committed gross violations of human rights</inline>.—</heading><content>The provision of assistance pursuant to a program under subsection (a) shall be subject to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s362">section 362 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida79e34dc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Duration of sustainment support</inline>.—</heading><content>Sustainment support may not be provided pursuant to a program under subsection (a), or for equipment previously provided by the Department of Defense under any authority available to the Secretary during fiscal year 2015 or 2016, for a period in excess of five years unless the notice on the program pursuant to subsection (e) includes the information specified in paragraph (7) of subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida79e34dd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice and Wait on Activities Under Programs</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 15 days before initiating activities under a program under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a written and electronic notice of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida79e34de-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The foreign country, and specific unit, whose capacity to engage in activities specified in subsection (a) will be built under the program, and the amount, type, and purpose of the support to be provided.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida79e34df-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A detailed evaluation of the capacity of the foreign country and unit to absorb the training or equipment to be provided under the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida79e34e0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The cost, implementation timeline, and delivery schedule for assistance under the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a0a5e1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> A description of the arrangements, if any, for the sustainment of the program and the estimated cost and source of funds to support sustainment of the capabilities and performance outcomes achieved under the program beyond its completion date, if applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a0a5e2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Information, including the amount, type, and purpose, on the security assistance provided the foreign country during the three preceding fiscal years pursuant to authorities under this title, the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, and any other train and equip authorities of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a0a5e3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/e/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> A description of the elements of the theater security cooperation plan of the geographic combatant command concerned, and of the interagency integrated country strategy, that will be advanced by the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a0a5e4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/e/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><chapeau> In the case of a program described in subsection (d)(3), each of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7a0a5e5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/e/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A written justification that the provision of sustainment support described in that subsection for a period in excess of five years will enhance the security interest of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7a0a5e6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/e/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> To the extent practicable, a plan to transition such sustainment support from funding through the Department to funding through another security sector assistance program of the United States Government or funding through partner nations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a0a5e7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/e/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> In the case of activities under a program that results in the provision of small-scale construction above $750,000, the location, project title, and cost of each small-scale construction project that will be carried out, a Department of Defense Form 1391 for each such project, and a masterplan of planned infrastructure investments at the location over the next 5 years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a0a5e8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/e/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><chapeau> In the case of a program described in subsection (a), each of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7a0a5e9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/e/9/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A description of whether assistance under the program could be provided pursuant to other authorities under this title, the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, or any other train and equip authorities of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7a0a5ea-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/e/9/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> An identification of each such authority described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7a0a5eb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Semi-Annual Monitoring Reports</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Director of the Defense Security Cooperation Agency shall, on a semi-annual basis, submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report setting forth, for the preceding 180 days, the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a0a5ec-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Information, by recipient country, of the delivery and execution status of all defense articles, training, defense services, supplies (including consumables), and small-scale construction under programs under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a0a5ed-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Information on the timeliness of delivery of defense articles, defense services, supplies (including consumables), and small-scale construction when compared with delivery schedules for such articles, services, supplies, and construction previously provided to Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a0a5ee-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Information, by recipient country, on the status of funds allocated for programs under subsection (a), including amounts of unobligated funds, unliquidated obligations, and disbursements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7a0a5ef-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Funding.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a0a5f0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sole source of funds</inline>.—</heading><content>Amounts for programs carried out pursuant to subsection (a) in a fiscal year, and for other purposes in connection with such programs as authorized by this section, may be derived only from amounts authorized to be appropriated for such fiscal year for the Department of Defense for operation and maintenance, Defense-wide, and available for the Defense Security Cooperation Agency for such programs and purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a0a5f1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Availability of funds for programs across fiscal years</inline>.—</heading><content>Amounts available in fiscal year 2025 or any subsequent fiscal year to carry out the authority in subsection (a) may be used for programs under that authority that begin in such fiscal year and end not later than the end of the third fiscal year thereafter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7a0a5f2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Equipment Disposition; Notice and Wait.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a0a5f3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may treat as stocks of the Department of Defense—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7a0a5f4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> equipment procured to carry out a program pursuant to subsection (a) that has not yet been transferred to a foreign country and is no longer needed to support such program or any other program carried out pursuant to such subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7a0a5f5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> equipment that has been transferred to a foreign country to carry out a program pursuant to subsection (a) and is returned by the foreign country to the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a0a5f6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice and wait</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 15 days before initiating activities under a program under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a written and electronic notice of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7a0a5f7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The foreign country, and specific unit, whose capacity was intended to be built under the program, and the amount, type, and purpose of the equipment that was to be provided.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7a0a5f8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> An explanation why the equipment is no longer needed to support such program or another program carried out pursuant to such subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7a0a5f9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">International Agreements.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a0a5fa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, may—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7a0a5fb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/i/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> allow a foreign country to provide sole-source direction for assistance in support of a program carried out pursuant to subsection (a); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7a0a5fc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/i/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> enter into an agreement with a foreign country to provide such sole-source direction.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a0a5fd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 72 hours after the Secretary of Defense enters into an agreement under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a written notification that includes the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7a0a5fe-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/i/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A description of the parameters of the agreement, including types of support, objectives, and duration of support and cooperation under the agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7a0a5ff-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/i/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A description and justification of any anticipated use of sole-source direction pursuant to such agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7a0a600-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/i/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> An assessment of the extent to which the equipment to be provided under the agreement—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="ida7a0a601-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/i/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> responds to the needs of the foreign country; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="ida7a0a602-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/i/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> can be sustained by the foreign country.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7a0a603-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/i/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> A determination as to whether the anticipated costs to be incurred under the agreement are fair and reasonable.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7a0a604-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/i/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> A certification that the agreement is in the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7a0a605-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s333/i/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> Any other matter relating to the agreement, as determined by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida7a0a606-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tXII/s1241/d/1">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2500">130 Stat. 2500</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tXII/s1204/b">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title XII, § 1204(b)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1643">131 Stat. 1643</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tXII">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII</ref>, §§ 1201, 1203(c), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/2016">132 Stat. 2016</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tXII/s1201">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XII, § 1201</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1620">133 Stat. 1620</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXII/s1201">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1201</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3908">134 Stat. 3908</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tXII/s1202/c">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XII, § 1202(c)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2823">136 Stat. 2823</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tXII/s1203/b">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XII, § 1203(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/441">137 Stat. 441</ref>, 442; <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tXII/s1201/a">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XII, § 1201(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2093">138 Stat. 2093</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXII/s1202">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title XII, § 1202</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1081">139 Stat. 1081</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida7a0a607-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida7a0a608-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="ida7a0a609-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, referred to in subsec. (e)(5), (9)(A), is <ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, <date date="1961-09-04">Sept. 4, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/424">75 Stat. 424</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 32 (§ 2151 et seq.) of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">section 2151 of Title 22</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="ida7a0a60a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 333 was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s253">section 253 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida7a0a60b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (g)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60">Pub. L. 119–60</ref> struck out “made” after “Amounts”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (g)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159">Pub. L. 118–159</ref> amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) related to availability of funds for programs across fiscal years.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2023—Subsecs. (h), (i). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31">Pub. L. 118–31</ref> added subsecs. (h) and (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Pub. L. 117–263</ref> substituted “Semi-Annual” for “Quarterly” in heading and “a semi-annual” for “a quarterly” and “180 days” for “calendar quarter” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (a)(7), (8). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1201/1">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1201(1)</ref>, (2), added par. (7) and redesignated former par. (7) as (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1201/3">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1201(3)</ref>, added par. (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (a)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s1201/a">Pub. L. 116–92, § 1201(a)</ref>, inserted “existing” before “international coalition operation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s1201/b">Pub. L. 116–92, § 1201(b)</ref>, added par. (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s1201">Pub. L. 115–232, § 1201</ref>, inserted at end “In developing and planning a program to build the capacity of the national security forces of a foreign country under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense and Secretary of State should jointly consider political, social, economic, diplomatic, and historical factors, if any, of the foreign country that may impact the effectiveness of the program.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s1203/c/1">Pub. L. 115–232, § 1203(c)(1)</ref>, inserted “supporting security cooperation programs under this section” after “small-scale construction”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s1203/c/2">Pub. L. 115–232, § 1203(c)(2)</ref>, added par. (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—Subsec. (c)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s1204/b/1/A">Pub. L. 115–91, § 1204(b)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “the rule of law, and civilian control of the military” for “and the rule of law”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s1204/b/1/B">Pub. L. 115–91, § 1204(b)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “Institutional capacity building” for “Respect for civilian control of the military”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s1204/b/2">Pub. L. 115–91, § 1204(b)(2)</ref>, in heading, substituted “Observance of and respect for the law of armed conflict, human rights and fundamental freedoms, the rule of law, and civilian control of the military” for “Human rights training” and in text, inserted “or the Department of State” after “Department of Defense” and substituted “training that includes a comprehensive curriculum on the law of armed conflict, human rights and fundamental freedoms, and the rule of law, and that enhances the capacity to exercise responsible civilian control of the military” for “human rights training that includes a comprehensive curriculum on human rights and the law of armed conflict”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s1204/b/3">Pub. L. 115–91, § 1204(b)(3)</ref>, substituted “that the Department of Defense or another department or agency is already undertaking, or will undertake as part of the security sector assistance provided to the foreign country concerned, a program of institutional capacity building with appropriate institutions of such foreign country to enhance the capacity of such foreign country to organize, administer, employ, manage, maintain, sustain, or oversee the national security forces of such foreign country.” for “that the Department is already undertaking, or will undertake as part of the program, a program of institutional capacity building with appropriate institutions of such foreign country that is complementary to the program with respect to such foreign country under subsection (a).” and struck out at end “The purpose of the program of institutional capacity building shall be to enhance the capacity of such foreign country to exercise responsible civilian control of the national security forces of such foreign country.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida7a0a60c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7a0a60d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Enhancing Security Partnership With Jordan and Lebanon</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXII/s1226">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title XII, § 1226</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1091">139 Stat. 1091</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXII/s1226">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense, pursuant to existing authorities, shall seek to provide assistance, including training, equipment, logistics support, supplies, and services, to the Government of Jordan and the Government of Lebanon for the purposes of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> supporting and enhancing efforts of the military forces of Jordan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> with respect to the Government of Lebanon, for increasing the capacity of the Lebanese armed forces in order to disarm the Iranian-backed terrorist group Hezbollah.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Plan.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2026-06-30">June 30, 2026</date>, the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Commander of the United States Central Command and in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall submit to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] a report that describes the plan of the Department of Defense to provide assistance under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The plan required by paragraph (1) shall, at a minimum, include the following elements:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> A description of the existing authorities to provide the assistance described in subsection (a) to the Government of Jordan and the Government of Lebanon.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> A description of the strategic objectives of the assistance described in subsection (a), including specific capability gaps that such assistance seeks to address and the recipient units of the military forces of Jordan and Lebanon for such assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> An identification of any opportunities to transfer military equipment, including aircraft and unmanned systems, from existing inventory of the Department of Defense to bolster the capabilities of the military forces of Jordan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> A rubric for assessing the progress of the Lebanese armed forces in disarming Hezbollah, and options for suspending assistance to the Lebanese armed forces if it is determined that such forces are unwilling to act to disarm Hezbollah.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7a0a60e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Baltic Security Initiative</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXII/s1247">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title XII, § 1247</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1106">139 Stat. 1106</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXII/s1247">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Pursuant to the authorities provided in chapter 16 of title 10, United States Code, the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Commander of United States European Command, shall establish and carry out an initiative, to be known as the ‘Baltic Security Initiative’, for the purpose of deepening security cooperation with the military forces of the Baltic countries.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Existing Authorities</inline>.—</heading><content>The initiative required by subsection (a) shall be carried out pursuant to the authorities provided in title 10, United States Code.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Objectives</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The objectives of the initiative required by subsection (a) should include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> to achieve United States national security objectives by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> deterring aggression by the Russian Federation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> implementing NATO’s Strategic Concept, which seeks to strengthen the Alliance’s deterrence and defense posture by denying potential adversaries any possible opportunities for aggression;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> to enhance regional planning and cooperation among the military forces of the Baltic countries, particularly with respect to long-term regional capability projects, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> long-range precision fire systems and capabilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> integrated air and missile defense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> maritime domain awareness;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> land forces development, including stockpiling large caliber ammunition;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> command, control, communications, computers, intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> special operations forces development;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> coordination with and security enhancements for Poland; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> other military capabilities, as determined by the Secretary of Defense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> with respect to the military forces of the Baltic countries, to improve cyber defenses and resilience to hybrid threats.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Strategy</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 120 [probably should be “120 days”] after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>], the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Commander of United States European Command, shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives a report setting forth a strategy to achieve the objectives described in subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Considerations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The strategy required by this subsection shall include a consideration of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> security cooperation programs for the Baltic countries that are authorized as of the date on which the report containing the strategy is submitted;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the ongoing security threats to NATO’s eastern flank posed by Russian aggression, including as a result of the Russian Federation’s 2022 invasion of Ukraine with support from Belarus;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the ongoing security threats to the Baltic countries posed by the presence, coercive economic policies, and other malign activities of the People’s Republic of China; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> a description of how NATO allies are supporting the Baltic countries to achieve the objectives described in subsection (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sense of Congress</inline>.—</heading><content>It is the sense of Congress that Baltic countries that participate in the initiative required by subsection (a) should make investments in Baltic defense in amounts that, at a minimum, match with total amounts provided by the Department of Defense for the initiative.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> the term ‘Baltic countries’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Estonia;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Latvia; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Lithuania; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the term ‘NATO’ means the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sunset</inline>.—</heading><content>The requirement under subsection (a) shall terminate on <date date="2028-12-31">December 31, 2028</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7a0a60f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Strategy To Strengthen Multilateral Defense in the Indo-Pacific</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXII/s1254">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title XII, § 1254</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1115">139 Stat. 1115</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXII/s1254">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall develop and implement a strategy to strengthen multilateral defense against regional aggression in the Indo-Pacific region by expanding multilateral coordination with United States allies and partners in the region.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Strategy Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The strategy required by subsection (a) shall describe current activities and initiatives and identify future actions to be taken over the next 5 years by the Department of Defense to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> expand existing bilateral engagements into multilateral forums with a focus on defense-related planning and military exercises;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> prioritize the acquisition and fielding of military capabilities necessary for enhancing multilateral defense, including long-range precision fires and integrated air defenses amongst United States allies and partners in the Indo-Pacific region;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> leverage reciprocal access agreements between the United States and its Indo-Pacific allies, particularly Japan, the Philippines, South Korea, and Australia, to expand regional access for allied and partner militaries, including for purposes of enhancing interoperability, prepositioning munitions stockpiles, and jointly supporting and leveraging shared facilities, operational access, and infrastructure;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> improve command and control structures to enable enhanced multilateral coordination with Indo-Pacific allies and partners;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> expand information-sharing and maritime domain awareness among the United States and Indo-Pacific allies and partners;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> expand the scope and scale of multilateral military exercises and operations in the region, including more frequent combined maritime operations through the Taiwan Strait and in the South China Sea; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> consider foreseeable strategic and operational contingencies affecting the security of strategic transit routes in the Indo-Pacific region.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission; Interim Report.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission of strategy</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives], the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate the strategy required by subsection (a), including an identification of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> any changes to funding or policy required to strengthen multilateral defense among the United States and allies and partners in the Indo-Pacific against regional aggression; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> any additional resources necessary to develop or to implement the requirements described in subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Interim report on implementation</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2027-03-15">March 15, 2027</date>, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report on the progress of the implementation of the strategy required by subsection (a), including a description of any gap in resources or authority that limits the ability of the Department to execute such strategy.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7a0a610-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Indo-Pacific Campaigning Initiative</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tXIII/s1304">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XIII, § 1304</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/489">137 Stat. 489</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tXIII/s1304">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall establish, and the Commander of the United States Indo-Pacific Command shall carry out, an Indo-Pacific Campaigning Initiative (in this section referred to as the ‘Initiative’) for purposes of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> strengthening United States alliances and partnerships with foreign military partners in the Indo-Pacific region;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> deterring military aggression by potential adversaries against the United States and allies and partners of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> dissuading strategic competitors from seeking to achieve their objectives through the conduct of military activities below the threshold of traditional armed conflict;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> improving the understanding of the United States Armed Forces with respect to the operating environment in the Indo-Pacific region;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> shaping the perception of potential adversaries with respect to United States military capabilities and the military capabilities of allies and partners of the United States in the Indo-Pacific region; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> improving the ability of the United States Armed Forces to coordinate and operate with foreign military partners in the Indo-Pacific region.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefing and Report.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefing</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2024-03-01">March 1, 2024</date>, the Secretary shall provide the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] with a briefing that describes ongoing and planned campaigning activities in the Indo-Pacific region for fiscal year 2024.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than <date date="2024-12-01">December 1, 2024</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> summarizes the campaigning activities conducted in the Indo-Pacific region during fiscal year 2024; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> includes—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> an assessment of the value each such activity contributes to meeting strategic or operational objectives relative to the commitment of resources of such activity;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> lessons learned in carrying out such activities;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> any identified resource or authority gap that has negatively impacted the implementation of the Initiative; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> proposed plans for additional campaigning activities in the Indo-Pacific region to fulfill the purposes described in subsection (a).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Campaigning Defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term ‘campaigning’—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> means the conduct and sequencing of logically linked military activities to achieve strategy aligned objectives, including modifying the security environment over time to the benefit of the United States and the allies and partners of the United States while limiting, frustrating, and disrupting competitor activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> includes deliberately planned military activities in the Indo-Pacific region involving bilateral and multilateral engagements with foreign partners, training, exercises, demonstrations, experiments, and other activities to achieve the objectives described in subsection (a).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7a0a611-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Enhancing Major Defense Partnership With India</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tXIII/s1316">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XIII, § 1316</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/498">137 Stat. 498</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tXIII/s1316">
<inline>“The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State and the head of any other relevant Federal department or agency, shall seek to ensure that India is appropriately considered for cooperative defense activities consistent with the status of India as a major defense partner of the United States, including with respect to the following lines of effort:</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> Eligibility for funding to initiate or facilitate cooperative research, development, testing, or evaluation projects with the Department of Defense, with priority given to projects in the areas of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> undersea domain awareness;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> air combat and support;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> munitions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> mobility.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> Eligibility to enter into agreements with the Department of Defense for cooperative bilateral or multilateral provision of training to build capacity in the areas of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> counterterrorism operations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> counter-weapons of mass destruction operations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> counter-illicit drug trafficking operations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> counter-transnational organized crime operations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> maritime and border security operations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> military intelligence operations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> air domain awareness operations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> cyberspace security and defensive cyberspace operations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Eligibility to enter into a memorandum of understanding or other formal agreement with the Department of Defense for the purpose of conducting cooperative research and development projects on defense equipment and munitions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Eligibility for entities from India to bid on contracts for the maintenance, repair, or overhaul of Department of Defense equipment located outside the United States.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7a0a612-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Military Cybersecurity Cooperation With Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tXV/s1508">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XV, § 1508</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2885">136 Stat. 2885</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tXV/s1508">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], the Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy, in concurrence with the Secretary of State and in coordination with the Commander of the United States Cyber Command and the Commander of the United States Central Command, shall seek to engage the Ministry of Defense of the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan for the purpose of expanding cooperation of military cybersecurity activities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cooperation Efforts</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In expanding the cooperation of military cybersecurity activities between the Department of Defense and the Ministry of Defense of the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense may carry out the following efforts:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Bilateral cybersecurity training activities and exercises.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> Efforts to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> actively defend military networks, infrastructure, and systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> eradicate malicious cyber activity that has compromised those networks, infrastructure, and systems; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> leverage United States commercial and military cybersecurity technology and services to harden and defend those networks, infrastructure, and systems.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Establishment of a regional cybersecurity center.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefings.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees a briefing on the implementation of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The briefing under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> An overview of efforts undertaken pursuant to this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> A description of the feasibility and advisability of expanding the cooperation of military cybersecurity activities between the Department of Defense and the Ministry of Defense of the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Identification of any challenges and resources that need to be addressed so as to expand such cooperation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Any other matter the Secretary determines relevant.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate Congressional Committees Defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term ‘appropriate congressional committees’ means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7a0a613-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pilot Program To Improve Cyber Cooperation With Covered Foreign Military Partners in Southeast Asia</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXII/s1256">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1256</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3956">134 Stat. 3956</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tXIII/s1315/a">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XIII, § 1315(a)</ref>–(g)(1), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/497">137 Stat. 497</ref>, 498; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXII/s1261">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title XII, § 1261</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1118">139 Stat. 1118</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXII/s1261">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, may establish, using existing authorities of the Department of Defense, a pilot program with covered foreign military partners—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to enhance the cyber security, resilience, and readiness of the military forces of covered foreign military partners; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to increase regional cooperation between the United States and covered foreign military partners on defensive cyber issues.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The activities of the pilot program under subsection (a) shall include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Provision of training to military officers and civilian officials in the ministries of defense of covered foreign military partners.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The facilitation of regular dialogues and trainings among the Department of Defense and the ministries of defense of covered foreign military partners with respect to the development of infrastructure to protect against foreign cyber attacks.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> To undertake, as part of cyber cooperation, training that includes curricula expressly relating to human rights, the rule of law, and internet freedom.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Design of pilot program</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2021-06-01">June 1, 2021</date>, the Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the design of the pilot program under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Progress report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than <date date="2021-12-31">December 31, 2021</date>, and annually thereafter until the date on which the pilot program terminates under subsection (e), the Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the pilot program that includes—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a description of the activities conducted and the results of such activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> an assessment of reforms relevant to cybersecurity and technology in enhancing the cyber security, resilience, and readiness of the military forces of covered foreign military partners;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> an assessment of the effectiveness of curricula relating to human rights, the rule of law, and internet freedom; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> the content and curriculum of any program made available to participants of such program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certification</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 30 days before the date on which the pilot program under subsection (a) is scheduled to commence with any covered foreign military partner, the Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a certification indicating whether such program would credibly enable, enhance, or facilitate violations of internet freedom or other human rights abuses in the covered foreign military partner.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading><content>The pilot program under subsection (a) shall terminate on <date date="2028-12-31">December 31, 2028</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate committees of congress</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘appropriate committees of Congress’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered foreign military partner</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘covered foreign military partner’ means the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Vietnam.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Thailand.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Indonesia.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> The Philippines.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> Malaysia.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7a0a614-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Guidance</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tXII/s1241/d/4">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(d)(4)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2504">130 Stat. 2504</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tXII/s1241/d/4">“Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall prescribe, and submit to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives], initial policy guidance on roles, responsibilities, and processes in connection with programs and activities authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s333">section 333 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, as so added. Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prescribe, and submit to the congressional defense committees, final policy guidance on roles, responsibilities, and processes in connection with such programs and activities.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7a0a615-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Training for Eastern European National Security Forces in the Course of Multilateral Exercises</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/92/dA/tXII/s1251">Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title XII, § 1251</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1070">129 Stat. 1070</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tXII/s1233">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1233</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2489">130 Stat. 2489</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tXII/s1205">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title XII, § 1205</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1643">131 Stat. 1643</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tXII/s1247/a">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XII, § 1247(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1662">133 Stat. 1662</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXII/s1243">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1243</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3947">134 Stat. 3947</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tXII/s1233">Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XII, § 1233</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1974">135 Stat. 1974</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tXII/s1249">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XII, § 1249</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/464">137 Stat. 464</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tXIII/s1302">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XIII, § 1302</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2110">138 Stat. 2110</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tXIII/s1302">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense may provide the training specified in subsection (b), and pay the incremental expenses incurred by a country as the direct result of participation in such training, for the national security forces provided for under subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Types of Training</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The training provided to the national security forces of a country under subsection (a) shall be limited to training that is—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> provided in the course of the conduct of a multilateral exercise in which the United States Armed Forces are a participant;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> comparable to or complimentary of the types of training the United States Armed Forces receive in the course of such multilateral exercise; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> for any purpose as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> To enhance and increase the interoperability of the security forces to be trained to increase their ability to participate in coalition efforts led by the United States or the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> To increase the capacity of such security forces to respond to external threats.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> To increase the capacity of such security forces to respond to hybrid warfare.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> To increase the capacity of such security forces to respond to calls for collective action within the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible Countries.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Training may be provided under subsection (a) to the national security forces of the countries determined by the Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, to be appropriate recipients of such training from among the countries as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Countries that are a signatory to the Partnership for Peace Framework Documents, but not a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Countries that became a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization after <date date="1999-01-01">January 1, 1999</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> The Republic of Kosovo.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> The Republic of Cyprus.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible countries</inline>.—</heading><content>Before providing training under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall, in coordination with the Secretary of State, submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a list of the countries determined pursuant to paragraph (1) to be eligible for the provision of training under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Funding of Incremental Expenses.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual funding</inline>.—</heading><content>Of the amounts specified in paragraph (2) for a fiscal year, up to a total of $28,000,000 may be used to pay incremental expenses under subsection (a) in that fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Amounts</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The amounts specified in this paragraph are as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Amounts authorized to be appropriated for a fiscal year for operation and maintenance, Army, and available for the Combatant Commands Direct Support Program for that fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Amounts authorized to be appropriated for a fiscal year for operation and maintenance, Defense-wide, and available for the Wales Initiative Fund for that fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Amounts authorized to be appropriated for a fiscal year for overseas contingency operations for operation and maintenance, Army, and available for additional activities for the European Deterrence Initiative for that fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Availability of funds for activities across fiscal years</inline>.—</heading><content>Amounts available in a fiscal year pursuant to this subsection may be used for incremental expenses of training that begins in that fiscal year and ends in the next fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations for payment of incremental expenses under subsection (a). Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this paragraph [<date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>], the Secretary shall submit the regulations to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Procedures to be included</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The regulations required under subparagraph (A) shall include procedures—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> to require reimbursement of incremental expenses from non-developing countries determined pursuant to subsection (c) to be eligible for the provision of training under subsection (a); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> to provide for a waiver of the requirement of reimbursement of incremental expenses under clause (i), on a case-by-case basis, if the Secretary of Defense determines special circumstances exist to provide for the waiver.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Quarterly report</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, on a quarterly basis, a report that includes a description of each waiver of the requirement of reimbursement of incremental expenses under subparagraph (B)(i) that was in effect at any time during the preceding calendar quarter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Non-developing country defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this paragraph, the term ‘non-developing country’ means a country that is not a developing country, as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s301/4">section 301(4) of title 10</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefing to Congress on Use of Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the end of each fiscal year in which the authority in subsection (a) is used, the Secretary shall brief the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives on the use of the authority during such fiscal year, including each country with which training under the authority was conducted and the types of training provided.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Construction of Authority</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The authority provided in subsection (a)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> is in addition to any other authority provided by law authorizing the provision of training for the national security forces of a foreign country, including chapter 16 of title 10, United States Code; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> shall not be construed to include authority for the training of irregular forces, groups, or individuals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Incremental Expenses Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘incremental expenses’ has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s301/5">section 301(5) of title 10</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination of Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority under this section shall terminate on <date date="2027-12-31">December 31, 2027</date>. Any activity under this section initiated before that date may be completed, but only using funds available for the period beginning on <date date="2015-10-01">October 1, 2015</date>, and ending on <date date="2027-12-31">December 31, 2027</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7a0a616-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Indo-Pacific Maritime Security Initiative; Indo-Pacific Maritime Domain Awareness Initiative</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tXIII/s1305">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XIII, § 1305</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/490">137 Stat. 490</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tXIII/s1305">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>], the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall seek to establish an initiative with allies and partners of the United States, including Australia, Japan, and India, to be known as the ‘Indo-Pacific Maritime Domain Awareness Initiative’ (in this section referred to as the ‘Initiative’), to bolster maritime domain awareness in the Indo-Pacific region.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Authorities</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out the Initiative, the Secretary of Defense may use the authorities provided in chapter 16 of title 10, United States Code, and other applicable statutory authorities available to the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The purposes of the Initiative are as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> To enhance the ability of allies and partners of the United States in the Indo-Pacific region to monitor the maritime domain of such region.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> To utilize emerging technologies to support maritime domain awareness objectives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> To provide a comprehensive understanding of the maritime domain in the Indo-Pacific region, including by facilitating information sharing among such allies and partners.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/114/92/dA/tXII/s1263">Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title XII, § 1263</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1073">129 Stat. 1073</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tXII/s1289">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1289</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2555">130 Stat. 2555</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tXII/s1252">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1252</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/2053">132 Stat. 2053</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tXII">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XII</ref>, §§ 1251, 1252(a), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1666-1668">133 Stat. 1666–1668</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tXII/s1241">Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XII, § 1241</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1976">135 Stat. 1976</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tXII/s1252">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XII, § 1252</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2850">136 Stat. 2850</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tXIII/s1312">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XIII, § 1312</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2112">138 Stat. 2112</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tXIII/s1312">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assistance and Training.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense is authorized, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, with the primary goal of increasing multilateral maritime security cooperation and maritime domain awareness of foreign countries in the area of responsibility of the United States Indo-Pacific Command—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> to provide assistance to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the national military or other security forces of any such country that has among its functional responsibilities a maritime security mission; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> any other national-level governmental organization of such a country that has among its functional responsibilities a maritime domain awareness mission, for purposes of helping to achieve the maritime domain awareness objectives of such country if such assistance directly contributes to the integration of a maritime domain awareness activity with the national military or other security forces described in clause (i); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> to provide training to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> ministry, agency, and headquarters-level organizations for such forces; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> other national-level governmental organizations described in paragraph (A)(ii).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Designation of assistance and training</inline>.—</heading><content>The provision of assistance and training under this section may be referred to as the ‘Indo-Pacific Maritime Security Initiative’.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Recipient Countries</inline>.—</heading><content>The foreign countries that may be provided assistance and training under subsection (a) are the countries located within the area of responsibility of the United States Indo-Pacific Command.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Types of Assistance and Training.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorized elements of assistance</inline>.—</heading><content>Assistance provided under subsection (a)(1)(A) may include the provision of equipment, supplies, training, and small-scale construction (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s301">section 301 of title 10</ref>, United States Code).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Required elements of assistance and training</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Assistance and training provided under subsection (a) shall include elements that promote the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Observance of and respect for the law of armed conflict, the rule of law, and human rights and fundamental freedoms.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Respect for legitimate civilian authority within the country to which the assistance is provided.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Priorities for Assistance and Training</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In developing programs for assistance or training to be provided under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall prioritize assistance, training, or both, to enhance—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> multilateral cooperation and coordination among recipient countries; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the capabilities of a recipient country to more effectively participate in a regional organization of which the recipient country is a member.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Incremental Expenses of Personnel of Recipient Countries for Training</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Secretary of Defense determines that the payment of incremental expenses (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s301">section 301 of title 10</ref>, United States Code) in connection with training described in subsection (a)(1)(B) will facilitate the participation in such training of organization personnel of recipient countries described in subsection (b), the Secretary may use amounts available under subsection (f) for assistance and training under subsection (a) for the payment of such incremental expenses.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Availability of Funds for Coast Guard Personnel and Capabilities</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense may use funds made available under this section to facilitate the participation of Coast Guard personnel in, and the use of Coast Guard capabilities for, training, exercises, and other activities with foreign countries under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitations.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assistance otherwise prohibited by law</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense may not use the authority in subsection (a) to provide any type of assistance described in subsection (c) that is otherwise prohibited by any provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on assistance to units that have committed gross violations of human rights</inline>.—</heading><content>The provision of assistance pursuant to a program under subsection (a) shall be subject to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s362">section 362 of title 10</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Security cooperation</inline>.—</heading><content>Assistance, training, and exercises with recipient countries described in subsection (b) shall be planned and prioritized consistent with applicable guidance relating to the security cooperation program and activities of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assessment, monitoring, and evaluation</inline>.—</heading><content>The provision of assistance and training pursuant to a program under subsection (a) shall be subject to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s383">section 383 of title 10</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice to Congress on Assistance and Training.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 15 days before exercising the authority under subsection (a) or (e) with respect to a recipient foreign country, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a notification containing the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The recipient foreign country, the specific unit or units or national-level governmental organization whose capacity to engage in activities under a program of assistance or training to be provided under subsection (a) will be built under the program, and the amount, type, and purpose of the support to be provided.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> A detailed justification of the program for the provision of the assistance or training concerned, its relationship to United States security interests, and an explanation of the manner in which such assistance or training will increase multilateral maritime security cooperation or maritime domain awareness.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> The budget for the program, including a timetable of planned expenditures of funds to implement the program, an implementation timeline for the program with milestones (including anticipated delivery schedules for any assistance under the program), the military department or component responsible for management of the program, and the anticipated completion date for the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> A description of the arrangements, if any, to support host nation sustainment of any capability developed pursuant to the program, and the source of funds to support sustainment efforts and performance outcomes to be achieved under the program beyond its completion date, if applicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> A description of the program objectives and an assessment framework to be used to develop capability and performance metrics associated with operational outcomes for the recipient force.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> Information, including the amount, type, and purpose, on assistance and training provided under subsection (a) during the three preceding fiscal years, if applicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> A description of the elements of the theater campaign plan of the United States Indo-Pacific Command and the interagency integrated country strategy that will be advanced by the assistance and training provided under subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><chapeau> A description of whether assistance and training provided under subsection (a) could be provided pursuant to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s333">section 333 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, or other security cooperation authorities of the Department of Defense; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> security cooperation authorities of the Department of State.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> An identification of each such authority described in subparagraph (H).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="J">“(J)</num><content> Such other matters as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate committees of congress defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subsection, the term ‘appropriate committees of Congress’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Monitoring Reports.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than <date date="2022-03-01">March 1, 2022</date>, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report setting forth, for the preceding calendar year, the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> The overall strategy for improving multilateral maritime security cooperation and maritime domain awareness across the theater, including an identification of the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> Priority countries and associated capabilities across the theater.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> Strategic objectives for the Indo-Pacific Maritime Security Initiative across the theater, lines of effort, and desired end results for such lines of effort.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> Significant challenges to improving multilateral maritime security cooperation and maritime domain awareness across the theater and the manner in which the United States Indo-Pacific Command is seeking to address such challenges.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> An assessment, by recipient foreign country, of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the country’s capabilities relating to maritime security and maritime domain awareness;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the country’s capability enhancement priorities, including how such priorities relate to the theater campaign strategy, country plan, and theater campaign plan relating to maritime security and maritime domain awareness; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> how such capabilities can be leveraged to improve multilateral maritime security cooperation and maritime domain awareness.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> A discussion, by recipient foreign country, of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> priority capabilities that the Department of Defense plans to enhance under the authority under subsection (a) and priority capabilities the Department plans to enhance under separate United States security cooperation and security assistance authorities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the anticipated timeline for assistance and training for each such capability.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Information, by recipient foreign country, on the status of funds allocated for assistance and training provided under subsection (a), including funds allocated but not yet obligated or expended.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> Information, by recipient foreign country, on the delivery and use of assistance and training provided under subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> Information, by recipient foreign country, on the timeliness of the provision of assistance and training under subsection (a) as compared to the timeliness of the provision of assistance and training previously provided to the foreign country under subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> A description of the reasons the Department of Defense chose to utilize the authority for assistance and training under subsection (a) in the preceding calendar year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> An explanation of any impediments to timely obligation or expenditure of funds allocated for assistance and training under subsection (a) or any significant delay in the delivery of such assistance and training.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate committees of congress defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this subsection, the term ‘appropriate committees of Congress’ has the meaning given the term in subsection (h)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="j">“(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Expiration</inline>.—</heading><content>Assistance and training may not be provided under this section after <date date="2027-12-31">December 31, 2027</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7a31717-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Training of Security Forces and Associated Security Ministries of Foreign Countries To Promote Respect for the Rule of Law and Human Rights</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tXII/s1206">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title XII, § 1206</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3538">128 Stat. 3538</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tXII/s1205/c">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1205(c)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/2018">132 Stat. 2018</ref>, authorized the Secretary of Defense to conduct human rights training of security forces and associated security ministries of foreign countries and terminated such authority on <date date="2020-09-30">Sept. 30, 2020</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
