<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida7a7d1ab-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s351"><num value="351">§ 351.</num><heading> Inter-American Defense College</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7a7d1ac-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s351/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority To Support</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may authorize members of the armed forces and civilian personnel of the Department of Defense to participate in the operation of and the provision of support to the Inter-American Defense College and provide logistic support, supplies, and services to the Inter-American Defense College, including the use of Department of Defense facilities and equipment, as the Secretary considers necessary to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a7d1ad-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s351/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> assist the Inter-American Defense College in its mission to develop and offer to military officers and civilian officials from member states of the Organization of American States advanced academic courses on matters related to military and defense issues, the inter-American system, and related disciplines; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a7d1ae-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s351/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> ensure that the Inter-American Defense College provides an academic program of a level of quality, rigor, and credibility that is commensurate with the standards of Department of Defense senior service colleges and that includes the promotion of security cooperation, human rights, humanitarian assistance and disaster response, peacekeeping, and democracy in the Western Hemisphere.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7a7d1af-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s351/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Memorandum of Understanding</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7a7d1b0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s351/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with the Inter-American Defense Board for the participation of members of the armed forces and civilian personnel of the Department of Defense in the operation of and provision of host nation support to the Inter-American Defense College under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7a7d1b1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s351/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If Department of Defense facilities, equipment, or funds will be used to support the Inter-American Defense College under subsection (a), a memorandum of understanding entered into under paragraph (1) shall include a description of any cost-sharing arrangement or other funding arrangement relating to the use of such facilities, equipment, or funds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7a7d1b2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s351/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A memorandum of understanding entered into under paragraph (1) shall also include a curriculum and a plan for academic program development.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7a7d1b3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s351/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Funds</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7a7d1b4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s351/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Funds appropriated to the Department of Defense for operation and maintenance may be used to pay costs that the Secretary determines are necessary for the participation of members of the armed forces and civilian personnel of the Department of Defense in the operation of and provision of host nation support to the Inter-American Defense College, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a7d1b5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s351/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the costs of expenses of such participants;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a7d1b6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s351/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the cost of hiring and retaining qualified professors, instructors, and lecturers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a7d1b7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s351/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> curriculum support costs, including administrative costs, academic outreach, and curriculum support personnel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a7d1b8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s351/c/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the cost of translation and interpretation services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a7d1b9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s351/c/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the cost of information and educational technology;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a7d1ba-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s351/c/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> the cost of utilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a7d1bb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s351/c/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> the cost of maintenance and repair of facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7a7d1bc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s351/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> No funds may be used under this section to provide for the pay of members of the armed forces or civilian personnel of the Department of Defense who participate in the operation of and the provision of host nation support to the Inter-American Defense College under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7a7d1bd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s351/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Funds available to carry out this section for a fiscal year may be used for activities that begin in such fiscal year and end in the next fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7a7d1be-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s351/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Waiver of Reimbursement</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense may waive reimbursement for developing countries (as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s301">section 301 of this title</ref>) of the costs of funding and other host nation support provided to the Inter-American Defense College under this section if the Secretary determines that the provision of such funding or support without reimbursement is in the national security interest of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7a7d1bf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s351/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Logistic Support, Supplies, and Services Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term “logistic support, supplies, and services” has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2350">section 2350 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida7a7d1c0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tXII/s1207/a">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1207(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/2019">132 Stat. 2019</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida7a7d1c1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida7a7d1c2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="ida7a7d1c3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 351 was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s261">section 261 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
