<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idaa2b96a9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603"><num value="3603">§ 3603.</num><heading> Software acquisition pathways</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa2b96aa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Software Acquisition and Development Pathways</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish pathways as described under subsection (b) to provide for the efficient and effective acquisition, development, integration, and timely delivery of software and covered hardware.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa2b96ab-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pathways</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may establish as many pathways under this section as the Secretary determines appropriate and shall establish the following pathways:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa2b96ac-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applications</inline>.—</heading><content>The applications pathway shall provide for the use of rapid development and implementation of applications and other software or software improvements operated by the Department of Defense, which may include applications and associated procurement of covered hardware (including modifications of a type not customarily available in the commercial marketplace to meet Department requirements), commercially available cloud computing platforms, and other nondevelopmental items.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa2b96ad-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Embedded systems</inline>.—</heading><content>The embedded systems pathway shall provide for the rapid development and insertion of upgrades and improvements for software and covered hardware embedded in weapon systems and other hardware systems unique to the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa2b96ae-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements for Pathways</inline>.—</heading><content>A pathway established under this section shall provide for the use of proven technologies and solutions to continuously engineer and deliver capabilities for software and covered hardware.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa2b96af-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Considerations for Use of Authority</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In using the authority under this section, the Secretary shall consider how such use will—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa2b96b0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> initiate the engineering of new software capabilities quickly and, if applicable, the integration of such capabilities into covered hardware;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa2b96b1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> demonstrate the viability and effectiveness of such capabilities for operational use not later than one year after the date on which funds are first obligated to acquire or develop software; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa2b96b2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> allow for the continuous updating and delivery of new capabilities not less frequently than annually to iteratively meet a requirement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa2b96b3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Treatment Not as Major Defense Acquisition Program</inline>.—</heading><content>Software and covered hardware acquired or developed using the authority under this section shall not be treated as a major defense acquisition program for purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4201">section 4201 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, or Department of Defense Directive 5000.01 without the specific designation of such software and covered hardware by the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment or a service acquisition executive.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa2b96b4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Risk-based Approach</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall use a risk-based approach for the consideration of innovative technologies and new capabilities for software and covered hardware to be acquired or developed under this authority to meet needs communicated by the Joint Chiefs of Staff and the combatant commanders.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa2b96b5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Expedited Process.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa2b96b6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A pathway established under this section shall provide for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa2b96b7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a streamlined and coordinated requirements, budget, and acquisition process to support rapid fielding of software applications and of software upgrades to embedded systems for operational use in a period of not more than one year from the time that the process is initiated;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa2b96b8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the collection of data on software and covered hardware fielded; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa2b96b9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/g/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> continuous engagement with the users of software and covered hardware to support—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idaa2b96ba-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/g/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> engineering activities of the Department of Defense; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idaa2b96bb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/g/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> delivery of software and covered hardware for operational use in periods of not more than one year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa2b96bc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Expedited software requirements process.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa2b96bd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/g/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability of joint capabilities integration and development system manual</inline>.—</heading><content>Software and covered hardware acquisition or development conducted under the authority of this section shall not be subject to the Joint Capabilities Integration and Development System Manual, except pursuant to a modified process specifically provided for the acquisition or development of software by the Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, in consultation with Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment and each service acquisition executive.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa2b96be-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/g/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability of defense acquisition system directive</inline>.—</heading><content>Software and covered hardware acquisition or development conducted under the authority of this section shall not be subject to Department of Defense Directive 5000.01, except when specifically provided for the acquisition or development of software by the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, in consultation with the Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff and each service acquisition executive.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa2b96bf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In implementing a pathway established under the authority of this section, the Secretary shall tailor requirements relating to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa2b96c0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> iterative development of requirements for software and covered hardware to be acquired or developed under the authority of this section through engagement with the user community and through user feedback, in order to continuously define and update priorities for such requirements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa2b96c1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> early identification of the warfighter or user needs including the rationale for how software and covered hardware to be acquired or developed under the authority of this section will be tailored to address such needs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa2b96c2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> initial contract requirements and format, including the use of summary-level lists of problems in existing software and desired features or capabilities of new or upgraded software;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa2b96c3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/h/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> continuous refinement and prioritization of contract requirements, informed by continuous engagement with users throughout the period of development and implementation of software and covered hardware to be acquired or developed under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa2b96c4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/h/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> continuous consideration of issues related to lifecycle costs, technical data rights, and systems interoperability;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa2b96c5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/h/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> planning for support of capabilities of software to be acquired or developed under this section if the software developer stops supporting the software;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa2b96c6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/h/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> rapid contracting procedures, including expedited timeframes for making awards, selecting contract types, defining teaming arrangements, and defining options;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa2b96c7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/h/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> program execution processes, including supporting development and test infrastructure, automation and tools, digital engineering, data collection and sharing with Department of Defense stakeholders and with Congress, the role of developmental and operational testing activities, key decision-making and oversight events, and supporting processes and activities (such as independent costing activity, operational demonstration, and performance metrics);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa2b96c8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/h/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> assurances that cybersecurity metrics of the software to be acquired or developed, such as metrics relating to the density of vulnerabilities within the code of such software, the time from vulnerability identification to patch availability, the existence of common weaknesses within such code, and other cybersecurity metrics based on widely-recognized standards and industry best practices, are generated and made available to the Department of Defense and the congressional defense committees;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa2b96c9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/h/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> administrative procedures, including procedures relating to who may initiate and approve an acquisition under this authority, the roles and responsibilities of persons implementing or supporting the use of authority under this section, team selection and staffing process, governance and oversight roles and responsibilities, and appropriate independent technology assessments, testing, and cost estimation (including relevant thresholds or designation criteria);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa2b96ca-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/h/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> mechanisms and waivers designed to ensure flexibility in the implementation of a pathway under this section, including the use of other transaction authority, broad agency announcements, and other procedures; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa2b96cb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/h/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> mechanisms the Secretary will use for appropriate reporting to Congress on the use of the authority under this section, including notice of initiation of the use of a pathway and data regarding individual programs or acquisition activities, how acquisition activities are reflected in budget justification materials or requests to reprogram appropriated funds, and compliance with other reporting requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa2b96cc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa2b96cd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The term “covered hardware” means hardware—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa2b96ce-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/i/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> that is a commercial product (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s103">section 103 of title 41</ref>) or a nondevelopmental item; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa2b96cf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/i/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in which software acquired under this section is embedded.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa2b96d0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s3603/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “nondevelopmental item” has the meaning given in <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s110">section 110 of title 41</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idaa2b96d1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tVIII/s805/a">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 805(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1969">138 Stat. 1969</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXVII/s1701/a/24">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(a)(24)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1209">139 Stat. 1209</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idaa2b96d2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idaa2b96d3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idaa2b96d4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tVIII/s800">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 800</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1478">133 Stat. 1478</ref>, which was set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4571">section 4571 of this title</ref>, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tVIII/s805/c/1">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 805(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1972">138 Stat. 1972</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idaa2b96d5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60">Pub. L. 119–60</ref> struck out “Such a pathway shall include the following:” at end.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idaa2b96d6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idaa2b96d7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Guidance Required</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tVIII/s805/b">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 805(b)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1972">138 Stat. 1972</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tVIII/s805/b">“Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall issue or modify guidance to implement the requirements of this section.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idaa2b96d8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Implementation of Recommendations of the Final Report of the Defense Science Board Task Force on the Design and Acquisition of Software for Defense Systems</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tVIII/s868">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 868</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1902">132 Stat. 1902</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tVIII/s868">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation Required</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall, except as provided under subsection (b), commence implementation of each recommendation submitted as part of the final report of the Defense Science Board Task Force on the Design and Acquisition of Software for Defense Systems.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Delayed implementation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense may commence implementation of a recommendation described under subsection (a) later than the date required under such subsection if the Secretary provides the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] with a specific justification for the delay in implementation of such recommendation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Nonimplementation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may opt not to implement a recommendation described under subsection (a) if the Secretary provides to the congressional defense committees—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the reasons for the decision not to implement the recommendation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a summary of the alternative actions the Secretary plans to take to address the purposes underlying the recommendation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation Plans</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For each recommendation that the Secretary is implementing, or that the Secretary plans to implement, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> a summary of actions that have been taken to implement the recommendation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> a schedule, with specific milestones, for completing the implementation of the recommendation.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
