<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida7a7d1f9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s362"><num value="362">§ 362.</num><heading> Prohibition on use of funds for assistance to units of foreign security forces that have committed a gross violation of human rights</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7a7d1fa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s362/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7a7d1fb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s362/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Of the amounts made available to the Department of Defense, none may be used for any training, equipment, or other assistance for a unit of a foreign security force if the Secretary of Defense has credible information that the unit has committed a gross violation of human rights.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7a7d1fc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s362/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall, in consultation with the Secretary of State, ensure that prior to a decision to provide any training, equipment, or other assistance to a unit of a foreign security force full consideration is given to any credible information available to the Department of State relating to human rights violations by such unit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7a7d1fd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s362/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading><content>The prohibition in subsection (a)(1) shall not apply if the Secretary of Defense, after consultation with the Secretary of State, determines that the government of such country has taken all necessary corrective steps, or if the equipment or other assistance is necessary to assist in disaster relief operations or other humanitarian or national security emergencies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7a7d1fe-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s362/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Waiver</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense, after consultation with the Secretary of State, may waive the prohibition in subsection (a)(1) if the Secretary determines that the waiver is required by extraordinary circumstances.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7a7d1ff-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s362/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Procedures</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish, and periodically update, procedures to ensure that any information in the possession of the Department of Defense about gross violations of human rights by units of foreign security forces is shared on a timely basis with the Department of State.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7a7d200-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s362/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 15 days after the application of any exception under subsection (b) or the exercise of any waiver under subsection (c), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a7d201-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s362/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> in the case of an exception under subsection (b), providing notice of the use of the exception and stating the grounds for the exception; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7a7d202-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s362/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> in the case of a waiver under subsection (c), describing—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7a7d203-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s362/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the information relating to the gross violation of human rights;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7a7d204-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s362/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the extraordinary circumstances that necessitate the waiver;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7a7d205-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s362/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the purpose and duration of the training, equipment, or other assistance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7a7d206-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s362/e/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the United States forces and the foreign security force unit involved.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida7a7d207-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tXII/s1204/a/1">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title XII, § 1204(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3531">128 Stat. 3531</ref>, § 2249e; renumbered § 362 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tXII/s1241">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241</ref>(<i>l</i>), <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2509">130 Stat. 2509</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida7a7d208-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida7a7d209-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida7a7d20a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—<ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1241">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1241</ref>(<i>l</i>)(1), renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2249e">section 2249e of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1241">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1241</ref>(<i>l</i>)(2), struck out subsec. (f) which defined “appropriate committees of Congress” for this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida7a7d20b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7a7d20c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plan To Provide Consistency of Administration of Authorities Relating to Vetting of Units of Security Forces of Foreign Countries; Modification of Assessment, Monitoring, and Evaluation of Security Cooperation Programs and Activities</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tXII/s1206">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XII, § 1206</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1622">133 Stat. 1622</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tXII/s1206">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>], the Secretary of Defense and Secretary of State shall jointly develop, implement, and submit to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives], the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a plan to provide consistency in administration of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s362">section 362 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, and section 620M of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2378d">22 U.S.C. 2378d</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Matters to Be Included</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The plan required by subsection (a) shall contain the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> Common standards and procedures which shall be used by the Department of Defense and Department of State to obtain and verify information regarding the vetting of units of the security forces of foreign countries for gross violation of human rights under the authorities described in subsection (a), including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> public guidelines for external sources to report information; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> methods and criteria employed by the Department of Defense and Department of State to determine whether sources, source reporting, and allegations are credible.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Measures to ensure the Department of Defense has read-only access to the International Vetting and Security Tracking (INVEST) system, and any successor or equivalent system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Measures to ensure the authorities described in subsection (a) are applied to any foreign forces, irregular forces, groups, and individuals that receive training, equipment, or other assistance from the United States military.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Form</inline>.—</heading><content>The plan required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Integration of Human Rights and Civilian Protection Into Assessment, Monitoring, and Evaluation of Security Cooperation Programs and Activities.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports required</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an interim report and a final report on the steps the Secretary will take to incorporate partner units’ activities, as such activities relate to human rights and protection of civilians, into the program elements described in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s383/b/1">section 383(b)(1) of title 10</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deadlines.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Interim report</inline>.—</heading><content>The interim report required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted to the appropriate congressional committees not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>] and shall include a summary of the progress of the Secretary in implementing the steps described in such paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Final report</inline>.—</heading><content>The final report required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted to the appropriate congressional committees not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act and shall specifically identify the actions the Secretary took to implement the steps described in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate congressional committees defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subsection, the term ‘appropriate congressional committees’ means the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7a7d20d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Human Rights Vetting of Afghan National Defense and Security Forces</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tXII/s1216">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title XII, § 1216</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1650">131 Stat. 1650</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tXII/s1216">“The Secretary of Defense may establish within the Department of Defense one or more permanent positions to oversee and support, in coordination with the Department of State, the implementation of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s362">section 362 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, with respect to the Afghan National Defense and Security Forces.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7a7d20e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Annual Reports</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tXII/s1204/b">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title XII, § 1204(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3533">128 Stat. 3533</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tXII/s1204/c/2">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1204(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/2017">132 Stat. 2017</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tXII/s1204/c/2">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than <date date="2015-03-31">March 31, 2015</date>, and every March 31 thereafter through 2024, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report setting forth for the preceding fiscal year the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The total number of cases submitted for vetting for purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s362">section 362 of title 10</ref>, United States Code (as added by subsection (a)), and the total number of such cases approved, or suspended or rejected for human rights reasons, non-human rights reasons, or administrative reasons.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> In the case of units rejected for non-human rights reasons, a detailed description of the reasons relating to the rejection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> A description of the interagency processes that were used to evaluate compliance with requirements to conduct vetting.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> An addendum that includes any comments by the commanders of the combatant commands about the impact of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s362">section 362 of title 10</ref>, United States Code (as so added), on their theater security cooperation plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> Such other matters with respect to the administration of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s362">section 362 of title 10</ref>, United States Code (as so added), as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Form</inline>.—</heading><content>Each report under this subsection shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate committees of congress defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this subsection, the term ‘appropriate committees of Congress’ has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s301/1">section 301(1) of title 10</ref>, United States Code.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For termination, effective <date date="2021-12-31">Dec. 31, 2021</date>, of annual reporting provisions in <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/s1204/b">section 1204(b) of Pub. L. 113–291</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1061">section 1061 of Pub. L. 114–328</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s111">section 111 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
