<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida7ac8c31-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s391a"><num value="391a">§ 391a.</num><heading> Annual reports on support by military departments for United States Cyber Command</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ac8c32-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s391a/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 15 days after the date on which the Secretary of Defense submits to Congress the defense budget materials (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s239">section 239 of this title</ref>) for a fiscal year, the Commander of the United States Cyber Command shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report containing the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ac8c33-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s391a/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An evaluation of whether each military department is meeting the requirements established by the Commander and validated by the Office of the Secretary of Defense, and is effectively implementing the plan required by section 1534 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023, and the requirements established pursuant to section 1533 of such Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ac8c34-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s391a/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> For each military department evaluated under paragraph (1)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7ac8c35-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s391a/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a certification that the military department is meeting such requirements; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7ac8c36-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s391a/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a detailed explanation regarding how the military department is not meeting such requirements.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ac8c37-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s391a/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements of Evaluation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each evaluation under subsection (a)(1) shall include, with respect to the military department being evaluated, the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ac8c38-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s391a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The adequacy of the policies, procedures, and execution of manning, training, and equipping personnel for employment within the Cyber Mission Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ac8c39-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s391a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The sufficiency and robustness of training curricula for personnel to be assigned to either the Cyber Mission Force or units within the cyberspace operations forces, and the compliance by the military department with training standards.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ac8c3a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s391a/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The adequacy of the policies and procedures relating to the assignment and assignment length of members of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force to the Cyber Mission Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ac8c3b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s391a/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The efficacy of the military department in filling key work roles within the Cyber Mission Force, including the proper force mix of civilian, military, and contractor personnel, and the means necessary to meet requirements established by the Commander and validated by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ac8c3c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s391a/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The adequacy of the investment to advance cyber-peculiar science and technology, particularly with respect to capability development for the Cyber Mission Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ac8c3d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s391a/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The sufficiency of the policies, procedures, and investments relating to the establishment and management of military occupational specialty, designator, rating, or Air Force specialty code for personnel responsible for cyberspace operations, including an assessment of the effectiveness of the combination of policies determining availability and retention of sufficient numbers of proficient personnel in key work roles, including length of service commitment, the use of bonuses and special pays, alternative compensation mechanisms, and consecutive tours in preferred assignments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ac8c3e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s391a/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> In coordination with the Principal Cyber Advisor of the Department of Defense, an evaluation of the use by the military department of the shared lexicon of the Department of Defense specific to cyberspace activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ac8c3f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s391a/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> The readiness of personnel serving in the Cyber Mission Force and the cyberspace operations forces to accomplish assigned missions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ac8c40-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s391a/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> The adequacy of actions taken during the period of evaluation by the military department to respond to findings from any previous years’ evaluations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ac8c41-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s391a/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> Any other element determined relevant by the Commander.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida7ac8c42-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tXV/s1502/a">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XV, § 1502(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2879">136 Stat. 2879</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida7ac8c43-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida7ac8c44-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="ida7ac8c45-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 1533 and 1534 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), are sections 1533 and 1534 of <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, also known as the James M. Inhofe National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023, which are set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s167b">section 167b of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida7ac8c46-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7ac8c47-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">First Report</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tXV/s1502/b">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XV, § 1502(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2880">136 Stat. 2880</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tXV/s1502/b">“The Commander of the United States Cyber Command shall submit to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] the first report under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s391a">section 391a of title 10</ref>, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), as soon as practicable after the date of the submission of the defense budget materials for fiscal year 2024.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
