<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida7b3b86f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s397"><num value="397">§ 397.</num><heading> Principal Information Operations Advisor</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7b3b870-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s397/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 30 days after the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall designate, from among officials appointed to a position in the Department of Defense by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, a Principal Information Operations Advisor to act as the principal advisor to the Secretary on all aspects of information operations conducted by the Department.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7b3b871-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s397/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Principal Information Operations Advisor shall have the following responsibilities:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7b3b872-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s397/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Oversight of policy, strategy, planning, resource management, operational considerations, personnel, and technology development across all the elements of information operations of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7b3b873-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s397/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Overall integration and supervision of the deterrence of, conduct of, and defense against information operations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7b3b874-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s397/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Promulgation of policies to ensure adequate coordination and deconfliction with the Department of State, the intelligence community (as such term is defined in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</ref>)), and other relevant agencies and departments of the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7b3b875-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s397/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Coordination with the head of the Global Engagement Center to support the purpose of the Center (as set forth by section 1287(a)(2) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<ref href="/us/pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2656">22 U.S.C. 2656</ref> note)) and liaison with the Center and other relevant Federal Government entities to support such purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7b3b876-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s397/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Establishing and supervising a rigorous risk management process to mitigate the risk of potential exposure of United States persons to information intended exclusively for foreign audiences.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7b3b877-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s397/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Promulgation of standards for the attribution or public acknowledgment, if any, of operations in the information environment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7b3b878-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s397/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Development of guidance for, and promotion of, the capability of the Department to liaison with the private sector and academia on matters relating to the influence activities of malign actors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7b3b879-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s397/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> Such other matters relating to information operations as the Secretary shall specify for purposes of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida7b3b87a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tXVI/s1631/a/1">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVI, § 1631(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1741">133 Stat. 1741</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tX/s1081/a/16">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(16)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3871">134 Stat. 3871</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida7b3b87b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida7b3b87c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="ida7b3b87d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The enactment of this Act, referred to in subsec. (a), probably means the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, which added this section and was approved <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida7b3b87e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> substituted “persons” for “Persons”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida7b3b87f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7b3b880-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Assessment and Optimization of Department of Defense Information and Influence Operations Conducted Through Cyberspace</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tXV/s1522">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XV, § 1522</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2897">136 Stat. 2897</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tXV/s1522">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assessment and Plan</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], the Principal Information Operations Advisor and the Principal Cyber Advisor to the Secretary of Defense shall complete both an assessment and an optimization plan for information and influence operations conducted through cyberspace.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The assessment under subsection (a) shall include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> An inventory of the components of the Department of Defense conducting information and influence operations conducted through cyberspace.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> An examination of sufficiency of resources allocated for information and influence operations conducted through cyberspace.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> An evaluation of the command and control, oversight, and management of matters related to information and influence operations conducted through cyberspace across the Office of the Secretary of Defense and the Joint Staff.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> An evaluation of the existing execution, coordination, synchronization, deconfliction, and consultative procedures and mechanisms for information and influence operations conducted through cyberspace.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Any other matters determined relevant by the Principal Information Operations Advisor and the Principal Cyber Advisor to the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Optimization Plan</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The optimization plan under subsection (a) shall include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Actions that the Department will implement to improve the execution, coordination, synchronization, deconfliction, and consultative procedures and mechanisms for information and influence operations conducted through cyberspace.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> An evaluation of potential organizational changes required to optimize information and influence operations conducted through cyberspace.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Any other matters determined relevant by the Principal Information Operations Advisor and the Principal Cyber Advisor to the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefings</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 30 days after completing the assessment and optimization plan under subsection (a), the Principal Information Operations Advisor and the Principal Cyber Advisor to the Secretary of Defense shall provide to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] a briefing on the assessment and plan.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the briefing is provided under subsection (d), the Secretary of Defense shall implement the optimization plan under subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7b3b881-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Conducting of Military Operations in the Information Environment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tXVI/s1631/b">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title XVI, § 1631(b)</ref>–(i), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1742-1745">133 Stat. 1742–1745</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tX/s1081/c/6">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1081(c)(6)</ref>, title XVII, § 1749(b), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3873">134 Stat. 3873</ref>, 4142, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tX/s1081/c/6">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Affirming the Authority of the Secretary of Defense to Conduct Military Operations in the Information Environment</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Congress affirms that the Secretary of Defense is authorized to conduct military operations, including clandestine operations, in the information environment to defend the United States, allies of the United States, and interests of the United States, including in response to malicious influence activities carried out against the United States or a United States person by a foreign power.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The military operations referred to in paragraph (1), when appropriately authorized include the conduct of military operations short of hostilities and in areas outside of areas of active hostilities for the purpose of preparation of the environment, influence, force protection, and deterrence of hostilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Clandestine Military Operations in the Information Environment as Traditional Military Activities</inline>.—</heading><content>A clandestine military operation in the information environment shall be considered a traditional military activity for the purposes of section 503(e)(2) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3093/e/2">50 U.S.C. 3093(e)(2)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Quarterly Information Operations Briefings</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not less frequently than once each quarter, the Secretary of Defense shall provide the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] a briefing on significant military operations, including all clandestine operations in the information environment, carried out by the Department of Defense during the immediately preceding quarter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> Each briefing under paragraph (1) shall include, with respect to the military operations in the information environment described in such paragraph, the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> An update, disaggregated by geographic and functional command, that describes the operations carried out by the commands.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> An overview of authorities and legal issues applicable to the operations, including any relevant legal limitations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> An outline of any interagency activities and initiatives relating to the operations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Such other matters as the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rule of Construction</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this section may be construed to limit, expand, or otherwise alter the authority of the Secretary to conduct military operations, including clandestine operations, in the information environment, to authorize specific military operations, or to limit, expand, or otherwise alter or otherwise affect the War Powers Resolution (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1541">50 U.S.C. 1541</ref> et seq.) or an authorization for use of military force that was in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cross-functional Team.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><content>The Principal Information Operations Advisor shall integrate the expertise in all elements of information operations and perspectives of appropriate organizations within the Office of the Secretary of Defense, Joint Staff, military departments, Defense Agencies, and combatant commands by establishing and maintaining a full-time cross-functional team composed of subject-matter experts selected from those organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Selection and organization</inline>.—</heading><content>The cross-functional team established under paragraph (1) shall be selected, organized, and managed in a manner consistent with section 911 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<ref href="/us/pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s111">10 U.S.C. 111</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Strategy and Posture Review.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Strategy and posture review required</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>], the Secretary of Defense, acting through the Principal Information Operations Advisor under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s397">section 397 of title 10</ref>, United States Code (as added by subsection (a)) and the cross-functional team established under subsection (f)(1), shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> develop or update, as appropriate, a strategy for operations in the information environment, including how such operations will be synchronized across the Department of Defense and the global, regional, and functional interests of the combatant commands;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> conduct an information operations posture review, including an analysis of capability gaps that inhibit the Department’s ability to successfully execute the strategy developed or updated pursuant to subparagraph (A);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> designate Information Operations Force Providers and Information Operations Joint Force Trainers for the Department of Defense;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> develop and persistently manage a joint lexicon for terms related to information operations, including ‘information operations’, ‘information environment’, ‘operations in the information environment’, and ‘information related capabilities’[;] and [sic]</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> determine the collective set of combat capabilities that will be treated as part of operations in the information environment, including cyber warfare, space warfare, military information support operations, electronic warfare, public affairs, and civil affairs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> designate a Department of Defense entity to develop, apply, and continually refine an assessment capability for defining and measuring the impact of Department information operations, which entity shall be organizationally independent of Department components performing or otherwise engaged in operational support to Department information operations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coordination on certain cyber matters</inline>.—</heading><content>For any matters in the strategy and posture review under paragraph (1) that involve or relate to Department of Defense cyber capabilities, the Principal Information Operations Advisor shall fully collaborate with the Principal Cyber Advisor to the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>At a minimum, the strategy developed or updated pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The establishment of lines of effort, objectives, and tasks that are necessary to implement such strategy and eliminate the capability gaps identified under paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> In partnership with the Principal Cyber Advisor to the Secretary of Defense and in coordination with any other component or Department of Defense entity as selected by the Secretary of Defense, an evaluation of any organizational changes that may be required within the Office of the Secretary of Defense, including potential changes to Under Secretary or Assistant Secretary-level positions to comprehensively conduct oversight of policy development, capabilities, and other aspects of operations in the information environment as determined pursuant to the information operations posture review under paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> An assessment of various models for operationalizing information operations, including the feasibility and advisability of establishing an Army Information Warfare Command.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> A review of the role of information operations in combatant commander operational planning, the ability of combatant commanders to respond to hostile acts by adversaries, and the ability of combatant commanders to engage and build capacity with allies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> A review of the law, policies, and authorities relating to, and necessary for, the United States to conduct military operations, including clandestine military operations, in the information environment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission to congress</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon completion, the Secretary of Defense shall present the strategy for operations in the information environment and the information operations posture review under subparagraphs (A) and (B), respectively, of paragraph (1) to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall provide the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives a report for the structuring and manning of information operations capabilities and forces across the Department of Defense. The Secretary shall provide such Committees with quarterly updates on such plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The plan required under paragraph (1) shall address the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> How the Department of Defense will organize to develop a combined information operations strategy and posture review under subsection (g).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> How the Department will fulfill the roles and responsibilities of the Principal Information Operations Advisor under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s397">section 397 of title 10</ref>, United States Code (as added by subsection (a)).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> How the Department will establish the information operations cross-functional team under subsection (f)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> How the Department will utilize boards and working groups involving senior-level Department representatives on information operations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> Such other matters as the Secretary of Defense considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The terms ‘foreign power’ and ‘United States person’ have the meanings given such terms in section 101 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1801">50 U.S.C. 1801</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘hostilities’ has the same meaning as such term is used in the War Powers Resolution (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1541">50 U.S.C. 1541</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> The term ‘clandestine military operation in the information environment’ means an operation or activity, or associated preparatory actions, authorized by the President or the Secretary of Defense, that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> is marked by, held in, or conducted with secrecy, where the intent is that the operation or activity will not be apparent or acknowledged publicly; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> is to be carried out—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> as part of a military operation plan approved by the President or the Secretary of Defense;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> to deter, safeguard, or defend against attacks or malicious influence activities against the United States, allies of the United States, and interests of the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> in support of hostilities or military operations involving the United States armed forces; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> in support of military operations short of hostilities and in areas where hostilities are not occurring for the purpose of preparation of the environment, influence, force protection, and deterrence.”</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1749/b">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1749(b)</ref>, to <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s1631/g">section 1631(g) of Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, set out above, was executed to reflect the probable intent of Congress, notwithstanding errors in the directory language.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[<ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tX/s1081/c">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1081(c)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3873">134 Stat. 3873</ref>, provided that the amendment made by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1081/c/6">section 1081(c)(6) of Pub. L. 116–283</ref> to <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s1631/i">section 1631(i) of Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, set out above, is effective as of <date date="2020-12-20">Dec. 20, 2020</date> (probably should be <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>) and as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Pub. L. 116–92</ref>.]</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
