<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idaa542d69-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062"><num value="4062">§ 4062.</num><heading> Defense Acquisition Challenge Program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d6a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program Required</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d6b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering, shall carry out a program to provide opportunities for the increased introduction of innovative and cost-saving technology in acquisition programs of the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d6c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The program, to be known as the Defense Acquisition Challenge Program (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Challenge Program”), shall provide any person or activity within or outside the Department of Defense with the opportunity to propose alternatives, to be known as challenge proposals, at the component, subsystem, system, or system-of-systems level of an existing Department of Defense acquisition program, or to address any broader functional challenge to Department of Defense missions that may not fall within an acquisition program, that would result in improvements in performance, affordability, manufacturability, or operational capability of that acquisition program or function.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d6d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Panels</inline>.—</heading><content>The Under Secretary shall establish one or more panels of highly qualified scientists and engineers (hereinafter in this section referred to as “Panels”) to provide preliminary evaluations of challenge proposals under subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d6e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Preliminary Evaluation by Panels</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d6f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Under procedures prescribed by the Under Secretary, a person or activity within or outside the Department of Defense may submit challenge proposals to a Panel, through the unsolicited proposal process or in response to a broad agency announcement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d70-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Under Secretary shall establish procedures pursuant to which appropriate officials of the Department of Defense may identify proposals submitted through the unsolicited proposal process as challenge proposals. The procedures shall provide for the expeditious referral of such proposals to a Panel for preliminary evaluation under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d71-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Under Secretary shall issue on an annual basis not less than one such broad agency announcement inviting interested parties to submit challenge proposals. Such announcements may also identify particular technology areas and acquisition programs or functions that will be given priority in the evaluation of challenge proposals.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d72-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d73-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> The Under Secretary shall establish procedures for the prompt issuance of a solicitation for challenge proposals addressing—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa542d74-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/c/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> any acquisition program for which, since the last such announcement, the Secretary concerned has determined under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4374">section 4374 of this title</ref> that the program’s acquisition unit cost or procurement unit cost has increased by a percentage equal to or greater than the critical cost growth threshold for the program (in this section referred to as a “critical cost growth threshold breach”);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa542d75-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/c/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any design, engineering, manufacturing, or technology integration issues, in accordance with the assessment required by <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4375/b">section 4375(b) of this title</ref>, that have contributed significantly to the cost growth of such program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa542d76-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/c/4/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> any functional challenges of importance to Department of Defense missions.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d77-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A solicitation under this paragraph may be included in a broad agency announcement issued pursuant to paragraph (3) as long as the broad agency announcement is released in an expeditious manner following the determination of the Secretary concerned that a critical cost growth threshold breach has occurred with respect to a major defense acquisition program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d78-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> Under procedures established by the Under Secretary, a Panel shall carry out a preliminary evaluation of each challenge proposal submitted in response to a broad agency announcement, or submitted through the unsolicited proposal process and identified as a challenge proposal in accordance with paragraph (2), to determine each of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa542d79-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/c/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Whether the challenge proposal has merit.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa542d7a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/c/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Whether the challenge proposal is likely to result in improvements in performance, affordability, manufacturability, or operational capability at the component, subsystem, system, or system-of-systems level of an acquisition program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa542d7b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/c/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Whether the challenge proposal could be implemented in the acquisition program rapidly, at an acceptable cost, and without unacceptable disruption to the acquisition program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa542d7c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/c/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Whether the challenge proposal is likely to result in improvements to any functional challenges of importance to Department of Defense missions, and whether the proposal could be implemented rapidly, at an acceptable cost, and without unacceptable disruption to such missions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d7d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> The Under Secretary—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa542d7e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/c/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> may establish procedures to ensure that the Challenge Program does not become an avenue for the repetitive submission of proposals that have been previously reviewed and found not to have merit; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa542d7f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/c/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> may establish procedures to ensure that the Challenge Program establishes appropriate priorities for proposals from businesses that are not major contractors with the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d80-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/c/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> If a Panel determines that a challenge proposal satisfies each of the criteria specified in paragraph (5), the person or activity submitting that challenge proposal shall be provided an opportunity to submit such challenge proposal for a full review and evaluation under subsection (d).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d81-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Full Review and Evaluation</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d82-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Under procedures prescribed by the Under Secretary, for each challenge proposal submitted for a full review and evaluation as provided in subsection (c)(7), the office carrying out the acquisition program to which the proposal relates shall, in consultation with the prime system contractor carrying out such program, conduct a full review and evaluation of the proposal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d83-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The full review and evaluation shall, independent of the determination of a Panel under subsection (c)(5), determine each of the matters specified in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of such subsection. The full review and evaluation shall also include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa542d84-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an assessment of the cost of adopting the challenge proposal and implementing it in the acquisition program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa542d85-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> consideration of any intellectual property issues associated with the challenge proposal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d86-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Action Upon Favorable Full Review and Evaluation</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d87-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Under procedures prescribed by the Under Secretary, each challenge proposal determined under a full review and evaluation to satisfy each of the criteria specified in subsection (c)(5) with respect to an acquisition program shall be considered by the office carrying out the applicable acquisition program and the prime system contractor for incorporation into the acquisition program as a new technology insertion at the component, subsystem, system, or system-of-systems level.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d88-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Under Secretary shall encourage the adoption of each challenge proposal referred to in paragraph (1) by providing suitable incentives to the office carrying out the acquisition program and the prime system contractor carrying out such program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d89-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In the case of a challenge proposal submitted in response to a solicitation issued as a result of a critical cost growth threshold breach that is determined under full review and evaluation to satisfy each of the criteria specified in subsection (c)(5), the Under Secretary shall establish guidelines for covering the costs of the challenge proposal. If appropriate, such guidelines shall not be restricted to funding provided by the Defense Acquisition Challenge Program, but shall also consider alternative funding sources, such as the acquisition program with respect to which the breach occurred.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d8a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Action Upon Unfavorable Full Review and Evaluation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Under procedures prescribed by the Under Secretary, if a challenge proposal is determined by a Panel to satisfy each of the criteria specified in subsection (c)(5), but is not determined under a full review and evaluation to satisfy such criteria, the following provisions apply:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa542d8b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The office carrying out the full review and evaluation shall provide to the Panel that conducted the preliminary evaluation a statement containing a summary of the rationale for the unfavorable evaluation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa542d8c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If the Panel disagrees with the rationale provided under paragraph (1), the Panel may return the challenge proposal to the office for further consideration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d8d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Access to Technical Resources</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d8e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Under procedures established by the Under Secretary, the technical resources of the laboratories, research, development, and engineering centers, test and evaluation activities, and other elements of the Department may be called upon to support the activities of the Challenge Program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d8f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Funds available to carry out this program may be used to compensate such laboratories, centers, activities, and elements for technical assistance provided to a Panel pursuant to paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d90-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Conflicts of Interest and Confidentiality</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out each preliminary evaluation under subsection (c) and full review under subsection (d), the Under Secretary shall ensure the elimination of conflicts of interest and that the identity of any person or activity submitting a challenge proposal is not disclosed outside the Federal Government, prior to contract award, without the consent of the person or activity. For purposes of the proceeding sentence, the term “Federal Government” includes both employees of the Federal Government and employees of Federal Government contractors providing advisory and assistance services as described in part 37 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d91-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Use of Funds</inline>.—</heading><content>Funds made available for the Challenge Program may be used only for activities authorized by this section, and not for implementation of challenge proposals.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d92-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Use of Certain Procedures as Use of Competitive Procedures</inline>.—</heading><content>The use of general solicitation competitive procedures established under subsection (c) shall be considered to be the use of competitive procedures for purposes of sections 3201 through 3205 of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d93-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">System Defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term “system”—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa542d94-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/k/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa542d95-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/k/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the organization of hardware, software, material, facilities, personnel, data, and services needed to perform a designated function with specified results (such as the gathering of specified data, its processing, and its delivery to users); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa542d96-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/k/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a combination of two or more interrelated pieces (or sets) of equipment arranged in a functional package to perform an operational function or to satisfy a requirement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa542d97-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/k/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> includes a major system.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa542d98-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/l"><num value="l">(l)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pilot Program for Programs Other Than Major Defense Acquisition Programs.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa542d99-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/l/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering shall carry out a pilot program to expand the use of the authority provided in this section to provide opportunities for the introduction of innovative and cost-saving approaches to programs other than major defense acquisition programs through the submission, review, and implementation, where appropriate, of qualifying proposals.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa542d9a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/l/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Qualifying proposals</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this subsection, a qualifying proposal is an offer to supply a nondevelopmental item that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa542d9b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/l/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is evaluated as achieving a level of performance that is at least equal to the level of performance of an item being procured under a covered acquisition program and as providing savings in excess of 15 percent after considering all costs to the Government of implementing such proposal; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa542d9c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/l/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is evaluated as achieving a level of performance that is significantly better than the level of performance of an item being procured under a covered acquisition program without any increase in cost to the Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa542d9d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/l/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Review procedures</inline>.—</heading><content>The Under Secretary shall adopt modifications as may be needed to the procedures applicable to the Challenge Program to provide for Department of Defense review of, and action on, qualifying proposals. Such procedures shall include, at a minimum, the issuance of a broad agency announcement inviting interested parties to submit qualifying proposals in areas of interest to the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa542d9e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/l/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subsection:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa542d9f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/l/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Nondevelopmental item</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “nondevelopmental item” has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s110">section 110 of title 41</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa542da0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/l/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered acquisition program</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “covered acquisition program” means any acquisition program of the Department of Defense other than a major defense acquisition program, but does not include any contract awarded under an exception to competitive acquisition authorized by the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s631">15 U.S.C. 631</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa542da1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/l/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Level of performance</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “level of performance”, with respect to a nondevelopmental item, means the extent to which the item demonstrates required item functional characteristics.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa542da2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4062/l/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sunset</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority to carry out the pilot program under this subsection shall terminate on <date date="2021-01-07">January 7, 2021</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idaa542da3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tII/s243/a">Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title II, § 243(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2495">116 Stat. 2495</ref>, § 2359b; amended <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tII/s213/b">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title II, § 213(b)</ref>, (d)–(g), <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2121-2123">120 Stat. 2121–2123</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/417">Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title VIII, § 821, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4531">122 Stat. 4531</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/dA/tVIII/s827">Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title VIII, § 827</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4270">124 Stat. 4270</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dA/tX/s1076/e/3">Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(e)(3)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1951">126 Stat. 1951</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tX/s1091/a/10">Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title X, § 1091(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/876">127 Stat. 876</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tX/s1071/a/6">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3504">128 Stat. 3504</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tVIII/s828">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 828</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2281">130 Stat. 2281</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tIX/s902/56">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(56)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1549">133 Stat. 1549</ref>; renumbered § 4062 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXVIII">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII</ref>, §§ 1842(b), 1883(b)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4244">134 Stat. 4244</ref>, 4294; <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tXVII/s1701/d/9">Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(d)(9)</ref>, (q)(1), (u)(3)(B), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/2137">135 Stat. 2137</ref>, 2148, 2152.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idaa542da4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idaa542da5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idaa542da6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Small Business Act, referred to in subsec. (<i>l</i>)(4)(B), is <ref href="/us/pl/85/536/s2">Pub. L. 85–536, § 2</ref>(1 et seq.), <date date="1958-07-18">July 18, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/384">72 Stat. 384</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 14A (§ 631 et seq.) of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s631">section 631 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idaa542da7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—<ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1842/b">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1842(b)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s1701/q/1">Pub. L. 117–81, § 1701(q)(1)</ref>, (u)(3)(B), renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2359b">section 2359b of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s1701/d/9/A/i">Pub. L. 117–81, § 1701(d)(9)(A)(i)</ref>, which directed the substitution of “section 4374” for “section 2433(d)”, could not be executed because of the intervening amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1883/b/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1883(b)(2)</ref>. See note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1883/b/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1883(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “section 4374” for “section 2433(d)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s1701/d/9/A/ii">Pub. L. 117–81, § 1701(d)(9)(A)(ii)</ref>, substituted “section 4375(b)” for “section 2433(e)(2)(A)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1883/b/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1883(b)(2)</ref>, which directed that each reference in the text of title 10 to a section that was redesignated by title XVIII of <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, as such section was in effect before the redesignation, be amended by striking such reference and inserting a reference to the appropriate redesignated section, could not be executed for “section 2433(e)(2)(A)” as there were no subparagraphs in subsec. (e)(2) of former <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2433">section 2433 of this title</ref> after general amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/23/tII/s206/a/3">Pub. L. 111–23, title II, § 206(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2009-05-22">May 22, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1728">123 Stat. 1728</ref>. Section 2433(e)(2) was transferred to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4375/b">section 4375(b) of this title</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s1701/d/9/B">Pub. L. 117–81, § 1701(d)(9)(B)</ref>, substituted “sections 3201 through 3205” for “chapter 137”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s1701/d/9/C">Pub. L. 117–81, § 1701(d)(9)(C)</ref>, which directed that “(as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2302/5">section 2302(5) of this title</ref>)” be struck out, was executed by striking out “(as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3041">section 3041 of this title</ref>)” before period at end to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the intervening amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1883/b/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1883(b)(2)</ref>. See note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1883/b/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1883(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “section 3041” for “section 2302(5)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsecs. (a)(1), (<i>l</i>)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Pub. L. 116–92</ref> substituted “Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering” for “Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s828/a">Pub. L. 114–328, § 828(a)</ref>, substituted “system, or system-of-systems level of an existing Department of Defense acquisition program, or to address any broader functional challenge to Department of Defense missions that may not fall within an acquisition program, that would result in improvements in performance, affordability, manufacturability, or operational capability of that acquisition program or function.” for “or system level of an existing Department of Defense acquisition program that would result in improvements in performance, affordability, manufacturability, or operational capability of that acquisition program.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s828/d/1">Pub. L. 114–328, § 828(d)(1)</ref>, inserted “or functions” after “acquisition programs”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4)(A)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s828/d/2">Pub. L. 114–328, § 828(d)(2)</ref>, added cl. (iii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s828/d/4">Pub. L. 114–328, § 828(d)(4)</ref>, substituted “system, or system-of-systems” for “or system”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s828/d/3">Pub. L. 114–328, § 828(d)(3)</ref>, added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s828/d/4">Pub. L. 114–328, § 828(d)(4)</ref>, substituted “system, or system-of-systems” for “or system”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s828/b/2">Pub. L. 114–328, § 828(b)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (j). Former subsec. (j) redesignated (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (k), (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s828/b/1">Pub. L. 114–328, § 828(b)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (j) and (k) as (k) and (<i>l</i>), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s828/c">Pub. L. 114–328, § 828(c)</ref>, substituted “2021” for “2016”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (k)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/113/291">Pub. L. 113–291</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s110">section 110 of title 41</ref>” for “section 4 of the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s403">41 U.S.C. 403</ref>)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (k)(4)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66">Pub. L. 113–66</ref> inserted period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239">Pub. L. 112–239</ref> substituted “<date date="2016-01-07">January 7, 2016</date>” for “the date that is five years after the date of the enactment of this Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsecs. (j) to (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383">Pub. L. 111–383</ref> redesignated subsec. (<i>l</i>) as (j), added subsec. (k), and struck out former subsecs. (j) and (k) which related to annual report and termination of authority, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/110/417">Pub. L. 110–417</ref> added subsec. (<i>l</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (c)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s213/b/1">Pub. L. 109–364, § 213(b)(1)</ref>, added par. (4) and redesignated former par. (4) as (5). Former par. (5) redesignated (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s213/b/1/A">Pub. L. 109–364, § 213(b)(1)(A)</ref>, (d), redesignated par. (5) as (6) and amended it generally. Prior to amendment, par. (6) read as follows: “The Under Secretary may establish procedures to ensure that the Challenge Program does not become an avenue for the repetitive submission of proposals that have been previously reviewed and found not to have merit.” Former par. (6) redesignated (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s213/b/1/A">Pub. L. 109–364, § 213(b)(1)(A)</ref>, (g)(1), redesignated par. (6) as (7) and substituted “paragraph (5)” for “paragraph (4)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s213/g/2">Pub. L. 109–364, § 213(g)(2)</ref>, substituted “subsection (c)(7)” for “subsection (c)(6)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s213/g/3">Pub. L. 109–364, § 213(g)(3)</ref>, substituted “subsection (c)(5)” for “subsection (c)(4)” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s213/g/4">Pub. L. 109–364, § 213(g)(4)</ref>, substituted “subsection (c)(5)” for “subsection (c)(4)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s213/b/2">Pub. L. 109–364, § 213(b)(2)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (f), (g). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s213/b/3">Pub. L. 109–364, § 213(b)(3)</ref>, added subsec. (f) and redesignated former subsec. (f) as (g). Former subsec. (g) redesignated (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s213/b/3/A">Pub. L. 109–364, § 213(b)(3)(A)</ref>, (e), redesignated subsec. (g) as (h), substituted “Conflicts of Interest and Confidentiality” for “Elimination of Conflicts of Interest” in heading, substituted “conflicts of interest and that the identity of any person or activity submitting a challenge proposal is not disclosed outside the Federal Government, prior to contract award, without the consent of the person or activity” for “conflicts of interest”, and inserted at end “For purposes of the proceeding sentence, the term ‘Federal Government’ includes both employees of the Federal Government and employees of Federal Government contractors providing advisory and assistance services as described in part 37 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation.” Former subsec. (h) redesignated (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s213/b/3/A">Pub. L. 109–364, § 213(b)(3)(A)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (h) as (i). Former subsec. (i) redesignated (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s213/b/3/A">Pub. L. 109–364, § 213(b)(3)(A)</ref>, (4), redesignated subsec. (i) as (j) and substituted “The report shall also include a list of each challenge proposal that was determined by a Panel to satisfy each of the criteria specified in subsection (c)(5), but was not determined under a full review and evaluation to satisfy such criteria, together with a detailed rationale for the Department’s determination that such criteria were not satisfied” for “No report is required for a fiscal year in which the Challenge Program is not carried out”. Former subsec. (j) redesignated (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s213/b/3/A">Pub. L. 109–364, § 213(b)(3)(A)</ref>, (f), redesignated subsec. (j) as (k) and substituted “2012” for “2007”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idaa567698-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idaa567699-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s1701/d/9">section 1701(d)(9) of Pub. L. 117–81</ref> to take effect immediately after the amendments made by title XVIII of <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> have taken effect, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s1701/a/3">section 1701(a)(3) of Pub. L. 117–81</ref>, set out in a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref> and note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 1701(q)(1), (u)(3)(B) of <ref href="/us/pl/117/81">Pub. L. 117–81</ref> applicable as if included in the enactment of title XVIII of <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> as enacted, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s1701/a/2">section 1701(a)(2) of Pub. L. 117–81</ref>, set out in a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref> and Effective Date note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> effective <date date="2022-01-01">Jan. 1, 2022</date>, with additional provisions for delayed implementation and applicability of existing law, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1801/d">section 1801(d) of Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
