<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idaa58e82a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093"><num value="4093">§ 4093.</num><heading> Science, Mathematics, and Research for Transformation (SMART) Defense Education Program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e82b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement for Program</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall carry out a program to provide financial assistance for education in science, mathematics, engineering, and technology skills and disciplines that, as determined by the Secretary, are critical to the national security functions of the Department of Defense and are needed in the Department of Defense workforce.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e82c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Financial Assistance</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e82d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Under the program under this section, the Secretary of Defense may award a scholarship or fellowship in accordance with this section to a person who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa58e82e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is a citizen of the United States or, subject to subsection (g), a country the government of which is a party to The Technical Cooperation Program (TTCP) memorandum of understanding of <date date="1995-10-24">October 24, 1995</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa58e82f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is pursuing an associates degree, undergraduate degree, or advanced degree in a critical skill or discipline described in subsection (a) at an accredited institution of higher education; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa58e830-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> enters into a service agreement with the Secretary of Defense as described in subsection (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e831-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The amount of the financial assistance provided under a scholarship or fellowship awarded to a person under this subsection shall be an amount determined by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e832-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Financial assistance provided under a scholarship or fellowship awarded under this section may be paid directly to the recipient of such scholarship or fellowship or to an administering entity for disbursement of the funds.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e833-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Service Agreement for Recipients of Financial Assistance</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e834-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> To receive financial assistance under this section—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa58e835-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in the case of an employee of the Department of Defense, the employee shall enter into a written agreement to continue in the employment of the department for the period of obligated service determined under paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa58e836-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> in the case of a person not an employee of the Department of Defense, the person shall enter into a written agreement to accept and continue employment for the period of obligated service determined under paragraph (2)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa58e837-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/c/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> with the Department, including by serving on active duty in the Armed Forces; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa58e838-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/c/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> with a public or private entity or organization outside of the Department if the Secretary—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idaa58e839-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/c/1/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> is unable to find an appropriate position for the person within the Department; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idaa58e83a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/c/1/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> determines that employment of the person with such entity or organization for the purpose of such obligated service would provide a benefit to the Department.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e83b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> For the purposes of this subsection, the period of obligated service for a recipient of financial assistance under this section shall be the period determined by the Secretary of Defense as being appropriate to obtain adequate service in exchange for such financial assistance. The period of service required of a recipient may not be less than the total period of pursuit of a degree that is covered by such financial assistance. The period of obligated service is in addition to any other period for which the recipient is obligated to serve in the civil service of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e83c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> An agreement entered into under this subsection by a person pursuing an academic degree shall include any terms and conditions that the Secretary of Defense determines necessary to protect the interests of the United States or otherwise appropriate for carrying out this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e83d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Employment of Program Participants</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa58e83e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> may, without regard to any provision of title 5 governing appointment of employees to competitive service positions within the Department of Defense, appoint to a position in the Department of Defense in the excepted service an individual who has successfully completed an academic program for which a scholarship or fellowship under this section was awarded and who, under the terms of the agreement for such scholarship or fellowship, at the time of such appointment, owes a service commitment to the Department;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa58e83f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> may, upon satisfactory completion of 2 years of substantially continuous service by an incumbent who was appointed to an excepted service position under the authority of paragraph (1), convert the appointment of such individual, without competition, to a career or career conditional appointment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa58e840-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> may establish arrangements so that participants may participate in a paid internship for an appropriate period with an industry sponsor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e841-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Refund for Period of Unserved Obligated Service</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e842-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e843-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A participant in the program under this section who is not an employee of the Department of Defense and who voluntarily fails to complete the educational program for which financial assistance has been provided under this section, or fails to maintain satisfactory academic progress as determined in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, shall refund to the United States an appropriate amount, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e844-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> A participant in the program under this section who is an employee of the Department of Defense and who—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa58e845-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/e/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> voluntarily fails to complete the educational program for which financial assistance has been provided, or fails to maintain satisfactory academic progress as determined in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa58e846-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/e/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> before completion of the period of obligated service required of such participant—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa58e847-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/e/1/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> voluntarily terminates such participant’s employment with the Department; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa58e848-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/e/1/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> is removed from such participant’s employment with the Department on the basis of misconduct,</content>
</subclause>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall refund the United States an appropriate amount, as determined by the Secretary.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e849-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An obligation to reimburse the United States imposed under paragraph (1) is for all purposes a debt owed to the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e84a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense may waive, in whole or in part, a refund required under paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines that recovery would be against equity and good conscience or would be contrary to the best interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e84b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> A discharge in bankruptcy under title 11 that is entered less than five years after the termination of an agreement under this section does not discharge the person signing such agreement from a debt arising under such agreement or under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e84c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Relationship to Other Programs</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e84d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall coordinate the provision of financial assistance under the authority of this section with the provision of financial assistance under the other authorities provided in this chapter in order to maximize the benefits derived by the Department of Defense from the exercise of all such authorities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e84e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall seek to enter into partnerships with minority institutions of higher education and appropriate public and private sector organizations to diversify the participants in the program under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e84f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In coordination with the efforts under paragraph (2), the Secretary of Defense shall additionally establish a program, which shall be known as the “Ronald V. Dellums Memorial Fellowship in STEM”, to provide financial assistance under this section to at least 30 students from communities that are underrepresented in the Department of Defense STEM workforce, not fewer of 50 percent of whom shall attend historically Black colleges and universities and minority-serving institutions. As part of such program, the Secretary shall establish an internship program that provides each student who is awarded a fellowship under this paragraph with an internship in an organization or element of the Department of Defense, and to the extent practicable, each such student shall be paired with a mid-level or a senior-level official of the relevant organization or element of the Department of Defense who shall serve as a mentor during the internship.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e850-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Participation</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e851-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary may not award scholarships or fellowships under this section to more than five individuals described in paragraph (2) per year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e852-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> An individual described in this paragraph is an individual who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa58e853-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/g/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> has not previously been awarded a scholarship or fellowship under the program under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa58e854-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/g/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is not a citizen of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa58e855-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/g/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> is a citizen of a country the government of which is a party to The Technical Cooperation Program (TTCP) memorandum of understanding of <date date="1995-10-24">October 24, 1995</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa58e856-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4093/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Institution of Higher Education Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idaa58e857-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tXI/s1104/d/1">Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title XI, § 1104(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3449">119 Stat. 3449</ref>, § 2192a; amended <ref href="/us/pl/110/417">Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title X, § 1061(a)(5), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4612">122 Stat. 4612</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/dA/tXI/s1102/a">Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XI, § 1102(a)</ref>–(d)(1), <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2484">123 Stat. 2484</ref>, 2485; <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tXI/s1105/a/1">Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title XI, § 1105(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/886">127 Stat. 886</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tII/s215">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title II, § 215</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3327">128 Stat. 3327</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/92/dA/tII/s212">Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title II, § 212</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/767">129 Stat. 767</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tII/s242">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title II, § 242</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3488">134 Stat. 3488</ref>; renumbered § 4093, <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXVIII/s1843/a">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1843(a)</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tXVII/s1701/u/4/A">Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(u)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/2153">135 Stat. 2153</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tX/s1083">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title X, § 1083</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2800">136 Stat. 2800</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idaa58e858-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idaa58e859-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idaa58e85a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/109/163">Pub. L. 109–163</ref>, consists of text of <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/dA/tXI/s1105">Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title XI, § 1105</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/2074">118 Stat. 2074</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tX/s1056/d">Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1056(d)</ref>, title XI, § 1104(a)–(c), <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3440">119 Stat. 3440</ref>, 3448, 3449; <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/dA/tX/s1075/h/5">Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(h)(5)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4377">124 Stat. 4377</ref>, which was formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2192">section 2192 of this title</ref>, and was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tXI/s1104/e/1">Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title XI, § 1104(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3450">119 Stat. 3450</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idaa58e85b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (f)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Pub. L. 117–263</ref> added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—<ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1843/a">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1843(a)</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s1701/u/4/A">Pub. L. 117–81, § 1701(u)(4)(A)</ref>, renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2192a">section 2192a of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s242/1">Pub. L. 116–283, § 242(1)</ref>, inserted “, including by serving on active duty in the Armed Forces” after “Department”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s242/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 242(2)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s242/3">Pub. L. 116–283, § 242(3)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/114/92/s212/1">Pub. L. 114–92, § 212(1)</ref>, inserted “or, subject to subsection (g), a country the government of which is a party to The Technical Cooperation Program (TTCP) memorandum of understanding of <date date="1995-10-24">October 24, 1995</date>” after “United States”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (g), (h). <ref href="/us/pl/114/92/s212/2">Pub. L. 114–92, § 212(2)</ref>, (3), added subsec. (g) and redesignated former subsec. (g) as (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (c)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/113/291">Pub. L. 113–291</ref> amended subpar. (B) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (B) read as follows: “in the case of a person not an employee of the Department of Defense, the person shall enter into a written agreement to accept and continue employment in the Department of Defense for the period of obligated service determined under paragraph (2).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66">Pub. L. 113–66</ref> substituted “an amount determined by the Secretary of Defense” for “the amount determined by the Secretary of Defense as being necessary to pay all educational expenses incurred by that person, including tuition, fees, cost of books, laboratory expenses, equipment expenses, and expenses of room and board”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/s1102/b">Pub. L. 111–84, § 1102(b)</ref>, substituted “The” for “Except as provided in subsection (d), the” in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/s1102/a">Pub. L. 111–84, § 1102(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (d) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (d) provided that, under certain circumstances, the Secretary of Defense could appoint or retain a SMART program participant as an interim employee and separate such participant from employment if no appropriate permanent position was available at the end of the interim period and that the period of interim service would count towards the participant’s obligated service requirements.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/s1102/c">Pub. L. 111–84, § 1102(c)</ref>, struck out “The program under this section is in addition to the authorities provided in chapter 111 of this title.” before “The Secretary” and substituted “the other authorities provided in this chapter” for “the authorities provided in such chapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (g), (h). <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/s1102/d/1">Pub. L. 111–84, § 1102(d)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (h) as (g) and struck out former subsec. (g). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Not later than <date date="2007-02-01">February 1, 2007</date>, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives, the Committee on Governmental Affairs of the Senate, and the Committee on Government Reform of the House of Representatives a plan for expanding and improving the national defense science and engineering workforce educational assistance program carried out under this section as appropriate to improve recruitment and retention to meet the requirements of the Department of Defense for its science and engineering workforce on a short-term basis and on a long-term basis.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (e)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/110/417/s1061/a/5/A">Pub. L. 110–417, § 1061(a)(5)(A)</ref>, substituted “title 11” for “title 11, United States Code,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/110/417/s1061/a/5/B">Pub. L. 110–417, § 1061(a)(5)(B)</ref>, substituted “this title” for “title 10, United States Code”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idaa58e85c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idaa58e85d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/117/81">Pub. L. 117–81</ref> applicable as if included in the enactment of title XVIII of <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> as enacted, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s1701/a/2">section 1701(a)(2) of Pub. L. 117–81</ref>, set out in a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref> and note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1843/a">section 1843(a) of Pub. L. 116–283</ref> effective <date date="2022-01-01">Jan. 1, 2022</date>, with additional provisions for delayed implementation and applicability of existing law, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1801/d">section 1801(d) of Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idaa58e85e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">National Security Workforce and Educational Diversity Activities</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tII/s250">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title II, § 250</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3495">134 Stat. 3495</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tII/s250">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall seek to diversify participation in the Science, Mathematics, and Research for Transformation (SMART) Defense Education Program under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2192a">section 2192a of title 10</ref>, United States Code [now <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4093">10 U.S.C. 4093</ref>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Activities</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> subject to the availability of appropriations for this purpose, set aside funds for financial assistance, scholarships, and fellowships for students at historically Black colleges or universities or at minority institutions of higher education and such other institutions as the Secretary considers appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> partner with institutions of higher education, and such other public and private sector organizations as the Secretary considers appropriate, to increase diversity of participants in the program described in subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> establish individual and organizational incentives, and such other activities as the Secretary considers appropriate, to increase diversity of student participation in the program described in subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> increase awareness of opportunities to participate in the program described in subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> evaluate the potential for new programs, fellowships, and other activities at historically Black colleges or universities and minority institutions of higher education to increase diversity in educational and workforce development programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> identify potential changes to the program described in subsection (a) that would improve diversity of participants in such program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> establish metrics to evaluate success of activities under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2024-09-30">September 30, 2024</date>, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] a report that evaluates the success of activities conducted by the Secretary in increasing diversity in appropriate programs of the Department of Defense and hiring and retaining diverse individuals in the science, mathematics, and research workforce of the public sector.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idaa58e85f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effect on Current Participants in SMART Pilot Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tXI/s1104/f">Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title XI, § 1104(f)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3450">119 Stat. 3450</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tXI/s1104/f">“Participation in the Science, Mathematics, and Research for Transformation (SMART) Defense Scholarship Pilot Program under <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s1105">section 1105 of Public Law 108–375</ref> [see Codification note above] by an individual who has entered into an agreement under that pilot program before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>] shall be governed by the terms of such agreement without regard to the amendments made by this section [enacting this section, amending <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3304">section 3304 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees, and amending and repealing provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2192">section 2192 of this title</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
