<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida7b8738f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s421"><num value="421">§ 421.</num><heading> Funds for foreign cryptologic support</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7b87390-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s421/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense may use appropriated funds available to the Department of Defense for intelligence and communications purposes to pay for the expenses of arrangements with foreign countries for cryptologic support.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7b87391-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s421/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may use funds other than appropriated funds to pay for the expenses of arrangements with foreign countries for cryptologic support without regard for the provisions of law relating to the expenditure of United States Government funds, except that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7b87392-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s421/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> no such funds may be expended, in whole or in part, by or for the benefit of the Department of Defense for a purpose for which Congress had previously denied funds; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7b87393-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s421/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> proceeds from the sale of cryptologic items may be used only to purchase replacement items similar to the items that are sold; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7b87394-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s421/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the authority provided by this subsection may not be used to acquire items or services for the principal benefit of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7b87395-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s421/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> Any funds expended under the authority of subsection (a) shall be reported to the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives pursuant to the provisions of title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3091">50 U.S.C. 3091</ref> et seq.). Funds expended under the authority of subsection (b) shall be reported pursuant to procedures jointly agreed upon by such committees and the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida7b87396-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/96/450/tIV/s401/a">Pub. L. 96–450, title IV, § 401(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-14">Oct. 14, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1977">94 Stat. 1977</ref>, § 140a; amended <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s3/b/2">Pub. L. 97–258, § 3(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1063">96 Stat. 1063</ref>; renumbered § 128 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/99/433/tI">Pub. L. 99–433, title I</ref>, §§ 101(a)(3), 110(d)(5), <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/994">100 Stat. 994</ref>, 1002; renumbered § 421, <ref href="/us/pl/100/26/s9/a/2">Pub. L. 100–26, § 9(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/287">101 Stat. 287</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/453/tVII/s701/a">Pub. L. 100–453, title VII, § 701(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1911">102 Stat. 1911</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tXVI/s1622/c/3">Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1622(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1604">103 Stat. 1604</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tX/s1071/c/3">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3508">128 Stat. 3508</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida7b87397-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida7b87398-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="ida7b87399-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Security Act of 1947, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343">act July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/495">61 Stat. 495</ref>. Title V of the Act is classified generally to subchapter III (§ 3091 et seq.) of chapter 44 of Title 50, War and National Defense. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida7b8739a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/113/291">Pub. L. 113–291</ref> substituted “(<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3091">50 U.S.C. 3091</ref> et seq.)” for “(<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s413">50 U.S.C. 413</ref> et seq.)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/101/189">Pub. L. 101–189</ref> substituted “House of Representatives pursuant to the provisions of title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s413">50 U.S.C. 413</ref> et seq.). Funds” for “House pursuant to the provisions of title V of the National Security Act of 1947, as amended, and funds”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/453">Pub. L. 100–453</ref> struck out “transfers” after “Funds” in section catchline and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Secretary of Defense may use funds available to the Department of Defense for intelligence and communications purposes to pay for the expenses of arrangements with foreign countries for cryptologic support.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—<ref href="/us/pl/100/26">Pub. L. 100–26</ref> renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s128">section 128 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—<ref href="/us/pl/99/433">Pub. L. 99–433</ref> renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s140a">section 140a of this title</ref> as <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s128">section 128 of this title</ref> and substituted “Funds” for “Secretary of Defense: funds” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—<ref href="/us/pl/97/258">Pub. L. 97–258</ref> struck out provision that payments under this section could be made without regard to section 3651 of the Revised Statutes of the United States (<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s543">31 U.S.C. 543</ref>).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida7b8739b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7b8739c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Comprehensive Independent Study of National Cryptography Policy</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tII/s267">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title II, § 267</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1611">107 Stat. 1611</ref>, directed Secretary of Defense, not later than 90 days after <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, to request National Research Council of National Academy of Sciences to conduct a comprehensive study to assess effect of cryptographic technologies on national security, law enforcement, commercial, and privacy interests, and effect of export controls on commercial interests, with cooperation of other agencies, and report findings and conclusions within 2 years after processing of security clearances to Secretary of Defense, and directed Secretary to submit a report in unclassified form to Committee on Armed Services, Committee on the Judiciary, and Select Committee on Intelligence of Senate and to Committee on Armed Services, Committee on the Judiciary, and Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of House of Representatives, not later than 120 days after the report is submitted to the Secretary.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
