<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida7bae51e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s428"><num value="428">§ 428.</num><heading> Defense industrial security</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7bae51f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s428/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Responsibility for Defense Industrial Security</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall be responsible for the protection of classified information disclosed to contractors of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7bae520-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s428/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consistency With Executive Orders and Directives</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall carry out the responsibility assigned under subsection (a) in a manner consistent with Executive Order 12829 (or any successor order to such executive order) and consistent with policies relating to the National Industrial Security Program (or any successor to such program).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7bae521-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s428/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Performance of Industrial Security Functions for Other Agencies</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may perform industrial security functions for other agencies of the Federal government upon request or upon designation of the Department of Defense as executive agent for the National Industrial Security Program (or any successor to such program).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7bae522-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s428/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations and Policy Guidance</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall prescribe, and from time to time revise, such regulations and policy guidance as are necessary to ensure the protection of classified information disclosed to contractors of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7bae523-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s428/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Dedication of Resources</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall ensure that sufficient resources are provided to staff, train, and support such personnel as are necessary to fully protect classified information disclosed to contractors of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida7bae524-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/110/417">Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title VIII, § 845(a)(1), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4541">122 Stat. 4541</ref>, § 438; renumbered § 428, <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/dA/tX/s1073/a/4">Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2472">123 Stat. 2472</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/dA/tX/s1075/b/11">Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title X, § 1075(b)(11)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4369">124 Stat. 4369</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tX/s1051/a/3">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1051(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1560">131 Stat. 1560</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida7bae525-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida7bae526-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="ida7bae527-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order 12829, referred to in subsec. (b), is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3161">section 3161 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida7bae528-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91">Pub. L. 115–91</ref> struck out subsec. (f) which related to biennial reports on expenditures and activities of the Department of Defense in carrying out the requirements of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383">Pub. L. 111–383</ref> struck out “, United States Code,” after “title 31”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—<ref href="/us/pl/111/84">Pub. L. 111–84</ref> renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s438">section 438 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida7bae529-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7bae52a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Facility Clearance Acceleration for Members of Defense Industrial Consortiums</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXVIII/s1845">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title XVIII, § 1845</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1261">139 Stat. 1261</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXVIII/s1845">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Acceleration of Facility Clearance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that each entity that is a member of the collaborative forum described in section 1844(a) of this Act [set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4811">section 4811 of this title</ref>]—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> is sponsored for a facility clearance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> is provided access to sensitive compartmented information facilities and classified networks where the member can perform classified work; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> not less than quarterly, is invited to in-person meetings with relevant personnel of the Department of Defense to discuss classified information.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Plan</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] a report detailing a plan to increase the number of facility clearances provided to members described in subsection (a) or to companies awarded contracts in accordance with Executive Order 12968 [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3161">50 U.S.C. 3161</ref> note]. Such plan shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> an assessment of any existing related efforts to increase sensitive compartmented information facilities and how such efforts might be accelerated and elevated in priority;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> target metrics for increased facility clearances in association with membership in the collaborative forum described in subsection (a) or to companies awarded contracts in accordance with Executive Order 12968;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> an identification of any additional funding or authorities required to support increased processing of facility clearances; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> any other matters the Secretary of Defense considers relevant.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7bae52b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Establishment of Pilot Program for Access to Shared Classified Commercial Infrastructure</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tVIII/s874">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 874</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2012">138 Stat. 2012</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tVIII/s874">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pilot Program Required</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall establish a pilot program on streamlining access for small business concerns and institutions of higher learning to shared classified commercial infrastructure—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to expand access to secret or collateral accredited facilities and sensitive compartmented information facilities and special access program facilities to securely perform work under existing classified contracts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to reduce the cost and administrative requirements for a facility to receive and maintain accreditation and certification as an accredited facility;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> to increase opportunities for small business concerns and institutions of higher learning to have access to and compete for classified contracts; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> to identify policy barriers that prevent components of the Department of Defense from more broadly using shared classified commercial infrastructure and prototyping proposed solutions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Designation of Principal Civilian Official.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall designate an existing civilian official of the Department of Defense who shall be responsible for the administration of the pilot program established under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The responsibilities of the civilian official designated under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> To seek to enter into a contact or other agreement with one or more private entities—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> for access for contractors and components of the Department of Defense to shared classified commercial infrastructure; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> to facilitate the use of such infrastructure by covered small business concerns and institutions of higher learning.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> In consultation with the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, to coordinate with the Director of the Defense Counterintelligence and Security Agency, the Director of the Defense Intelligence Agency, and the Director of the Defense Information Systems Agency to update or prescribe policies and regulations governing the process and timelines pertaining to how shared commercial classified infrastructure may obtain relevant facility authorizations and access to secure information technology networks from the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> To make recommendations to the Secretary of Defense regarding the modernization, streamlining, and acceleration of the approval process of the Department of Defense for contacts, subcontracts, and co-use or joint use agreements for shared classified commercial infrastructure.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> The development and maintenance of metrics tracking the outcomes of each request made under the pilot program for the accreditation of shared commercial classified infrastructure as an accredited facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Policies and regulations</inline>.—</heading><content>As part of the pilot program established under subsection (a), the Director of the Defense Counterintelligence and Security Agency, the Director of the Defense Intelligence Agency, and the Director of the Defense Information Systems Agency shall each update or prescribe policies and regulations governing the processes and timelines pertaining to how shared commercial classified infrastructure may obtain relevant facility sponsorship, associated authorizations and accreditation, and access to relevant secure information technology networks from the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Modernization, streamlining, and acceleration</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the pilot program established under subsection (a) includes efforts to modernize, streamline, and accelerate the approval process of the Department of Defense for shared, co-use, and joint use agreements to facilitate the access of small business concerns and institutions of higher learning performing under contracts or other agreements with the Department to classified environments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives], Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate, a report on the pilot program established under subsection (a)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> after the establishment of such pilot program, but not later than two years after the establishment of such pilot program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> after the termination of such pilot program pursuant to subsection (e), but not later than 120 days after such termination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each report submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> A list of each request made under the pilot program for the accreditation of a facility as an accredited facility, including the date on which the request was made to the civilian official designated under subsection (b) and to the relevant facility accreditation agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> A list of the total number of personnel authorized to conduct inspections under the pilot program for the accreditation and certification of facilities as accredited facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Actions taken by the civilian official designated under subsection (b) to streamline the process of the Department of Defense for approval of co-use and joint use agreements to facilitate the access of small business concerns and institutions of higher learning performing under contracts or other agreements with the Department to classified environments, including any updated or new policies or guidance issued as a result of the pilot program.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> A list of all unutilized and currently accredited sensitive compartmented information facilities owned and operated by the Department of Defense that are located within 25 miles of a facility described in subsection (a)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> A list of the metrics or other measures used by the Department of Defense to assess the benefits to the Department from the pilot program established under subsection (a), and any other metrics the Secretary of Defense deems appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority to carry out the pilot program required by subsection (a) and the requirements of this section shall terminate on <date date="2030-09-30">September 30, 2030</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The term ‘institution of higher learning’ has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s3452/f">section 3452(f) of title 38</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘shared commercial classified infrastructure’ means fully managed, shared, classified infrastructure (including physical facilities), and associated services that are operated by a private third-party for the benefit of appropriately cleared government and contractor personnel who have limited or constrained access to secret collateral and sensitive compartmented information facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The term ‘small business concern’ has the meaning given such term under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s632">15 U.S.C. 632</ref>).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7bae52c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pilot Program for Department of Defense Controlled Unclassified Information in the Hands of Industry</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tX/s1048">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title X, § 1048</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1961">132 Stat. 1961</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tX/s1048">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> shall establish and implement a pilot program for oversight of designated Department of Defense controlled unclassified information in the hands of defense contractors with foreign ownership, control, or influence concerns; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> may designate an entity within the Department to be responsible for the pilot program under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The pilot program under subsection (a) shall have the following elements:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The use of a capability to rapidly identify companies subject to foreign ownership, control, or influence that are processing designated controlled unclassified information, including unclassified controlled technical information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The use, in consultation with the Chief of Information Officer of the Department, of a capability or means for assessing industry compliance with Department cybersecurity standards.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> A means of demonstrating whether and under what conditions the risk to national security posed by access to Department controlled unclassified information, including unclassified controlled technical information, by a company under foreign ownership, control, or influence company can be mitigated and how such mitigation could be enforced.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefing Required</inline>.—</heading><content>By not later than 30 days after the completion of the pilot program under this section, but in no case later than <date date="2019-12-01">December 1, 2019</date>, the Secretary shall provide to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] a briefing on the results of the pilot program and any decisions about whether to implement the pilot program on a Department-wide basis.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7bae52d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Requirements Relating to Multi-Use Sensitive Compartmented Information Facilities</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tXVI/s1628">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title XVI, § 1628</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1735">131 Stat. 1735</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tXVI/s1628">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>In order to facilitate access for small business concerns and nontraditional defense contractors to affordable secure spaces, the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, shall develop processes and procedures necessary to build, certify, and maintain certifications for multi-use sensitive compartmented information facilities not tied to a single contract and where multiple companies can securely work on multiple projects at different security levels.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The term ‘small business concern’ has the meaning given that term under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s632">15 U.S.C. 632</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘nontraditional defense contractors’ has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2302">section 2302 of title 10</ref>, United States Code [now <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3014">10 U.S.C. 3014</ref>].”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7bae52e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Requirement for Entities With Facility Clearances That Are Not Under Foreign Ownership Control or Influence Mitigation</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/383/dA/tVIII/s845">Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title VIII, § 845</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4285">124 Stat. 4285</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/383/dA/tVIII/s845">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall develop a plan to ensure that covered entities employ and maintain policies and procedures that meet requirements under the national industrial security program. In developing the plan, the Secretary shall consider whether or not covered entities, or any category of covered entities, should be required to establish government security committees similar to those required for companies that are subject to foreign ownership control or influence mitigation measures.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered Entity</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A covered entity under this section is an entity—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to which the Department of Defense has granted a facility clearance; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> that is not subject to foreign ownership control or influence mitigation measures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guidance</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall issue guidance, including appropriate compliance mechanisms, to implement the requirement in subsection (a). To the extent determined appropriate by the Secretary, the guidance shall require covered entities, or any category of covered entities, to establish government security committees similar to those required for companies that are subject to foreign ownership control or influence mitigation measures.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>], the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on the plan developed pursuant to subsection (a) and the guidance issued pursuant to subsection (c). The report shall specifically address the rationale for the Secretary’s decision on whether or not to require covered entities, or any category of covered entities, to establish government security committees similar to those required for companies that are subject to foreign ownership control or influence mitigation measures.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7bae52f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Submission of First Biennial Report</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/417">Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title VIII, § 845(b), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4542">122 Stat. 4542</ref>, required the first biennial report under former subsec. (f) of this section to be submitted no later than <date date="2009-09-01">Sept. 1, 2009</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
