<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idaa7326b0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351"><num value="4351">§ 4351.</num><heading> Selected Acquisition Reports</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326b1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326b2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “program acquisition unit cost”, with respect to a major defense acquisition program, means the amount equal to (A) the total cost for development and procurement of, and system-specific military construction for, the acquisition program, divided by (B) the number of fully-configured end items to be produced for the acquisition program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326b3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “procurement unit cost”, with respect to a major defense acquisition program, means the amount equal to (A) the total of all funds programmed to be available for obligation for procurement for the program, divided by (B) the number of fully-configured end items to be procured.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326b4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “major contract”, with respect to a major defense acquisition program, means each of the six largest prime, associate, or Government-furnished equipment contracts under the program that is in excess of $40,000,000 and that is not a firm, fixed price contract.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326b5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The term “full life-cycle cost”, with respect to a major defense acquisition program, means all costs of development, procurement, military construction, and operations and support, without regard to funding source or management control.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326b6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326b7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress at the end of each fiscal-year quarter a report on current major defense acquisition programs and any program that is estimated by the Secretary of Defense to require an eventual total expenditure for research, development, test, and evaluation of more than $300,000,000 (based on fiscal year 1990 constant dollars) or an eventual total expenditure for procurement, including all planned increments or spirals, of more than $1,800,000,000 (based on fiscal year 1990 constant dollars). Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), each such report shall include a status report on each defense acquisition program that at the end of such quarter is a major defense acquisition program. Reports under this section shall be known as Selected Acquisition Reports.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326b8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> A status report on a major defense acquisition program need not be included in the Selected Acquisition Report for the second, third, or fourth quarter of a fiscal year if such a report was included in a previous Selected Acquisition Report for that fiscal year and during the period since that report there has been—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326b9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> less than a 15 percent increase in program acquisition unit cost and current procurement unit cost for the program (or for each designated subprogram under the program); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326ba-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> less than a six-month delay in any program schedule milestone shown in the Selected Acquisition Report.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326bb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326bc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may waive the requirement for submission of Selected Acquisition Reports for a program for a fiscal year if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326bd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/b/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the program has not entered system development and demonstration;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326be-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/b/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a reasonable cost estimate has not been established for such program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326bf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/b/3/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the system configuration for such program is not well defined.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326c0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives a written notification of each waiver under subparagraph (A) for a program for a fiscal year not later than 60 days before the President submits the budget to Congress pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105">section 1105 of title 31</ref> in that fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326c1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326c2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Each Selected Acquisition Report for the first quarter for a fiscal year shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326c3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the same information, in detailed and summarized form, as is provided in reports submitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4205">section 4205 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326c4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> for each major defense acquisition program or designated major subprogram included in the report—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa7326c5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/c/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the Baseline Estimate (as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4371/a/4">section 4371(a)(4) of this title</ref>), along with the associated risk and sensitivity analysis of that estimate;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa7326c6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/c/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the original Baseline Estimate (as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4214/d/1">section 4214(d)(1) of this title</ref>), along with the associated risk and sensitivity analysis of that estimate;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa7326c7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/c/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> if the original Baseline Estimate was adjusted or revised pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4214/d/2">section 4214(d)(2) of this title</ref>, such adjusted or revised estimate, along with the associated risk and sensitivity analysis of that estimate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaa7326c8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/c/1/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the primary risk parameters associated with the current procurement cost for the program (as that term is used in subsection (e)(4));</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326c9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a summary of the history of significant developments from the date each major defense acquisition program or designated major subprogram included in the report was first included in a Selected Acquisition Report and program highlights since the last Selected Acquisition Report;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326ca-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/c/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the significant schedule and technical risks for each such program or subprogram, identified at each major milestone and as of the quarter for which the current report is submitted;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326cb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/c/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the current program acquisition cost and program acquisition unit cost for each such program or subprogram included in the report and the history of those costs from the December 2001 reporting period to the end of the quarter for which the current report is submitted;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326cc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/c/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> the current procurement unit cost for each such program or subprogram included in the report and the history of that cost from the December 2001 reporting period to the end of the quarter for which the current report is submitted;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326cd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/c/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> for each major defense acquisition program that receives Milestone B approval after <date date="2019-01-01">January 1, 2019</date>, a brief summary description of the key elements of the modular open system approach as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4401">section 4401 of this title</ref> or, if a modular open system approach was not used, the rationale for not using such an approach; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326ce-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/c/1/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> such other information as the Secretary of Defense considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326cf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Each Selected Acquisition Report for the first quarter of a fiscal year shall be designed to provide to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives the information such Committees need to perform their oversight functions. Whenever the Secretary of Defense proposes to make changes in the content of a Selected Acquisition Report, the Secretary shall submit a notice of the proposed changes to such committees. The changes shall be considered approved by the Secretary, and may be incorporated into the report, only after the end of the 60-day period beginning on the date on which the notice is received by those committees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326d0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> In addition to the material required by paragraphs (1) and (2), each Selected Acquisition Report for the first quarter of a fiscal year shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326d1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A full life-cycle cost analysis for each major defense acquisition program and each designated major subprogram included in the report that is in the system development and demonstration stage or has completed that stage. The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that this subparagraph is implemented in a uniform manner, to the extent practicable, throughout the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326d2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> If the system that is included in that major defense acquisition program has an antecedent system, a full life-cycle cost analysis for that system.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326d3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Selected Acquisition Reports for the first quarter of a fiscal year shall be known as comprehensive annual Selected Acquisition Reports.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326d4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326d5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Each Selected Acquisition Report for the second, third, and fourth quarters of a fiscal year shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326d6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> with respect to each major defense acquisition program that was included in the most recent comprehensive annual Selected Acquisition Report, the information described in subsection (e); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326d7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> with respect to each major defense acquisition program that was not included in the most recent comprehensive annual Selected Acquisition Report, the information described in subsection (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326d8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Selected Acquisition Reports for the second, third, and fourth quarters of a fiscal year shall be known as Quarterly Selected Acquisition Reports.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326d9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><chapeau> Information to be included under this subsection in a Quarterly Selected Acquisition Report with respect to a major defense acquisition program is as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326da-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The quantity of items to be purchased under the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326db-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The program acquisition cost.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326dc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The program acquisition unit cost for the program (or for each designated major subprogram under the program).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326dd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The current procurement cost for the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326de-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The current procurement unit cost for the program (or for each designated major subprogram under the program).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326df-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/e/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The reasons for any change in program acquisition cost, program acquisition unit cost, procurement cost, or procurement unit cost or in program schedule from the previous Selected Acquisition Report.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326e0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/e/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The reasons for any significant changes (from the previous Selected Acquisition Report) in the total program cost for development and procurement of the software component of the program or subprogram, schedule milestones for the software component of the program or subprogram, or expected performance for the software component of the program or subprogram that are known, expected, or anticipated by the program manager.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326e1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/e/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> The major contracts under the program and designated major subprograms under the program and the reasons for any cost or schedule variances under those contracts since the last Selected Acquisition Report.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326e2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/e/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> Program highlights since the last Selected Acquisition Report.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326e3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> Each comprehensive annual Selected Acquisition Report shall be submitted within 30 days after the date on which the President transmits the Budget to Congress for the following fiscal year, and each Quarterly Selected Acquisition Report shall be submitted within 45 days after the end of the fiscal-year quarter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326e4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> The requirements of this section with respect to a major defense acquisition program or designated major subprogram shall cease to apply after 90 percent of the items to be delivered to the United States under the program or subprogram (shown as the total quantity of items to be purchased under the program or subprogram in the most recent Selected Acquisition Report) have been delivered or 90 percent of planned expenditures under the program or subprogram have been made.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326e5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326e6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Total program reporting under this section shall apply to a major defense acquisition program when funds have been appropriated for such program and the Secretary of Defense has decided to proceed to system development and demonstration of such program. Reporting may be limited to the development program as provided in paragraph (2) before a decision is made by the Secretary of Defense to proceed to system development and demonstration if the Secretary notifies the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives of the intention to submit a limited report under this subsection not less than 15 days before a report is due under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326e7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> A limited report under this subsection shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326e8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The same information, in detail and summarized form, as is provided in reports submitted under subsections (b)(1) and (b)(3) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4205">section 4205 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326e9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Reasons for any change in the development cost and schedule.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326ea-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/h/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The major contracts under the development program and designated major subprograms under the program and the reasons for any cost or schedule variances under those contracts since the last Selected Acquisition Report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326eb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/h/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Program highlights since the last Selected Acquisition Report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa7326ec-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/h/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Other information as the Secretary of Defense considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326ed-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The submission requirements for a limited report under this subsection shall be the same as for quarterly Selected Acquisition Reports for total program reporting.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326ee-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Form of Report</inline>.—</heading><content>A Selected Acquisition Report required under this section shall be submitted in unclassified form without any designation relating to dissemination control, but may contain a classified annex.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa7326ef-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4351/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading><content>The requirements under this section shall terminate after the final submission covering fiscal year 2023.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idaa7326f0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/97/252/tXI/s1107/a/1">Pub. L. 97–252, title XI, § 1107(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-08">Sept. 8, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/739">96 Stat. 739</ref>, § 139a; amended <ref href="/us/pl/98/525/tXII/s1242/a">Pub. L. 98–525, title XII, § 1242(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2606">98 Stat. 2606</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/145/tXII/s1201">Pub. L. 99–145, title XII, § 1201</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/715">99 Stat. 715</ref>; renumbered § 2432 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/99/433/tI">Pub. L. 99–433, title I</ref>, §§ 101(a)(5), 110(d)(13), (g)(7), <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/995">100 Stat. 995</ref>, 1003, 1004; <ref href="/us/pl/99/500/s101/c/tX/s961/a">Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(c) [title X, § 961(a)]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1783-82">100 Stat. 1783–82</ref>, 1783–175, and <ref href="/us/pl/99/591/s101/c/tX/s961/a">Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(c) [title X, § 961(a)]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3341-82">100 Stat. 3341–82</ref>, 3341–175; <ref href="/us/pl/99/661/dA/tIX">Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title IX</ref>, formerly title IV, § 961(a), <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3955">100 Stat. 3955</ref>, renumbered title IX, <ref href="/us/pl/100/26/s3/5">Pub. L. 100–26, § 3(5)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/273">101 Stat. 273</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/26/s7/b/3">Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(b)(3)</ref>, (k)(2), <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/279">101 Stat. 279</ref>, 284; <ref href="/us/pl/100/180/dA/tXII/s1233/a/1">Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title XII, § 1233(a)(1)</ref>, title XIII, § 1314(a)(1), <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1161">101 Stat. 1161</ref>, 1175; <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tVIII/s811/c">Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title VIII, § 811(c)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1493">103 Stat. 1493</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXIV">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV</ref>, §§ 1407(a)–(c), 1484(f)(4), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1681">104 Stat. 1681</ref>, 1717; <ref href="/us/pl/102/25/tVII/s701/f/3">Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 701(f)(3)</ref>, <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/115">105 Stat. 115</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/dA/tVIII/s801/b/2">Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title VIII, § 801(b)(2)</ref>, title X, § 1061(a)(14), <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1412">105 Stat. 1412</ref>, 1473; <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dA/tVIII/s817/c">Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title VIII, § 817(c)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2455">106 Stat. 2455</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/355/tIII/s3002/a/1">Pub. L. 103–355, title III, § 3002(a)(1)</ref>, (b)–(h), <date date="1994-10-13">Oct. 13, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3328">108 Stat. 3328</ref>, 3329; <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tXV/s1502/a/1">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/502">110 Stat. 502</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tVIII/s806">Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title VIII, § 806</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2606">110 Stat. 2606</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tVIII/s841/c">Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title VIII, § 841(c)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1843">111 Stat. 1843</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tX/s1067/1">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/774">113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tVIII/s821/a">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title VIII, § 821(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1181">115 Stat. 1181</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tX/s1045/a/6">Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1045(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1612">117 Stat. 1612</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/dA/tVIII/s801/b/2">Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title VIII, § 801(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/2004">118 Stat. 2004</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tX/s1071/g/10">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1071(g)(10)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2402">120 Stat. 2402</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/417">Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title VIII, § 811(b), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4521">122 Stat. 4521</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/dA/tVIII/s812">Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VIII, § 812</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1491">125 Stat. 1491</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tVIII/s812/a">Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title VIII, § 812(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/807">127 Stat. 807</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tX/s1071/g/2">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(g)(2)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3511">128 Stat. 3511</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tVIII">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 805(b), 841, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2255">130 Stat. 2255</ref>, 2288; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tVIII/s830/a">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 830(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1492">133 Stat. 1492</ref>; renumbered § 4351 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXVIII/s1849/a">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1849(a)</ref>–(d), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4259">134 Stat. 4259</ref>, 4260; <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tVIII/s805/a">Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title VIII, § 805(a)</ref>, title XVII, § 1701(<i>o</i>)(1), (3), (4), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1816">135 Stat. 1816</ref>, 2146, 2147; <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tXVIII/s1801/a/35">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVIII, § 1801(a)(35)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/685">137 Stat. 685</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idaa7326f1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idaa7326f2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idaa7326f3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1849/a">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1849(a)</ref>–(<i>l</i>), which had initially directed the enactment of sections 4350 to 4358 of this title, the transfers of various subsections of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2432">section 2432 of this title</ref> to those new sections, and the subsequent repeal of section 2432, was amended by <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s1701">Pub. L. 117–81, § 1701</ref>(<i>o</i>)(1)–(5), by revising subsecs. (a) to (d), striking out subsecs. (e) to (k), and redesignating subsec. (<i>l</i>) as (e). After that amendment, those enactments and transfers were no longer directed. Instead, <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1849/b">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1849(b)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/117/81">Pub. L. 117–81</ref>, directed the transfer of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2432">section 2432 of this title</ref> in its entirety to this section, thereby omitting what would have been sections 4350 and 4352 to 4358 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/591">Pub. L. 99–591</ref> is a corrected version of <ref href="/us/pl/99/500">Pub. L. 99–500</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idaa7326f4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2023—Subsec. (c)(1)(B)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31">Pub. L. 118–31</ref> substituted “subsection (e)(4)” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4355/4">section 4355(4) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—<ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1849/b">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1849(b)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s1701">Pub. L. 117–81, § 1701</ref>(<i>o</i>)(1)(B), renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2432">section 2432 of this title</ref> as this section. See Codification note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1849/c/1">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1849(c)(1)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s1701">Pub. L. 117–81, § 1701</ref>(<i>o</i>)(3), substituted “section 4205” for “section 2431”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1849/c/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1849(c)(2)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s1701">Pub. L. 117–81, § 1701</ref>(<i>o</i>)(3), substituted “section 4371(a)(4)” for “section 2433(a)(2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1849/c/3">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1849(c)(3)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s1701">Pub. L. 117–81, § 1701</ref>(<i>o</i>)(3), substituted “section 4214(d)(1)” for “section 2435(d)(1)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1849/c/4">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1849(c)(4)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s1701">Pub. L. 117–81, § 1701</ref>(<i>o</i>)(3), substituted “section 4214(d)(2)” for “section 2435(d)(2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(B)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1849/c/5">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1849(c)(5)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s1701">Pub. L. 117–81, § 1701</ref>(<i>o</i>)(3), substituted “section 4355(4)” for “section 2432(e)(4)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(G). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1849/c/6">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1849(c)(6)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s1701">Pub. L. 117–81, § 1701</ref>(<i>o</i>)(3), substituted “section 4401” for “section 2446a”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1849/d">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1849(d)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s1701">Pub. L. 117–81, § 1701</ref>(<i>o</i>)(4), substituted “section 4205” for “section 2431”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s805/a">Pub. L. 117–81, § 805(a)</ref>, substituted “fiscal year 2023” for “fiscal year 2021”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s830/a/1">Pub. L. 116–92, § 830(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “and any program that is estimated by the Secretary of Defense to require an eventual total expenditure for research, development, test, and evaluation of more than $300,000,000 (based on fiscal year 1990 constant dollars) or an eventual total expenditure for procurement, including all planned increments or spirals, of more than $1,800,000,000 (based on fiscal year 1990 constant dollars)” after “major defense acquisition programs”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (i), (j). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s830/a/2">Pub. L. 116–92, § 830(a)(2)</ref>, added subsecs. (i) and (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (c)(1)(G), (H). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s805/b">Pub. L. 114–328, § 805(b)</ref>, added subpar. (G) and redesignated former subpar. (G) as (H).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s841">Pub. L. 114–328, § 841</ref>, substituted “30” for “45” before “days after the date”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (c)(1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/s1071/g/2">Pub. L. 113–291, § 1071(g)(2)</ref>, amended <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s812/a/3/B">Pub. L. 113–66, § 812(a)(3)(B)</ref>. See 2013 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (c)(1)(B) to (D). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s812/a/2">Pub. L. 113–66, § 812(a)(2)</ref>, added subpars. (B) to (D). Former subpars. (B) to (D) redesignated (E) to (G), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s812/a/3/B">Pub. L. 113–66, § 812(a)(3)(B)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/s1071/g/2">Pub. L. 113–291, § 1071(g)(2)</ref>, inserted “program acquisition cost and” after “current” the first place appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s812/a/1">Pub. L. 113–66, § 812(a)(1)</ref>, (3)(A), (C), (D), redesignated subpar. (B) as (E) and substituted “such program or subprogram” for “major defense acquisition program or designated major subprogram”, “those costs” for “that cost”, and “December 2001 reporting period” for “date the program or subprogram was first included in a Selected Acquisition Report”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s812/a/1">Pub. L. 113–66, § 812(a)(1)</ref>, (4), redesignated subpar. (C) as (F) and substituted “such program or subprogram” for “major defense acquisition program or designated major subprogram” and “December 2001 reporting period” for “date the program or subprogram was first included in a Selected Acquisition Report”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(G). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s812/a/1">Pub. L. 113–66, § 812(a)(1)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (D) as (G).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/112/81">Pub. L. 112–81</ref> substituted “45 days after the date” for “60 days after the date”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (b)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/110/417/s811/b/1">Pub. L. 110–417, § 811(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “for the program (or for each designated subprogram under the program)” after “procurement unit cost”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/110/417/s811/b/2/A">Pub. L. 110–417, § 811(b)(2)(A)</ref>, inserted “or designated major subprogram” after “for each major defense acquisition program” and “or subprogram” after “the program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/110/417/s811/b/2/B">Pub. L. 110–417, § 811(b)(2)(B)</ref>, inserted “or designated major subprogram” after “major defense acquisition program” and “or subprogram” after “the program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/110/417/s811/b/2/C">Pub. L. 110–417, § 811(b)(2)(C)</ref>, inserted “and each designated major subprogram” after “for each major defense acquisition program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/110/417/s811/b/3/A">Pub. L. 110–417, § 811(b)(3)(A)</ref>, inserted “for the program (or for each designated major subprogram under the program)” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/110/417/s811/b/3/B">Pub. L. 110–417, § 811(b)(3)(B)</ref>, inserted “(or for each designated major subprogram under the program)” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/110/417/s811/b/3/C">Pub. L. 110–417, § 811(b)(3)(C)</ref>, inserted “or subprogram” after “of the program” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/110/417/s811/b/3/D">Pub. L. 110–417, § 811(b)(3)(D)</ref>, inserted “and designated major subprograms under the program” after “the program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/110/417/s811/b/4">Pub. L. 110–417, § 811(b)(4)</ref>, inserted “or designated major subprogram” after “major defense acquisition program” and “or subprogram” after “the program” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/110/417/s811/b/5">Pub. L. 110–417, § 811(b)(5)</ref>, inserted “and designated major subprograms under the program” after “the development program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (e)(7) to (9). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364">Pub. L. 109–364</ref> made technical correction to directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s801/b/2">Pub. L. 108–375, § 801(b)(2)</ref>. See 2004 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (e)(7) to (9). <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s801/b/2">Pub. L. 108–375, § 801(b)(2)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/109/364">Pub. L. 109–364</ref>, added par. (7) and redesignated former pars. (7) and (8) as (8) and (9), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (h)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136">Pub. L. 108–136</ref> inserted “program” after “for such” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—Subsecs. (b)(3)(A)(i), (c)(3)(A), (h)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/107">Pub. L. 107–107</ref> substituted “system development and demonstration” for “engineering and manufacturing development” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsecs. (b)(3)(B), (c)(2), (h)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/106/65">Pub. L. 106–65</ref> substituted “and the Committee on Armed Services” for “and the Committee on National Security”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (h)(2)(D) to (F). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85">Pub. L. 105–85</ref> redesignated subpars. (E) and (F) as (D) and (E), respectively, and struck out former subpar. (D) which read as follows: “The completion status of the development program expressed—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) as the percentage that the number of years for which funds have been appropriated for the development program is of the number of years for which it is planned that funds will be appropriated for the program; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) as the percentage that the amount of funds that have been appropriated for the development program is of the total amount of funds which it is planned will be appropriated for the program.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106">Pub. L. 104–106</ref> substituted “Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on National Security of the House of Representatives” for “Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/s806/1">Pub. L. 104–201, § 806(1)</ref>, struck out “and” at end of subpar. (B), added subpar. (C), and redesignated former subpar. (C) as (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106">Pub. L. 104–106</ref> substituted “Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on National Security of the House of Representatives” for “Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(8), (9). <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/s806/2">Pub. L. 104–201, § 806(2)</ref>, redesignated par. (9) as (8) and struck out former par. (8) which read as follows: “The completion status of the program (A) expressed as the percentage that the number of years for which funds have been appropriated for the program is of the number of years for which it is planned that funds will be appropriated for the program, and (B) expressed as the percentage that the amount of funds that have been appropriated for the program is of the total amount of funds which it is planned will be appropriated for the program.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106">Pub. L. 104–106</ref> substituted “Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on National Security of the House of Representatives” for “Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/355/s3002/a/1">Pub. L. 103–355, § 3002(a)(1)</ref>, struck out “for a fiscal year, reduced by the amount of funds programmed to be available for obligation for such fiscal year for advanced procurement for such program in any subsequent year and increased by any amount appropriated in years before such fiscal year for advanced procurement for such program in such fiscal year” after “procurement for the program” in cl. (A), “with such funds during such fiscal year” after “procured” in cl. (B), and last sentence which read as follows: “If for any fiscal year the funds appropriated, or the number of fully-configured end items to be purchased, differ from those programmed, the procurement unit cost shall be revised to reflect the appropriated amounts and quantities.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/103/355/s3002/b">Pub. L. 103–355, § 3002(b)</ref>, inserted before period at end “and that is not a firm, fixed price contract”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/103/355/s3002/c">Pub. L. 103–355, § 3002(c)</ref>, substituted “means all costs of development, procurement, military construction, and operations and support, without regard to funding source or management control.” for “has the meaning given the term ‘cost of the program’ in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2434/b/2">section 2434(b)(2) of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/103/355/s3002/h/1">Pub. L. 103–355, § 3002(h)(1)</ref>, struck out “full scale development or” before “engineering”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/355/s3002/d">Pub. L. 103–355, § 3002(d)</ref>, substituted second sentence for former second sentence which read as follows: “The Secretary of Defense may approve changes in the content of the Selected Acquisition Report if the Secretary provides such Committees with written notification of such changes at least 60 days before the date of the report that incorporates the changes.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/103/355/s3002/f/2">Pub. L. 103–355, § 3002(f)(2)</ref>, (h)(2), substituted “engineering and manufacturing” for “full-scale engineering” and inserted at end “The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that this subparagraph is implemented in a uniform manner, to the extent practicable, throughout the Department of Defense.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/103/355/s3002/e">Pub. L. 103–355, § 3002(e)</ref>, struck out subpar. (C) which required production information for each major defense acquisition program included in report that is produced at rate of six units or more per year.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/103/355/s3002/f/1">Pub. L. 103–355, § 3002(f)(1)</ref>, struck out par. (5) which read as follows: “The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that paragraph (4) of subsection (a) is implemented in a uniform manner, to the extent practicable, throughout the Department of Defense.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/103/355/s3002/g">Pub. L. 103–355, § 3002(g)</ref>, struck out last sentence which read as follows: “A preliminary report shall be submitted for each annual Selected Acquisition Report within 30 days of the date on which the President submits the Budget to Congress.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/355/s3002/h/3">Pub. L. 103–355, § 3002(h)(3)</ref>, substituted “engineering and manufacturing” for “full-scale engineering” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s817/c/1">Pub. L. 102–484, § 817(c)(1)</ref>, added par. (3) and struck out former par. (3) which read as follows: “The term ‘major contract’, with respect to a major defense acquisition program, means (A) each prime contract under the program, and (B) each associate or Government-furnished equipment contract under the program that is one of the six largest contracts under the program in dollar amount and that is in excess of $40,000,000.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s817/c/2">Pub. L. 102–484, § 817(c)(2)</ref>, added par. (3) and struck out former par. (3) which read as follows: “A status report on a particular major defense acquisition program need not be included in any Selected Acquisition Report with the approval of the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s817/c/3">Pub. L. 102–484, § 817(c)(3)</ref>, added sentence at end and struck out former last sentence which read as follows: “A change in the content of the Selected Acquisition Report for the first quarter of a fiscal year from the content as reported for the first quarter of the previous fiscal year may not be made until appropriate officials of the Department of Defense consult with such Committees regarding the proposed changes.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(C)(i) to (vii). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s817/c/4">Pub. L. 102–484, § 817(c)(4)</ref>, added cls. (i) to (vii) and struck out former cls. (i) to (vii) which contained similar specification and estimation requirements.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/s801/b/2">Pub. L. 102–190, § 801(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “2434(b)(2)” for “2434(c)(2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/102/25">Pub. L. 102–25</ref> substituted “subsection (a)” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2432/a">section 2432(a) of title 10</ref>, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)(2),”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/s1061/a/14">Pub. L. 102–190, § 1061(a)(14)</ref>, substituted “(b)(1) and (b)(3)” for “(c)(1) and (c)(3)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s1407/b">Pub. L. 101–510, § 1407(b)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s1484/f/4/A">Pub. L. 101–510, § 1484(f)(4)(A)</ref>, substituted “include the following:” for “include—” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s1407/a">Pub. L. 101–510, § 1407(a)</ref>, amended subpar. (A) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (A) read as follows: “a full life-cycle cost analysis for each major defense acquisition program included in the report that—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) is in the full-scale engineering development stage or has completed that stage; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) was first included in a Selected Acquisition Report for a quarter after the first quarter of fiscal year 1985;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s1484/f/4/B">Pub. L. 101–510, § 1484(f)(4)(B)</ref>, (C), substituted “If” for “if” and a period for “; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s1484/f/4/B">Pub. L. 101–510, § 1484(f)(4)(B)</ref>, (D), substituted “Production” for “production” and “program) the following:” for “program)—” in introductory provisions, “Specification” for “specification” in cls. (i) to (iv), “Estimation” for “estimation” in cls. (v) to (vii), a period for a semicolon in cls. (i) to (v), and a period for “; and” in cl. (vi).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s1407/c">Pub. L. 101–510, § 1407(c)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (b)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/101/189">Pub. L. 101–189</ref> substituted “15 percent increase in program acquisition unit cost and current procurement unit cost” for “5 percent change in total program cost”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—<ref href="/us/pl/100/180/s1314/a/1">Pub. L. 100–180, § 1314(a)(1)</ref>, made technical amendment to directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/99/433/s101/a/5">Pub. L. 99–433, § 101(a)(5)</ref>. See 1986 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/26/s7/b/3/A">Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(b)(3)(A)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/180/s1233/a/1">Pub. L. 100–180, § 1233(a)(1)</ref>, redesignated pars. (2) to (4) as (1) to (3), respectively, and struck out former par. (1) which defined “major defense acquisition program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/26/s7/k/2/A">Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(k)(2)(A)</ref>, inserted “The term” after each par. designation and struck out uppercase letter of first word after first quotation marks in each par. and substituted lowercase letter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/26/s7/b/3/B">Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(b)(3)(B)</ref>, substituted “programmed” for “programed” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—<ref href="/us/pl/99/433/s101/a/5">Pub. L. 99–433, § 101(a)(5)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/180/s1314/a/1">Pub. L. 100–180, § 1314(a)(1)</ref>, renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s139a">section 139a of this title</ref> as section 2432.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/433/s110/d/13">Pub. L. 99–433, § 110(d)(13)</ref>, struck out “Oversight of cost growth in major programs:” before “Selected Acquisition Reports” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/99/500">Pub. L. 99–500</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/99/591/s101/c/s961/a/1">Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(c) [§ 961(a)(1)]</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/99/661/s961/a/1">Pub. L. 99–661, § 961(a)(1)</ref>, amended par. (3) identically, inserting provision that if for any fiscal year the funds appropriated, or the number of fully-configured end items to be purchased, differ from those programmed, the procurement unit cost shall be revised to reflect the appropriated amounts and quantities.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/99/500">Pub. L. 99–500</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/99/591/s101/c/s961/a/2">Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(c) [§ 961(a)(2)]</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/99/661/s961/a/2">Pub. L. 99–661, § 961(a)(2)</ref>, amended par. (4) identically, substituting “$40,000,000” for “$2,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/99/500">Pub. L. 99–500</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/99/591/s101/c/s961/a/3">Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(c) [§ 961(a)(3)]</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/99/661/s961/a/3">Pub. L. 99–661, § 961(a)(3)</ref>, amended subpar. (B) identically, substituting “six-month” for “three-month”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/433/s110/g/7">Pub. L. 99–433, § 110(g)(7)</ref>, substituted “section 2431” for “section 139”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/500">Pub. L. 99–500</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/99/591/s101/c/s961/a/4">Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(c) [§ 961(a)(4)]</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/99/661/s961/a/4">Pub. L. 99–661, § 961(a)(4)</ref>, amended subsec. (c) identically, enacting a new par. (2) and striking out former par. (2) which read as follows: “Each Selected Acquisition Report for the first quarter of a fiscal year shall be prepared and submitted with the same content as was used for the Selected Acquisition Report for the first quarter of fiscal year 1984.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/99/500">Pub. L. 99–500</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/99/591/s101/c/s961/a/5">Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(c) [§ 961(a)(5)]</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/99/661/s961/a/5">Pub. L. 99–661, § 961(a)(5)</ref>, amended subpar. (C) identically, inserting in provision preceding cl. (i) “that is produced at a rate of six units or more per year” after “report”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/99/500">Pub. L. 99–500</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/99/591/s101/c/s961/a/6">Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(c) [§ 961(a)(6)]</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/99/661/s961/a/6">Pub. L. 99–661, § 961(a)(6)</ref>, amended section identically, adding subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/145">Pub. L. 99–145</ref> amended subsec. (c) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (c) read as follows: “Each Selected Acquisition Report for the first quarter of a fiscal year shall include (1) the same information, in detailed and summarized form, as is provided in reports submitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s139">section 139 of this title</ref>, (2) the current program acquisition unit cost for each major defense acquisition program included in the report and the history of that cost from the date the program was first included in a Selected Acquisition Report to the end of the quarter for which the current report is submitted, and (3) such other information as the Secretary of Defense considers appropriate. Selected Acquisition Reports for the first quarter of a fiscal year shall be known as comprehensive annual Selected Acquisition Reports.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/98/525/s1242/a/1">Pub. L. 98–525, § 1242(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “funds programed to be available for obligation for procurement” for “procurement funds appropriated” and “of funds programed to be available for obligation” for “of funds appropriated”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/98/525/s1242/a/2">Pub. L. 98–525, § 1242(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “and that is in excess of $2,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/525/s1242/a/3">Pub. L. 98–525, § 1242(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “during the period since that report there has been— (A) less than a 5 percent change in total program cost; and (B) less than a three-month delay in any program schedule milestone shown in the Selected Acquisition Report” for “there has been no change in program cost, performance, or schedule since the most recent such report”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/98/525/s1242/a/4">Pub. L. 98–525, § 1242(a)(4)</ref>, substituted: “60” for “30”, “45” for “30, and “A preliminary report shall be submitted for each annual Selected Acquisition Report within 30 days of the date on which the President submits the Budget to Congress” for “If a preliminary report is submitted for the comprehensive annual Selected Acquisition Report in any year, the final report shall be submitted within 15 days after the submission of the preliminary report”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/98/525/s1242/a/5">Pub. L. 98–525, § 1242(a)(5)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idaa7597f5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idaa7597f6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/117/81">Pub. L. 117–81</ref> applicable as if included in the enactment of title XVIII of <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> as enacted, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s1701/a/2">section 1701(a)(2) of Pub. L. 117–81</ref>, set out in a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref> and Effective Date note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> effective <date date="2022-01-01">Jan. 1, 2022</date>, with additional provisions for delayed implementation and applicability of existing law, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1801/d">section 1801(d) of Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idaa7597f7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2014 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tX/s1071/g">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1071(g)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3511">128 Stat. 3511</ref>, provided that the amendment made by section 1071(g)(2) is effective as of <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, and as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/113/66">Pub. L. 113–66</ref> as enacted.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idaa7597f8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2013 Amendment; Phase-In of Additional Information Requirements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tVIII/s812/b">Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title VIII, § 812(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/807">127 Stat. 807</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tVIII/s812/b">
<inline>“<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2432/c/1">Section 2432(c)(1) of title 10</ref>, United States Code [now <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4351/c/1">10 U.S.C. 4351(c)(1)</ref>], as amended by subsection (a), shall apply to Selected Acquisition Reports after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>] as follows:</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> For the December 2014 reporting period, to Selected Acquisition Reports for five major defense acquisition programs or designated major subprograms, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> For the December 2019 reporting period and each reporting period thereafter, to Selected Acquisition Reports for all major defense acquisition programs or designated major subprograms.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idaa7597f9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2006 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tX/s1071/g">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1071(g)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2402">120 Stat. 2402</ref>, provided that the amendment made by section 1071(g)(10) is effective as of <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, and as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/108/375">Pub. L. 108–375</ref> as enacted.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idaa7597fa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2004 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/375/dA/tVIII/s801/c">Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title VIII, § 801(c)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/2004">118 Stat. 2004</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/375/dA/tVIII/s801/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and former <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2433">section 2433 of this title</ref>] shall take effect on the date occurring 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>], and shall apply with respect to reports due to be submitted to Congress on or after such date.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idaa7597fb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tXIV/s1407/d">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1407(d)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1681">104 Stat. 1681</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/102/25/tVII/s704/a/8">Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 704(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/119">105 Stat. 119</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/25/tVII/s704/a/8">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect with respect to Selected Acquisition Reports submitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2432">section 2432 of title 10</ref>, United States Code [now <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4351">10 U.S.C. 4351</ref>], after <date date="1991-12-31">December 31, 1991</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idaa7597fc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1987 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/180/s1233/a/1">section 1233(a)(1) of Pub. L. 100–180</ref> applicable as if included in enactment of the Defense Technical Corrections Act of 1987, <ref href="/us/pl/100/26">Pub. L. 100–26</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/180/s1233/c">section 1233(c) of Pub. L. 100–180</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/180/s1314/a/1">section 1314(a)(1) of Pub. L. 100–180</ref> applicable as if included in enactment of the Goldwater-Nichols Department of Defense Reorganization Act of 1986, <ref href="/us/pl/99/433">Pub. L. 99–433</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/180/s1314/e">section 1314(e) of Pub. L. 100–180</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s743">section 743 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idaa7597fd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/500/s101/c/tX/s961/c">Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(c) [title X, § 961(c)]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1783-82">100 Stat. 1783–82</ref>, 1783–176, <ref href="/us/pl/99/591/s101/c/tX/s961/c">Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(c) [title X, § 961(c)]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3341-82">100 Stat. 3341–82</ref>, 3341–176, and <ref href="/us/pl/99/661/dA/tIX">Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title IX</ref>, formerly title IV, § 961(c), <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3956">100 Stat. 3956</ref>, renumbered title IX, <ref href="/us/pl/100/26/s3/5">Pub. L. 100–26, § 3(5)</ref>, <date date="1987-04-21">Apr. 21, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/273">101 Stat. 273</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/26/s3/5">“The amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) [amending this section and former <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2433">section 2433 of this title</ref>] shall take effect on <date date="1987-01-01">January 1, 1987</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idaa7597fe-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/252/tXI/s1107/c">Pub. L. 97–252, title XI, § 1107(c)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-08">Sept. 8, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/746">96 Stat. 746</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/252/tXI/s1107/c">“Sections 139a [now <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4351">10 U.S.C. 4351</ref>] and 139b [see <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4371">10 U.S.C. 4371</ref> to 4375] of title 10, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall take effect on <date date="1983-01-01">January 1, 1983</date>, and shall apply beginning with respect to reports for the first quarter of fiscal year 1983. The repeal made by subsection (b) [repealing <ref href="/us/pl/94/106/s811">section 811 of Pub. L. 94–106</ref>, formerly set out as a Reports to Congress of Acquisitions for Major Defense Systems note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2431">section 2431 of this title</ref>] shall take effect on <date date="1983-01-01">January 1, 1983</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idaa7597ff-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Acquisition Reporting System</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tVIII/s809/a">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2705">136 Stat. 2705</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dC/tXXXI/s3111/c/2/A">Pub. L. 119–60, div. C, title XXXI, § 3111(c)(2)(A)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1460">139 Stat. 1460</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dC/tXXXI/s3111/c/2/A">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall institute a defense acquisition reporting system to replace the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4351">section 4351 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, as soon as practicable but not later than <date date="2023-06-30">June 30, 2023</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The reporting system required under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> produce the information necessary to carry out the actions specified in chapter 325 of title 10, United States Code;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> produce the information necessary to carry out the actions specified in sections 6125 and 6161 of title 10, United States Code;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> incorporate—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the lessons learned from the demonstration carried out under subsection (b) of section 805 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022 (<ref href="/us/pl/117/81">Public Law 117–81</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/135/1816">135 Stat. 1816</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the plans required under subsection (c) of such section (<ref href="/us/pl/117/81">Public Law 117–81</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/135/1817">135 Stat. 1817</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> provide the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] and other designated Government entities with access to acquisition reporting that is updated on a not less than quarterly basis; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> include such other information and functions as the Secretary of Defense determines appropriate to support the acquisition reporting needs of the Department of Defense.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idaa759800-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2021-12-31">Dec. 31, 2021</date>, of provisions in this section requiring submittal of reports to Congress, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/s1051/x">section 1051(x) of Pub. L. 115–91</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s111">section 111 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idaa759801-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Annual Reporting</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tVIII/s847/b">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 847(b)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2292">130 Stat. 2292</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tVIII/s847/b">“The Secretary of Defense shall include in each comprehensive annual Selected Acquisition Report submitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2432">section 2432 of title 10</ref>, United States Code [now <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4351">10 U.S.C. 4351</ref>], a listing of all programs or projects being developed or procured under the exceptions to the definition of major defense acquisition program set forth in paragraph (2) of section 2430(a) of [title 10,] United States Code [now <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4201/b">10 U.S.C. 4201(b)</ref>], as added by subsection (a)(1)(C) of this section.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idaa759802-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Selected Acquisition Reports for Certain Programs</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/180/dA/tI/s127">Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title I, § 127</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1044">101 Stat. 1044</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dA/tVIII/s817/a">Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title VIII, § 817(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2454">106 Stat. 2454</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/484/dA/tVIII/s817/a">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">SAR Coverage for ATB, ACM, and ATA Programs</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives, in accordance with the provisions of subsection (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2432">section 2432 of title 10</ref>, United States Code [now <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4351/b">10 U.S.C. 4351(b)</ref>], a Selected Acquisition Report with respect to each program referred to in subsection (b), notwithstanding that such a report would not otherwise be required under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2432">section 2432 of title 10</ref>, United States Code [now <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4351">10 U.S.C. 4351</ref>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered Programs</inline>.—</heading><content>Subsection (a) applies to the Advanced Technology Bomber program, the Advanced Cruise Missile program, and the Advanced Tactical Aircraft program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Selected Acquisition Report Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>As used in subsection (a), the term ‘Selected Acquisition Report’ means a report containing the information referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2432">section 2432 of title 10</ref>, United States Code [now <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4351">10 U.S.C. 4351</ref>].”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
