<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida7c2109a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s461"><num value="461">§ 461.</num><heading> Management rights</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7c2109b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s461/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Scope</inline>.—</heading><content>If there is no obligation under the provisions of chapter 71 of title 5 for the head of an agency of the United States to consult or negotiate with a labor organization on a particular matter by reason of that matter being covered by a provision of law or a Governmentwide regulation, the Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency is not obligated to consult or negotiate with a labor organization on that matter even if that provision of law or regulation is inapplicable to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7c2109c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s461/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Bargaining Units</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency shall accord exclusive recognition to a labor organization under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7111">section 7111 of title 5</ref> only for a bargaining unit that was recognized as appropriate for the Defense Mapping Agency on <date date="1996-09-30">September 30, 1996</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7c2109d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s461/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination of Bargaining Unit Coverage of Position Modified To Affect National Security Directly</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7c2109e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s461/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If the Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency determines that the responsibilities of a position within a collective bargaining unit should be modified to include intelligence, counterintelligence, investigative, or security duties not previously assigned to that position and that the performance of the newly assigned duties directly affects the national security of the United States, then, upon such a modification of the responsibilities of that position, the position shall cease to be covered by the collective bargaining unit and the employee in that position shall cease to be entitled to representation by a labor organization accorded exclusive recognition for that collective bargaining unit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7c2109f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s461/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A determination described in paragraph (1) that is made by the Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency may not be reviewed by the Federal Labor Relations Authority or any court of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida7c210a0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tXI/s1112/a/2">Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2681">110 Stat. 2681</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tIX/s921/d/2/A">Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title IX, § 921(d)(2)(A)</ref>, (C), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1568">117 Stat. 1568</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida7c210a1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida7c210a2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida7c210a3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/s921/d/2/A">Pub. L. 108–136, § 921(d)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency” for “National Imagery and Mapping Agency” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/s921/d/2/C">Pub. L. 108–136, § 921(d)(2)(C)</ref>, substituted “The Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency” for “The National Imagery and Mapping Agency” and “on <date date="1996-09-30">September 30, 1996</date>” for “on the day before the date on which employees and positions of the Defense Mapping Agency in that bargaining unit became employees and positions of the National Imagery and Mapping Agency under the National Imagery and Mapping Agency Act of 1996 (title XI of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1997)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/s921/d/2/A">Pub. L. 108–136, § 921(d)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency” for “National Imagery and Mapping Agency” in two places.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida7c210a4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="ida7c210a5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1996-10-01">Oct. 1, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/s1124">section 1124 of Pub. L. 104–201</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1996 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s193">section 193 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
