<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida7c45a2a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483"><num value="483">§ 483.</num><heading> Notifications related to basing decision-making process</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7c45a2b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notification Required</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>At each point in the decision-making process specified in subsection (b), the Secretary concerned shall notify the congressional defense committees of the decision-making process to be used or the decision-making process used, whichever applies—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7c45a2c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to select a military installation to serve as the first permanent location for a new major headquarters, covered military unit, or major weapon system; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7c45a2d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to make a permanent change in the basing of a major headquarters, covered military unit, or major weapon system by relocating the major headquarters, covered military unit, or major weapon system from its current military installation to a different military installation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7c45a2e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deadlines for Submission of Notice</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary concerned shall provide the notice required by subsection (a) within seven days after each of the following decision points during the decision-making process:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7c45a2f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> When the Secretary concerned issues any formal internal guidance to begin the decision-making process regarding the location or relocation of a major headquarters, covered military unit, or major weapon system.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7c45a30-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> When the Secretary concerned selects between two and five military installations as the most likely candidate locations for a major headquarters, covered military unit, or major weapon system in order to subject those installations to additional analysis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7c45a31-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> When the Secretary concerned selects a specific military installation as the preferred location for the major headquarters, covered military unit, or major weapon system.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7c45a32-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Required Elements of Notification</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In a notice required by subsection (a), the Secretary concerned shall include at a minimum the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7c45a33-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A description of the manner in which the joint and all-domain training capabilities at each candidate location, if applicable to the type of basing decision-making process at issue, will be or was, whichever applies, comparatively analyzed among candidate military installations, separate from and in addition to the mission criteria to be used or that was used to make the basing decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7c45a34-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A description of the manner in which the airspace and training areas available at each candidate location, if applicable to the type of basing decision-making process at issue, will be or was, whichever applies, comparatively analyzed among candidate military installations, separate from and in addition to the mission criteria to be used or that was used to make the basing decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7c45a35-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A description of the manner in which community support for the basing decision-making process described in subsection (a) will be or was, whichever applies, comparatively analyzed among candidate military installations, including consultation with appropriate State officials and officials of units of local government in which each installation is located regarding matters affecting the local community, such as transportation, utility infrastructure, housing, education, and family support activities. In any case in which the Secretary concerned selects as the preferred location a military installation with less community support compared to other locations, as indicated by such a comparative analysis, an explanation of the operational considerations that formed the basis for such selection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7c45a36-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> An explanation of how each candidate location will be or was, whichever applies, scored against the factors referred to in the preceding paragraphs, including the weight assigned to each factor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7c45a37-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> A summary of any internal score cards that will be or were, whichever applies, used to make the basing decision.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7c45a38-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> With respect to any decision of the Secretary concerned that would result in a significant increase in the number of members of the Armed Forces assigned to a military installation, a description of the consultation with appropriate State and local entities regarding the basing decision to ensure consideration of matters affecting the local community, including requirements for transportation, utility infrastructure, housing, education, and family support activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7c45a39-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice and Wait Requirements</inline>.—</heading><content>No irrevocable action may be taken to effect or implement a basing decision reached through the decision-making process described in subsection (a) until the end of the 14-day period beginning on the date on which the Secretary concerned submits, in an electronic medium pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s480">section 480 of this title</ref>, the notice referred to in subsection (b)(3) regarding a preferred location for the major headquarters, covered military unit, or major weapon system.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7c45a3a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Reporting Requirement.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7c45a3b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report required</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 10 days after the date on which the budget request for a fiscal year is submitted to Congress under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105">section 1105 of title 31</ref>, the Secretary concerned shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report providing the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7c45a3c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> An update on the status and anticipated completion date of each decision-making process that was commenced or was underway during the previous two fiscal years regarding the location or relocation of a major headquarters, covered military unit, or major weapon system.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7c45a3d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A list and description of anticipated basing decisions to be made regarding the location or relocation of a major headquarters, covered military unit, or major weapon system over the period covered by the future-years defense plan.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7c45a3e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> A timeline for a congressional engagement plan to brief the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate during the decision-making process and when decision notifications would be provided to interested Members of Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7c45a3f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements of report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>To satisfy the requirements of paragraph (1)(B), a report under this subsection shall include at a minimum the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7c45a40-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> An estimate of the number of members of the armed forces and civilian personnel potentially impacted by the basing decision.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7c45a41-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The locations to be considered, if already known.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7c45a42-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The expected timeline for beginning the decision-making process and reaching a final determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7c45a43-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7c45a44-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “covered military unit” means a unit of the armed forces whose initial assignment to a military installation or relocation from a military installation to a different military installation requires the preparation of an environmental impact statement in accordance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7c45a45-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “major headquarters” means the headquarters of a military unit or command that is the appropriate command of a general officer or flag officer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7c45a46-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “major weapon system” means a weapon system that is treatable as a major system under section 3041(a) and (b) of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7c45a47-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The term “military installation” means a base, camp, post, station, yard, center, homeport facility for any ship, or other activity under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense, including any leased facility. Such term does not include any facility used primarily for civil works, rivers and harbors projects, or flood control projects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7c45a48-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/f/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> The term “Secretary concerned” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7c45a49-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/f/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Secretary of the military department concerned; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7c45a4a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s483/f/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Secretary of Defense with respect to matters concerning the Defense Agencies and the Joint Staff.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida7c45a4b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added and amended <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXVIII/s1883/b/2">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1883(b)(2)</ref>, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2871(b), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4294">134 Stat. 4294</ref>, 4363; <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tX/s1081/a/10">Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(10)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1920">135 Stat. 1920</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dB/tXXVIII/s2861">Pub. L. 117–263, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2861</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3010">136 Stat. 3010</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dB/tXXVIII/s2801">Pub. L. 118–159, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2801</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2247">138 Stat. 2247</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida7c45a4c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida7c45a4d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="ida7c45a4e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, referred to in subsec. (f)(1), is <ref href="/us/pl/91/190">Pub. L. 91–190</ref>, <date date="1970-01-01">Jan. 1, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/852">83 Stat. 852</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 55 (§ 4321 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">section 4321 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="ida7c45a4f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 483, added <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tIII/s323/a">Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title III, § 323(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1675">111 Stat. 1675</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tX/s1067/1">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/774">113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title III, § 372], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–80, related to reports on transfers from high-priority readiness appropriations, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tX/s1084/a/1/A">Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title X, § 1084(a)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/871">127 Stat. 871</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida7c45a50-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (f)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159">Pub. L. 118–159</ref> struck out “, which is located within any of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or Guam” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (c)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Pub. L. 117–263</ref> added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (f)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81">Pub. L. 117–81</ref> inserted “this” before “title”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1883/b/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1883(b)(2)</ref>, which directed that each reference in the text of title 10 to a section that was redesignated by title XVIII of <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, as such section was in effect before the redesignation, be amended by striking such reference and inserting a reference to the appropriate redesignated section, was executed by substituting “section 3041(a) and (b) of this title” for “section 2302(5) of title”. <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1806/c/2">Section 1806(c)(2) of Pub. L. 116–283</ref> first redesignated <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2302/5">section 2302(5) of this title</ref> as section 3041(a) and subsequently designated the third sentence thereof as subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida7c45a51-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida7c45a52-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1883/b/2">section 1883(b)(2) of Pub. L. 116–283</ref> effective <date date="2022-01-01">Jan. 1, 2022</date>, with additional provisions for delayed implementation and applicability of existing law, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1801/d">section 1801(d) of Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
