<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idaa994cbd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4832"><num value="4832">§ 4832.</num><heading> Encouragement of technology transfer</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa994cbe-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4832/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Encouragement of Transfer Required</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall encourage, to the extent consistent with national security objectives, the transfer of technology between laboratories and research centers of the Department of Defense and other Federal agencies, State and local governments, colleges and universities, and private persons in cases that are likely to result in accomplishing the objectives set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4811/a">section 4811(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa994cbf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4832/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Examination and Implementation of Methods To Encourage Transfer</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall examine and implement methods, in addition to the encouragement referred to in subsection (a) and the program described in subsection (c), that are consistent with national security objectives and will enable Department of Defense personnel to promote technology transfer.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa994cc0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4832/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program To Encourage Diversification of Defense Laboratories</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa994cc1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4832/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall establish and implement a program to be known as the Federal Defense Laboratory Diversification Program (hereinafter in this subsection referred to as the “Program”). The purpose of the Program shall be to encourage greater cooperation in research and production activities carried out by defense laboratories and by private industry of the United States in order to enhance and improve the products of such research and production activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa994cc2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4832/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Under the Program, the defense laboratories, in coordination with the Office of Technology Transfer in the Office of the Secretary of Defense, shall carry out cooperative activities with private industry in order to promote (by the use or exchange of patents, licenses, cooperative research and development agreements and other cooperative agreements, and the use of symposia, meetings, and other similar mechanisms) the transfer of defense or dual-use technologies from the defense laboratories to private industry, and the development and application of such technologies by the defense laboratories and private industry, for the purpose of the commercial utilization of such technologies by private industry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa994cc3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4832/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall develop and annually update a plan for each defense laboratory that participates in the Program under which plan the laboratory shall carry out cooperative activities with private industry to promote the transfers described in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa994cc4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4832/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> In this subsection, the term “defense laboratory” means any laboratory owned or operated by the Department of Defense that carries out research in fiscal year 1993 in an amount in excess of $50,000,000.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idaa994cc5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dD/tXLII/s4224/a">Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLII, § 4224(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2682">106 Stat. 2682</ref>, § 2514; amended <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tVIII/s829/f">Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title VIII, § 829(f)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2614">110 Stat. 2614</ref>; renumbered § 4832 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXVIII/s1868/b">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1868(b)</ref>, (c)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4282">134 Stat. 4282</ref>, 4283.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idaa994cc6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idaa994cc7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idaa994cc8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 4832, <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041">act Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/272">70A Stat. 272</ref>, authorized Secretary of the Army to prescribe regulations for the accounting for Army property, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/110/181/dA/tIII">Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title III</ref>, §375(c)(1)(A), <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/83">122 Stat. 83</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in subsecs. (a) and (b) of this section were contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2363">section 2363 of this title</ref> prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/102/484">Pub. L. 102–484</ref>, §§ 4224(c), 4271(a)(2).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idaa994cc9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—<ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1868/b">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1868(b)</ref>, renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2514">section 2514 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1868/c/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1868(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “section 4811(a)” for “section 2501(a)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (c)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/104/201">Pub. L. 104–201</ref> struck out par. (5) which read as follows: “The Secretary shall coordinate the Program with the National Defense Technology and Industrial Base Council.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idaa994cca-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idaa994ccb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> effective <date date="2022-01-01">Jan. 1, 2022</date>, with additional provisions for delayed implementation and applicability of existing law, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1801/d">section 1801(d) of Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idaa994ccc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">National Action Plan on Advanced Superconductivity Research and Development</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Superconductivity research and development activities by Secretary of Defense and by Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s5207">section 5207 of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idaa994ccd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pilot Program To Improve Incentives for Technology Transfer From Department of Defense Laboratories</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tII/s233">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title II, § 233</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1339">131 Stat. 1339</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tII/s216/c">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title II, § 216(c)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3460">134 Stat. 3460</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tII/s216/c">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of distributing royalties and other payments as described in this section. Under the pilot program, except as provided in subsections (b) and (d), any royalties or other payments received by a Federal agency from the licensing and assignment of inventions under agreements entered into by Department of Defense laboratories, and from the licensing of inventions of Department of Defense laboratories, shall be retained by the laboratory which produced the invention and shall be disposed of as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The laboratory director shall pay each year the first $2,000, and thereafter at least 20 percent, of the royalties or other payments, other than payments of patent costs as delineated by a license or assignment agreement, to the inventor or coinventors, if the inventor’s or coinventor’s rights are directly assigned to the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> A laboratory director may provide appropriate incentives, from royalties or other payments, to laboratory employees who are not an inventor of such inventions but who substantially increased the technical value of the inventions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> The laboratory shall retain the royalties and other payments received from an invention until the laboratory makes payments to employees of a laboratory under subparagraph (A) or (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> The balance of the royalties or other payments shall be transferred by the agency to its laboratories, with the majority share of the royalties or other payments from any invention going to the laboratory where the invention occurred. The royalties or other payments so transferred to any laboratory may be used or obligated by that laboratory during the fiscal year in which they are received or during the 2 succeeding fiscal years—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> to reward scientific, engineering, and technical employees of the laboratory, including developers of sensitive or classified technology, regardless of whether the technology has commercial applications;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> to further scientific exchange among the laboratories of the agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> for education and training of employees consistent with the research and development missions and objectives of the agency or laboratory, and for other activities that increase the potential for transfer of the technology of the laboratories of the agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> for payment of expenses incidental to the administration and licensing of intellectual property by the agency or laboratory with respect to inventions made at that laboratory, including the fees or other costs for the services of other agencies, persons, or organizations for intellectual property management and licensing services; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> for scientific research and development consistent with the research and development missions and objectives of the laboratory.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> All royalties or other payments retained by the laboratory after payments have been made pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2) that are unobligated and unexpended at the end of the second fiscal year succeeding the fiscal year in which the royalties and other payments were received shall be paid into the Treasury of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Payments to Employees.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Any payment made to an employee under the pilot program shall be in addition to the regular pay of the employee and to any other awards made to the employee, and shall not affect the entitlement of the employee to any regular pay, annuity, or award to which the employee is otherwise entitled or for which the employee is otherwise eligible or limit the amount thereof. Any payment made to an inventor as such shall continue after the inventor leaves the laboratory.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cumulative payments</inline>.—</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Cumulative payments made under the pilot program while the inventor is still employed at the laboratory shall not exceed $500,000 per year to any one person, unless the Secretary concerned (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101/a">section 101(a) of title 10</ref>, United States Code) approves a larger award.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Cumulative payments made under the pilot program after the inventor leaves the laboratory shall not exceed $150,000 per year to any one person, unless the head of the agency approves a larger award (with the excess over $150,000 being treated as an agency award to a former employee under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s4505">section 4505 of title 5</ref>, United States Code).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Invention Management Services</inline>.—</heading><content>Under the pilot program, a laboratory receiving royalties or other payments as a result of invention management services performed for another Federal agency or laboratory under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s207">section 207 of title 35</ref>, United States Code, may retain such royalties or payments to the extent required to offset payments to inventors under subparagraph (A) of subsection (a)(1), costs and expenses incurred under subparagraph (D) of subsection (a)(2), and the cost of foreign patenting and maintenance for any invention of the other agency. All royalties and other payments remaining after offsetting the payments to inventors, costs, and expenses described in the preceding sentence shall be transferred to the agency for which the services were performed, for distribution in accordance with subsection (a)(2).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certain Assignments</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Under the pilot program, if the invention involved was one assigned to the laboratory—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> by a contractor, grantee, or participant, or an employee of a contractor, grantee, or participant, in an agreement or other arrangement with the agency; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> by an employee of the agency who was not working in the laboratory at the time the invention was made,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the agency unit that was involved in such assignment shall be considered to be a laboratory for purposes of this section.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sunset</inline>.—</heading><content>The pilot program under this section shall terminate on <date date="2025-09-30">September 30, 2025</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idaa994cce-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Enhanced Transfer of Technology Developed at Department of Defense Laboratories</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tVIII/s801">Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/802">127 Stat. 802</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tVIII/s818">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 818</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2273">130 Stat. 2273</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tVIII/s832">Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title VIII, § 832</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1832">135 Stat. 1832</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tVIII/s832">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>As used in this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The term ‘military department’ has the meaning provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101">section 101 of title 10</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> The term ‘DOD laboratory’ or ‘laboratory’ means any facility or group of facilities that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> is owned, leased, operated, or otherwise used by the Department of Defense; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> meets the definition of ‘laboratory’ as provided in subsection (d)(2) of section 12 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3710a">15 U.S.C. 3710a</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of a military department each may authorize the heads of DOD laboratories to grant nonexclusive, exclusive, or partially exclusive licenses, royalty free or for royalties or for rights to other intellectual property, for computer software and its related documentation developed at a DOD laboratory, but only if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the computer software and related documentation would be a trade secret under the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552/b/4">section 552(b)(4) of title 5</ref>, United States Code, if the information had been obtained from a non-Federal party;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the public is notified of the availability of the software and related documentation for licensing and interested parties have a fair opportunity to submit applications for licensing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> such licensing activities and licenses comply with the requirements under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s209">section 209 of title 35</ref>, United States Code; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> the software originally was developed to meet the military needs of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Protections against unauthorized disclosure</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of a military department each shall provide appropriate precautions against the unauthorized disclosure of any computer software or documentation covered by paragraph (1)(A), including exemption from <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">section 552 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, for a period of up to 5 years after the development of the computer software by the DOD laboratory.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Royalties.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of royalties</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Except as provided in paragraph (2), any royalties or other payments received by the Department of Defense or a military department from licensing computer software or documentation under paragraph (b)(1) shall be retained by the Department of Defense or the military department and shall be disposed of as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The Department of Defense or the military department shall pay each year the first $2,000, and thereafter at least 15 percent, of the royalties or other payments, to be divided among the employees who developed the computer software.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> The Department of Defense or the military department may provide appropriate lesser incentives, from the royalties or other payments, to laboratory employees who are not developers of such computer software but who substantially increased the technical value of the software.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> The Department of Defense or the military department shall retain the royalties and other payments received until it makes payments to employees of a DOD laboratory under clause (i) or (ii).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> The Department of Defense or the military department may retain an amount reasonably necessary to pay expenses incidental to the administration and distribution of royalties or other payments under this section by an organizational unit of the Department of Defense or military department other than its laboratories.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> The balance of the royalties or other payments shall be transferred by the Department of Defense or the military department to its laboratories, with the majority share of the royalties or other payments going to the laboratory where the development occurred. The royalties or other payments so transferred to any DOD laboratory may be used or obligated by that laboratory during the fiscal year in which they are received or during the 2 succeeding fiscal years—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> to reward scientific, engineering, and technical employees of the DOD laboratory, including developers of sensitive or classified technology, regardless of whether the technology has commercial applications;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> to further scientific exchange among the laboratories of the agency;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> for education and training of employees consistent with the research and development missions and objectives of the Department of Defense, military department, or DOD laboratory, and for other activities that increase the potential for transfer of the technology of the DOD laboratory;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> for payment of expenses incidental to the administration and licensing of computer software or other intellectual property made at the DOD laboratory, including the fees or other costs for the services of other agencies, persons, or organizations for intellectual property management and licensing services; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="v">“(v)</num><content> for scientific research and development consistent with the research and development missions and objectives of the DOD laboratory.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> All royalties or other payments retained by the Department of Defense, military department, or DOD laboratory after payments have been made pursuant to subparagraphs (A) and (B) that are unobligated and unexpended at the end of the second fiscal year succeeding the fiscal year in which the royalties and other payments were received shall be paid into the Treasury of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading><content>If, after payments under paragraph (1)(A), the balance of the royalties or other payments received by the Department of Defense or the military department in any fiscal year exceed 5 percent of the funds received for use by the DOD laboratory for research, development, engineering, testing, and evaluation or other related administrative, processing, or value-added activities for that year, 75 percent of such excess shall be paid to the Treasury of the United States and the remaining 25 percent may be used or obligated under paragraph (1)(B). Any funds not so used or obligated shall be paid into the Treasury of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Status of payments to employees</inline>.—</heading><content>Any payment made to an employee under this section shall be in addition to the regular pay of the employee and to any other awards made to the employee, and shall not affect the entitlement of the employee to any regular pay, annuity, or award to which the employee is otherwise entitled or for which the employee is otherwise eligible or limit the amount thereof except that the monetary value of an award for the same project or effort shall be deducted from the amount otherwise available under this paragraph. Payments, determined under the terms of this paragraph and made to an employee developer as such, may continue after the developer leaves the DOD laboratory or the Department of Defense or military department. Payments made under this section shall not exceed $75,000 per year to any one person, unless the President approves a larger award (with the excess over $75,000 being treated as a Presidential award under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s4504">section 4504 of title 5</ref>, United States Code).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Data Collection</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall develop and implement a plan to collect and analyze data on the use of authority under this section for the purposes of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> developing and sharing best practices; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> providing information to the Secretary of Defense and Congress on the use of authority under this section and related policy issues.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall submit a report to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] on the activities carried out under this section not later than <date date="2025-12-31">December 31, 2025</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Expiration</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority provided in this section shall expire on <date date="2026-12-31">December 31, 2026</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idaa9bbccf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Technology Transfer to Private Sector</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/180/dA/tII/s218/c">Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title II, § 218(c)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-04">Dec. 4, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1053">101 Stat. 1053</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tIX/s904/f">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title IX, § 904(f)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1729">107 Stat. 1729</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tIX/s911/a/1">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title IX, § 911(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/717">113 Stat. 717</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tIX/s911/a/1">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics, shall take appropriate action to ensure that high-temperature superconductivity technology resulting from the research activities of the Department of Defense is transferred to the private sector. Such transfer shall be made in accordance with section 10(e) of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3710/e">15 U.S.C. 3710(e)</ref>), other applicable provisions of law, and Executive Order Number 12591, dated <date date="1987-04-10">April 10, 1987</date> [set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3710">15 U.S.C. 3710</ref>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics, shall ensure that the national laboratories of the Department of Energy participate, to the maximum appropriate extent, in the transfer to the private sector of technology developed under the Department of Defense superconductivity program in the national laboratories.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
