<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idaa9e0796-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4852"><num value="4852">§ 4852.</num><heading> Offset policy; notification</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa9e0797-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4852/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Offset Policy</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The President shall establish, consistent with the requirements of this section, a comprehensive policy with respect to contractual offset arrangements in connection with the purchase of defense equipment or supplies which addresses the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa9e0798-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4852/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Transfer of technology in connection with offset arrangements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa9e0799-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4852/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Application of offset arrangements, including cases in which United States funds are used to finance the purchase by a foreign government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa9e079a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4852/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Effects of offset arrangements on specific subsectors of the industrial base of the United States and for preventing or ameliorating any serious adverse effects on such subsectors.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa9e079b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4852/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Technology Transfer</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa9e079c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4852/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> No official of the United States may enter into a memorandum of understanding or other agreement with a foreign government that would require the transfer of United States defense technology to a foreign country or a foreign firm in connection with a contract that is subject to an offset arrangement if the implementation of such memorandum or agreement would significantly and adversely affect the defense industrial base of the United States and would result in a substantial financial loss to a United States firm.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa9e079d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4852/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Paragraph (1) shall not apply in the case of a memorandum of understanding or agreement described in paragraph (1) if the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of State, determines that a transfer of United States defense technology pursuant to such understanding or agreement will result in strengthening the national security of the United States and so certifies to Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa9e079e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4852/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If a United States firm is required under the terms of a memorandum of understanding, or other agreement entered into by the United States with a foreign country, to transfer defense technology to a foreign country, the United States firm may protest the determination to the Secretary of Defense on the grounds that the transfer of such technology would adversely affect the defense industrial base of the United States and would result in substantial financial loss to the protesting firm. The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of State, shall make the final determination of the validity of the protesting firm’s claim.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa9e079f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4852/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notification Regarding Offsets</inline>.—</heading><content>If at any time a United States firm enters into a contract for the sale of a weapon system or defense-related item to a foreign country or foreign firm and such contract is subject to an offset arrangement exceeding $50,000,000 in value, such firm shall notify the Secretary of Defense of the proposed sale. Notification shall be made under this subsection in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaa9e07a0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4852/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa9e07a1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4852/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “United States firm” means a business entity that performs substantially all of its manufacturing, production, and research and development activities in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaa9e07a2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4852/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “foreign firm” means a business entity other than a United States firm.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idaa9e07a3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/100/456/dA/tVIII/s825/b">Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title VIII, § 825(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2020">102 Stat. 2020</ref>, § 2505; renumbered § 2532, <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dD/tXLII/s4202/a">Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLII, § 4202(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2659">106 Stat. 2659</ref>; renumbered § 4852, <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXVIII/s1870/b">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1870(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4284">134 Stat. 4284</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idaa9e07a4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idaa9e07a5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idaa9e07a6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—<ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2532">section 2532 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—<ref href="/us/pl/102/484">Pub. L. 102–484</ref> renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2505">section 2505 of this title</ref> as section 2532.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idaa9e07a7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idaa9e07a8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> effective <date date="2022-01-01">Jan. 1, 2022</date>, with additional provisions for delayed implementation and applicability of existing law, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1801/d">section 1801(d) of Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idaa9e07a9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Contractual Offset Arrangements; Congressional Statement of Findings</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/456/dA/tVIII/s825/a">Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title VIII, § 825(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2019">102 Stat. 2019</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/456/dA/tVIII/s825/a">
<inline>“Congress makes the following findings:</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> Many contracts entered into by United States firms for the supply of weapon systems or defense-related items to foreign countries and foreign firms are subject to contractual arrangements under which United States firms must agree—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> to have a specified percentage of work under, or monetary amount of, the contract performed by one or more foreign firms;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> to purchase a specified amount or quantity of unrelated goods or services from domestic sources of such foreign countries; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> to invest a specified amount in domestic businesses of such foreign countries.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I31" class="indent1 firstIndent0">Such contractual arrangements, known as ‘offsets’, are a component of international trade and could have an impact on United States defense industry opportunities in domestic and foreign markets.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Some United States contractors and subcontractors may be adversely affected by such contractual arrangements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Many contracts which provide for or are subject to offset arrangements require, in connection with such arrangements, the transfer of United States technology to foreign firms.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The use of such transferred technology by foreign firms in conjunction with foreign trade practices permitted under the trade policies of the countries of such firms can give foreign firms a competitive advantage against United States firms in world markets for products using such technology.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> A purchase of defense equipment pursuant to an offset arrangement may increase the cost of the defense equipment to the purchasing country and may reduce the amount of defense equipment that a country may purchase.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> The exporting of defense equipment produced in the United States is important to maintain the defense industrial base of the United States, lower the unit cost of such equipment to the Department of Defense, and encourage the standardized utilization of United States equipment by the allies of the United States.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idaa9e07aa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Negotiations With Countries Requiring Offset Arrangements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/456/dA/tVIII/s825/c">Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title VIII, § 825(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2021">102 Stat. 2021</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tVIII/s816">Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title VIII, § 816</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1501">103 Stat. 1501</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tVIII/s816">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The President shall enter into negotiations with foreign countries that have a policy of requiring an offset arrangement in connection with the purchase of defense equipment or supplies from the United States. The negotiations should be conducted with a view to achieving an agreement with the countries concerned that would limit the adverse effects that such arrangements have on the defense industrial base of each such country. Every effort shall be made to achieve such agreements within two years after <date date="1988-09-29">September 29, 1988</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> In the negotiation or renegotiation of any memorandum of understanding between the United States and one or more foreign countries relating to the reciprocal procurement of defense equipment and supplies or research and development, the President shall make every effort to achieve an agreement with the country or countries concerned that would limit the adverse effects that offset arrangements have on the defense industrial base of the United States.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For delegation of functions of President under <ref href="/us/pl/100/456/s825/c">section 825(c) of Pub. L. 100–456</ref> to Secretary of Defense and United States Trade Representative, see section 5–201 of Ex. Ord. No. 12661, 54 F.R. 779, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2901">section 2901 of Title 19</ref>, Customs Duties.]</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
