<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idaab11a81-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4974"><num value="4974">§ 4974.</num><heading> Fees charged and collected</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaab11a82-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4974/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exposure Fees</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall charge a fee (known as “exposure fee”) for each guarantee issued under this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaab11a83-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4974/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Amount of Exposure Fee</inline>.—</heading><content>To the extent that the cost of the loan guarantees under this subchapter is not otherwise provided for in appropriations Acts, the fee imposed under subsection (a) with respect to a loan guarantee shall be fixed in an amount that is sufficient to meet potential liabilities of the United States under the loan guarantee.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaab11a84-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4974/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Payment Terms</inline>.—</heading><content>The fee under subsection (a) for each guarantee shall become due as the guarantee is issued. In the case of a guarantee for a loan which is disbursed incrementally, and for which the guarantee is correspondingly issued incrementally as portions of the loan are disbursed, the fee shall be paid incrementally in proportion to the amount of the guarantee that is issued.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaab11a85-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4974/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Administrative Fees</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaab11a86-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4974/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall charge a fee for each guarantee issued under this subchapter to reflect the additional administrative costs of the Department of Defense that are directly attributable to the administration of the program under this subchapter. Such fees shall be credited to a special account in the Treasury. Amounts in the special account shall be available, to the extent and in amounts provided in appropriations Acts, for paying the costs of administrative expenses of the Department of Defense that are attributable to the loan guarantee program under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaab11a87-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4974/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaab11a88-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4974/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> If for any fiscal year amounts in the special account established under paragraph (1) are not available (or are not anticipated to be available) in a sufficient amount for administrative expenses of the Department of Defense for that fiscal year that are directly attributable to the administration of the program under this subchapter, the Secretary may use amounts currently available for operations and maintenance for Defense-wide activities, not to exceed $500,000 in any fiscal year, for those expenses.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaab11a89-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s4974/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary shall, from funds in the special account established under paragraph (1), replenish operations and maintenance accounts for amounts expended under subparagraph (A) as soon as the Secretary determines practicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idaab11a8a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tXIII/s1321/a/1">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XIII, § 1321(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/476">110 Stat. 476</ref>, § 2540c; amended <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1081(a)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–284; renumbered § 4974, <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXVIII/s1873/b">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1873(b)</ref>, (c)(1), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4290">134 Stat. 4290</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idaab11a8b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idaab11a8c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idaab11a8d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—<ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2540c">section 2540c of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/106/398">Pub. L. 106–398</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idaab11a8e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idaab11a8f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> effective <date date="2022-01-01">Jan. 1, 2022</date>, with additional provisions for delayed implementation and applicability of existing law, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1801/d">section 1801(d) of Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idaab11a90-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2000 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1081(b), (c)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–284, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effective Date</inline>.—</heading><content>Paragraph (2) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2540c/d">section 2540c(d) of title 10</ref>, United States Code [now <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4974/d/2">10 U.S.C. 4974(d)(2)</ref>], as added by subsection (a), shall take effect on <date date="2000-10-01">October 1, 2000</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation Pending Submission of Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense may not exercise the authority provided by paragraph (2) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2540c/d">section 2540c(d) of title 10</ref>, United States Code [now <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4974/d/2">10 U.S.C. 4974(d)(2)</ref>], as added by subsection (a), until the Secretary submits to Congress a report on the operation of the Defense Export Loan Guarantee Program under [former] subchapter V of chapter 148 of title 10, United States Code [see chapter 385 of this title]. The report shall include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> A discussion of the effectiveness of the loan guarantee program in furthering the sale of United States defense articles, defense services, and design and construction services to nations that are specified in section 2540(b) of such title [now <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4971/b">10 U.S.C. 4971(b)</ref>], to include a comparison of the loan guarantee program with other United States Government programs that are intended to contribute to the sale of United States defense articles, defense services, and design and construction services and other comparisons the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> A discussion of the requirements and resources (including personnel and funds) for continued administration of the loan guarantee program by the Defense Department, to include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> an itemization of the requirements necessary and resources available (or that could be made available) to administer the loan guarantee program for each of the following entities: the Defense Security Cooperation Agency, the Department of Defense International Cooperation Office, and other Defense Department agencies, offices, or activities as the Secretary may specify; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> for each such activity, agency, or office, a comparison of the use of Defense Department personnel exclusively to administer, manage, and oversee the program with the use of contracted commercial entities to administer and manage the program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Any legislative recommendations that the Secretary believes could improve the effectiveness of the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> A determination made by the Secretary of Defense indicating which Defense Department agency, office, or other activity should administer, manage, and oversee the loan guarantee program to increase sales of United States defense articles, defense services, and design and construction services, such determination to be made based on the information and analysis provided in the report.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
