<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida7cb85e7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s499b"><num value="499b">§ 499b.</num><heading> Participation in United States Strategic Command strategic deterrence exercises</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7cb85e8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s499b/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Participation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In the case of annual strategic deterrence exercises held by the United States Strategic Command during fiscal years 2022 through 2032—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7cb85e9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s499b/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs is encouraged to participate in each such exercise that occurs during an even-numbered year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7cb85ea-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s499b/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the Deputy Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs is encouraged to participate in each such exercise that occurs during an odd-numbered year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7cb85eb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s499b/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy shall participate, in whole or in part, in each such exercise;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7cb85ec-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s499b/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff shall participate, in whole or in part, in each such exercise;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7cb85ed-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s499b/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> appropriate senior staff of the Executive Office of the President or appropriate organizations supporting the White House relating to continuity of government activities are encouraged to participate in each such exercise;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7cb85ee-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s499b/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> appropriate general or flag officers of the military departments, and appropriate employees of Federal agencies in Senior Executive Service positions (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3132">section 3132 of title 5</ref>), shall participate, in whole or in part, in each such exercise, to provide relevant expertise to the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs and the Deputy Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7cb85ef-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s499b/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><chapeau> in the case of such an exercise for which a unified combatant command has a geographic area of responsibility relevant to the scenario planned to be used for the exercise, not fewer than two of the following individuals from that command shall participate, in whole or in part, in the exercise:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7cb85f0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s499b/a/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Commander.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7cb85f1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s499b/a/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Deputy Commander.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7cb85f2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s499b/a/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Director of the Joint Staff for Operations.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida7cb85f3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s499b/a/7/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The Director of the Joint Staff for Strategic Plans and Policy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7cb85f4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s499b/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Briefing</inline>.—</heading><content>Not fewer than once every four years (or more frequently if appropriate) during the period specified in subsection (a), the President shall be provided a briefing on the annual strategic deterrence exercise held by the United States Strategic Command during the year in which the briefing is provided, including the principal findings resulting from the exercise.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7cb85f5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s499b/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7cb85f6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s499b/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Not later than 30 days after the completion of an annual strategic deterrence exercise described in subsection (a), the Commander of the United States Strategic Command shall submit to the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff and the Secretary of Defense a report on the exercise, which, at a minimum, shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7cb85f7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s499b/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A description of the purpose and scope of the exercise.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7cb85f8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s499b/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> An identification of the principal personnel participating in the exercise.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7cb85f9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s499b/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> A statement of the principal findings resulting from the exercise that specifically relate to the nuclear command, control, and communications or senior leader decision-making process and a description of any deficiencies in that process identified a result of the exercise.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7cb85fa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s499b/c/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Whether the President was briefed on the exercise and the principal findings resulting from the exercise.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7cb85fb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s499b/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Not later than 60 days after the completion of an annual strategic deterrence exercise described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7cb85fc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s499b/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an unedited copy of the report of the Commander submitted under paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7cb85fd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s499b/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any additional recommendations or other matters the Secretary considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida7cb85fe-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tXVI/s1631">Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVI, § 1631</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/2089">135 Stat. 2089</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
