<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida7dc4f0e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s527"><num value="527">§ 527.</num><heading> Authority to suspend sections 523, 525, and 526</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In time of war, or of national emergency declared by Congress or the President after <date date="1980-11-30">November 30, 1980</date>, the President may suspend the operation of any provision of section 523, 525, or 526 of this title. So long as such war or national emergency continues, any such suspension may be extended by the President. Any such suspension shall, if not sooner ended, end on the last day of the two-year period beginning on the date on which the suspension (or the last extension thereof) takes effect or on the last day of the one-year period beginning on the date of the termination of the war or national emergency, whichever occurs first. With respect to the end of any such suspension, the preceding sentence supersedes the provisions of title II of the National Emergencies Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1621–162">50 U.S.C. 1621–162</ref>2) which provide that powers or authorities exercised by reason of a national emergency shall cease to be exercised after the date of the termination of the emergency.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="ida7dc4f0f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/96/513/tI/s103">Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2845">94 Stat. 2845</ref>, § 526; renumbered § 527 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/370/s1/b/1/A">Pub. L. 100–370, § 1(b)(1)(A)</ref>, (2), <date date="1988-07-19">July 19, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/840">102 Stat. 840</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tXVI/s1671/c/4">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1671(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3014">108 Stat. 3014</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida7dc4f10-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida7dc4f11-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="ida7dc4f12-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Emergencies Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/94/412">Pub. L. 94–412</ref>, <date date="1976-09-14">Sept. 14, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1255">90 Stat. 1255</ref>, as amended. Title II of the National Emergencies Act is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 1621 et seq.) of chapter 34 of Title 50, War and National Defense. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1601">section 1601 of Title 50</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida7dc4f13-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/337">Pub. L. 103–337</ref> struck out “524,” after “523,” in section catchline and in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/370">Pub. L. 100–370</ref> renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s526">section 526 of this title</ref> as this section, substituted “524, 525, and 526” for “524, and 525” in section catchline, and “524, 525, or 526” for “524, or 525” in text.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida7dc4f14-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida7dc4f15-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/337">Pub. L. 103–337</ref> effective <date date="1994-12-01">Dec. 1, 1994</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s1691">section 1691 of Pub. L. 103–337</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s10001">section 10001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="ida7dc4f16-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1981-09-15">Sept. 15, 1981</date>, but the authority to prescribe regulations under this section effective <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/513/s701">section 701 of Pub. L. 96–513</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1980 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7dc4f17-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Authority To Waive Grade Strength Laws For Fiscal Year 1991; Certification; Relationship to Other Suspension Authority</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/25/tII">Pub. L. 102–25, title II</ref>, §§ 201(b), 202, 205(b), <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/79">105 Stat. 79</ref>, 80, authorized Secretary of a military department to suspend, for fiscal year 1991, the operation of any provision of section 517, 523, 524, 525, or 526 of this title with respect to that military department, that such Secretary may exercise such authority only after submission to the congressional defense committees of a certification in writing that such authority is necessary because of personnel actions associated with Operation Desert Storm, and that such authority is in addition to the authority provided in this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="ida7dc4f18-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="ida7dc4f19-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of President under this section to suspend operation of sections 523, 524 [now 12011], and 525 of this title, relating to authorized strength of commissioned officers, delegated to Secretary of Defense to perform during a time of war or national emergency, without approval, ratification, or other action by President, and with authority for Secretary to redelegate, provided that, during a national emergency declared by President, the exercise of any such authority be specifically directed by President in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1631">section 1631 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, and that Secretary ensure that actions taken pursuant to any authority so delegated be accounted for as required by <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1641">section 1641 of Title 50</ref>, see Ex. Ord. No. 12396, §§ 2, 3, <date date="1982-12-09">Dec. 9, 1982</date>, 47 F.R. 55897, 55898, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of Title 3</ref>, The President.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7dc4f1a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Authority</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Authority of President under this section as invoked by sections 2 and 3 of Ex. Ord. No. 13223, <date date="2001-09-14">Sept. 14, 2001</date>, 66 F.R. 48201, as amended, delegated to Secretary of Defense by section 4 of Ex. Ord. No. 13223, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12302">section 12302 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
