<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida7dc4f1b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s528"><num value="528">§ 528.</num><heading> Officers serving in certain intelligence positions: military status; application of distribution and strength limitations; pay and allowances</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7dc4f1c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s528/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Military Status</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An officer of the armed forces, while serving in a position covered by this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7dc4f1d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s528/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> shall not be subject to supervision or control by the Secretary of Defense or any other officer or employee of the Department of Defense, except as directed by the Secretary of Defense concerning reassignment from such position; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7dc4f1e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s528/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> may not exercise, by reason of the officer’s status as an officer, any supervision or control with respect to any of the military or civilian personnel of the Department of Defense except as otherwise authorized by law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7dc4f1f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s528/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Director and Deputy Director of CIA</inline>.—</heading><content>When the position of Director or Deputy Director of the Central Intelligence Agency is held by an officer of the armed forces, the position, so long as the officer serves in the position, shall be designated, pursuant to subsection (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s526">section 526 of this title</ref>, as one of the general officer and flag officer positions to be excluded from the limitations in subsection (a) of such section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7dc4f20-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s528/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Associate Director of Military Affairs, CIA</inline>.—</heading><content>When the position of Associate Director of Military Affairs, Central Intelligence Agency, or any successor position, is held by an officer of the armed forces, the position, so long as the officer serves in the position, shall be designated, pursuant to subsection (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s526">section 526 of this title</ref>, as one of the general officer and flag officer positions to be excluded from the limitations in subsection (a) of such section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7dc4f21-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s528/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Officers Serving in Office of DNI</inline>.—</heading><content>When a position in the Office of the Director of National Intelligence designated by agreement between the Secretary of Defense and the Director of National Intelligence is held by a general officer or flag officer of the armed forces, the position, so long as the officer serves in the position, shall be designated, pursuant to subsection (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s526">section 526 of this title</ref>, as one of the general officer and flag officer positions to be excluded from the limitations in subsection (a) of such section. However, not more than five of such positions may be included among the excluded positions at any time.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7dc4f22-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s528/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effect of Appointment</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (a), the appointment or assignment of an officer of the armed forces to a position covered by this section shall not affect—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7dc4f23-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s528/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the status, position, rank, or grade of such officer in the armed forces; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7dc4f24-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s528/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> any emolument, perquisite, right, privilege, or benefit incident to or arising out of such status, position, rank, or grade.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7dc4f25-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s528/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Military Pay and Allowances</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7dc4f26-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s528/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An officer of the armed forces on active duty who is appointed or assigned to a position covered by this section shall, while serving in such position and while remaining on active duty, continue to receive military pay and allowances and shall not receive the pay prescribed for such position.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7dc4f27-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s528/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Funds from which pay and allowances under paragraph (1) are paid to an officer while so serving shall be reimbursed as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7dc4f28-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s528/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> For an officer serving in a position within the Central Intelligence Agency, such reimbursement shall be made from funds available to the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7dc4f29-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s528/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> For an officer serving in a position within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, such reimbursement shall be made from funds available to the Director of National Intelligence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7dc4f2a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s528/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered Positions</inline>.—</heading><content>The positions covered by this section are the positions specified in subsections (b) and (c) and the positions designated under subsection (d).</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida7dc4f2b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tV/s507/a">Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 507(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1458">117 Stat. 1458</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/109/163/dA/tV/s507/a">Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 507(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-06">Jan. 6, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3228">119 Stat. 3228</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tV/s501/a">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2175">120 Stat. 2175</ref>, 2176; <ref href="/us/pl/110/417">Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title IX, § 933, <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4576">122 Stat. 4576</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/259/tVIII/s803">Pub. L. 111–259, title VIII, § 803</ref>, <date date="2010-10-07">Oct. 7, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2746">124 Stat. 2746</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/dA/tV/s502/d/1">Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 502(d)(1)</ref>, (2)(A), <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1387">125 Stat. 1387</ref>, 1388.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida7dc4f2c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida7dc4f2d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="ida7dc4f2e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 528, added <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tIV/s405/b/1">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title IV, § 405(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2744">108 Stat. 2744</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tIV/s403/b">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title IV, § 403(b)</ref>, title XV, § 1503(a)(4), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/287">110 Stat. 287</ref>, 511; <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tX/s1074/a/3">Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title X, § 1074(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2658">110 Stat. 2658</ref>, which related to limitation on number of officers on active duty in grades of general and admiral, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tV/s501/a">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1079">115 Stat. 1079</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida7dc4f2f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—<ref href="/us/pl/112/81/s502/d/2/A">Pub. L. 112–81, § 502(d)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “Officers serving in certain intelligence positions: military status; application of distribution and strength limitations; pay and allowances” for “Officers serving in certain intelligence positions: military status; exclusion from distribution and strength limitations; pay and allowances” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b) to (d). <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/s502/d/1">Pub. L. 112–81, § 502(d)(1)</ref>, added subsecs. (b) to (d) and struck out former subsecs. (b) to (d) which related to Director and Deputy Director of CIA, Associate Director of Military Affairs of CIA, and Officers Serving in the Office of DNI, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/111/259">Pub. L. 111–259</ref> substituted “Associate Director of Military Affairs, CIA” for “Associate Director of CIA for Military Affairs” in heading and “Associate Director of Military Affairs, Central Intelligence Agency, or any successor position” for “Associate Director of the Central Intelligence Agency for Military Affairs” in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/110/417">Pub. L. 110–417</ref> substituted “Military Affairs” for “Military Support” in heading and text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—<ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s501/b/1">Pub. L. 109–364, § 501(b)(1)</ref>, amended section catchline generally, substituting “Officers serving in certain intelligence positions: military status; exclusion from distribution and strength limitations; pay and allowances” for “Exclusion: officers serving in certain intelligence positions”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/163">Pub. L. 109–163</ref> amended section catchline and text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(a) When none of the individuals serving in a position specified in subsection (b) is an officer of the armed forces, an officer of the armed forces assigned to the position of Associate Director of Central Intelligence for Military Support, while serving in that position, shall not be counted against the numbers and percentages of officers of the grade of that officer authorized for that officer’s armed force.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(b) The positions referred to in subsection (a) are the following:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) Director of Central Intelligence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) Deputy Director of Central Intelligence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(3) Deputy Director of Central Intelligence for Community Management.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (a), (b). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s501/a/1">Pub. L. 109–364, § 501(a)(1)</ref>, added subsecs. (a) and (b) and struck out former subsecs. (a) and (b) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(a) <inline class="small-caps">Exclusion of Officer Serving in Certain CIA Positions</inline>.—When either of the individuals serving in a position specified in subsection (b) is an officer of the armed forces, one of those officers, while serving in that position, shall be excluded from the limitations in sections 525 and 526 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(b) <inline class="small-caps">Covered Positions</inline>.—The positions referred to in this subsection are the following:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) Director of the Central Intelligence Agency.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) Deputy Director of the Central Intelligence Agency.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e) to (g). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s501/a/2">Pub. L. 109–364, § 501(a)(2)</ref>, added subsecs. (e) to (g).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
