<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida7e109f7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s576"><num value="576">§ 576.</num><heading> Information to be furnished to selection boards; selection procedures</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e109f8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s576/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> The Secretary concerned shall furnish to each selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s573">section 573 of this title</ref> the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7e109f9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s576/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The maximum number of warrant officers that may be recommended for promotion from those serving in any grade (or grade and competitive category) to be considered, as determined in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s574">section 574 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7e109fa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s576/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The names and pertinent records of all officers in each grade (or grade and competitive category) to be considered.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7e109fb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s576/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Such information or guidelines relating to the needs of the armed force concerned for warrant officers having particular skills, including guidelines or information relating to the need for either a minimum number or a maximum number of officers with particular skills within a grade or competitive category, as the Secretary concerned determines to be relevant in relation to the requirements of that armed force.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e109fc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s576/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> From each promotion zone for a grade (or grade and competitive category), the selection board shall recommend for promotion to the next higher warrant officer grade those warrant officers whom it considers best qualified for promotion, but no more than the number specified by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e109fd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s576/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><chapeau> The names of warrant officers selected for promotion under this section shall be arranged in the report of such board in the following order of priority:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7e109fe-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s576/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Warrant officers recommended under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s575/e">section 575(e) of this title</ref> to be placed higher on the promotion list, in the order in which the board determines.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7e109ff-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s576/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Warrant officers otherwise recommended for promotion, in the order of seniority on the warrant officer active-duty list.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a00-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s576/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> Under such regulations as the Secretary concerned may prescribe, the selection board shall report the names of those warrant officers considered by it whose records establish, in its opinion, their unfitness or unsatisfactory performance. A regular warrant officer whose name is so reported shall be considered, under regulations provided by the Secretary concerned, for retirement or separation under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1166">section 1166 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a01-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s576/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> The report of the selection board shall be submitted to the Secretary concerned. The Secretary may approve or disapprove all or part of the report.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a02-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s576/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a03-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s576/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Upon receipt of the report of a selection board submitted to him under subsection (e), the Secretary concerned shall review the report to determine whether the board has acted contrary to law or regulation or to guidelines furnished the board under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a04-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s576/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If, on the basis of a review of the report under paragraph (1), the Secretary concerned determines that the board acted contrary to law or regulation or to guidelines furnished the board under this section, the Secretary shall return the report, together with a written explanation of the basis for such determination, to the board for further proceedings. Upon receipt of a report returned by the Secretary concerned under this paragraph, the selection board (or a subsequent selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s573">section 573 of this title</ref> for the same grade and competitive category) shall conduct such proceedings as may be necessary in order to revise the report to be consistent with law, regulation, and such guidelines and shall resubmit the report, as revised, to the Secretary in accordance with subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida7e10a05-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/dA/tXI/s1112/a">Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1496">105 Stat. 1496</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tV">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 501(b), 541(b)(4), <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2748">108 Stat. 2748</ref>, 2764; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tV/s508/b">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 508(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2560">136 Stat. 2560</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida7e10a06-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida7e10a07-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="ida7e10a08-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s560">section 560 of this title</ref> prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/s1112/a">Pub. L. 102–190, § 1112(a)</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida7e10a09-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Pub. L. 117–263</ref> amended subsec. (c) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (c) read as follows: “The names of warrant officers selected for promotion under this section shall be arranged in the board’s report in order of the seniority on the warrant officer active-duty list.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s541/b/4/A">Pub. L. 103–337, § 541(b)(4)(A)</ref>, struck out “of the military department” after “The Secretary” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s541/b/4/B">Pub. L. 103–337, § 541(b)(4)(B)</ref>, struck out “of the military department” after “submitted to the Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s501/b">Pub. L. 103–337, § 501(b)</ref>, struck out after first sentence “Following such review, unless the Secretary concerned makes a determination as described in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall submit the report as required by subsection (e).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s541/b/4/C">Pub. L. 103–337, § 541(b)(4)(C)</ref>, struck out “of the military department” after “paragraph (1), the Secretary”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida7e10a0a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida7e10a0b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s541/b/4">section 541(b)(4) of Pub. L. 103–337</ref> effective on the first day of the fourth month beginning after <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s541/h">section 541(h) of Pub. L. 103–337</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s571">section 571 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="ida7e10a0c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1992-02-01">Feb. 1, 1992</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/s1132">section 1132 of Pub. L. 102–190</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1991 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s521">section 521 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
