<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida7e10a2f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580"><num value="580">§ 580.</num><heading> Regular warrant officers twice failing of selection for promotion: involuntary retirement or separation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a30-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a31-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Unless retired or separated sooner under some other provision of law, a regular chief warrant officer who has twice failed of selection for promotion to the next higher regular warrant officer grade shall be retired under paragraph (2) or (3) or separated from active duty under paragraph (4).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a32-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If a warrant officer described in paragraph (1) has more than 20 years of creditable active service on (A) the date on which the Secretary concerned approves the report of the board under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s576/e">section 576(e) of this title</ref>, or (B) the date on which his name was removed from the recommended list under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s579">section 579 of this title</ref>, whichever applies, the warrant officer shall be retired. The date of such retirement shall be not later than the first day of the seventh calendar month beginning after the applicable date under the preceding sentence, except as provided by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8301">section 8301 of title 5</ref>. A warrant officer retired under this paragraph shall receive retired pay computed under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1401">section 1401 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a33-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If a warrant officer described in paragraph (1) has at least 18 but not more than 20 years of creditable active service on (A) the date on which the Secretary concerned approves the report of the board under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s576/e">section 576(e) of this title</ref>, or (B) the date on which his name was removed from the recommended list under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s579">section 579 of this title</ref>, whichever applies, the warrant officer shall be retired not later than the date determined under the next sentence unless he is selected for promotion to the next higher regular warrant officer grade before that date. The date of the retirement of a warrant officer under the preceding sentence shall be on a date specified by the Secretary concerned, but not later than the first day of the seventh calendar month beginning after the date upon which he completes 20 years of active service, except as provided by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8301">section 8301 of title 5</ref>. A warrant officer retired under this paragraph shall receive retired pay computed under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1401">section 1401 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a34-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a35-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> If a warrant officer described in paragraph (1) has less than 18 years of creditable active service on (i) the date on which the Secretary concerned approves the report of the board under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s576/e">section 576(e) of this title</ref>, or (ii) the date on which his name was removed from the recommended list under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s579">section 579 of this title</ref>, whichever applies, the warrant officer shall be separated (except as provided in subparagraph (C)). The date of such separation shall be not later than the first day of the seventh calendar month beginning after the applicable date under the preceding sentence.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a36-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> A warrant officer separated under this paragraph shall receive separation pay computed under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1174">section 1174 of this title</ref>, or severance pay computed under section 286a <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002036">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002036"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of title 14, as appropriate, except in a case in which—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7e10a37-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/a/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> upon his request and in the discretion of the Secretary concerned, he is enlisted in the grade prescribed by the Secretary; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7e10a38-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/a/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> he is serving on active duty in a grade above chief warrant officer, W–5, and he elects, with the consent of the Secretary concerned, to remain on active duty in that status.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a39-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/a/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> If on the date on which a warrant officer is to be separated under subparagraph (A) the warrant officer has at least 18 years of creditable active service, the warrant officer shall be retained on active duty until retired under paragraph (3) in the same manner as if the warrant officer had had at least 18 years of service on the applicable date under subparagraph (A) or (B) of that paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a3a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> A warrant officer who is subject to retirement or discharge under this subsection is not eligible for further consideration for promotion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a3b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> In this subsection, the term “creditable active service” means active service that could be credited to a warrant officer under section 511 of the Career Compensation Act of 1949, as amended (<ref href="/us/stat/70/114">70 Stat. 114</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a3c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The Secretary concerned may defer, for not more than four months, the retirement or separation under this section of a warrant officer if, because of unavoidable circumstances, evaluation of his physical condition and determination of his entitlement to retirement or separation for physical disability require hospitalization or medical observation that cannot be completed before the date on which he would otherwise be required to retire or be separated under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a3d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The Secretary concerned may defer, until such date as he prescribes, the retirement under subsection (a) of a warrant officer who is serving on active duty in a grade above chief warrant officer, W–5, and who elects to continue to so serve.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a3e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> If a warrant officer who also holds a grade above chief warrant officer, W–5, is retired or separated under subsection (a), his commission in the higher grade shall be terminated on the date on which he is so retired or separated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a3f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a40-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> A regular warrant officer subject to discharge or retirement under this section may, subject to the needs of the service, be continued on active duty if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7e10a41-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in the case of a warrant officer in the grade of chief warrant officer, W–2, or chief warrant officer, W–3, the warrant officer is selected for continuation on active duty by a selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s573/c">section 573(c) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7e10a42-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case of a warrant officer in the grade of chief warrant officer, W–4, the warrant officer is selected for continuation on active duty by the Secretary concerned under such procedures as the Secretary may prescribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a43-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a44-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A warrant officer who is selected for continuation on active duty under this subsection but declines to continue on active duty shall be discharged, retired, or retained on active duty, as appropriate, in accordance with this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a45-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A warrant officer in the grade of chief warrant officer, W–4, who is retained on active duty pursuant to procedures prescribed under paragraph (1)(B) is eligible for further consideration for promotion while remaining on active duty.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a46-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Each warrant officer who is continued on active duty under this subsection, not subsequently promoted or continued on active duty, and not on a list of warrant officers recommended for continuation or for promotion to the next higher regular grade shall, unless sooner retired or discharged under another provision of law—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7e10a47-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> be discharged upon the expiration of his period of continued service; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7e10a48-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if he is eligible for retirement under any provision of law, be retired under that law on the first day of the first month following the month in which he completes his period of continued service.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), a warrant officer who would otherwise be discharged under such subparagraph and who is within two years of qualifying for retirement under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1293">section 1293 of this title</ref> shall, unless he is sooner retired or discharged under some other provision of law, be retained on active duty until he is qualified for retirement under that section and then be retired.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a49-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The retirement or discharge of a warrant officer pursuant to this subsection shall be considered to be an involuntary retirement or discharge for purposes of any other provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a4a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Continuation of a warrant officer on active duty under this subsection pursuant to the action of a selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s573/c">section 573(c) of this title</ref> is subject to the approval of the Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a4b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/e/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security, when the Coast Guard is not operating as a service in the Navy, shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e10a4c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s580/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> A warrant officer subject to discharge or retirement under this section, but against whom any action has been commenced with a view to trying the officer by court-martial, may be continued on active duty, without prejudice to such action, until the completion of such action.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida7e10a4d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/dA/tXI/s1112/a">Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1498">105 Stat. 1498</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tV/s505/a">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 505(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1645">107 Stat. 1645</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tV/s541/b/5">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 541(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2765">108 Stat. 2765</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/296/tXVII/s1704/b/1">Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1704(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2314">116 Stat. 2314</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tV/s505/a">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 505(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2179">120 Stat. 2179</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/dA/tV/s541">Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 541</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4218">124 Stat. 4218</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida7e10a4e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida7e10a4f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="ida7e10a50-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t14/s286a">Section 286a of title 14</ref>, referred to in subsec. (a)(4)(B), was redesignated <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s2147">section 2147 of title 14</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/115/282/tI/s112/b">Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 112(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-04">Dec. 4, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4216">132 Stat. 4216</ref>, and references to <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s286a">section 286a of title 14</ref> deemed to refer to such redesignated section, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/282/s123/b/1">section 123(b)(1) of Pub. L. 115–282</ref>, set out as a References to Sections of Title 14 as Redesignated by <ref href="/us/pl/115/282">Pub. L. 115–282</ref> note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s101">section 101 of Title 14</ref>, Coast Guard.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 511 of the Career Compensation Act of 1949, referred to in subsec. (a)(6), is section 511 of <ref href="/us/act/1949-10-12/ch681">act Oct. 12, 1949, ch. 681</ref>, which was formerly set out as a note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="ida7e35441-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s564">section 564 of this title</ref> prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/s1112/a">Pub. L. 102–190, § 1112(a)</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida7e35442-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383">Pub. L. 111–383</ref> added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s505/a">Pub. L. 109–364, § 505(a)</ref>, substituted “continued on active duty if—” and subpars. (A) and (B) for “continued on active duty if he is selected for continuation on active duty by a selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s573/c">section 573(c) of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s505/b">Pub. L. 109–364, § 505(b)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A) and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (e)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref> substituted “of Homeland Security” for “of Transportation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a)(4)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s541/b/5/A">Pub. L. 103–337, § 541(b)(5)(A)</ref>, inserted “, or severance pay computed under <ref href="/us/usc/t14/s286a">section 286a of title 14</ref>, as appropriate,” after “<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1174">section 1174 of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s541/b/5/B">Pub. L. 103–337, § 541(b)(5)(B)</ref>, inserted “and the Secretary of Transportation, when the Coast Guard is not operating as a service in the Navy,” after “Secretary of Defense”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (a)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/103/160/s505/a/1">Pub. L. 103–160, § 505(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “(except as provided in subparagraph (C))” after “shall be separated”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/103/160/s505/a/2">Pub. L. 103–160, § 505(a)(2)</ref>, added subpar. (C).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida7e35443-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida7e35444-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2002 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref> effective on the date of transfer of the Coast Guard to the Department of Homeland Security, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/296/s1704/g">section 1704(g) of Pub. L. 107–296</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida7e35445-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/337">Pub. L. 103–337</ref> effective on the first day of the fourth month beginning after <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s541/h">section 541(h) of Pub. L. 103–337</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s571">section 571 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida7e35446-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1993 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tV/s505/b">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 505(b)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1646">107 Stat. 1646</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tV/s505/b">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to warrant officers who have not been separated pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s580/a/4">section 580(a)(4) of title 10</ref>, United States Code, before the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="ida7e35447-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1992-02-01">Feb. 1, 1992</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/s1132">section 1132 of Pub. L. 102–190</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1991 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s521">section 521 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7e35448-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Retired and Retainer Pay of Members on Retired Lists or Receiving Retainer Pay</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1949-10-12/ch681/tV/s511">Act Oct. 12, 1949, ch. 681, title V, § 511</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/829">63 Stat. 829</ref>, as amended <ref href="/us/act/1952-05-19/ch310/s4">May 19, 1952, ch. 310, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/80">66 Stat. 80</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1956-04-23/ch208/s1">Apr. 23, 1956, ch. 208, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/114">70 Stat. 114</ref>, set forth methods of computing retired pay, retirement pay, retainer pay, or equivalent pay on and after <date date="1949-10-01">Oct. 1, 1949</date>, for members of the uniformed services who had retired for reasons other than for physical disability before <date date="1949-10-01">Oct. 1, 1949</date>, members who had transferred to the Fleet Reserve or the Fleet Marine Corps Reserve before such date, and certain members of the Army Nurse Corps or the Navy Nurse Corps who had retired before such date, and provided that the amount of such pay would not exceed 75 percentum of the monthly basic pay upon which the computation had been based.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
