<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida7e35461-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s581"><num value="581">§ 581.</num><heading> Selective retirement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e35462-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s581/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> A regular warrant officer who holds a warrant officer grade above warrant officer, W–1, and whose name is not on a list of warrant officers recommended for promotion and who is eligible to retire under any provision of law may be considered for retirement by a selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s573/c">section 573(c) of this title</ref>. The Secretary concerned shall specify the maximum number of warrant officers that such a board may recommend for retirement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e35463-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s581/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> A warrant officer who is recommended for retirement under this section and whose retirement is approved by the Secretary concerned shall be retired, under any provision of law under which he is eligible to retire, on the date requested by him and approved by the Secretary concerned, which date shall be not later than the first day of the seventh calendar month beginning after the month in which the Secretary concerned approves the report of the board which recommended the officer for retirement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e35464-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s581/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The retirement of a warrant officer pursuant to this section shall be considered to be an involuntary retirement for purposes of any other provision of law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e35465-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s581/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e35466-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s581/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary concerned shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e35467-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s581/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Such regulations shall require that when the Secretary concerned submits a list of regular warrant officers to a selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s573/c">section 573(c) of this title</ref> to consider regular warrant officers for selection for retirement under this section, the list shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7e35468-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s581/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the name of each warrant officer on the active-duty list in the same grade or same grade and competitive category whose position on the active-duty list is between that of the most junior regular warrant officer in that grade whose name is submitted to the board and that of the most senior regular warrant officer in that grade whose name is submitted to the board; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7e35469-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s581/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> with respect to a group of warrant officers designated under subparagraph (A) who are in a particular grade and competitive category, only those warrant officers in that grade and competitive category who are also in a particular year group or specialty, or any combination thereof determined by the Secretary concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e3546a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s581/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Such regulations shall establish procedures to exclude from consideration by the board any warrant officer who has been approved for voluntary retirement, or who is to be mandatorily retired under any other provision of law, during the fiscal year in which the board is convened or during the following fiscal year. An officer not considered by a selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s573/c">section 573(c) of this title</ref> under such regulations because the officer has been approved for voluntary retirement shall be retired on the date approved for the retirement of such officer as of the convening date of such selection board unless the Secretary concerned approves a modification of such date in order to prevent a personal hardship for the officer or for other humanitarian reasons.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e3546b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s581/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e3546c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s581/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary concerned may defer for not more than three months the retirement of an officer otherwise approved for early retirement under this section in order to prevent a personal hardship to the officer or for other humanitarian reasons. Any such deferral shall be made on a case-by-case basis considering the circumstances of the case of the particular officer concerned. The authority of the Secretary to grant such a deferral may not be delegated.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e3546d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s581/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An officer recommended for early retirement under this section, if approved for deferral under paragraph (1), shall be retired on the date requested by the officer, and approved by the Secretary concerned, which date shall be not later than the first day of the tenth calendar month beginning after the month in which the Secretary concerned approves the report of the board which recommended the officer for early retirement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida7e3546e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/dA/tXI/s1112/a">Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title XI, § 1112(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1500">105 Stat. 1500</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dA/tX/s1052/5">Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1052(5)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2499">106 Stat. 2499</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tV/s541/b/6">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title V, § 541(b)(6)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/2765">108 Stat. 2765</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tV/s504/a">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 504(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/295">110 Stat. 295</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tV">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 501, 502(a), <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3353">128 Stat. 3353</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida7e3546f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida7e35470-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida7e35471-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/s501">Pub. L. 113–291, § 501</ref>, redesignated second sentence of par. (1) as (2) and former par. (2) as (3), and, in par. (2), substituted “the list shall include—” for “the list shall include each”, inserted “(A) the name of each” before “warrant officer on the active-duty list”, substituted “; or” for period at end, and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/s502/a">Pub. L. 113–291, § 502(a)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), substituted “three months” for “90 days”, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106">Pub. L. 104–106</ref> added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/337">Pub. L. 103–337</ref> struck out “in the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps” after “A regular warrant officer”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484">Pub. L. 102–484</ref> substituted “board” for “Board” in two places in first sentence.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida7e35472-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida7e35473-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/337">Pub. L. 103–337</ref> effective on the first day of the fourth month beginning after <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s541/h">section 541(h) of Pub. L. 103–337</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s571">section 571 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="ida7e35474-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1992-02-01">Feb. 1, 1992</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/s1132">section 1132 of Pub. L. 102–190</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1991 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s521">section 521 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
