<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida7e8362e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s612"><num value="612">§ 612.</num><heading> Composition of selection boards</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e8362f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s612/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e83630-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s612/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Members of selection boards shall be appointed by the Secretary of the military department concerned in accordance with this section. A selection board shall consist of five or more officers of the same armed force as the officers under consideration by the board. Each member of a selection board (except as provided in paragraphs (2), (3), and (4)) shall be an officer on the active-duty list. Each member of a selection board must be serving in a grade higher than the grade of the officers under consideration by the board, except that no member of a board may be serving in a grade below major or lieutenant commander. The members of a selection board shall represent the diverse population of the armed force concerned to the extent practicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e83631-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s612/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e83632-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s612/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a selection board shall include at least one officer from each competitive category of officers to be considered by the board.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e83633-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s612/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A selection board need not include an officer from a competitive category to be considered by the board when there are no officers of that competitive category on the active-duty list in a grade higher than the grade of the officers to be considered by the board and eligible to serve on the board. However, in such a case the Secretary of the military department concerned, in his discretion, may appoint as a member of the board an officer of that competitive category who is not on the active-duty list from among officers of the same armed force as the officers under consideration by the board who hold a higher grade than the grade of the officers under consideration and who are retired officers, reserve officers serving on active duty but not on the active-duty list, or members of the Ready Reserve.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e83634-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s612/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> When reserve officers of an armed force are to be considered by a selection board, the membership of the board shall include at least one reserve officer of that armed force on active duty (whether or not on the active-duty list). The actual number of reserve officers shall be determined by the Secretary of the military department concerned, in the Secretary’s discretion. Notwithstanding the first sentence of this paragraph, in the case of a board which is considering officers in the grade of colonel or brigadier general or, in the case of officers of the Navy, captain or rear admiral (lower half), no reserve officer need be included if there are no reserve officers of that armed force on active duty in the next higher grade who are eligible to serve on the board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e83635-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s612/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), if qualified officers on the active-duty list are not available in sufficient number to comprise a selection board, the Secretary of the military department concerned shall complete the membership of the board by appointing as members of the board officers who are members of the same armed force and hold a grade higher than the grade of the officers under consideration by the board and who are retired officers, reserve officers serving on active duty but not on the active-duty list, or members of the Ready Reserve.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e83636-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s612/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> A retired general or flag officer who is on active duty for the purpose of serving on a selection board shall not, while so serving, be counted against any limitation on the number of general and flag officers who may be on active duty.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e83637-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s612/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> No officer may be a member of two successive selection boards convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s611/a">section 611(a) of this title</ref> for the consideration of officers of the same competitive category and grade.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e83638-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s612/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e83639-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s612/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Each selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s611/a">section 611(a) of this title</ref> that will consider an officer described in paragraph (2) shall include at least one officer designated by the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff who is a joint qualified officer.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e8363a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s612/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Paragraph (1) applies with respect to an officer who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7e8363b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s612/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is serving on, or has served on, the Joint Staff; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7e8363c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s612/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is a joint qualified officer.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7e8363d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s612/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of Defense may waive the requirement in paragraph (1) in the case of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7e8363e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s612/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> any selection board of the Marine Corps or the Space Force; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7e8363f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s612/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any selection board that is considering officers in specialties identified in paragraph (2) or (3) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s619a/b">section 619a(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida7e83640-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/96/513/tI/s105">Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2851">94 Stat. 2851</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/97/22/s4/a">Pub. L. 97–22, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-07-10">July 10, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/125">95 Stat. 125</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/86/tIV/s405/b/1">Pub. L. 97–86, title IV, § 405(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1105">95 Stat. 1105</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/145/tV/s514/b/1">Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 514(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/628">99 Stat. 628</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/433/tIV/s402/a">Pub. L. 99–433, title IV, § 402(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1030">100 Stat. 1030</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 504(a)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–101; <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/dA/tV/s522/a">Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 522(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4214">124 Stat. 4214</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tV/s503/a/1">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 503(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3564">134 Stat. 3564</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tV/s521/d/2">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 521(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1881">138 Stat. 1881</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida7e83641-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida7e83642-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida7e83643-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (c)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159">Pub. L. 118–159</ref> inserted “or the Space Force” after “of the Marine Corps”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> inserted at end “The members of a selection board shall represent the diverse population of the armed force concerned to the extent practicable.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383">Pub. L. 111–383</ref> amended subsec. (c) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (c) read as follows: “Each selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s611/a">section 611(a) of this title</ref> that will consider officers who are serving in, or have served in, joint duty assignments shall include at least one officer designated by the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff who is currently serving in a joint duty assignment. The Secretary of Defense may waive the preceding sentence in the case of any selection board of the Marine Corps.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 504(a)(1)], struck out “who are on the active-duty list” after “five or more officers” in second sentence and inserted after second sentence “Each member of a selection board (except as provided in paragraphs (2), (3), and (4)) shall be an officer on the active-duty list.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 504(a)(2)], substituted “of that armed force on active duty (whether or not on the active-duty list). The actual number of reserve officers shall be” for “of that armed force, with the exact number of reserve officers to be” and “the Secretary’s discretion. Notwithstanding the first sentence of this paragraph,” for “his discretion, except that”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/433">Pub. L. 99–433</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/99/145">Pub. L. 99–145</ref> substituted “rear admiral (lower half)” for “commodore”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/97/22/s4/a/1">Pub. L. 97–22, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A), substituted “Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a selection board” for “A selection board”, and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/97/86">Pub. L. 97–86</ref> substituted “commodore” for “commodore admiral”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/97/22/s4/a/2">Pub. L. 97–22, § 4(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “, with the exact number of reserve officers to be determined by the Secretary of the military department concerned in his discretion” after “at least one reserve officer of that armed force” and inserted “who are eligible to serve on the board” after “the next higher grade”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/97/22/s4/a/3">Pub. L. 97–22, § 4(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3)” for “Except as provided in paragraph (3)” and “officers who are members of the same armed force and hold a grade higher than the grade of the officers under consideration by the board and who are retired officers, reserve officers serving on active duty but not on the active-duty list, or members of the Ready Reserve” for “retired officers of the same armed force who hold a retired grade higher than the grade of the officers under consideration by the board” and designated as par. (5) provisions that retired general or flag officers on active duty for the purpose of serving on a selection board not be counted against any limitation on the number of general and flag officers who may be on active duty.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/97/22/s4/a/3">Pub. L. 97–22, § 4(a)(3)</ref>, added par. (5) consisting of provisions, formerly contained in par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/97/22/s4/a/4">Pub. L. 97–22, § 4(a)(4)</ref>, inserted “convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s611/a">section 611(a) of this title</ref>” after “selection boards”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida7e83644-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida7e83645-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2000 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 504(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–102, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to any selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s611/a">section 611(a) of title 10</ref>, United States Code, on or after <date date="1981-08-01">August 1, 1981</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida7e83646-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/433/tIV/s406/f">Pub. L. 99–433, title IV, § 406(f)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1034">100 Stat. 1034</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/433/tIV/s406/f">“The amendments made by section 402 [amending this section and sections 615 and 618 of this title] shall take effect with respect to selection boards convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s611/a">section 611(a) of title 10</ref>, United States Code, after the end of the 120-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida7e83647-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/86">Pub. L. 97–86</ref> effective <date date="1981-09-15">Sept. 15, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/86/s405/f">section 405(f) of Pub. L. 97–86</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="ida7e83648-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1981-09-15">Sept. 15, 1981</date>, but the authority to prescribe regulations under this section effective on <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/513/s701">section 701 of Pub. L. 96–513</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1980 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida7e83649-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Authority To Waive Prohibition on Officers Serving on Successive Selection Boards for Boards To Consider Officers for Promotion to Major General or Rear Admiral</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tV/s507">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title V, § 507</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/859">139 Stat. 859</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tV/s507">“Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of a military department may, during the three-year period following the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>], waive the limitation in section 612(b)(1) [probably should be “612(b)”] of title 10, United States Code, in the case of a selection board that will consider officers for recommendation for promotion to the grade of major general or rear admiral if the Secretary of the military department determines that qualified officers on the active-duty list or Space Force officer list or otherwise authorized to serve on the board are not available in sufficient number to comprise that selection board.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
