<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idaabf7294-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6132"><num value="6132">§ 6132.</num><heading> Long-term plan for meeting national security requirements for unencumbered uranium</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaabf7295-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6132/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than December 31 of each odd-numbered year through 2031, the Secretary of Energy shall submit to the congressional defense committees a plan for meeting national security requirements for unencumbered uranium through 2070.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaabf7296-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6132/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Plan Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The plan required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaabf7297-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6132/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An inventory of unencumbered uranium (other than depleted uranium), by program source and enrichment level, that, as of the date of the plan, is allocated to national security requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaabf7298-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6132/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An inventory of unencumbered uranium (other than depleted uranium), by program source and enrichment level, that, as of the date of the plan, is not allocated to national security requirements but could be allocated to such requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaabf7299-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6132/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> An identification of national security requirements for unencumbered uranium through 2070, by program source and enrichment level.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaabf729a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6132/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> An assessment of current and projected unencumbered uranium production by private industry in the United States that could support future defense requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaabf729b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6132/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> A description of any shortfall in obtaining unencumbered uranium to meet national security requirements and an assessment of whether that shortfall could be mitigated through the blending down of uranium that is of a higher enrichment level.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaabf729c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6132/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> An inventory of unencumbered depleted uranium, an assessment of the portion of that uranium that could be allocated to national security requirements through re-enrichment, and an estimate of the costs of re-enriching that uranium.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaabf729d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6132/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> A description of the swap and barter agreements involving unencumbered uranium needed to meet national security requirements that are in effect on the date of the plan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaabf729e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6132/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><chapeau> An assessment of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaabf729f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6132/b/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> when additional enrichment of uranium will be required to meet national security requirements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaabf72a0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6132/b/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the options the Secretary is considering to meet such requirements, including an estimated cost and timeline for each option and a description of any changes to policy or law that the Secretary determines would be required for each option.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaabf72a1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6132/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> An assessment of how options to provide additional enriched uranium to meet national security requirements could, as an additional benefit, contribute to the establishment of a sustained domestic enrichment capacity and allow the commercial sector of the United States to reduce reliance on importing uranium from adversary countries.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaabf72a2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6132/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Form of Plan</inline>.—</heading><content>The plan required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaabf72a3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6132/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Comptroller General Briefing</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the congressional defense committees receive each plan under subsection (a), the Comptroller General of the United States shall provide to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate a briefing that includes an assessment of the plan.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaabf72a4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6132/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaabf72a5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6132/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “depleted”, with respect to uranium, means that the uranium is depleted in uranium-235 compared with natural uranium.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaabf72a6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6132/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “unencumbered”, with respect to uranium, means that the United States has no obligation to foreign governments to use the uranium for only peaceful purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idaabf72a7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dC/tXXXI/s3111/a">Pub. L. 119–60, div. C, title XXXI, § 3111(a)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1367">139 Stat. 1367</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idaabf72a8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idaabf72a9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idaabf72aa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2538c">section 2538c of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s3111/b/1">Pub. L. 119–60, § 3111(b)(1)</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
