<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idaac1e348-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153"><num value="6153">§ 6153.</num><heading> Disposition of weapons-usable plutonium at Savannah River Site</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e349-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Plan for Construction and Operation of MOX Facility</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e34a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not later than <date date="2003-02-01">February 1, 2003</date>, the Secretary of Energy shall submit to Congress a plan for the construction and operation of the MOX facility at the Savannah River Site, Aiken, South Carolina.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e34b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The plan under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e34c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a schedule for construction and operations so as to achieve, as of <date date="2012-01-01">January 1, 2012</date>, and thereafter, the MOX production objective, and to produce 1 metric ton of mixed-oxide fuel by <date date="2012-12-31">December 31, 2012</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e34d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a schedule of operations of the MOX facility designed so that 34 metric tons of defense plutonium and defense plutonium materials at the Savannah River Site will be processed into mixed-oxide fuel by <date date="2019-01-01">January 1, 2019</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e34e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e34f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Not later than February 15 each year, beginning in 2004 and continuing through 2024, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation of the plan required by paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e350-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Each report under subparagraph (A) for years before 2010 shall include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e351-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/a/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> an assessment of compliance with the schedules included with the plan under paragraph (2); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e352-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/a/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a certification by the Secretary whether or not the MOX production objective can be met by January 2012.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e353-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> Each report under subparagraph (A) for years after 2014 shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e354-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/a/3/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> address whether the MOX production objective has been met; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e355-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/a/3/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> assess progress toward meeting the obligations of the United States under the Plutonium Management and Disposition Agreement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e356-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/a/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> Each report under subparagraph (A) for years after 2019 shall also include an assessment of compliance with the MOX production objective and, if not in compliance, the plan of the Secretary for achieving one of the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e357-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/a/3/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Compliance with such objective.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e358-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/a/3/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Removal of all remaining defense plutonium and defense plutonium materials from the State of South Carolina.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e359-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Corrective Actions</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e35a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If a report under subsection (a)(3) indicates that construction or operation of the MOX facility is behind the applicable schedule under subsection (g) by 12 months or more, the Secretary shall submit to Congress, not later than August 15 of the year in which such report is submitted, a plan for corrective actions to be implemented by the Secretary to ensure that the MOX facility project is capable of meeting the MOX production objective.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e35b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If a plan is submitted under paragraph (1) in any year after 2008, the plan shall include corrective actions to be implemented by the Secretary to ensure that the MOX production objective is met.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e35c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Any plan for corrective actions under paragraph (1) or (2) shall include established milestones under such plan for achieving compliance with the MOX production objective.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e35d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> If, before <date date="2012-01-01">January 1, 2012</date>, the Secretary determines that there is a substantial and material risk that the MOX production objective will not be achieved by 2012 because of a failure to achieve milestones set forth in the most recent corrective action plan under this subsection, the Secretary shall suspend further transfers of defense plutonium and defense plutonium materials to be processed by the MOX facility until such risk is addressed and the Secretary certifies that the MOX production objective can be met by 2012.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e35e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> If, after <date date="2014-01-01">January 1, 2014</date>, the Secretary determines that the MOX production objective has not been achieved because of a failure to achieve milestones set forth in the most recent corrective action plan under this subsection, the Secretary shall suspend further transfers of defense plutonium and defense plutonium materials to be processed by the MOX facility until the Secretary certifies that the MOX production objective can be met.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e35f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e360-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/b/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Upon making a determination under paragraph (4) or (5), the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the options for removing from the State of South Carolina an amount of defense plutonium or defense plutonium materials equal to the amount of defense plutonium or defense plutonium materials transferred to the State of South Carolina after <date date="2002-04-15">April 15, 2002</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e361-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/b/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Each report under subparagraph (A) shall include an analysis of each option set forth in the report, including the cost and schedule for implementation of such option, and any requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.) relating to consideration or selection of such option.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e362-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/b/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Upon submittal of a report under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall commence any analysis that may be required under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 in order to select among the options set forth in the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e363-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contingent Requirement for Removal of Plutonium and Materials From Savannah River Site</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If the MOX production objective is not achieved as of <date date="2014-01-01">January 1, 2014</date>, the Secretary shall, consistent with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.) and other applicable laws, remove from the State of South Carolina, for storage or disposal elsewhere—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e364-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> not later than <date date="2016-01-01">January 1, 2016</date>, not less than 1 metric ton of defense plutonium or defense plutonium materials; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e365-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> not later than <date date="2022-01-01">January 1, 2022</date>, an amount of defense plutonium or defense plutonium materials equal to the amount of defense plutonium or defense plutonium materials transferred to the Savannah River Site between <date date="2002-04-15">April 15, 2002</date>, and <date date="2022-01-01">January 1, 2022</date>, but not processed by the MOX facility.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e366-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Economic and Impact Assistance</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e367-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> If the MOX production objective is not achieved as of <date date="2016-01-01">January 1, 2016</date>, the Secretary shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, pay to the State of South Carolina each year beginning on or after that date through 2021 for economic and impact assistance an amount equal to $1,000,000 per day, not to exceed $100,000,000 per year, until the later of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e368-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the date on which the MOX production objective is achieved in such year; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e369-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the date on which the Secretary has removed from the State of South Carolina in such year at least 1 metric ton of defense plutonium or defense plutonium materials.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e36a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e36b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> If, as of <date date="2022-01-01">January 1, 2022</date>, the MOX facility has not processed mixed-oxide fuel from defense plutonium and defense plutonium materials in the amount of not less than—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e36c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/d/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> one metric ton, in each of any two consecutive calendar years; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e36d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/d/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> three metric tons total,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Secretary shall, from funds available to the Secretary, pay to the State of South Carolina for economic and impact assistance an amount equal to $1,000,000 per day, not to exceed $100,000,000 per year, until the removal by the Secretary from the State of South Carolina of an amount of defense plutonium or defense plutonium materials equal to the amount of defense plutonium or defense plutonium materials transferred to the Savannah River Site between <date date="2002-04-15">April 15, 2002</date>, and <date date="2022-01-01">January 1, 2022</date>, but not processed by the MOX facility.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e36e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to terminate, supersede, or otherwise affect any other requirements of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e36f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If the State of South Carolina obtains an injunction that prohibits the Department of Energy from taking any action necessary for the Department to meet any deadline specified by this subsection, that deadline shall be extended for a period of time equal to the period of time during which the injunction is in effect.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e370-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Failure to Complete Planned Disposition Program</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If less than 34 metric tons of defense plutonium or defense plutonium materials have been processed by the MOX facility by <date date="2026-10-01">October 1, 2026</date>, the Secretary shall, not later than <date date="2026-12-01">December 1, 2026</date>, and on a biennial basis thereafter, submit to Congress a plan for—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e371-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> completing the processing of 34 metric tons of defense plutonium and defense plutonium material by the MOX facility; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e372-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> removing from the State of South Carolina an amount of defense plutonium or defense plutonium materials equal to the amount of defense plutonium or defense plutonium materials transferred to the Savannah River Site after <date date="2002-04-15">April 15, 2002</date>, but not processed by the MOX facility.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e373-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Removal of Mixed-oxide Fuel Upon Completion of Operations of MOX Facility</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If, one year after the date on which operation of the MOX facility permanently ceases, any mixed-oxide fuel remains at the Savannah River Site, the Secretary shall submit to Congress—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e374-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a report on when such fuel will be transferred for use in commercial nuclear reactors; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e375-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a plan for removing such fuel from the State of South Carolina.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e376-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Baseline</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2006-12-31">December 31, 2006</date>, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the construction and operation of the MOX facility that includes a schedule for revising the requirements of this section during fiscal year 2007 to conform with the schedule established by the Secretary for the MOX facility, which shall be based on estimated funding levels for the fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e377-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e378-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “MOX production objective” means production at the MOX facility of mixed-oxide fuel from defense plutonium and defense plutonium materials at an average rate equivalent to not less than one metric ton of mixed-oxide fuel per year. The average rate shall be determined by measuring production at the MOX facility from the date the facility is declared operational to the Nuclear Regulatory Commission through the date of assessment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e379-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “MOX facility” means the mixed-oxide fuel fabrication facility at the Savannah River Site, Aiken, South Carolina.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e37a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6153/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The terms “defense plutonium” and “defense plutonium materials” mean weapons-usable plutonium.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idaac1e37b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added and amended <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dC/tXXXI/s3111/a">Pub. L. 119–60, div. C, title XXXI, § 3111(a)</ref>, (d)(2), <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1373">139 Stat. 1373</ref>, 1462.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idaac1e37c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idaac1e37d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idaac1e37e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, referred to in subsecs. (b)(6)(B), (C) and (c), is <ref href="/us/pl/91/190">Pub. L. 91–190</ref>, <date date="1970-01-01">Jan. 1, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/852">83 Stat. 852</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 55 (§ 4321 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">section 4321 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idaac1e37f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 6153 was enumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s8264">section 8264 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2566">section 2566 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s3111/b/1">Pub. L. 119–60, § 3111(b)(1)</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idaac1e380-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—<ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s3111/d/2/B">Pub. L. 119–60, § 3111(d)(2)(B)</ref>, realigned margins.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s3111/d/2/A">Pub. L. 119–60, § 3111(d)(2)(A)</ref>, struck out pars. (1) to (3) headings which corresponded to the defined term in each par.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
