<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idaac1e395-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155"><num value="6155">§ 6155.</num><heading> Acceleration of removal or security of fissile materials, radiological materials, and related equipment at vulnerable sites worldwide</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e396-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sense of Congress</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e397-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> It is the sense of Congress that the security, including the rapid removal or secure storage, of high-risk, proliferation-attractive fissile materials, radiological materials, and related equipment at vulnerable sites worldwide should be a top priority among the activities to achieve the national security of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e398-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> It is the sense of Congress that the President may establish in the Department of Energy a task force to be known as the Task Force on Nuclear Materials to carry out the program authorized by subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e399-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program Authorized</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Energy may carry out a program to undertake an accelerated, comprehensive worldwide effort to mitigate the threats posed by high-risk, proliferation-attractive fissile materials, radiological materials, and related equipment located at sites potentially vulnerable to theft or diversion.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e39a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program Elements</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e39b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Activities under the program under subsection (b) may include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e39c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Accelerated efforts to secure, remove, or eliminate proliferation-attractive fissile materials or radiological materials in research reactors, other reactors, and other facilities worldwide.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e39d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Arrangements for the secure shipment of proliferation-attractive fissile materials, radiological materials, and related equipment to other countries willing to accept such materials and equipment, or to the United States if such countries cannot be identified, and the provision of secure storage or disposition of such materials and equipment following shipment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e39e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The transportation of proliferation-attractive fissile materials, radiological materials, and related equipment from sites identified as proliferation risks to secure facilities in other countries or in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e39f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/c/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The processing and packaging of proliferation-attractive fissile materials, radiological materials, and related equipment in accordance with required standards for transport, storage, and disposition.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e3a0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/c/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> The provision of interim security upgrades for vulnerable, proliferation-attractive fissile materials, radiological materials, and related equipment pending their removal from their current sites.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e3a1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/c/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> The utilization of funds to upgrade security and accounting at sites where proliferation-attractive fissile materials or radiological materials will remain for an extended period of time in order to ensure that such materials are secure against plausible potential threats and will remain so in the future.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e3a2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/c/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> The management of proliferation-attractive fissile materials, radiological materials, and related equipment at secure facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e3a3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/c/1/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> Actions to ensure that security, including security upgrades at sites and facilities for the storage or disposition of proliferation-attractive fissile materials, radiological materials, and related equipment, continues to function as intended.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e3a4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/c/1/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> The provision of technical support to the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA), other countries, and other entities to facilitate removal of, and security upgrades to facilities that contain, proliferation-attractive fissile materials, radiological materials, and related equipment worldwide.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e3a5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/c/1/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><content> The development of alternative fuels and irradiation targets based on low-enriched uranium to convert research or other reactors fueled by highly-enriched uranium to such alternative fuels, as well as the conversion of reactors and irradiation targets employing highly-enriched uranium to employment of such alternative fuels and targets.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e3a6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/c/1/K"><num value="K">(K)</num><content> Accelerated actions for the blend down of highly-enriched uranium to low-enriched uranium.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e3a7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/c/1/L"><num value="L">(L)</num><content> The provision of assistance in the closure and decommissioning of sites identified as presenting risks of proliferation of proliferation-attractive fissile materials, radiological materials, and related equipment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e3a8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/c/1/M"><num value="M">(M)</num><chapeau> Programs to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaac1e3a9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/c/1/M/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> assist in the placement of employees displaced as a result of actions pursuant to the program in enterprises not representing a proliferation threat; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaac1e3aa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/c/1/M/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> convert (including through the use of alternative technologies) sites identified as presenting risks of proliferation regarding proliferation-attractive fissile materials, radiological materials, and related equipment to purposes not representing a proliferation threat to the extent necessary to eliminate the proliferation threat.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e3ab-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary of Energy shall, in coordination with the Secretary of State, carry out the program in consultation with, and with the assistance of, appropriate departments, agencies, and other entities of the United States Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e3ac-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary of Energy shall, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, carry out activities under the program in collaboration with such foreign governments, non-governmental organizations, and other international entities as the Secretary of Energy considers appropriate for the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e3ad-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading><content>Amounts authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Energy for defense nuclear nonproliferation activities shall be available for purposes of the program under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e3ae-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Participation by Other Governments and Organizations</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e3af-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Energy may, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, enter into one or more agreements with any person (including a foreign government, international organization, or multinational entity) that the Secretary of Energy considers appropriate under which the person contributes funds for purposes of the programs described in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e3b0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The programs described in this paragraph are any programs within the Office of Defense Nuclear Nonproliferation of the National Nuclear Security Administration.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e3b1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3302">section 3302 of title 31</ref>, the Secretary of Energy may retain and use amounts contributed under an agreement under paragraph (1) for purposes of the programs described in paragraph (2). Amounts so contributed shall be retained in a separate fund established in the Treasury for such purposes and shall be available for use without further appropriation and without fiscal year limitation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e3b2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> If an amount contributed under an agreement under paragraph (1) is not used under this subsection within 5 years after it was contributed, the Secretary of Energy shall return that amount to the person who contributed it.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e3b3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> Not later than October 31 of each year, the Secretary of Energy shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the receipt and use of amounts under this subsection during the preceding fiscal year. Each report for a fiscal year shall set forth—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e3b4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/e/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a statement of any amounts received under this subsection, including, for each such amount, the value of the contribution and the person who contributed it;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e3b5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/e/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a statement of any amounts used under this subsection, including, for each such amount, the purposes for which the amount was used; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e3b6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/e/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a statement of the amounts retained but not used under this subsection, including, for each such amount, the purposes (if known) for which the Secretary intends to use the amount.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac1e3b7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e3b8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “fissile materials” means plutonium, highly-enriched uranium, or other material capable of sustaining an explosive nuclear chain reaction, including irradiated items containing such materials if the radiation field from such items is not sufficient to prevent the theft or misuse of such items.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e3b9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “radiological materials” includes Americium-241, Californium-252, Cesium-137, Cobalt-60, Iridium-192, Plutonium-238, Radium-226, Strontium-90, Curium-244, and irradiated items containing such materials, or other materials designated by the Secretary of Energy for purposes of this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e3ba-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “related equipment” includes equipment useful for enrichment of uranium in the isotope 235 and for extraction of fissile materials from irradiated fuel rods and other equipment designated by the Secretary of Energy for purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e3bb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The term “highly-enriched uranium” means uranium enriched to or above 20 percent in the isotope 235.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e3bc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/f/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The term “low-enriched uranium” means uranium enriched below 20 percent in the isotope 235.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e3bd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/f/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The term “proliferation-attractive”, in the case of fissile materials and radiological materials, means quantities and types of such materials that are determined by the Secretary of Energy to present a significant risk to the national security of the United States if diverted to a use relating to proliferation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac1e3be-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6155/f/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The term “alternative technologies” means technologies, such as accelerator-based equipment, that do not use radiological materials.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idaac1e3bf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added and amended <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dC/tXXXI/s3111/a">Pub. L. 119–60, div. C, title XXXI, § 3111(a)</ref>, (d)(2), <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1377">139 Stat. 1377</ref>, 1462.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idaac1e3c0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idaac1e3c1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idaac1e3c2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 6155 was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s8266">section 8266 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2569">section 2569 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s3111/b/1">Pub. L. 119–60, § 3111(b)(1)</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idaac1e3c3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—<ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s3111/d/2/B">Pub. L. 119–60, § 3111(d)(2)(B)</ref>, realigned margins.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s3111/d/2/A">Pub. L. 119–60, § 3111(d)(2)(A)</ref>, struck out pars. (1) to (5) headings which read as follows: “<inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>”, “<inline class="small-caps">Programs covered</inline>”, “<inline class="small-caps">Retention and use of amounts</inline>”, “<inline class="small-caps">Return of amounts not used within </inline>5<inline class="small-caps"> years</inline>”, and “<inline class="small-caps">Annual report</inline>”, respectively.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
