<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida7ea7fb6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618"><num value="618">§ 618.</num><heading> Action on reports of selection boards</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ea7fb7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ea7fb8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Upon receipt of the report of a selection board submitted to him under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s617/a">section 617(a) of this title</ref>, the Secretary of the military department concerned shall review the report to determine whether the board has acted contrary to law or regulation or to guidelines furnished the board under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s615/b">section 615(b) of this title</ref>. Following such review, unless the Secretary concerned makes a determination as described in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall submit the report as required by subsection (b) or (c), as appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ea7fb9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If, on the basis of a review of the report under paragraph (1), the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that the board acted contrary to law or regulation or to guidelines furnished the board under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s615/b">section 615(b) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall return the report, together with a written explanation of the basis for such determination, to the board for further proceedings. Upon receipt of a report returned by the Secretary concerned under this paragraph, the selection board (or a subsequent selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s611/a">section 611(a) of this title</ref> for the same grade and competitive category) shall conduct such proceedings as may be necessary in order to revise the report to be consistent with law, regulation, and such guidelines and shall resubmit the report, as revised, to the Secretary in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s617">section 617 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ea7fba-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ea7fbb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> After completing the requirements of subsection (a), the Secretary concerned, in the case of the report of a selection board that considered officers who are serving on, or have served on, the Joint Staff or are joint qualified officers, shall submit the report to the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ea7fbc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Chairman, in accordance with guidelines furnished to the Chairman by the Secretary of Defense, shall review the report for the purpose of determining if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ea7fbd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the selection board acted consistent with the guidelines of the Secretary of Defense under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s615/c">section 615(c) of this title</ref> to ensure that selection boards give appropriate consideration to the performance of officers who are serving on, or have served on, the Joint Staff or are joint qualified officers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ea7fbe-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the selection board otherwise gave appropriate consideration to the performance of officers who are serving on, or have served on, the Joint Staff or are joint qualified officers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ea7fbf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> After reviewing the report, the Chairman shall return the report, with his determinations and comments, to the Secretary concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ea7fc0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> If the Chairman determines that the board acted contrary to the guidelines of the Secretary of Defense under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s615/c">section 615(c) of this title</ref> or otherwise failed to give appropriate consideration to the performance of officers who are serving on, or have served on, the Joint Staff or are joint qualified officers, the Secretary concerned may—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ea7fc1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> return the report, together with the Chairman’s determinations and comments, to the selection board (or a subsequent selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s611/a">section 611(a) of this title</ref> for the same grade and competitive category) for further proceedings in accordance with subsection (a);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ea7fc2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> convene a special selection board in the manner provided for under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s628">section 628 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ea7fc3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/b/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> take other appropriate action to satisfy the concerns of the Chairman.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ea7fc4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> If, after completion of all actions taken under paragraph (4), the Secretary concerned and the Chairman remain in disagreement with respect to the report of a selection board, the Secretary concerned shall indicate such disagreement, and the reasons for such disagreement, as part of his transmittal of the report of the selection board to the Secretary of Defense under subsection (c). Such transmittal shall include any comments submitted by the Chairman.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ea7fc5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ea7fc6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> After his final review of the report of a selection board, the Secretary concerned shall submit the report, with his recommendations thereon, to the Secretary of Defense for transmittal to the President for his approval or disapproval. The Secretary of Defense shall, before transmitting the report of a selection board to the President, take appropriate action to resolve any disagreement between the Secretary concerned and the Chairman transmitted to him under subsection (b)(5). If the authority of the President under this paragraph to approve or disapprove the report of a selection board is delegated to the Secretary of Defense, it may not be redelegated except to an official in the Office of the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ea7fc7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If the report of a selection board names an officer as having a record which indicates that the officer should be required to show cause for his retention on active duty, the Secretary concerned may provide for the review of the record of that officer as provided for under regulations prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1181">section 1181 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ea7fc8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ea7fc9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the name of an officer recommended for promotion by a selection board may be removed from the report of the selection board only by the President.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ea7fca-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In the case of an officer recommended by a selection board for promotion to a grade below brigadier general or rear admiral (lower half), the name of the officer may also be removed from the report of the selection board by the Secretary of Defense or the Deputy Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ea7fcb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of Defense shall notify the congressional defense committees of the removal of the name of an officer from the report of a selection board by the President or the Secretary or Deputy Secretary of Defense under paragraph (1) or paragraph (2), respectively, for any reason other than misconduct—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ea7fcc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> not later than 30 days after the name of an officer is removed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ea7fcd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> prior to submission to the Senate of a promotion list with respect to such report pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s624/c">section 624(c) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ea7fce-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ea7fcf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The names of the officers recommended for promotion in the report of a selection board shall be disseminated to the armed force concerned as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ea7fd0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In the case of officers recommended for promotion to a grade below brigadier general or rear admiral (lower half), such names may be disseminated upon, or at any time after, the transmittal of the report to the President.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ea7fd1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In the case of officers recommended for promotion to a grade above colonel or, in the case of the Navy, captain, such names may be disseminated upon, or at any time after, the approval of the report by the President.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ea7fd2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> In the case of officers whose names have not been sooner disseminated, such names shall be promptly disseminated upon confirmation by the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ea7fd3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> A list of names of officers disseminated under paragraph (1) may not include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ea7fd4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> any name removed by the President from the report of the selection board containing that name, if dissemination is under the authority of subparagraph (B) of such paragraph; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ea7fd5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the name of any officer whose promotion the Senate failed to confirm, if dissemination is under the authority of subparagraph (C) of such paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" status="repealed" id="ida7ea7fd6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/f"><num value="f">[(f)</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tV/s547/a/2">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 547(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2216">120 Stat. 2216</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ea7fd7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s618/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> If the Secretary of a military department or the Secretary of Defense makes a recommendation under this section that the name of an officer be removed from a report of a selection board and the recommendation is accompanied by information that was not presented to that selection board, that information shall be made available to that officer. The officer shall then be afforded a reasonable opportunity to submit comments on that information to the officials making the recommendation and the officials reviewing the recommendation. If an eligible officer cannot be given access to such information because of its classification status, the officer shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be provided with an appropriate summary of the information.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida7ea7fd8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/96/513/tI/s105">Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2853">94 Stat. 2853</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/98/525/tV/s524/a">Pub. L. 98–525, title V, § 524(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2524">98 Stat. 2524</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/433/tIV/s402/c">Pub. L. 99–433, title IV, § 402(c)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1030">100 Stat. 1030</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/456/dA/tV/s501/d">Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title V, § 501(d)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1966">102 Stat. 1966</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/dA/tV/s504/c">Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title V, § 504(c)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1357">105 Stat. 1357</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dA/tX/s1052/8">Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1052(8)</ref>, (9), <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2499">106 Stat. 2499</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 503(a)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–100; <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tV">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 513(a), 547(a)(2), <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2184">120 Stat. 2184</ref>, 2216; <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/dA/tV/s522/c">Pub. L. 111–383, div. A, title V, § 522(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4215">124 Stat. 4215</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tV/s503/a/1">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title V, § 503(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/855">139 Stat. 855</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida7ea7fd9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida7ea7fda-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida7ea7fdb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60">Pub. L. 119–60</ref> added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s522/c/1">Pub. L. 111–383, § 522(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “are serving on, or have served on, the Joint Staff or are joint qualified officers” for “are serving, or have served, in joint duty assignments”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s522/c/2">Pub. L. 111–383, § 522(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “of officers who are serving on, or have served on, the Joint Staff or are joint qualified officers” for “in joint duty assignments of officers who are serving, or have served, in such assignments” in subpars. (A) and (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/111/383/s522/c/3">Pub. L. 111–383, § 522(c)(3)</ref>, substituted “who are serving on, or have served on, the Joint Staff or are joint qualified officers” for “in joint duty assignments” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s513/a">Pub. L. 109–364, § 513(a)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), substituted “Except as provided in paragraph (2), the name” for “The name”, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/s547/a/2">Pub. L. 109–364, § 547(a)(2)</ref>, struck out subsec. (f) which read as follows: “Except as authorized or required by this section, proceedings of a selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s611/a">section 611(a) of this title</ref> may not be disclosed to any person not a member of the board.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/106/398">Pub. L. 106–398</ref> amended subsec. (e) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (e) read as follows: “Upon approval by the President of the report of a selection board, the names of the officers recommended for promotion by the selection board (other than any name removed by the President) may be disseminated to the armed force concerned. If such names have not been sooner disseminated, such names (other than the name of any officer whose promotion the Senate failed to confirm) shall be promptly disseminated to the armed force concerned upon confirmation by the Senate.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a)(1), (2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s1052/8">Pub. L. 102–484, § 1052(8)</ref>, substituted “section 615(b)” for “section 615(a)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(A), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/s1052/9">Pub. L. 102–484, § 1052(9)</ref>, substituted “section 615(c)” for “section 615(b)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/102/190">Pub. L. 102–190</ref> added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/456/s501/d/1">Pub. L. 100–456, § 501(d)(1)</ref>, amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) read as follows: “If, after reviewing the report of a selection board submitted to him under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s617/a">section 617(a) of this title</ref>, the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that the board has acted contrary to law or regulation, the Secretary shall return the report to the board for further proceedings. Upon receipt of a report returned by the Secretary concerned under this subsection, the selection board (or a subsequent selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s611/a">section 611(a) of this title</ref> for the same grade and competitive category) shall conduct such proceedings as may be necessary in order to revise the report and shall resubmit the report, as revised, to the Secretary in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s617">section 617 of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/456/s501/d/2">Pub. L. 100–456, § 501(d)(2)</ref>, struck out “, modification,” after “for his approval” and inserted at end “If the authority of the President under this paragraph to approve or disapprove the report of a selection board is delegated to the Secretary of Defense, it may not be redelegated except to an official in the Office of the Secretary of Defense.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/433/s402/c/1">Pub. L. 99–433, § 402(c)(1)</ref>, (2), added subsec. (b). Former subsec. (b) redesignated (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/433/s402/c/1">Pub. L. 99–433, § 402(c)(1)</ref>, (3), redesignated subsec. (b) as (c) and in par. (1) inserted provisions directing the Secretary of Defense, before transmitting the report, to take appropriate action to resolve any disagreement between the Secretary concerned and the Chairman. Former subsec. (c) redesignated (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d) to (f). <ref href="/us/pl/99/433/s402/c/1">Pub. L. 99–433, § 402(c)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (c) to (e) as (d) to (f), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/525">Pub. L. 98–525</ref> substituted “If the report of a selection board names an officer as having a record which indicates that the officer should be required to show cause for his retention on active duty, the Secretary concerned may provide for the review of the record of that officer as provided for under regulations prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1181">section 1181 of this title</ref>” for “The Secretary concerned may submit to a board of officers convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1181">section 1181 of this title</ref> the name of any officer who is named in the report of a selection board as having a record which indicates that the officer should be required to show cause for his retention on active duty”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida7ea7fdc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida7ea7fdd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2006 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tV/s513/c">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 513(c)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2185">120 Stat. 2185</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tV/s513/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s14111">section 14111 of this title</ref>] shall apply with respect to selection boards convened on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida7ea7fde-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1991 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/190">Pub. L. 102–190</ref> applicable to selection boards convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s611/a">section 611(a) of this title</ref> after end of 60-day period beginning <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/s504/e">section 504(e) of Pub. L. 102–190</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s615">section 615 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida7ea7fdf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/456">Pub. L. 100–456</ref> effective 60 days after <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, and applicable with respect to selection boards convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s611/a">section 611(a) of this title</ref> on or after that effective date, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/456/s501/e">section 501(e) of Pub. L. 100–456</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s615">section 615 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida7ea7fe0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/433">Pub. L. 99–433</ref> effective with respect to selection boards convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s611/a">section 611(a) of this title</ref> after end of 120-day period beginning on <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/433/s406/f">section 406(f) of Pub. L. 99–433</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s612">section 612 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="ida7ea7fe1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1981-09-15">Sept. 15, 1981</date>, but the authority to prescribe regulations under this section effective on <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/513/s701">section 701 of Pub. L. 96–513</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1980 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="ida7ea7fe2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="ida7ea7fe3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of President under subsec. (b)(1) to approve, modify, or disapprove report of a selection board delegated to Secretary of Defense to perform, without approval, ratification, or other action by President, and with authority for Secretary to redelegate, see Ex. Ord. No. 12396, §§ 1(a), 3, <date date="1982-12-09">Dec. 9, 1982</date>, 47 F.R. 55897, 55898, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of Title 3</ref>, The President.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Nothing in section 1 of Ex. Ord. No. 12396 deemed to delegate authority vested in President by subsec. (c) of this section to remove a name from a selection board report, see section 1(g) of Ex. Ord. No. 12396.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
