<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idaac42e0f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192"><num value="6192">§ 6192.</num><heading> Defense site acceleration completion</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac42e10-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding the provisions of the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10101">42 U.S.C. 10101</ref> et seq.), the requirements of section 202 of the Energy Reorganization Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5842">42 U.S.C. 5842</ref>), and other laws that define classes of radioactive waste, with respect to material stored at a Department of Energy site at which activities are regulated by a covered State pursuant to approved closure plans or permits issued by the State, the term “high-level radioactive waste” does not include radioactive waste resulting from the reprocessing of spent nuclear fuel that the Secretary of Energy (in this section referred to as the “Secretary”), in consultation with the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (in this section referred to as the “Commission”), determines—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac42e11-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> does not require permanent isolation in a deep geologic repository for spent fuel or high-level radioactive waste;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac42e12-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> has had highly radioactive radionuclides removed to the maximum extent practical; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac42e13-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac42e14-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> does not exceed concentration limits for Class C low-level waste as set out in section 61.55 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations, and will be disposed of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaac42e15-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/a/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> in compliance with the performance objectives set out in subpart C of part 61 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaac42e16-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/a/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> pursuant to a State-approved closure plan or State-issued permit, authority for the approval or issuance of which is conferred on the State outside of this section; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac42e17-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> exceeds concentration limits for Class C low-level waste as set out in section 61.55 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations, but will be disposed of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaac42e18-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/a/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> in compliance with the performance objectives set out in subpart C of part 61 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaac42e19-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/a/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> pursuant to a State-approved closure plan or State-issued permit, authority for the approval or issuance of which is conferred on the State outside of this section; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaac42e1a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/a/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> pursuant to plans developed by the Secretary in consultation with the Commission.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac42e1b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Monitoring by Nuclear Regulatory Commission</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac42e1c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Commission shall, in coordination with the covered State, monitor disposal actions taken by the Department of Energy pursuant to subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(3) for the purpose of assessing compliance with the performance objectives set out in subpart C of part 61 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac42e1d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> If the Commission considers any disposal actions taken by the Department of Energy pursuant to those subparagraphs to be not in compliance with those performance objectives, the Commission shall, as soon as practicable after discovery of the noncompliant conditions, inform the Department of Energy, the covered State, and the following congressional committees:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac42e1e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac42e1f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, the Committee on Environment and Public Works, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac42e20-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> For fiscal year 2005, the Secretary shall, from amounts available for defense site acceleration completion, reimburse the Commission for all expenses, including salaries, that the Commission incurs as a result of performance under subsection (a) and this subsection for fiscal year 2005. The Department of Energy and the Commission may enter into an interagency agreement that specifies the method of reimbursement. Amounts received by the Commission for performance under subsection (a) and this subsection may be retained and used for salaries and expenses associated with those activities, notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3302">section 3302 of title 31</ref>, and shall remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac42e21-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> For fiscal years after 2005, the Commission shall include in the budget justification materials submitted to Congress in support of the Commission budget for that fiscal year (as submitted with the budget of the President under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105/a">section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>) the amounts required, not offset by revenues, for performance under subsection (a) and this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac42e22-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inapplicability to Certain Materials</inline>.—</heading><content>Subsection (a) shall not apply to any material otherwise covered by that subsection that is transported from the covered State.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac42e23-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered States</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this section, the following States are covered States:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac42e24-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The State of South Carolina.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac42e25-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The State of Idaho.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac42e26-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Construction</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac42e27-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Nothing in this section shall impair, alter, or modify the full implementation of any Federal Facility Agreement and Consent Order or other applicable consent decree for a Department of Energy site.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac42e28-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Nothing in this section establishes any precedent or is binding on the State of Washington, the State of Oregon, or any other State not covered by subsection (d) for the management, storage, treatment, and disposition of radioactive and hazardous materials.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac42e29-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Nothing in this section amends the definition of “transuranic waste” or regulations for repository disposal of transuranic waste pursuant to the Waste Isolation Pilot Plant Land Withdrawal Act (<ref href="/us/pl/102/579">Public Law 102–579</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/106/4777">106 Stat. 4777</ref>) or part 191 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac42e2a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect in any way the obligations of the Department of Energy to comply with section 6154.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac42e2b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Nothing in this section amends the West Valley Demonstration Act <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002140">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002140"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> (<ref href="/us/pl/96/368">Public Law 96–368</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2021a">42 U.S.C. 2021a</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac42e2c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Judicial Review</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Judicial review shall be available in accordance with chapter 7 of title 5, for the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac42e2d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any determination made by the Secretary or any other agency action taken by the Secretary pursuant to this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaac42e2e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6192/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any failure of the Commission to carry out its responsibilities under subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idaac42e2f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dC/tXXXI/s3111/a">Pub. L. 119–60, div. C, title XXXI, § 3111(a)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1395">139 Stat. 1395</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idaac42e30-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idaac42e31-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idaac42e32-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/97/425">Pub. L. 97–425</ref>, <date date="1983-01-07">Jan. 7, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2201">96 Stat. 2201</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 108 (§ 10101 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10101">section 10101 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Waste Isolation Pilot Plant Land Withdrawal Act, referred to in subsec. (e)(3), is <ref href="/us/pl/102/579">Pub. L. 102–579</ref>, <date date="1992-10-30">Oct. 30, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4777">106 Stat. 4777</ref>, which is not classified to the Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The West Valley Demonstration Act, referred to in subsec. (e)(5), probably means the West Valley Demonstration Project Act, <ref href="/us/pl/96/368">Pub. L. 96–368</ref>, <date date="1980-10-01">Oct. 1, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1347">94 Stat. 1347</ref>, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2021a">section 2021a of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idaac42e33-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/s3116">section 3116 of Pub. L. 108–375</ref>, which was set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2602">section 2602 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s3111/b/16">Pub. L. 119–60, § 3111(b)(16)</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
