<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idaac90f11-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6244"><num value="6244">§ 6244.</num><heading> Authority to provide certificate of commendation to Department of Energy and contractor employees for exemplary service in stockpile stewardship and security</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac90f12-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6244/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority to Present Certificate of Commendation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Energy may present a certificate of commendation to any current or former employee of the Department of Energy, and any current or former employee of a Department contractor, whose service to the Department in matters relating to stockpile stewardship and security assisted the Department in furthering the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac90f13-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6244/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certificate</inline>.—</heading><content>The certificate of commendation presented to a current or former employee under subsection (a) shall include an appropriate citation of the service of the current or former employee described in that subsection, including a citation for dedication, intellect, and sacrifice in furthering the national security interests of the United States by maintaining a strong, safe, and viable United States nuclear deterrent during the cold war or thereafter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaac90f14-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6244/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Department of Energy Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this section, the term “Department of Energy” includes any predecessor agency of the Department of Energy.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idaac90f15-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dC/tXXXI/s3111/a">Pub. L. 119–60, div. C, title XXXI, § 3111(a)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1417">139 Stat. 1417</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idaac90f16-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idaac90f17-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idaac90f18-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 6244 was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s8294">section 8294 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2705">section 2705 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s3111/b/1">Pub. L. 119–60, § 3111(b)(1)</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Prior sections 6245 to 6250 were renumbered sections 8295 to 8300 of this title, respectively.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
