<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idaacb59a9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6286"><num value="6286">§ 6286.</num><heading> Use of best practices for capital asset projects and nuclear weapon life extension programs</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaacb59aa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6286/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Analyses of Alternatives</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016 (<ref href="/us/pl/114/92">Public Law 114–92</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/129/726">129 Stat. 726</ref>), the Secretary of Energy, in coordination with the Administrator, shall ensure that analyses of alternatives are conducted (including through contractors, as appropriate) in accordance with best practices for capital asset projects and life extension programs of the Administration and capital asset projects relating to defense environmental management.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaacb59ab-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6286/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cost Estimates</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of such Act, the Secretary, in coordination with the Administrator, shall develop cost estimates in accordance with cost estimating best practices for capital asset projects and life extension programs of the Administration and capital asset projects relating to defense environmental management.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaacb59ac-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6286/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Revisions to Departmental Project Management Order and Nuclear Weapon Life Extension Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of such Act, but not later than two years after such date of enactment, the Secretary shall revise—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaacb59ad-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6286/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the capital asset project management order of the Department of Energy to require the use of best practices for preparing cost estimates and for conducting analyses of alternatives for Administration and defense environmental management capital asset projects; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaacb59ae-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6286/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the nuclear weapon life extension program procedures of the Department to require the use of best practices for preparing cost estimates and conducting analyses of alternatives for Administration life extension programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idaacb59af-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dC/tXXXI/s3111/a">Pub. L. 119–60, div. C, title XXXI, § 3111(a)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1434">139 Stat. 1434</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idaacb59b0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idaacb59b1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idaacb59b2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016 and the date of the enactment of such Act, referred to in text, is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/114/92">Pub. L. 114–92</ref>, which was approved <date date="2015-11-15">Nov. 15, 2015</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idaacb59b3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in <ref href="/us/pl/114/92/s3117">section 3117 of Pub. L. 114–92</ref>, which was set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2754">section 2754 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s3111/b/18">Pub. L. 119–60, § 3111(b)(18)</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
