<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida7ef61e6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a"><num value="628a">§ 628a.</num><heading> Special selection review boards</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef61e7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef61e8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef61e9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> If the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that a person recommended by a promotion board for promotion to a grade at or below the grade of major general or rear admiral in the Navy is the subject of credible information of an adverse nature, including any substantiated adverse finding or conclusion described in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s615/a/3/A">section 615(a)(3)(A) of this title</ref>, that was not furnished to the promotion board during its consideration of the person for promotion as otherwise required by such section, the Secretary shall convene a special selection review board under this section to review the person and recommend whether the recommendation for promotion of the person should be sustained.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef61ea-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent a Secretary concerned from deferring consideration of adverse information concerning an officer subject to this section until the next regularly scheduled promotion board applicable to such officer, in lieu of furnishing such adverse information to a special selection review board under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef61eb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> If a person and the recommendation for promotion of the person is subject to review under this section by a special selection review board convened under this section, the name of the person—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ef61ec-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall not be disseminated or publicly released on the list of officers recommended for promotion by the promotion board recommending the promotion of the person; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ef61ed-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall not be forwarded for appointment or nomination to the Secretary of Defense, the President, or the Senate, as applicable.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef61ee-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Convening</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef61ef-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any special selection review board convened under this section shall be convened in accordance with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s628/f">section 628(f) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef61f0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any special selection review board convened under this section may review such number of persons, and recommendations for promotion of such persons, as the Secretary of the military department concerned shall specify in convening such special selection review board.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef61f1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Information Considered</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef61f2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In reviewing a person and recommending whether the recommendation for promotion of the person should be sustained under this section, a special selection review board convened under this section shall be furnished and consider the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ef61f3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The record and information concerning the person furnished in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s615/a/2">section 615(a)(2) of this title</ref> to the promotion board that recommended the person for promotion.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ef61f4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any credible information of an adverse nature on the person, including any substantiated adverse finding or conclusion from an officially documented investigation or inquiry described in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s615/a/3/A">section 615(a)(3)(A) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef61f5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The furnishing of information to a special selection review board under paragraph (1)(B) shall be governed by the standards and procedures referred to in paragraph (3)(C) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s615/a">section 615(a) of this title</ref> applicable to the furnishing of information described in paragraph (3)(A) of such section to selection boards in accordance with that section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef61f6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef61f7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Before information on a person described in paragraph (1)(B) is furnished to a special selection review board for purposes of this section, the Secretary of the military department concerned shall ensure that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ef61f8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/c/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> such information is made available to the person; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ef61f9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/c/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> subject to subparagraphs (C) and (D), the person is afforded a reasonable opportunity to submit comments on such information to the special selection review board before its review of the person and the recommendation for promotion of the person under this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef61fa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> If information on a person described in paragraph (1)(B) is not made available to the person as otherwise required by subparagraph (A)(i) due to the classification status of such information, the person shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be furnished a summary of such information appropriate to the person’s authorization for access to classified information.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef61fb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef61fc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/c/3/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> An opportunity to submit comments on information is not required for a person under subparagraph (A)(ii) if—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ef61fd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/c/3/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> such information was made available to the person in connection with the furnishing of such information under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s615/a">section 615(a) of this title</ref> to the promotion board that recommended the promotion of the person subject to review under this section; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ef61fe-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/c/3/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the person submitted comments on such information to that promotion board.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef61ff-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/c/3/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The comments on information of a person described in clause (i)(II) shall be furnished to the special selection review board.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef6200-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/c/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> A person may waive either or both of the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ef6201-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/c/3/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The right to submit comments to a special selection review board under subparagraph (A)(ii).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ef6202-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/c/3/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The furnishing of comments to a special selection review board under subparagraph (C)(ii).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef6203-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consideration</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef6204-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In considering the record and information on a person under this section, the special selection review board shall compare such record and information with an appropriate sampling of the records of those officers of the same competitive category who were recommended for promotion by the promotion board that recommended the person for promotion, and an appropriate sampling of the records of those officers who were considered by and not recommended for promotion by that promotion board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef6205-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Records and information shall be presented to a special selection review board for purposes of paragraph (1) in a manner that does not indicate or disclose the person or persons for whom the special selection review board was convened.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef6206-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In considering whether the recommendation for promotion of a person should be sustained under this section, a special selection review board shall, to the greatest extent practicable, apply standards used by the promotion board that recommended the person for promotion.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef6207-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> The recommendation for promotion of a person may be sustained under this section only if the special selection review board determines that the person—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ef6208-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/d/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> ranks in the upper half of an order of merit created by the special selection review board or ranks on an order of merit created by the special selection review board as better qualified for promotion than the sample officer highest on the order of merit list who was considered by and not recommended for promotion by the promotion board concerned; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7ef6209-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/d/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is comparable in qualification for promotion to those sample officers who were recommended for promotion by that promotion board.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef620a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> A recommendation for promotion of a person may be sustained under this section only by a vote of a majority of the members of the special selection review board.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef620b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> If a special selection review board does not sustain a recommendation for promotion of a person under this section, the person shall be considered to have failed of selection for promotion.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef620c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef620d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Each special selection review board convened under this section shall submit to the Secretary of the military department concerned a written report, signed by each member of the board, containing the name of each person whose recommendation for promotion it recommends for sustainment and certifying that the board has carefully considered the record and information of each person whose name was referred to it.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef620e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The provisions of sections 617(b) and 618 of this title apply to the report and proceedings of a special selection review board convened under this section in the same manner as they apply to the report and proceedings of a promotion board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s611/a">section 611(a) of this title</ref>. However, in the case of an officer on the Space Force officer list, the provisions of sections 618, 20215, and 20216 of this title apply to the report and proceedings of a special selection review board convened under this section in the same manner as they apply to the report and proceedings of a promotion board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s20211">section 20211 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef620f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appointment of Persons</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef6210-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If the report of a special selection review board convened under this section recommends the sustainment of the recommendation for promotion to the next higher grade of a person whose name was referred to it for review under this section, and the President approves the report, the person shall, as soon as practicable, be appointed to that grade in accordance with subsections (b) and (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s624">section 624 of this title</ref>. However, if the report of a special selection review board convened under this section recommends the sustainment of the recommendation for promotion to the next higher grade of an officer on the Space Force officer list who was referred to it for review under this section, and the President approves the report, the officer shall, as soon as practicable, be appointed to the grade in accordance with subsections (b) and (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s20252">section 20252 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef6211-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A person who is appointed to the next higher grade as described in paragraph (1) shall, upon that appointment, have the same date of rank, the same effective date for the pay and allowances of that grade, and the same position on the active-duty list as the person would have had pursuant to the original recommendation for promotion of the promotion board concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef6212-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef6213-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section. Such regulations shall apply uniformly across the military departments.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef6214-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any regulation prescribed by the Secretary of a military department to supplement the regulations prescribed pursuant to paragraph (1) may not take effect without the approval of the Secretary of Defense, in writing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7ef6215-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s628a/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Promotion Board Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term “promotion board” means a selection board convened by the Secretary of a military department under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s611/a">section 611(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida7ef6216-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tV/s505/a/1">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 505(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3565">134 Stat. 3565</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tV/s521">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 521</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2570">136 Stat. 2570</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tV/s507/a">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 507(a)</ref>, title XVII, § 1722(b)(5), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/242">137 Stat. 242</ref>, 668; <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tV/s506/a">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 506(a)</ref>, title XVII, § 1701(a)(15), <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1870">138 Stat. 1870</ref>, 2203.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida7ef6217-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida7ef6218-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida7ef6219-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (d)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s506/a">Pub. L. 118–159, § 506(a)</ref>, inserted “ranks in the upper half of an order of merit created by the special selection review board or” before “ranks on an order of merit created by the special selection review board as better qualified”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s1701/a/15/A">Pub. L. 118–159, § 1701(a)(15)(A)</ref>, substituted “apply to the report and proceedings of a promotion board convened under section 20211” for “apply to report and proceedings of a promotion board convened under section 20211”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s1701/a/15/B">Pub. L. 118–159, § 1701(a)(15)(B)</ref>, substituted “section 20252” for “section 20251”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2023—Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s1722/b/5/A">Pub. L. 118–31, § 1722(b)(5)(A)</ref>, substituted “major general or” for “major general,” and struck out “, or an equivalent grade in the Space Force” after “in the Navy”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s507/a">Pub. L. 118–31, § 507(a)</ref>, amended subpar. (B) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (B) read as follows: “shall not be forwarded to the Secretary of Defense, the President, or the Senate, as applicable, or included on a promotion list under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s624/a">section 624(a) of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s1722/b/5/B">Pub. L. 118–31, § 1722(b)(5)(B)</ref>, inserted at end: “However, in the case of an officer on the Space Force officer list, the provisions of sections 618, 20215, and 20216 of this title apply to the report and proceedings of a special selection review board convened under this section in the same manner as they apply to report and proceedings of a promotion board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s20211">section 20211 of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s1722/b/5/C">Pub. L. 118–31, § 1722(b)(5)(C)</ref>, inserted at end: “However, if the report of a special selection review board convened under this section recommends the sustainment of the recommendation for promotion to the next higher grade of an officer on the Space Force officer list who was referred to it for review under this section, and the President approves the report, the officer shall, as soon as practicable, be appointed to the grade in accordance with subsections (b) and (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s20251">section 20251 of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s521/1">Pub. L. 117–263, § 521(1)</ref>, which directed amendment of par. (1) by inserting subpar. (A) designation before “If the Secretary concerned”, was executed by inserting the designation before “If the Secretary of the military department concerned”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s521/2">Pub. L. 117–263, § 521(2)</ref>, added subpar. (B).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
