<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida7f1ac2a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s631"><num value="631">§ 631.</num><heading> Effect of failure of selection for promotion: first lieutenants and lieutenants (junior grade)</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f1ac2b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s631/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> Except an officer of the Navy and Marine Corps who is an officer designated for limited duty (to whom section 8146(e) or 8372 of this title applies), each officer of the Army, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force on the active-duty list who holds the grade of first lieutenant and has failed of selection for promotion to the grade of captain for the second time, and each officer of the Navy on the active-duty list who holds the grade of lieutenant (junior grade) and has failed of selection for promotion to the grade of lieutenant for the second time, whose name is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion to the next higher grade shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7f1ac2c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s631/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> be discharged on the date requested by him and approved by the Secretary of the military department concerned, which date shall be not later than the first day of the seventh calendar month beginning after the month in which the Secretary concerned releases the promotion results of the board which considered the officer for the second time to the public;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7f1ac2d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s631/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> if he is eligible for retirement under any provision of law, be retired under that law on the date requested by him and approved by the Secretary concerned, which date shall be not later than the first day of the seventh calendar month beginning after the month in which the Secretary concerned releases the promotion results of the board which considered the officer for the second time to the public; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7f1ac2e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s631/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> if on the date on which he is to be discharged under paragraph (1) he is within two years of qualifying for retirement under section 7311, 8323, or 9311 of this title, be retained on active duty until he is qualified for retirement and then be retired under that section, unless he is sooner retired or discharged under another provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f1ac2f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s631/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The retirement or discharge of an officer pursuant to this section shall be considered to be an involuntary retirement or discharge for purposes of any other provision of law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f1ac30-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s631/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> An officer who is subject to discharge under subsection (a)(1) is not eligible for further consideration for promotion.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f1ac31-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s631/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> For the purposes of this chapter, an officer of the Army, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force who holds the grade of first lieutenant, and an officer of the Navy who holds the grade of lieutenant (junior grade), shall be treated as having failed of selection for promotion if the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that the officer would be eligible for consideration for promotion to the next higher grade by a selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s611/a">section 611(a) of this title</ref> if such a board were convened but is not fully qualified for promotion when recommending for promotion under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s624/a/3">section 624(a)(3) of this title</ref> all fully qualified officers of the officer’s armed force in such grade who would be eligible for such consideration.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida7f1ac32-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/96/513/tI/s105">Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2861">94 Stat. 2861</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/98/525/tV/s525/c">Pub. L. 98–525, title V, § 525(c)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2525">98 Stat. 2525</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tV/s505/a/2">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 505(a)(2)</ref>, (d)(3), (4)(B), <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1086">115 Stat. 1086</ref>, 1088; <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tV/s505/b">Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 505(b)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1457">117 Stat. 1457</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tVIII/s809/a">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1840">132 Stat. 1840</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tIX/s924/b/3/I">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(3)(I)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3821">134 Stat. 3821</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tV/s505/b/1">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, § 505(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1869">138 Stat. 1869</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida7f1ac33-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida7f1ac34-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida7f1ac35-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (a)(1), (2). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159">Pub. L. 118–159</ref> substituted “the Secretary concerned releases the promotion results of the board which considered the officer for the second time to the public” for “the President approves the report of the board which considered him for the second time”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsecs. (a), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> substituted “Marine Corps, or Space Force” for “or Marine Corps” in introductory provisions in subsec. (a) and in subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232">Pub. L. 115–232</ref> substituted “section 8146(e) or 8372” for “section 5596(e) or 6383” in introductory provisions and “section 7311, 8323, or 9311” for “section 3911, 6323, or 8911” in par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136">Pub. L. 108–136</ref> substituted “paragraph” for “clause”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—<ref href="/us/pl/107/107/s505/d/4/B">Pub. L. 107–107, § 505(d)(4)(B)</ref>, struck out “regular” before “first lieutenants” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/s505/d/3">Pub. L. 107–107, § 505(d)(3)</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted “Army, Air Force, or Marine Corps on the active-duty list” for “Regular Army, Regular Air Force, or Regular Marine Corps” and “Navy on the active-duty list” for “Regular Navy” and struck out “regular” before “grade” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/s505/a/2">Pub. L. 107–107, § 505(a)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/98/525">Pub. L. 98–525</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida7f1ac36-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida7f1ac37-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2018 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/115/232">Pub. L. 115–232</ref> effective <date date="2019-02-01">Feb. 1, 2019</date>, with provision for the coordination of amendments and special rule for certain redesignations, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s800">section 800 of Pub. L. 115–232</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="ida7f1ac38-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1981-09-15">Sept. 15, 1981</date>, but the authority to prescribe regulations under this section effective on <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/513/s701">section 701 of Pub. L. 96–513</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1980 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
