<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idaacdcaf8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s6332"><num value="6332">§ 6332.</num><heading> Laboratory-directed research and development</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0"> Of the funds made available by the Department of Energy for activities at government-owned, contractor-operated laboratories funded in this Act <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002148">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002148"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> or subsequent Energy and Water Development Appropriations Acts, the Secretary may authorize a specific amount, not to exceed 8 percent of such funds, to be used by such laboratories for laboratory directed research and development: <i>Provided</i>, That the Secretary may also authorize a specific amount not to exceed 4 percent of such funds, to be used by the plant manager of a covered nuclear weapons production plant or the manager of the Nevada Site Office for plant or site directed research and development: <i>Provided further</i>, That notwithstanding Department of Energy order 413.2A, dated <date date="2001-01-08">January 8, 2001</date>, beginning in fiscal year 2006 and thereafter, all DOE laboratories may be eligible for laboratory directed research and development funding.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idaacdcaf9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dC/tXXXI/s3111/a">Pub. L. 119–60, div. C, title XXXI, § 3111(a)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1448">139 Stat. 1448</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idaacdcafa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idaacdcafb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idaacdcafc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in text, means div. C of <ref href="/us/pl/111/8">Pub. L. 111–8</ref>, <date date="2009-03-11">Mar. 11, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/601">123 Stat. 601</ref>, known as the Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2009. Prior to repeal and restatement as this section, this section was <ref href="/us/pl/111/8/dC/s308">section 308 of div. C of Pub. L. 111–8</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idaacdcafd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 6332 was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s8332">section 8332 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2791a">section 2791a of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s3111/b/6">Pub. L. 119–60, § 3111(b)(6)</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
