<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida7f1aca5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638"><num value="638">§ 638.</num><heading> Selective early retirement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f1aca6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f1aca7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> A regular officer on the active-duty list of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force may be considered for selective early retirement by a selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s611/b">section 611(b) of this title</ref> if the officer is described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (D) as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7f1aca8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> An officer holding the regular grade of lieutenant colonel or commander who has failed of selection for promotion to the grade of colonel or, in the case of an officer of the Navy, captain two or more times and whose name is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7f1aca9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> An officer holding the regular grade of colonel or, in the case of an officer of the Navy, captain who has served at least four years of active duty in that grade and whose name is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7f1acaa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> An officer holding the regular grade of brigadier general or rear admiral (lower half) who has served at least three and one-half years of active duty in that grade and whose name is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7f1acab-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> An officer holding the regular grade of major general or rear admiral who has served at least three and one-half years of active duty in that grade.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f1acac-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary of the military department concerned shall specify the number of officers described in paragraphs (1)(A) and (1)(B) which a selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s611/b">section 611(b) of this title</ref> may recommend for early retirement. Such number may not be more than 30 percent of the number of officers considered in each grade in each competitive category.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f1acad-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A regular officer on the active-duty list of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force may also be considered for early retirement under the circumstances prescribed in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s638a">section 638a of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f1acae-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f1acaf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f1acb0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> An officer in a grade below brigadier general or rear admiral (lower half) who is recommended for early retirement under this section or <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s638a">section 638a of this title</ref> and whose early retirement is approved by the Secretary concerned shall be retired, under any provision of law under which he is eligible to retire, on the date requested by him and approved by the Secretary concerned, which date shall be not later than the first day of the seventh calendar month beginning after the month in which the Secretary concerned approves the report of the board which recommended the officer for early retirement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f1acb1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> If an officer described in subparagraph (A) is not eligible for retirement under any provision of law, the officer shall be retained on active duty until the officer is qualified for retirement under section 7311, 8323, or 9311 of this title, and then be retired under that section, unless the officer is sooner retired or discharged under some other provision of law, with such retirement under that section occurring not later than the later of the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7f1acb2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/b/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The first day of the month beginning after the month in which the officer becomes qualified for retirement under that section.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida7f1acb3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/b/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The first day of the seventh calendar month beginning after the month in which the Secretary concerned approves the report of the board which recommended the officer for early retirement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f1acb4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An officer who holds the regular grade of brigadier general, major general, rear admiral (lower half), or rear admiral who is recommended for early retirement under this section and whose early retirement is approved by the Secretary concerned shall be retired, under any provision of law under which he is eligible to retire, on the date requested by him and approved by the Secretary concerned, which date shall be not later than the first day of the tenth calendar month beginning after the month in which the Secretary concerned approved the report of the board which recommended the officer for early retirement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f1acb5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f1acb6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary concerned may defer for not more than three months the retirement of an officer otherwise approved for early retirement under this section or <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s638a">section 638a of this title</ref> in order to prevent a personal hardship to the officer or for other humanitarian reasons. Any such deferral shall be made on a case-by-case basis considering the circumstances of the case of the particular officer concerned. The authority of the Secretary to grant such a deferral may not be delegated.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f1acb7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> An officer recommended for early retirement under paragraph (1)(A) or <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s638a">section 638a of this title</ref>, if approved for deferral under subparagraph (A), shall be retired on the date requested by the officer, and approved by the Secretary concerned, which date shall be not later than the first day of the tenth calendar month beginning after the month in which the Secretary concerned approves the report of the board which recommended the officer for early retirement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f1acb8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Secretary concerned may defer the retirement of an officer otherwise approved for early retirement under paragraph (1)(B), but in no case later than the first day of the tenth calendar month beginning after the month in which the Secretary concerned approves the report of the board which recommended the officer for early retirement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f41cb9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/b/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> An officer recommended for early retirement under paragraph (2), if approved for deferral under subparagraph (A), shall be retired on the date requested by the officer, and approved by the Secretary concerned, which date shall be not later than the first day of the thirteenth calendar month beginning after the month in which the Secretary concerned approves the report of the board which recommended the officer for early retirement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f41cba-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> So long as an officer in a grade below brigadier general or rear admiral (lower half) holds the same grade, he may not be considered for early retirement under this section more than once in any five-year period.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f41cbb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> The retirement of an officer pursuant to this section shall be considered to be an involuntary retirement for purposes of any other provision of law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f41cbc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f41cbd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f41cbe-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f41cbf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Such regulations shall require that when the Secretary of the military department concerned submits a list of officers to a selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s611/b">section 611(b) of this title</ref> to consider officers for selection for early retirement under this section, such list (except as provided in subparagraph (B)) shall include each officer on the active-duty list in the same grade and competitive category whose position on the active-duty list is between that of the most junior officer in that grade and competitive category whose name is submitted to the board and that of the most senior officer in that grade and competitive category whose name is submitted to the board.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f41cc0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A list under subparagraph (A) may not include an officer in that grade and competitive category (i) who has been approved for voluntary retirement under section 7311, 8323, or 9311 of this title, or (ii) who is to be involuntarily retired under any provision of law during the fiscal year in which the selection board is convened or during the following fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f41cc1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s638/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> An officer not considered by a selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s611/b">section 611(b) of this title</ref> by reason of subparagraph (B) shall be retired on the date approved for the retirement of that officer as of the convening date of such selection board unless the Secretary concerned approves a modification of such date in order to prevent a personal hardship for the officer or for other humanitarian reasons.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida7f41cc2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/96/513/tI/s105">Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2864">94 Stat. 2864</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/97/22/s4/f">Pub. L. 97–22, § 4(f)</ref>, <date date="1981-07-10">July 10, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/127">95 Stat. 127</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/86/tIV/s405/b/1">Pub. L. 97–86, title IV, § 405(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-01">Dec. 1, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1105">95 Stat. 1105</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/145/tV/s514/b/1">Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 514(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/628">99 Stat. 628</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/456/dA/tV/s504">Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1967">102 Stat. 1967</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tV/s521/b/2">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 521(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1561">104 Stat. 1561</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/dA/tV/s503/a">Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title V, § 503(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-05">Dec. 5, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1355">105 Stat. 1355</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tV/s506">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 506</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1646">107 Stat. 1646</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tV/s504/b">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 504(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/295">110 Stat. 295</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tV/s502/b">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title V, § 502(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3354">128 Stat. 3354</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tVIII/s809/a">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1840">132 Stat. 1840</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tIX/s924/b/3/L">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 924(b)(3)(L)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3821">134 Stat. 3821</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida7f41cc3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida7f41cc4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida7f41cc5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (a)(1), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> substituted “Marine Corps, or Space Force” for “or Marine Corps” in introductory provisions of par. (1) and in par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsecs. (b)(1)(B), (e)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232">Pub. L. 115–232</ref> substituted “section 7311, 8323, or 9311” for “section 3911, 6323, or 8911”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/s502/b/1">Pub. L. 113–291, § 502(b)(1)</ref>, added par. (1) and struck out former par. (1) which read as follows: “An officer in a grade below brigadier general or rear admiral (lower half) who is recommended for early retirement under this section or <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s638a">section 638a of this title</ref> and whose early retirement is approved by the Secretary concerned shall—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) be retired, under any provision of law under which he is eligible to retire, on the date requested by him and approved by the Secretary concerned, which date shall be not later than the first day of the seventh calendar month beginning after the month in which the Secretary concerned approves the report of the board which recommended the officer for early retirement; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) if the officer is not eligible for retirement under any provision of law, be retained on active duty until he is qualified for retirement under section 3911, 6323, or 8911 of this title, and then be retired under that section, unless he is sooner retired or discharged under some other provision of law.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/s502/b/2">Pub. L. 113–291, § 502(b)(2)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A), substituted “three months” for “90 days”, and added subpars. (B) to (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106">Pub. L. 104–106</ref> added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (e)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/103/160">Pub. L. 103–160</ref> inserted “(i)” after “grade and competitive category”, inserted “(ii)” after “of this title, or”, and struck out comma after “any provision of law”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/102/190">Pub. L. 102–190</ref> designated existing provisions as pars. (1) and (2)(A), in par. (2)(A) inserted “(except as provided in subparagraph (B))” after “under this section, such list”, and added subpars. (B) and (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s521/b/2/A">Pub. L. 101–510, § 521(b)(2)(A)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s521/b/2/B">Pub. L. 101–510, § 521(b)(2)(B)</ref>, inserted “or <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s638a">section 638a of this title</ref>” after “under this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/456">Pub. L. 100–456</ref> amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) read as follows: “A regular officer on the active-duty list of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) who holds the regular grade of lieutenant colonel or commander and has failed of selection for promotion to the grade of colonel or, in the case of an officer of the Navy, captain two or more times and whose name is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) who holds the regular grade of colonel or, in the case of an officer of the Navy, captain and has served at least four years of active duty in that grade and whose name is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(3) who holds the regular grade of brigadier general or rear admiral (lower half) and has served at least three and one-half years of active duty in that grade and whose name is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(4) who holds the regular grade of major general or rear admiral and has served at least three and one-half years of active duty in that grade,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">may be considered for early retirement by a selection board convened under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s611/b">section 611(b) of this title</ref>. The Secretary of the military department concerned shall specify the number of officers described in clauses (1) and (2) which such a board may recommend for early retirement, but such number may not be more than 30 percent of the number of officers considered in each grade in each competitive category.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsecs. (a)(3), (b), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/145">Pub. L. 99–145</ref> substituted “rear admiral (lower half)” for “commodore” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/97/86">Pub. L. 97–86</ref> substituted “commodore” for “commodore admiral”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/97/22">Pub. L. 97–22</ref> substituted “three and one-half years of active duty” for “four years of active duty”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/86">Pub. L. 97–86</ref> substituted “commodore” for “commodore admiral” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida7f41cc6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida7f41cc7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2018 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/115/232">Pub. L. 115–232</ref> effective <date date="2019-02-01">Feb. 1, 2019</date>, with provision for the coordination of amendments and special rule for certain redesignations, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s800">section 800 of Pub. L. 115–232</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="ida7f41cc8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/86">Pub. L. 97–86</ref> effective <date date="1981-09-15">Sept. 15, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/86/s405/f">section 405(f) of Pub. L. 97–86</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="ida7f41cc9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1981-09-15">Sept. 15, 1981</date>, but the authority to prescribe regulations under this section effective on <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/513/s701">section 701 of Pub. L. 96–513</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1980 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
