<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida7f41d1b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s640"><num value="640">§ 640.</num><heading> Deferment of retirement or separation for medical reasons</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f41d1c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s640/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> If the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that the evaluation of the physical condition of an officer and determination of the officer’s entitlement to retirement or separation for physical disability require hospitalization or medical observation and that such hospitalization or medical observation cannot be completed with confidence in a manner consistent with the member’s well being before the date on which the officer would otherwise be required to retire or be separated under this title, the Secretary may defer the retirement or separation of the officer under this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida7f41d1d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s640/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> A deferral of retirement or separation under subsection (a) may not extend for more than 30 days after completion of the evaluation requiring hospitalization or medical observation.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida7f41d1e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/96/513/tI/s105">Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2866">94 Stat. 2866</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tV/s507">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title V, § 507</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1090">115 Stat. 1090</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida7f41d1f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida7f41d20-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida7f41d21-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2001—<ref href="/us/pl/107/107">Pub. L. 107–107</ref> amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Secretary of the military department concerned may defer the retirement or separation under this title of any officer if the evaluation of the physical condition of the officer and determination of the officer’s entitlement to retirement or separation for physical disability require hospitalization or medical observation that cannot be completed before the date on which the officer would otherwise be required to retire or be separated under this title.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida7f41d22-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="ida7f41d23-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1981-09-15">Sept. 15, 1981</date>, but the authority to prescribe regulations under this section effective on <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/513/s701">section 701 of Pub. L. 96–513</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1980 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
