<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida8000474-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s707a"><num value="707a">§ 707a.</num><heading> Payment upon disapproval of certain board of inquiry recommendations for excess leave required to be taken</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8000475-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s707a/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> An officer—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8000476-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s707a/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> who is required to take leave under section 1182(c)(2) or 20503 of this title, any period of which is charged as excess leave under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s706/a">section 706(a) of this title</ref>, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida8000477-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s707a/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> whose recommendation for removal from active duty in a report of a board of inquiry is not approved by the Secretary concerned under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1184">section 1184 of this title</ref>,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be paid, as provided in subsection (b), for the period of leave charged as excess leave.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8000478-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s707a/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8000479-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s707a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An officer entitled to be paid under this section shall be deemed, for purposes of this section, to have accrued pay and allowances for each day of leave required to be taken under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1182/c/2">section 1182(c)(2) of this title</ref> that is charged as excess leave (except any day of accrued leave for which the officer has been paid under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s706/b/1">section 706(b)(1) of this title</ref> and which has been charged as excess leave).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida800047a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s707a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The officer shall be paid the amount of pay and allowances that is deemed to have accrued to the officer under paragraph (1), reduced by the total amount of his income from wages, salaries, tips, other personal service income, unemployment compensation, and public assistance benefits from any Government agency during the period the officer is deemed to have accrued pay and allowances. Except as provided in paragraph (3), such payment shall be made within 60 days after the date on which the Secretary concerned decides not to remove the officer from active duty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida800047b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s707a/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If an officer is entitled to be paid under this section, but fails to provide sufficient information in a timely manner regarding the officer’s income when such information is requested under regulations prescribed under subsection (c), the period of time prescribed in paragraph (2) shall be extended until 30 days after the date on which the member provides the information requested.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida800047c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s707a/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> This section shall be administered under uniform regulations prescribed by the Secretaries concerned. The regulations may provide for the method of determining an officer’s income during any period the officer is deemed to have accrued pay and allowances, including a requirement that the officer provide income tax returns and other documentation to verify the amount of the officer’s income.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida800047d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tV/s506/b">Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title V, § 506(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2535">116 Stat. 2535</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tXVII/s1722/d/2">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1722(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/670">137 Stat. 670</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida800047e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida800047f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida8000480-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2023—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31">Pub. L. 118–31</ref> inserted “or 20503” after “section 1182(c)(2)”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
