<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idaaf3eef9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461"><num value="7461">§ 7461.</num><heading> Policy on sexual harassment and sexual violence</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaaf3eefa-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Required Policy</inline>.—</heading><content>Under guidance prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Army shall direct the Superintendent of the Academy to prescribe a policy on sexual harassment and sexual violence applicable to the cadets and other personnel of the Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaaf3eefb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Matters To Be Specified in Policy</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The policy on sexual harassment and sexual violence prescribed under this section shall include specification of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaaf3eefc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Programs to promote awareness of the incidence of rape, acquaintance rape, and other sexual offenses of a criminal nature that involve cadets or other Academy personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaaf3eefd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Procedures that a cadet should follow in the case of an occurrence of sexual harassment or sexual violence, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaaf3eefe-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> if the cadet chooses to report an occurrence of sexual harassment or sexual violence, a specification of the person or persons to whom the alleged offense should be reported and the options for confidential reporting;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaaf3eeff-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a specification of any other person whom the victim should contact; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaaf3ef00-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> procedures on the preservation of evidence potentially necessary for proof of criminal sexual assault.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaaf3ef01-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Procedures for disciplinary action in cases of alleged criminal sexual assault involving a cadet or other Academy personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaaf3ef02-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Any other sanction authorized to be imposed in a substantiated case of sexual harassment or sexual violence involving a cadet or other Academy personnel in rape, acquaintance rape, or any other criminal sexual offense, whether forcible or nonforcible.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaaf3ef03-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Required training on the policy for all cadets and other Academy personnel, including the specific training required for personnel who process allegations of sexual harassment or sexual violence involving Academy personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaaf3ef04-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Assessment</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaaf3ef05-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense, through the Secretary of the Army, shall direct the Superintendent to conduct at the Academy during each Academy program year an assessment, to be administered by the Department of Defense, to determine the effectiveness of the policies, training, and procedures of the Academy with respect to sexual harassment and sexual violence involving Academy personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaaf3ef06-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> For the assessment at the Academy under paragraph (1) with respect to an Academy program year that begins in an odd-numbered calendar year, the Secretary of the Army shall conduct a survey, to be administered by the Department of Defense, of Academy personnel—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaaf3ef07-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> to measure—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaaf3ef08-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/c/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the incidence, during that program year, of sexual harassment and sexual violence events, on or off the Academy reservation, that have been reported to officials of the Academy; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaaf3ef09-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/c/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the incidence, during that program year, of sexual harassment and sexual violence events, on or off the Academy reservation, that have not been reported to officials of the Academy; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaaf3ef0a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> to assess the perceptions of Academy personnel of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaaf3ef0b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/c/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the policies, training, and procedures on sexual harassment and sexual violence involving Academy personnel;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaaf3ef0c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/c/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the enforcement of such policies;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaaf3ef0d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/c/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the incidence of sexual harassment and sexual violence involving Academy personnel; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaaf3ef0e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/c/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> any other issues relating to sexual harassment and sexual violence involving Academy personnel.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaaf3ef0f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaaf3ef10-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense may postpone the conduct of an assessment under this subsection if the Secretary determines that conducting such assessment is not practicable due to a war or national emergency declared by the President or Congress.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaaf3ef11-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that an assessment postponed under subparagraph (A) is conducted as soon as practicable after the end of the period of war or national emergency concerned, or earlier if the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaaf3ef12-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall notify Congress of a determination under subparagraph (A) not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary makes such determination.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaaf3ef13-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaaf3ef14-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of the Army shall direct the Superintendent of the Academy to submit to the Secretary a report on sexual harassment and sexual violence involving cadets or other personnel at the Academy for each Academy program year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaaf3ef15-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Each report under paragraph (1) shall include, for the Academy program year covered by the report, the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaaf3ef16-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The number of sexual assaults, rapes, and other sexual offenses involving cadets or other Academy personnel that have been reported to Academy officials during the program year and, of those reported cases, the number that have been substantiated.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaaf3ef17-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The policies, procedures, and processes implemented by the Secretary of the Army and the leadership of the Academy in response to sexual harassment and sexual violence involving cadets or other Academy personnel during the program year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaaf3ef18-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> A plan for the actions that are to be taken in the following Academy program year regarding prevention of and response to sexual harassment and sexual violence involving cadets or other Academy personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaaf3ef19-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Each report under paragraph (1) for an Academy program year that begins in an odd-numbered calendar year shall include the results of the survey conducted in that program year under subsection (c)(2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaaf3ef1a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaaf3ef1b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/d/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary of the Army shall transmit to the Secretary of Defense, and to the Board of Visitors of the Academy, each report received by the Secretary under this subsection, together with the Secretary’s comments on the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaaf3ef1c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/d/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense shall transmit each such report, together with the Secretary’s comments on the report, to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaaf3ef1d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consideration of Request for Transfer of a Cadet Who Is the Victim of a Sexual Assault or Related Offense</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaaf3ef1e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of the Army shall provide for timely consideration of and action on a request submitted by a cadet appointed to the United States Military Academy who is the victim of an alleged sexual assault or other offense covered by section 920, 920c, or 930 of this title (article 120, 120c, or 130 of the Uniform Code of Military Justice) for transfer to another military service academy or to enroll in a Senior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps program affiliated with another institution of higher education.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaaf3ef1f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of the Army shall prescribe regulations to carry out this subsection, within guidelines provided by the Secretary of Defense that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaaf3ef20-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> provide that the Superintendent of the United States Military Academy shall ensure that any cadet who has been appointed to the United States Military Academy and who is a victim of an alleged sexual assault or other offense referred to in paragraph (1), is informed of the right to request a transfer pursuant to this section, and that any formal request submitted by a cadet is processed as expeditiously as practicable through the chain of command for review and action by the Superintendent;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaaf3ef21-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> direct the Superintendent of the United States Military Academy, in coordination with the Superintendent of the military service academy to which the cadet requests to transfer—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaaf3ef22-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/e/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to take action on a request for transfer under this subsection not later than 72 hours after receiving the formal request from the cadet;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaaf3ef23-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/e/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to approve such request for transfer unless there are exceptional circumstances that require denial of the request; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaaf3ef24-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/e/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> upon approval of such request, to take all necessary and appropriate action to effectuate the transfer of the cadet to the military service academy concerned as expeditiously as possible; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idaaf3ef25-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> direct the Superintendent of the United States Military Academy, in coordination with the Secretary of the military department that sponsors the Senior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps program at the institution of higher education to which the cadet requests to transfer—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaaf3ef26-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/e/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to take action on a request for transfer under this subsection not later than 72 hours after receiving the formal request from the cadet;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaaf3ef27-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/e/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> subject to the cadet’s acceptance for admission to the institution of higher education to which the cadet wishes to transfer, to approve such request for transfer unless there are exceptional circumstances that require denial of the application; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idaaf3ef28-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/e/2/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> to take all necessary and appropriate action to effectuate the cadet’s enrollment in the institution of higher education to which the cadet wishes to transfer and to process the cadet for participation in the relevant Senior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps program as expeditiously as possible.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaaf3ef29-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If the Superintendent of the United States Military Academy denies a request for transfer under this subsection, the cadet may request review of the denial by the Secretary of the Army, who shall take action on such request not later than 72 hours after receipt of the formal request for review.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaaf3ef2a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Secretary concerned shall ensure that all records of any request, determination, transfer, or other action under this subsection remain confidential, consistent with applicable law and regulation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idaaf3ef2b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s7461/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> A cadet who transfers under this subsection may retain the cadet’s appointment to the United States Military Academy or may be appointed to the military service academy to which the cadet transfers without regard to the limitations and requirements set forth in sections 7442, 8454, and 9442 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idaaf3ef2c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tV/s532/a/1">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 532(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2200">120 Stat. 2200</ref>, § 4361; renumbered § 7461, <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tVIII/s808/c/1">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1839">132 Stat. 1839</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tV/s555/a">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 555(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1388">133 Stat. 1388</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tV/s552/b/1">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 552(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3632">134 Stat. 3632</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idaaf3ef2d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idaaf3ef2e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idaaf3ef2f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Pub. L. 116–92</ref> added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—<ref href="/us/pl/115/232">Pub. L. 115–232</ref> renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4361">section 4361 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idaaf3ef30-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idaaf3ef31-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2018 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/115/232">Pub. L. 115–232</ref> effective <date date="2019-02-01">Feb. 1, 2019</date>, with provision for the coordination of amendments and special rule for certain redesignations, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s800">section 800 of Pub. L. 115–232</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idaaf3ef32-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2021-12-31">Dec. 31, 2021</date>, of provisions in subsec. (d)(4)(B) of this section requiring submittal of annual report to Congress, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1061">section 1061 of Pub. L. 114–328</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s111">section 111 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idaaf3ef33-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Policy for Military Service Academies on Separation of Alleged Victims and Alleged Perpetrators in Incidents of Sexual Assault</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tV/s539">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title V, § 539</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3606">134 Stat. 3606</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tV/s539">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall, in consultation with the Secretaries of the military departments and the Superintendent of each military service academy, prescribe in regulations a policy under which a cadet or midshipman of a military service academy who is the alleged victim of a sexual assault and a cadet or midshipman who is the alleged perpetrator of such assault shall, to the extent practicable, each be given the opportunity to complete their course of study at the academy without—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> taking classes together; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> otherwise being in close proximity to each other during mandatory activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the policy developed under subsection (a)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> permits an alleged victim to elect not to be covered by the policy with respect to a particular incident of sexual assault;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> protects the alleged victim as necessary, including by prohibiting retaliatory harassment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> minimizes the prejudicial impact of the policy, to the extent practicable, on both the alleged victim and the alleged perpetrator, and allows the alleged victim and the alleged perpetrator to complete their course of study at the institution with minimal disruption;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> protects the privacy of both the alleged victim and the alleged perpetrator by ensuring that information about the alleged sexual assault and the individuals involved is not revealed to third parties who are not specifically authorized to receive such information in the course of performing their regular duties, except that such policy shall not preclude the alleged victim or the alleged perpetrator from making such disclosures to third parties; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> minimizes the burden on the alleged victim when taking steps to separate the alleged victim and alleged perpetrator.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special Rule</inline>.—</heading><content>The policy developed under subsection (a) shall not preclude a military service academy from taking other administrative or disciplinary action when appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Military Service Academy Defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section, the term ‘military service academy’ means the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The United States Military Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The United States Naval Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The United States Air Force Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The United States Coast Guard Academy.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idaaf3ef34-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Development of Resource Guides Regarding Sexual Assault for the Military Service Academies</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tV/s545">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 545</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1764">132 Stat. 1764</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tV/s545">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Development</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>], each Superintendent of a military service academy shall develop and maintain a resource guide for students at the respective military service academies regarding sexual assault.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each guide developed under this section shall include the following information with regards to the relevant military service academy:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Process overview and definitions.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> An explanation of prohibited conduct, including examples.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> An explanation of consent.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Victims’ rights.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Clearly described complaint process, including to whom a complaint may be filed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> Explanations of restricted and unrestricted reporting.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> List of mandatory reporters.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> Protections from retaliation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> Assurance that leadership will take appropriate corrective action.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> References to specific policies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="J">“(J)</num><content> Resources for survivors.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Emergency services.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Contact information.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Location.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Support and counseling</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Contact information for the following support and counseling resources:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The Sexual Assault Prevention and Response Victim Advocate or other equivalent advocate or counselor available to students in cases of sexual assault.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The Sexual Harassment/Assault Response and Prevention Resource Program Center.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Peer counseling.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Medical care.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> Legal counsel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> Hotlines.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> Chaplain or other spiritual representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Distribution</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each Superintendent shall provide the current guide developed by that Superintendent under this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> not later than 30 days after completing development under subsection (a) to each student who is enrolled at the military service academy of that Superintendent on the date of the enactment of this Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> at the beginning of each academic year after the date of the enactment of this Act to each student who enrolls at the military service academy of that Superintendent; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> as soon as practicable to a student at the military service academy of that Superintendent who reports that such student is a victim of sexual assault.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idaaf3ef35-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Applicability of Sexual Assault Prevention and Response and Related Military Justice Enhancements to Military Service Academies</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tV/s552/a">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title V, § 552(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3377">128 Stat. 3377</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tV/s552/a">“The Secretary of the military department concerned shall ensure that the provisions of title XVII of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 (<ref href="/us/pl/113/66">Public Law 113–66</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/127/950">127 Stat. 950</ref>) [see Tables for classification], including amendments made by that title, and the provisions of subtitle D [subtitle D (§§ 531–547) of title V of div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/113/291">Pub. L. 113–291</ref>, see Tables for classification], including amendments made by such subtitle, apply to the United States Military Academy, the Naval Academy, and the Air Force Academy, as applicable.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idaaf3ef36-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prevention of Sexual Assault at Military Service Academies</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tXVII/s1746">Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title XVII, § 1746</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/983">127 Stat. 983</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tXVII/s1746">“The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the United States Military Academy, the United States Naval Academy, and the United States Air Force Academy include a section in the curricula of that military service academy that outlines honor, respect, and character development as such pertain to the issue of preventing sexual assault in the Armed Forces. Such curricula section shall include a brief history of the problem of sexual assault in the Armed Forces, a definition of sexual assault, information relating to reporting a sexual assault, victims’ rights, and dismissal and dishonorable discharge for offenders. Training in such section in the curricula shall be provided within 14 days after the initial arrival of a new cadet or midshipman at that military service academy and repeated annually thereafter.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idaaf3ef37-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Further Information From Cadets and Midshipmen at the Service Academies on Sexual Assault and Sexual Harassment Issues</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tV/s532/b">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 532(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2205">120 Stat. 2205</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tV/s532/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of focus groups for years when survey not required</inline>.—</heading><content>In any year in which the Secretary of a military department is not required by law to conduct a survey at the service academy under the Secretary’s jurisdiction on matters relating to sexual assault and sexual harassment issues at that Academy, the Secretary shall provide for focus groups to be conducted at that Academy for the purposes of ascertaining information relating to sexual assault and sexual harassment issues at that Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inclusion in report</inline>.—</heading><content>Information ascertained from a focus group conducted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be included in the Secretary’s annual report to Congress on sexual harassment and sexual violence at the service academies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Service academies</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this subsection, the term ‘service academy’ means the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The United States Military Academy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The United States Naval Academy.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> The United States Air Force Academy.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
