<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idab390f33-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b"><num value="8669b">§ 8669b.</num><heading> Senior Technical Authority for each naval vessel class</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab390f34-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Senior Technical Authority.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab390f35-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Designation for each vessel class required</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of the Navy shall designate, in writing, a Senior Technical Authority for each class of naval vessels as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab390f36-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In the case of a class of vessels which has received Milestone A approval, an approval to enter into technology maturation and risk reduction, or an approval to enter into a subsequent Department of Defense or Department of the Navy acquisition phase as of the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020, not later than 30 days after such date of enactment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab390f37-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In the case of any class of vessels which has not received any approval described in subparagraph (A) as of such date of enactment, at or before the first of such approvals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab390f38-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Individuals eligible for designation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each individual designated as a Senior Technical Authority under paragraph (1) shall be an employee of the Navy in the Senior Executive Service in an organization of the Navy that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab390f39-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> possesses the technical expertise required to carry out the responsibilities specified in subsection (b); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab390f3a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> reports directly to the portfolio acquisition executive, established under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1732">section 1732 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab390f3b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Term</inline>.—</heading><content>Each Senior Technical Authority shall be designated for a fixed term, not shorter than the time anticipated to establish demonstrated successful performance of the class of vessels concerned in accordance with its approved capabilities document, as determined by the Secretary at the time of designation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab390f3c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Voluntary departure</inline>.—</heading><content>If an individual designated as a Senior Technical Authority voluntarily departs the position before demonstrated successful performance of the class of vessels concerned, the Secretary shall designate, in writing, a replacement, and shall notify, in writing, the congressional defense committees not later than 90 days after such departure.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab390f3d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Removal</inline>.—</heading><content>An individual may be removed involuntarily from designation as a Senior Technical Authority only by the Secretary. Not later than 15 days after the involuntary removal of an individual from such designation, the Secretary shall notify, in writing, the congressional defense committees of the removal, including the reasons for the removal. Not later than 90 days after the involuntary removal, the Secretary shall designate, in writing, a replacement, and shall notify, in writing, the congressional defense committees of such designation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab390f3e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reassignment for mission needs</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to paragraphs (4) and (5), the Secretary may reassign a Senior Technical Authority or remove an individual from designation as a Senior Technical Authority in furtherance of Department of the Navy mission needs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab390f3f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities and Authority</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab390f40-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Each Senior Technical Authority shall be responsible for, and have the authority to, establish, monitor, and approve technical standards, tools, and processes for the class of naval vessels for which designated under this section in conformance with applicable laws and Department of Defense and Department of the Navy policies, requirements, architectures, and standards.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab390f41-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Each Senior Technical Authority shall also be responsible for the determination that all design requirements for a vessel class are directly related to a key performance parameter or key system attribute established in the capability development document for such class. Any such requirement that the Senior Technical Authority determines is unnecessary to meet a key performance parameter or key system attribute shall not be approved.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab390f42-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Obligation of Funds on Lead Vessel in Vessel Class.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab390f43-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>On or after <date date="2021-01-01">January 1, 2021</date>, funds authorized to be appropriated for Shipbuilding and Conversion, Navy or Other Procurement, Navy may not be obligated for the first time on the lead vessel in a class of naval vessels unless the Secretary of the Navy certifies as described in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab390f44-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certification elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The certification on a class of naval vessels described in this paragraph is a certification containing each of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab390f45-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The name or names of the individual or individuals designated as the Senior Technical Authority for such class of vessels, and the qualifications and professional biography or biographies of the individual or individuals so designated.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab390f46-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A description by the Senior Technical Authority of the systems engineering, technology, and ship integration risks for such class of vessels.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab390f47-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The designation by the Senior Technical Authority of each critical hull, mechanical, electrical, propulsion, and combat system of such class of vessels, including systems relating to power generation, power distribution, and key operational mission areas.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab390f48-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/c/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The date on which the Senior Technical Authority approved the systems engineering, engineering development, and land-based engineering and testing plans for such class of vessels.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab390f49-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/c/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> A description by the Senior Technical Authority of the key technical knowledge objectives and demonstrated system performance of each plan approved as described in subparagraph (D).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab390f4a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/c/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> A determination by the Senior Technical Authority that such plans are sufficient to achieve thorough technical knowledge of critical systems of such class of vessels before the start of detail design and construction.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab390f4b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/c/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> A determination by the Senior Technical Authority that actual execution of activities in support of such plans as of the date of the certification have been and continue to be effective and supportive of the acquisition schedule for such class of vessels.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab390f4c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/c/2/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> A description by the Senior Technical Authority of other technology maturation and risk reduction efforts not included in such plans for such class of vessels taken as of the date of the certification.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab3b7f4d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/c/2/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> A certification by the Senior Technical Authority that each critical system covered by subparagraph (C) has been demonstrated through testing of a prototype or identical component in its final form, fit, and function in a realistic environment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab3b7f4e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/c/2/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><content> A determination by the Secretary that the plans approved as described in subparagraph (D) are fully funded and will be fully funded in the future-years defense program for the fiscal year beginning in the year in which the certification is submitted.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab3b7f4f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/c/2/K"><num value="K">(K)</num><content> A determination by the Secretary that the Senior Technical Authority will approve, in writing, the ship specification for such class of vessels before the request for proposals for detail design, construction, or both, as applicable, is released.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab3b7f50-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deadline for submittal of certification</inline>.—</heading><content>The certification required by this subsection with respect to a class of naval vessels shall be submitted, in writing, to the congressional defense committees not fewer than 30 days before the Secretary obligates for the first time funds authorized to be appropriated for Shipbuilding and Conversion, Navy or Other Procurement, Navy for the lead vessel in such class of naval vessels.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab3b7f51-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab3b7f52-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The term “class of naval vessels”—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab3b7f53-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> means any group of similar undersea or surface craft procured with Shipbuilding and Conversion, Navy or Other Procurement, Navy funds, including manned, unmanned, and optionally-manned craft; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab3b7f54-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> includes—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idab3b7f55-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/d/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a substantially new class of craft (including craft procured using “new start” procurement); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idab3b7f56-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/d/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a class of craft undergoing a significant incremental change in its existing class (such as a next “flight” of destroyers or next “block” of attack submarines).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab3b7f57-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “future-years defense program” has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s221">section 221 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab3b7f58-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8669b/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “Milestone A approval” means a decision to enter into technology maturation and risk reduction pursuant to guidance prescribed by the Secretary of Defense for the management of Department of Defense acquisition programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idab3b7f59-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tX/s1034/a">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title X, § 1034(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1580">133 Stat. 1580</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXVIII/s1883/b/2">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1883(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4294">134 Stat. 4294</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tX/s1013">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title X, § 1013</ref>, div. A, title XVIII, § 1805(b)(2), <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1030">139 Stat. 1030</ref>, 1236.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idab3b7f5a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idab3b7f5b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idab3b7f5c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 and such date of enactment, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, which was approved <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idab3b7f5d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s1013/1">Pub. L. 119–60, § 1013(1)</ref>, amended subpar. (B) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (B) read as follows: “operates independently of chains-of-command for acquisition program management.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s1013/2">Pub. L. 119–60, § 1013(2)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s1805/b/2">Pub. L. 119–60, § 1805(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “means a decision to enter into technology maturation and risk reduction pursuant to guidance prescribed by the Secretary of Defense for the management of Department of Defense acquisition programs.” for “has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s4211">section 4211 of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> substituted “section 4211” for “section 2431a”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idab3b7f5e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idab3b7f5f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1883/b/2">section 1883(b)(2) of Pub. L. 116–283</ref> effective <date date="2022-01-01">Jan. 1, 2022</date>, with additional provisions for delayed implementation and applicability of existing law, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1801/d">section 1801(d) of Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idab3b7f60-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Exemption of Unmanned Surface Vessels and Unmanned Underwater Vehicles From Certain Technical Authority Requirements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tX/s1020">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title X, § 1020</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1033">139 Stat. 1033</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tX/s1020">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exemption From Senior Technical Authority Requirements</inline>.—</heading><content>Unmanned surface vessels and unmanned underwater vehicles acquired or developed by the Department of the Navy are exempt from any requirement for oversight by a senior technical authority established under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s8669b">section 8669b of title 10</ref>, United States Code, except the requirements, specifications, and approvals described in subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation Relating to Office of the Chief Engineer</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to subsection (c), the Chief Engineer of the Naval Sea Systems Command may not establish any requirement, specification, or approval for an unmanned surface vessel or an unmanned underwater vehicle unless such action is approved in advance by the program manager responsible for the respective unmanned system.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading><content>As the Secretary of the Navy considers appropriate, unmanned surface vessels and unmanned underwater vehicles may be subject to requirements, specifications, and approvals established by technical domain managers or technical warrant holders with responsibility for cybersecurity, ordnance and explosives, or warfare systems, without advanced approval described in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The term ‘unmanned surface vessel’ means a vessel designed to operate on the surface of the water without an onboard human crew.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘unmanned underwater vehicle’ means a vehicle designed to operate below the surface of the water without an onboard human crew.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
