<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idab3b8012-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8677"><num value="8677">§ 8677.</num><heading> Disposals to foreign nations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab3b8013-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8677/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Larger or Newer Vessels</inline>.—</heading><content>A naval vessel that is in excess of 3,000 tons or that is less than 20 years of age may not be disposed of to another nation (whether by sale, lease, grant, loan, barter, transfer, or otherwise) unless the disposal of that vessel, or of a vessel of the class of that vessel, is authorized by law enacted after <date date="1974-08-05">August 5, 1974</date>. A lease or loan of such a vessel under such a law may be made only in accordance with the provisions of chapter 6 of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2796">22 U.S.C. 2796</ref> et seq.) or chapter 2 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2311">22 U.S.C. 2311</ref> et seq.). In the case of an authorization by law for the disposal of such a vessel that names a specific vessel as being authorized for such disposal, the Secretary of Defense may substitute another vessel of the same class, if the vessel substituted has virtually identical capabilities as the named vessel. In the case of an authorization by law for the disposal of vessels of a specified class, the Secretary may dispose of vessels of that class pursuant to that authorization only in the number of such vessels specified in that law as being authorized for disposal.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab3b8014-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8677/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other Vessels</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab3b8015-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8677/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> A naval vessel not subject to subsection (a) may be disposed of to another nation (whether by sale, lease, grant, loan, barter, transfer, or otherwise) in accordance with applicable provisions of law, but only after—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab3b8016-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8677/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Secretary of the Navy notifies the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives in writing of the proposed disposition; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab3b8017-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8677/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> 30 days of continuous session of Congress have expired following the date on which such notice is sent to those committees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab3b8018-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8677/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> For purposes of paragraph (1)(B), the continuity of a session of Congress is broken only by an adjournment of the Congress sine die, and the days on which either House is not in session because of an adjournment of more than 3 days to a day certain are excluded in the computation of such 30-day period.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idab3b8019-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tVIII/s824/b">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title VIII, § 824(b)</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1709">107 Stat. 1709</ref>, § 7307; amended <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tXV/s1502/a/1">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/502">110 Stat. 502</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tX/s1067/1">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/774">113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tX/s1013">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1013</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2376">120 Stat. 2376</ref>; renumbered § 8677, <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tVIII/s807/d/2">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1836">132 Stat. 1836</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idab3b801a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idab3b801b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idab3b801c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Arms Export Control Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/90/629">Pub. L. 90–629</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1320">82 Stat. 1320</ref>, as amended. Chapter 6 of that Act is classified generally to subchapter VI (§ 2796 et seq.) of chapter 39 of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of Title 22</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, <date date="1961-09-04">Sept. 4, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/424">75 Stat. 424</ref>, as amended. Chapter 2 of part II of that Act is classified generally to part II (§ 2311 et seq.) of subchapter II of chapter 32 of Title 22. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">section 2151 of Title 22</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idab3b801d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—<ref href="/us/pl/115/232">Pub. L. 115–232</ref> renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s7307">section 7307 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364">Pub. L. 109–364</ref> substituted “disposal of that vessel, or of a vessel of the class of that vessel, is authorized” for “disposition of that vessel is approved” and inserted at end “In the case of an authorization by law for the disposal of such a vessel that names a specific vessel as being authorized for such disposal, the Secretary of Defense may substitute another vessel of the same class, if the vessel substituted has virtually identical capabilities as the named vessel. In the case of an authorization by law for the disposal of vessels of a specified class, the Secretary may dispose of vessels of that class pursuant to that authorization only in the number of such vessels specified in that law as being authorized for disposal.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/106/65">Pub. L. 106–65</ref> substituted “and the Committee on Armed Services” for “and the Committee on National Security”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106">Pub. L. 104–106</ref> substituted “Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on National Security of the House of Representatives” for “Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idab3dca0e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idab3dca0f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2018 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/115/232">Pub. L. 115–232</ref> effective <date date="2019-02-01">Feb. 1, 2019</date>, with provision for the coordination of amendments and special rule for certain redesignations, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s800">section 800 of Pub. L. 115–232</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
