<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idab4c225b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8782"><num value="8782">§ 8782.</num><heading> Naval and Marine Corps Historical Centers: fee for providing historical information to the public</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab4c225c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8782/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subsection (b), the Secretary of the Navy may charge a person a fee for providing the person with information from the United States Naval Historical Center or the Marine Corps Historical Center that is requested by that person.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab4c225d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8782/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A fee may not be charged under this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab4c225e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8782/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to a person for information that the person requests to carry out a duty as a member of the armed forces or an officer or employee of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab4c225f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8782/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> for a release of information under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">section 552 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab4c2260-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8782/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Amount</inline>.—</heading><content>A fee charged for providing information under this section may not exceed the cost of providing the information.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab4c2261-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8782/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Retention of Fees</inline>.—</heading><content>Amounts received under subsection (a) for providing information from the United States Naval Historical Center or the Marine Corps Historical Center in any fiscal year shall be credited to the appropriation or appropriations charged the costs of providing information to the public from that historical center during that fiscal year.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab4c2262-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8782/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab4c2263-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8782/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “United States Naval Historical Center” means the archive for historical records and materials of the Navy that the Secretary of the Navy designates as the primary archive for such records and materials.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab4c2264-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8782/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “Marine Corps Historical Center” means the archive for historical records and materials of the Marine Corps that the Secretary of the Navy designates as the primary archive for such records and materials.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab4c2265-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s8782/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The terms “officer of the United States” and “employee of the United States” have the meanings given the terms “officer” and “employee”, respectively, in sections 2104 and 2105, respectively, of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idab4c2266-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title X, § 1085(b)(1)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–288, § 7582; renumbered § 8782, <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tVIII/s807/d/9">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(9)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1837">132 Stat. 1837</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idab4c2267-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idab4c2268-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idab4c2269-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Prior sections 8782 to 8787 and 8791 to 8797 were repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/96/513/tII/s213">Pub. L. 96–513, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2885">94 Stat. 2885</ref>, effective <date date="1981-09-15">Sept. 15, 1981</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 8782, acts <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041">Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/543">70A Stat. 543</ref>; <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/86/616/s7/a">Pub. L. 86–616, § 7(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/391">74 Stat. 391</ref>, provided for boards of inquiry, composed of three or more officers, to be convened at such places as Secretary of Air Force prescribes, to receive evidence and make findings and recommendations whether an officer, required to show cause under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s8781">section 8781 of this title</ref>, should be retained on active list of Regular Air Force. See <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1182">section 1182 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 8783, acts <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041">Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/543">70A Stat. 543</ref>; <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/86/616/s7/a">Pub. L. 86–616, § 7(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/391">74 Stat. 391</ref>, provided for boards of review, composed of three or more officers, to be convened by Secretary of Air Force, at such places as he prescribes, to review records of cases of officers recommended by boards of inquiry for removal from active list of Regular Air Force.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 8784, acts <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041">Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/543">70A Stat. 543</ref>; <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/86/616/s7/a">Pub. L. 86–616, § 7(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/392">74 Stat. 392</ref>, authorized Secretary of Air Force to remove an officer from active list of Regular Air Force if his removal is recommended by a board of review and provided that decision of Secretary in such case is final and conclusive. See <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1184">section 1184 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 8785, acts <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041">Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/543">70A Stat. 543</ref>; <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/86/616/s7/a">Pub. L. 86–616, § 7(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/392">74 Stat. 392</ref>, provided that each officer under consideration for removal from active list of Regular Air Force under this chapter, be given written notification, at least 30 days prior to a board of inquiry hearing, that he is being required to show cause for retention on active list, be allowed reasonable time to prepare a defense, be allowed to appear in person and by counsel at proceedings before a board of inquiry, and be allowed full access to, and furnished copies of, records relevant to his case at all stages of the proceeding. See <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1185">section 1185 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 8786, acts <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041">Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/544">70A Stat. 544</ref>; <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/86/616/s7/a">Pub. L. 86–616, § 7(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/392">74 Stat. 392</ref>, authorized Secretary of Air Force, at any time during proceedings under this chapter and before removal of an officer from active list of Regular Air Force, to grant that officer’s request for voluntary retirement, if he is otherwise qualified therefor, or for honorable discharge with severance benefits. See <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1186">section 1186 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 8787, added <ref href="/us/pl/86/616/s7/a">Pub. L. 86–616, § 7(a)</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/392">74 Stat. 392</ref>, provided that no officer serve on a board under this chapter unless he holds a regular or temporary grade above lieutenant colonel, and is senior in regular grade to, and outranks, any officer considered by that board and that no person be a member of more than one board convened under this chapter for same officer. See <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1187">section 1187 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 8791, added <ref href="/us/pl/86/616/s8/a">Pub. L. 86–616, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/393">74 Stat. 393</ref>, authorized Secretary of Air Force to convene at any time a board of general officers to review record of any commissioned officer on active list of Regular Air Force to determine whether he should be required, because of moral dereliction, professional dereliction, or because his retention is not clearly consistent with the interests of national security, to show cause for his retention on active list. See <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1181/b">section 1181(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 8792, added <ref href="/us/pl/86/616/s8/a">Pub. L. 86–616, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/393">74 Stat. 393</ref>, provided for boards of inquiry, composed of three or more general officers, to be convened at such places as Secretary of Air Force prescribes, to receive evidence and make findings and recommendations whether an officer, required to show cause under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s8791">section 8791 of this title</ref>, should be retained on active list of the Regular Air Force. See <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1182">section 1182 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 8793, added <ref href="/us/pl/86/616/s8/a">Pub. L. 86–616, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/393">74 Stat. 393</ref>, provided for boards of review, composed of three or more general officers, to be convened by Secretary of Air Force, at such places as he prescribes, to review the records of cases of officers recommended by boards of inquiry for removal from active list of Regular Air Force.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 8794, added <ref href="/us/pl/86/616/s8/a">Pub. L. 86–616, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/394">74 Stat. 394</ref>, authorized Secretary of Air Force to remove an officer from active list of Regular Air Force if his removal is recommended by a board of review and provided that decision of Secretary in such a case is final and conclusive. See <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1184">section 1184 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 8795, added <ref href="/us/pl/86/616/s8/a">Pub. L. 86–616, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/394">74 Stat. 394</ref>, provided that each officer under consideration for removal from active list of Regular Air Force under this chapter be given written notification, at least 30 days prior to a board of inquiry hearing, that he is being required to show cause for retention on active list, be allowed reasonable time to prepare a defense, be allowed to appear in person and by counsel at proceedings before the board of inquiry, and be allowed full access to, and furnished copies of, records relevant to his case at all stages of the proceedings, except records that the Secretary determines be withheld in interests of national security, in which case, a summary, to the extent national security permits, be furnished. See <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1185">section 1185 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 8796, added <ref href="/us/pl/86/616/s8/a">Pub. L. 86–616, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/394">74 Stat. 394</ref>, authorized Secretary of Air Force, at any time during proceedings under this chapter and before removal of an officer from active list of Regular Air Force, to grant that officer’s request for voluntary retirement, if he is otherwise qualified therefor, or for honorable discharge with severance benefits. See <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1186">section 1186 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 8797, added <ref href="/us/pl/86/616/s8/a">Pub. L. 86–616, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/394">74 Stat. 394</ref>, provided that no officer serve on a board under this chapter unless he holds a regular or temporary grade above lieutenant colonel, and is senior in regular grade to, and outranks, any officer considered by that board and that no person be a member of more than one board convened under this chapter for the same officer. See <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1187">section 1187 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idab4e926a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—<ref href="/us/pl/115/232">Pub. L. 115–232</ref> renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s7582">section 7582 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idab4e926b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idab4e926c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2018 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/115/232">Pub. L. 115–232</ref> effective <date date="2019-02-01">Feb. 1, 2019</date>, with provision for the coordination of amendments and special rule for certain redesignations, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s800">section 800 of Pub. L. 115–232</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
