<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idab5cc331-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9025"><num value="9025">§ 9025.</num><heading> Office of Expanded Competition</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab5cc332-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9025/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><content>There is in the Office of the Secretary of the Air Force an office to be known as the Office of Expanded Competition (in this section referred to as the “Office”).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab5cc333-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9025/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Director</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The head of the Office shall be the Director. The Director shall be appointed by the Secretary of the Air Force from among employees of the Department of Defense with requisite subject matter expertise who—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab5cc334-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9025/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> are in a Senior Executive Service position (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3132">section 3132 of title 5</ref>) at the time of appointment; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab5cc335-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9025/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> are not in a Senior Executive Service position at the time of appointment, but meet the Executive Core Qualifications (ECQs) for such a position.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab5cc336-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9025/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The duties of the Office are as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab5cc337-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9025/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In consultation with other components of the Department of Defense and the Federal Government, conduct coordinated and integrated assessments of adversarial capital flows into industries or businesses of interest to the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab5cc338-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9025/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Identify and prioritize promising critical technologies and assets for the Joint Force in need of capital assistance, including critical technologies and assets available from foreign entities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab5cc339-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9025/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Fund investments in such technologies and assets, including supply chain technologies not always supported through direct investment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab5cc33a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9025/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Support the coordination and outreach efforts of technology scouting and acquisition elements within the Department of Defense to enable investment decision-making by those elements that counteract entities employing adversarial capital flows against industries or businesses described in paragraph (1), including the employment of relevant authorities vested in other components of the Department and the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab5cc33b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9025/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Identify, accelerate, and sustain the establishment, research, development, construction, procurement, leasing, consolidation, alteration, improvement, modernization, and repair of tangible and intangible assets vital to the national security of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab5cc33c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9025/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Help the Department of Defense provide capital assistance to entities, including foreign entities, engaged in investments that facilitate the efforts of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab5cc33d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9025/c/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Experiment, prototype, test, or validate Government-developed or commercially developed analytical tools, processes, and tradecraft to improve the due diligence and investment analysis processes for the Department of Defense, including the employment of relevant delegated authorities vested in other components of the Department and the Federal Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab5cc33e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9025/c/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> Assist the Secretary of Defense in developing access and placement using commercial means.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab5cc33f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9025/c/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> Otherwise engage with, coordinate, and collaborate with other components of the Department of Defense and the Federal Government to maximize efficiencies and promote whole-of-government solutions to protect the national security of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab5cc340-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9025/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab5cc341-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9025/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The term “adversarial capital flow” means an investment by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab5cc342-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9025/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the government of a country that is an adversary of the United States; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab5cc343-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9025/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> an entity organized under the laws of, or otherwise subject to the jurisdiction of, such a country.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab5cc344-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9025/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “capital assistance” means a loan, loan guarantee, or technical assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idab5cc345-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tIX/s924/a">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title IX, § 924(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2039">138 Stat. 2039</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
