<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idab74b844-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442"><num value="9442">§ 9442.</num><heading> Cadets: appointment; numbers, territorial distribution</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab74b845-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> The authorized strength of cadets of the Academy (determined for any year as of the day before the last day of the academic year) is 4,400 or such lower number as may be prescribed by the Secretary of the Air Force under subsection (j). Subject to that limitation, cadets are selected as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab74b846-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> 65 cadets selected in order of merit as established by competitive examination from the children of members of the armed forces who were killed in action or died of, or have a service-connected disability rated at not less than 100 per centum resulting from wounds or injuries received or diseases contracted in, or preexisting injury or disease aggravated by, active service, children of members who are in a “missing status” as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t37/s551/2">section 551(2) of title 37</ref>, and children of civilian employees who are in “missing status” as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5561/5">section 5561(5) of title 5</ref>. The determination of the Department of Veterans Affairs as to service connection of the cause of death or disability, and the percentage at which the disability is rated, is binding upon the Secretary of the Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab74b847-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Five cadets nominated at large by the Vice President or, if there is no Vice President, by the President pro tempore of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab74b848-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Ten cadets from each State, five of whom are nominated by each Senator from that State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab74b849-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Five cadets from each congressional district, nominated by the Representative from the district.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab74b84a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Five cadets from the District of Columbia, nominated by the Delegate to the House of Representatives from the District of Columbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab74b84b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Four cadets from the Virgin Islands, nominated by the Delegate in Congress from the Virgin Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab74b84c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Six cadets from Puerto Rico, five of whom are nominated by the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico and one who is a native of Puerto Rico nominated by the Governor of Puerto Rico.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab74b84d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> Five cadets from Guam, nominated by the Delegate in Congress from Guam.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab74b84e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> Three cadets from American Samoa, nominated by the Delegate in Congress from American Samoa.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab74b84f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> Three cadets from the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, nominated by the Delegate in Congress from the commonwealth.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Each Senator, Representative, and Delegate in Congress, including the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico, is entitled to nominate 15 persons for each vacancy that is available to him under this section. Nominees may be submitted without ranking or with a principal candidate and up to 14 ranked or unranked alternates. Qualified nominees not selected for appointment under this subsection shall be considered qualified alternates for the purposes of selection under other provisions of this chapter. When a nominee of a Senator, Representative, or Delegate is selected for appointment as a cadet, the Senator, Representative, or Delegate shall be notified at least 48 hours before the official notification or announcement of the appointment is made.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab74b850-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> In addition, there may be appointed each year at the Academy cadets as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab74b851-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> one hundred selected by the President from the children of members of an armed force who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab74b852-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> are on active duty (other than for training) and who have served continuously on active duty for at least eight years;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab74b853-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> are, or who died while they were, retired with pay or granted retired or retainer pay;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab74b854-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> are serving as members of reserve components, or the Space Force, and are credited with at least eight years of service computed under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12733">section 12733 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab74b855-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> would be, or who died while they would have been, entitled to retired pay under chapter 1223 of this title except for not having attained 60 years of age;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">however, a person who is eligible for selection under paragraph (1) of subsection (a) may not be selected under this paragraph.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab74b856-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> 85 nominated by the Secretary of the Air Force from enlisted members of the Regular Air Force or the Space Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab74b857-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> 85 nominated by the Secretary of the Air Force from enlisted members of reserve components of the Air Force.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab74b858-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> 20 nominated by the Secretary of the Air Force, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, from the honor graduates of schools designated as honor schools by the Department of the Army, the Department of the Navy, or the Department of the Air Force, and from members of the Air Force Reserve Officers’ Training Corps.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab74b859-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> 200 <sup>1</sup> selected by the Secretary of the Air Force in order of merit (prescribed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s9443">section 9443 of this title</ref>) from qualified alternates nominated by persons named in paragraphs (3) through (10) of subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab74b85a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The President may also appoint as cadets at the Academy children of persons who have been awarded the Medal of Honor for acts performed while in the armed forces.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab74b85b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> The Superintendent may nominate for appointment each year 50 persons from the country at large. Persons nominated under this paragraph may not displace any appointment authorized under paragraphs (2) through (9) of subsection (a) and may not cause the total strength of cadets to exceed the authorized number.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab74b85c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> If the annual quota of cadets under subsection (b)(1), (2), or (3) is not filled, the Secretary may fill the vacancies by nominating for appointment other candidates from any of these sources who were found best qualified on examination for admission and not otherwise nominated.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab74b85d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> Each candidate for admission nominated under paragraphs (3) through (9) of subsection (a) must be domiciled in the State, or in the congressional district, from which he is nominated, or in the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, American Samoa, Guam, or the Virgin Islands, if nominated from one of those places.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab74b85e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of the Air Force may limit the number of cadets authorized to be appointed under this section to the number that can be adequately accommodated at the Academy as determined by the Secretary after consulting with the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives, subject to the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab74b85f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Cadets chargeable to each nominating authority named in subsection (a)(3) or (4) may not be limited to less than four.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab74b860-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> If the Secretary limits the number of appointments under subsection (a)(3) or (4), appointments under subsection (b)(1)–(4) are limited as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab74b861-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/g/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> 27 appointments under subsection (b)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab74b862-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/g/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> 27 appointments under subsection (b)(2);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab74b863-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/g/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> 27 appointments under subsection (b)(3); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab74b864-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/g/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> 13 appointments under subsection (b)(4).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab74b865-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> If the Secretary limits the number of appointments under subsection (b)(5), appointments under subsection (b)(2)–(4) are limited as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab74b866-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/g/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> 27 appointments under subsection (b)(2);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab74b867-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/g/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> 27 appointments under subsection (b)(3); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idab74b868-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/g/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> 13 appointments under subsection (b)(4).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idab74b869-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The limitations provided for in this subsection do not affect the operation of subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab74b86a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content> The Superintendent shall furnish to any Member of Congress, upon the written request of such Member, the name of the Congressman or other nominating authority responsible for the nomination of any named or identified person for appointment to the Academy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab74b86b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> For purposes of the limitation in subsection (a) establishing the aggregate authorized strength of cadets, the Secretary of the Air Force may for any year permit a variance in that limitation by not more than one percent. In applying that limitation, and any such variance, the last day of an academic year shall be considered to be graduation day.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab74b86c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab74b86d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Beginning with the 2003–2004 academic year, the Secretary of the Air Force may prescribe annual increases in the cadet strength limit in effect under subsection (a). For any academic year, any such increase shall be by no more than 100 cadets or such lesser number as applies under paragraph (3) for that year. Such annual increases may be prescribed until the cadet strength limit is 4,400.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab74b86e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any increase in the cadet strength limit under paragraph (1) with respect to an academic year shall be prescribed not later than the date on which the budget of the President is submitted to Congress under sections 1105 of title 31 for the fiscal year beginning in the same year as the year in which that academic year begins. Whenever the Secretary prescribes such an increase, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a notice in writing of the increase. The notice shall state the amount of the increase in the cadet strength limit and the new cadet strength limit, as so increased, and the amount of the increase in Senior Air Force Reserve Officers’ Training Corps enrollment under each of sections 2104 and 2107 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab74b86f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/j/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The amount of an increase under paragraph (1) in the cadet strength limit for an academic year may not exceed the increase (if any) for the preceding academic year in the total number of cadets enrolled in the Air Force Senior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps program under chapter 103 of this title who have entered into an agreement under section 2104 or 2107 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idab74b870-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s9442/j/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> In this subsection, the term “cadet strength limit” means the authorized maximum strength of cadets of the Academy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idab74b871-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(<ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041">Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/563">70A Stat. 563</ref>, § 9342; <ref href="/us/pl/87/663/s1/5">Pub. L. 87–663, § 1(5)</ref>, (6), <date date="1962-09-14">Sept. 14, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/547">76 Stat. 547</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/276/s4/1">Pub. L. 88–276, § 4(1)</ref>, <date date="1964-03-03">Mar. 3, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/151">78 Stat. 151</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/650/s1/1">Pub. L. 89–650, § 1(1)</ref>–(3), (5), <date date="1966-10-13">Oct. 13, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/896">80 Stat. 896</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/374">Pub. L. 90–374</ref>, <date date="1968-07-05">July 5, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/283">82 Stat. 283</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/623/s2/8">Pub. L. 90–623, § 2(8)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1314">82 Stat. 1314</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/405/tII/s204/c">Pub. L. 91–405, title II, § 204(c)</ref>, <date date="1970-09-22">Sept. 22, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/852">84 Stat. 852</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/365/s1/3">Pub. L. 92–365, § 1(3)</ref>, <date date="1972-08-07">Aug. 7, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/505">86 Stat. 505</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/171/s3/1">Pub. L. 93–171, § 3(1)</ref>–(4), <date date="1973-11-29">Nov. 29, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/690">87 Stat. 690</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/106/tVIII/s803/b/1">Pub. L. 94–106, title VIII, § 803(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1975-10-07">Oct. 7, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/538">89 Stat. 538</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/513/tV/s514/11">Pub. L. 96–513, title V, § 514(11)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2935">94 Stat. 2935</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/600/s2/c">Pub. L. 96–600, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/3493">94 Stat. 3493</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/60/tII/s203/c/1">Pub. L. 97–60, title II, § 203(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-10-14">Oct. 14, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1006">95 Stat. 1006</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/94/tX/s1005/a/3">Pub. L. 98–94, title X, § 1005(a)(3)</ref>, (b)(3), <date date="1983-09-24">Sept. 24, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/660">97 Stat. 660</ref>, 661; <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tXVI/s1621/a/1">Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1621(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1602">103 Stat. 1602</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/dA/tV/s532/c/1">Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title V, § 532(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1563">104 Stat. 1563</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tV/s531">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 531</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1657">107 Stat. 1657</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dA/tXVI/s1674/c/3">Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1674(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3017">108 Stat. 3017</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tV/s532/c">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title V, § 532(c)</ref>, title XV, § 1502(a)(1), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/315">110 Stat. 315</ref>, 502; <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tX/s1073/a/62">Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title X, § 1073(a)(62)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1903">111 Stat. 1903</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tV/s531/b/3">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 531(b)(3)</ref>, title X, § 1067(1), <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/602">113 Stat. 602</ref>, 774; <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 531(c)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–110; <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tV/s532/c">Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title V, § 532(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2546">116 Stat. 2546</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dA/tV/s524/c">Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 524(c)</ref>, title X, § 1031(a)(58), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1464">117 Stat. 1464</ref>, 1603; <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dA/tX/s1071/a/38">Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1071(a)(38)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2400">120 Stat. 2400</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/229/tVII/s718/c">Pub. L. 110–229, title VII, § 718(c)</ref>, <date date="2008-05-08">May 8, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/869">122 Stat. 869</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/417">Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title V, § 540(c), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4454">122 Stat. 4454</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/dA/tV/s527/c">Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title V, § 527(c)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2288">123 Stat. 2288</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dA/tX/s1076/f/42">Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title X, § 1076(f)(42)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1954">126 Stat. 1954</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/92/dA/tV/s556/c">Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title V, § 556(c)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/825">129 Stat. 825</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tV/s566/c">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 566(c)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2139">130 Stat. 2139</ref>; renumbered § 9442 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tVIII">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII</ref>, §§ 806(a)(3), 809(a), <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/1832">132 Stat. 1832</ref>, 1840; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tIX/s923/d/10">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(d)(10)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3815">134 Stat. 3815</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dA/tV/s552/c">Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 552(c)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2592">136 Stat. 2592</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tV">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V</ref>, §§ 561(c), 562(c), title XVII, § 1721(c)(2), <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/273">137 Stat. 273</ref>, 274, 666; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tV/s555/c">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title V, § 555(c)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/878">139 Stat. 878</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idab770262-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idab770263-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<html:table class="HNR" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc: c3,L2,tp7,s10,xls80,xs80,tp7,s10,xls80,xs80; " id="idab770264-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 38pt;" />
<html:col style="width:84pt ; max-width:84pt;" />
<html:col style="width:84pt ; max-width:84pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style=""><html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Historical and Revision Notes</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="min-width: 38.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Revised section</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:84.0pt ; max-width:84.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (U.S. Code)</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:84.0pt ; max-width:84.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (Statutes at Large)</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em; margin-bottom:0em;" class="leaders"><html:span>9342(a)</html:span></html:p><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em; margin-top:0em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em; margin-bottom:0em;">10:1092a (1st par., less clauses (a) through (e)).</html:p><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em; margin-top:0em;">10:1092a (clauses (a), less 14th through 52d words after 4th semicolon; and less last 32 words).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em; margin-bottom:0em;">R.S. 1317.</html:p><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em; margin-top:0em;"><html:a href="/us/act/1950-06-30/ch421">June 30, 1950, ch. 421</html:a>, §§ 1, 2 (last proviso), <html:a href="/us/stat/64/303">64 stat. 303</html:a>, 304; <html:a href="/us/act/1954-06-03/ch251/s2">June 3, 1954, ch. 251, § 2</html:a>, <html:a href="/us/stat/68/169">68 Stat. 169</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">10:1092a (1st 13 words of clause (b)).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">10:1092a (1st 26 words of clause (c)).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">10:1092a (clause (d)).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">10:1092a (clause (e), less last 53 words).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>9342(b)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">10:1092a (last par.).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">10:1098.</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>9342(c)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">10:1092a (14th through 52d words after 4th semicolon of clause (a)).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I22;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"> </html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">10:1092b (last proviso).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>9342(d)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">10:1092a (last 32 words of clause (a)).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>9342(e)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">10:1092a (clause (b), less 1st 13 words, and less 1st proviso).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>9342(f)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">10:1092a (1st proviso of clause (b)).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>9342(g)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">10:1092a (clause (c), less 1st 26 words).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
<html:tr style="-uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>9342(h)</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">10:1092a (last 53 words of clause (e)).</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:right; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;" /></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (a), the words “the authorized strength * * * is as follows—” are substituted for the words “shall be authorized and consist of the following”. The words “at large” and “which totals two thousand four hundred and ninety-six”, and 10:1092a (clause (d)) are omitted as surplusage.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (b), the words “from whatever source of admission”, in 10:1092a, are omitted as surplusage. 10:1098 (words before last semicolon) is omitted as obsolete.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (c), the first 15 words are substituted for the words “all of which cadets shall be”. The words “domiciled in” are substituted for the words “actual residents of” to conform to opinions of the Judge Advocate General of the Army (R. 29, 83; J.A.G. 351.11, <date date="1925-02-10">Feb. 10, 1925</date>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (e)(4), the words “armed forces” are substituted for the description of the land or naval forces. The date <date date="1955-02-01">February 1, 1955</date>, fixed by Proclamation No. 3080 (<date date="1955-01-07">Jan. 7, 1955</date>; 20 F.R. 173), is substituted for the words “such date as shall thereafter be determined by Presidential proclamation or concurrent resolution of the Congress under <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s745">section 745 of title 38</ref>”. The words “including male and female members of * * * and all components thereof” are omitted as surplusage.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (f), the words “whether a death is service-connected” are substituted for the words “as to the service connection of the cause of death”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (g), the words “(National Guard of the United States, the Air National Guard of the United States and Army Reserve, and the Air Force Reserve)”, “Regular components”, “by members of the National Guard of the United States, and the Air National Guard of the United States”, and “established at the competitive entrance examination” are omitted as surplusage. The word “grades” is substituted for the words “proficiency averages”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (h), the words “or shall hereafter be” are omitted as surplusage.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idab770265-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idab770266-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 9442 was renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s9492">section 9492 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another prior section 9442, added <ref href="/us/pl/98/525/tXV/s1533/b/1">Pub. L. 98–525, title XV, § 1533(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2632">98 Stat. 2632</ref>, related to assistance of Civil Air Patrol by other agencies, prior to the general amendment of former chapter 909 (now 959) of this title by <ref href="/us/pl/106/398">Pub. L. 106–398</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idab770267-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60">Pub. L. 119–60</ref> substituted “up to 14 ranked or unranked alternates” for “9 ranked or unranked alternates” in concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2023—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s561/c/1">Pub. L. 118–31, § 561(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “15 persons” for “10 persons” in concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s562/c">Pub. L. 118–31, § 562(c)</ref>, substituted “Five” for “Four”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s1721/c/2/A">Pub. L. 118–31, § 1721(c)(2)(A)</ref>, inserted “, or the Space Force,” after “members of reserve components”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s1721/c/2/B">Pub. L. 118–31, § 1721(c)(2)(B)</ref>, struck out “Regular” before “Space Force”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s561/c/2">Pub. L. 118–31, § 561(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “200” for “150”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Pub. L. 117–263</ref> substituted “paragraphs (3) through (10)” for “paragraphs (3) and (4)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—<ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s923/d/10/A/i">Pub. L. 116–283, § 923(d)(10)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “cadets” for “Air Force Cadets” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s923/d/10/A/ii">Pub. L. 116–283, § 923(d)(10)(A)(ii)</ref>, inserted “or the Regular Space Force” after “Regular Air Force”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s923/d/10/B">Pub. L. 116–283, § 923(d)(10)(B)</ref>, substituted “prescribed by the Secretary” for “prescribed by him”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—<ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s806/a/3">Pub. L. 115–232, § 806(a)(3)</ref>, renumbered <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s9342">section 9342 of this title</ref> as this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s809/a">Pub. L. 115–232, § 809(a)</ref>, substituted “section 9443” for “section 9343”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328">Pub. L. 114–328</ref> inserted at end of concluding provisions “When a nominee of a Senator, Representative, or Delegate is selected for appointment as a cadet, the Senator, Representative, or Delegate shall be notified at least 48 hours before the official notification or announcement of the appointment is made.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/114/92/s556/c/1">Pub. L. 114–92, § 556(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “Four” for “Three”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/114/92/s556/c/2">Pub. L. 114–92, § 556(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “Four” for “Three”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/114/92/s556/c/3">Pub. L. 114–92, § 556(c)(3)</ref>, substituted “Three” for “Two”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/114/92/s556/c/4">Pub. L. 114–92, § 556(c)(4)</ref>, substituted “Three” for “Two”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1076/f/42/A/i">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1076(f)(42)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “paragraph” for “clause” in two places in concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b)(5), (d), (f). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s1076/f/42/A/ii">Pub. L. 112–239, § 1076(f)(42)(A)(ii)</ref>–(C), substituted “paragraphs” for “clauses”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (a)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/111/84">Pub. L. 111–84</ref> substituted “Two cadets” for “One cadet”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/110/417/s540/c/1">Pub. L. 110–417, § 540(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “4,400 or such lower number” for “4,000 or such higher number” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/110/229">Pub. L. 110–229</ref> substituted “Delegate in Congress” for “resident representative”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/110/417/s540/c/2">Pub. L. 110–417, § 540(c)(2)</ref>, struck out last sentence which read as follows: “However, no increase may be prescribed for any academic year after the 2007–2008 academic year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (a)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/109/364">Pub. L. 109–364</ref> substituted “cadets” for “cadet”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (a)(6), (8). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/s524/c/1">Pub. L. 108–136, § 524(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “Three” for “Two”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/s524/c/2">Pub. L. 108–136, § 524(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “Two” for “One”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/s1031/a/58">Pub. L. 108–136, § 1031(a)(58)</ref>, substituted “Superintendent” for “Secretary of the Air Force”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s532/c/1">Pub. L. 107–314, § 532(c)(1)</ref>, inserted before period at end of first sentence “or such higher number as may be prescribed by the Secretary of the Air Force under subsection (j)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s532/c/2">Pub. L. 107–314, § 532(c)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (b)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 531(c)(1)], struck out “, other than those granted retired pay under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12731">section 12731 of this title</ref> (or under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1331">section 1331 of this title</ref> as in effect before the effective date of the Reserve Officer Personnel Management Act)” after “retired or retainer pay”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(C), (D). <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title V, § 531(c)(2)], added subpars. (C) and (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/s531/b/3/A">Pub. L. 106–65, § 531(b)(3)(A)</ref>, substituted “(determined for any year as of the day before the last day of the academic year) is 4,000. Subject to that limitation, Air Force Cadets are selected as follows:” for “is as follows:” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/s1067/1">Pub. L. 106–65, § 1067(1)</ref>, substituted “and the Committee on Armed Services” for “and the Committee on National Security” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/s531/b/3/B">Pub. L. 106–65, § 531(b)(3)(B)</ref>, added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (a)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/105/85">Pub. L. 105–85</ref> substituted “Mariana” for “Marianas”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s532/c">Pub. L. 104–106, § 532(c)</ref>, added par. (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s1502/a/1">Pub. L. 104–106, § 1502(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on National Security of the House of Representatives” for “Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/103/337">Pub. L. 103–337</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s12731">section 12731 of this title</ref> (or under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1331">section 1331 of this title</ref> as in effect before the effective date of the Reserve Officer Personnel Management Act)” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1331">section 1331 of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/160">Pub. L. 103–160</ref>, in concluding provisions, substituted “10 persons” for “a principal candidate and nine alternates” and inserted at end “Nominees may be submitted without ranking or with a principal candidate and 9 ranked or unranked alternates. Qualified nominees not selected for appointment under this subsection shall be considered qualified alternates for the purposes of selection under other provisions of this chapter.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a)(8) to (10). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s532/c/1/A">Pub. L. 101–510, § 532(c)(1)(A)</ref>, redesignated cls. (9) and (10) as (8) and (9), respectively, and struck out former cl. (8) which read as follows: “One cadet nominated by the Administrator of the Panama Canal Commission from the children of civilian personnel of the United States Government residing in the Republic of Panama who are citizens of the United States.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s532/c/1/B">Pub. L. 101–510, § 532(c)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “clauses (2) through (9)” for “clauses (2)–(7), (9), or (10)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/101/510/s532/c/1/C">Pub. L. 101–510, § 532(c)(1)(C)</ref>, substituted “clauses (3) through (9)” for “clauses (3)–(7), (9) and (10)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/189">Pub. L. 101–189</ref> substituted “Department of Veterans Affairs” for “Veterans’ Administration”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (a)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/98/94/s1005/b/3">Pub. L. 98–94, § 1005(b)(3)</ref>, substituted: “One cadet nominated by the Administrator of the Panama Canal Commission from the children of civilian personnel of the United States Government residing in the Republic of Panama who are citizens of the United States” for “One cadet nominated by the Governor of the Panama Canal from the children of civilians residing in the Canal Zone or the children of civilian personnel of the United States Government, or the Panama Canal Company, residing in the Republic of Panama”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/98/94/s1005/a/3">Pub. L. 98–94, § 1005(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “One cadet from American Samoa, nominated by the Delegate in Congress from American Samoa” for “One cadet from American Samoa nominated by the Secretary of the Air Force upon recommendation of the Governor of American Samoa”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/60">Pub. L. 97–60</ref> substituted provisions authorizing the Superintendent to nominate for appointment each year 50 persons from the country at large for provisions that all cadets were to be appointed by the President and that all such appointments were conditional until the cadets were admitted. See <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s9341a">section 9341a of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a)(6), (9). <ref href="/us/pl/96/600">Pub. L. 96–600</ref> substituted “Two cadets” for “One cadet”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/96/513">Pub. L. 96–513</ref> substituted “The” for “Effective beginning with the nominations for appointment to the Academy in the calendar year 1964, the”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsecs. (a)(1), (8), (b)(1), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/94/106">Pub. L. 94–106</ref> substituted “children” for “sons” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/93/171/s3/1">Pub. L. 93–171, § 3(1)</ref>, substituted “One cadet from the Virgin Islands, nominated by the Delegate in Congress from the Virgin Islands” for “Five cadets from each Territory, nominated by the Delegate in Congress from that Territory”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/93/171/s3/2">Pub. L. 93–171, § 3(2)</ref>, struck out reference to American Samoa and Virgin Islands.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/93/171/s3/3">Pub. L. 93–171, § 3(3)</ref>, added cl. (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/93/171/s3/4">Pub. L. 93–171, § 3(4)</ref>, substituted “, (9) and (10) of subsection (a)” for “and (9) of subsection (a)” and struck out reference to Territory.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1972—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/92/365">Pub. L. 92–365</ref> increased number of Air Force Cadets from 40 to 65 and added sons of members who are in missing status and sons of civilian employees who are in missing status as eligible for competitive examination.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/91/405">Pub. L. 91–405</ref> substituted “delegate to the House of Representatives from the District of Columbia” for “Commissioner of that District”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/90/374">Pub. L. 90–374</ref> increased from five to nine the number of alternates for each vacancy each Senator, Representative, and Delegate in Congress, including the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico, is entitled to nominate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/90/623">Pub. L. 90–623</ref> substituted “Commissioner” for “Commissioners”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/89/650/s1/1">Pub. L. 89–650, § 1(1)</ref>, provided for selection of cadets to the Air Force Academy from sons of members of the armed forces who have a 100 per centum service-connected disability and removed the limitation to active service during World War I or World War II or after <date date="1950-06-26">June 26, 1950</date>, and before <date date="1955-02-01">Feb. 1, 1955</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/89/650/s1/2">Pub. L. 89–650, § 1(2)</ref>, provided for nominations to Air Force Academy by President pro tempore of Senate if there is no Vice President.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/89/650/s1/3">Pub. L. 89–650, § 1(3)</ref>, increased number of Presidential appointments to Air Force Academy from 75 to 100, provided for selection of eligible persons as stated in items (A) and (B), previously chosen from sons of members of regular components, and declared persons eligible under subsec. (a)(1) ineligible under subsec. (b)(1) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/89/650/s1/5">Pub. L. 89–650, § 1(5)</ref>, substituted “reserve components of the Air Force” for “the Air Force Reserve”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1964—<ref href="/us/pl/88/276">Pub. L. 88–276</ref> amended section generally, and among other changes, in the noncompetitive appointments, increased the number of cadets nominated by the Vice President from three to five, each Senator, Representative and Delegate from 4 to 5, and the Commissioner of Puerto Rico from 4 to 5, authorized the Governor of Puerto Rico to appoint one cadet, each Senator, Representative and Delegate to nominate a principal and five alternates for each vacancy, and, in the competitive appointments, permitted the President to appoint 75 cadets annually from the sons of members of the Regular components, instead of a cumulative total of 89, the Secretary of the Air Force to appoint 85 cadets annually from enlisted members of the Regular Air Force, instead of a cumulative total of 90, 85 annually from enlisted members of the Air Force Reserve, instead of a cumulative total of 90, 20 annually from honor graduates of designated honor schools and the A.F.R.O.T.C., instead of a cumulative total of 40 from honor schools only, 150 annually, in order of merit, from among the qualified alternates nominated by Members of Congress, and when the quota of cadets selected under subsec. (b)(1), (2), (3) is not filled, to fill the vacancies by appointing those best qualified from any of the three sources, decreased the number of cadets nominated by the Commissioners of the District of Columbia from 6 to 5, and by the Governor of the Panama Canal from 2 to 1, limited appointments to the number that can be adequately accommodated at the Academy, within the limitation that congressional appointments cannot be limited to less than four, and if limited, a priority of selection is established for the other categories, and, beginning in 1964, the Secretary may upon request of a Member of Congress, furnish him the name of any nominating authority responsible for the nomination of any identified person to the Academy.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Subsec. (a)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/87/663/s1/5">Pub. L. 87–663, § 1(5)</ref>, added cl. (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/87/663/s1/6">Pub. L. 87–663, § 1(6)</ref>, inserted references to American Samoa, Guam, and the Virgin Islands, and substituted “Clauses (1)–(5) and (10)” for “clauses (1)–(5)”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idab770268-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idab770269-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2023 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s561/c">section 561(c) of Pub. L. 118–31</ref> applicable to nominations of candidates and appointments to the Service Academies for classes entering such Service Academies beginning with the 2025-2026 academic year, see <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/s561/d">section 561(d) of Pub. L. 118–31</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s7442">section 7442 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idab77026a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2018 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/115/232">Pub. L. 115–232</ref> effective <date date="2019-02-01">Feb. 1, 2019</date>, with provision for the coordination of amendments and special rule for certain redesignations, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s800">section 800 of Pub. L. 115–232</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idab77026b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2016 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/114/328">Pub. L. 114–328</ref> applicable with respect to the appointment of cadets and midshipmen to the United States Military Academy, the United States Naval Academy, the United States Air Force Academy, and the United States Merchant Marine Academy for classes entering these service academies after <date date="2018-01-01">Jan. 1, 2018</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s566/e">section 566(e) of Pub. L. 114–328</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s7442">section 7442 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idab77026c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2015 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/114/92">Pub. L. 114–92</ref> applicable with respect to the nomination of candidates for appointment to the United States Military Academy, Naval Academy, and Air Force Academy for classes entering after <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/92/s556/d">section 556(d) of Pub. L. 114–92</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s7442">section 7442 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idab77026d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2009 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/84">Pub. L. 111–84</ref> applicable with respect to appointments to the United States Air Force Academy beginning with the first class of candidates nominated for appointment after <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/s527/d">section 527(d) of Pub. L. 111–84</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s7442">section 7442 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idab77026e-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/110/417">Pub. L. 110–417</ref> applicable with respect to academic years at the Air Force Academy after the 2007–2008 academic year, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/417/s540/d">section 540(d) of Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s7442">section 7442 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idab77026f-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2003 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/s524/c">section 524(c) of Pub. L. 108–136</ref> applicable with respect to nomination of candidates for appointment to United States Air Force Academy for classes entering after <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/s524/d">section 524(d) of Pub. L. 108–136</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s7442">section 7442 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idab770270-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/337">Pub. L. 103–337</ref> effective <date date="1994-12-01">Dec. 1, 1994</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/337/s1691">section 1691 of Pub. L. 103–337</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s10001">section 10001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idab770271-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/60">Pub. L. 97–60</ref> effective with respect to nominations for appointment to the first class admitted to each Academy after <date date="1981-10-14">Oct. 14, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/60/s203/d">section 203(d) of Pub. L. 97–60</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s7441a">section 7441a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idab770272-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/600">Pub. L. 96–600</ref> effective beginning with nominations for appointment to the service academies for academic years beginning more than one year after <date date="1980-12-24">Dec. 24, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/600/s2/d">section 2(d) of Pub. L. 96–600</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s7442">section 7442 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/513">Pub. L. 96–513</ref> effective <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/513/s701/b/3">section 701(b)(3) of Pub. L. 96–513</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101">section 101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idab770273-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1973 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/93/171">Pub. L. 93–171</ref> effective beginning with the nominations for appointment to the service academies in the calendar year 1974, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/171/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 93–171</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s7442">section 7442 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idab770274-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1970 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/405">Pub. L. 91–405</ref> effective <date date="1970-09-22">Sept. 22, 1970</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/405/s206/b">section 206(b) of Pub. L. 91–405</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s25a">section 25a of Title 2</ref>, The Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idab770275-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1968 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/90/623">Pub. L. 90–623</ref> intended to restate without substantive change the law in effect on <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/623/s6">section 6 of Pub. L. 90–623</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5334">section 5334 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idab770276-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date; Interim System for Appointment of Cadets</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041/s52/b">Act Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, § 52(b)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/641">70A Stat. 641</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/85/182">Pub. L. 85–182</ref>, <date date="1957-08-28">Aug. 28, 1957</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/71/463">71 Stat. 463</ref>, provided that section 9342(a) [now 9442(a)] of Title 10, Armed Forces would take effect four years after the entrance of the initial class at the United States Air Force Academy. However, for the four-year period beginning with the class of cadets entering in July 1959, not more than one quarter of the number of cadets authorized by clause (1), (2), (3), (4), (7), or (8) of that section could be appointed in any one academic year; two of the number of cadets authorized by clause (5) of that section could be appointed in the first and third years of that four-year period, and not more than one of the number authorized by it could be appointed in the second and fourth years of that period; and one cadet authorized by clause (6) of that section could be appointed in the first two years of that four-year period, and not more than one of the number authorized by it could be appointed in the second two years of that period. In addition, during that four-year period, the nominating authority named in clauses (1) to (6) of that section could select for each cadet allocated to him for the year concerned a principal candidate and not more than ten alternate candidates, or he could nominate as many candidates as the Secretary prescribed and authorize the Secretary to select the principal candidates in order of merit as determined by competitive examination. In carrying out section 9343 [now 9443] of Title 10, during that four-year period, only qualified alternates who were nominated by the authorities named in clauses (1) to (4) of section 9342(a) could be nominated for appointment as cadets. Not more than one qualified alternate nominated by any one authority named in those classes could be appointed as a cadet, after nomination under section 9343 [now 9443], during each year of that four-year period.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idab770277-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Limitation on Number of Cadets and Midshipmen Authorized To Attend Service Academies</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Authorized strength of service academies not to exceed 4,000 per academy for class years beginning after 1994, and any reduction in number of appointments not to be achieved by reduction in number of appointments under subsec. (a) of this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/190/s511">section 511 of Pub. L. 102–190</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s7442">section 7442 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idab770278-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Eligibility of Female Individuals for Appointment and Admission to Service Academies; Uniform Application of Academic and Other Standards to Male and Female Individuals</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Secretary required to take such action as may be necessary and appropriate to insure that (1) female individuals shall be eligible for appointment and admission to the United States Air Force Academy, beginning with appointments to such academy for the class beginning in calendar year 1976, and (2) the academic and other relevant standards required for appointment, admission, training, graduation, and commissioning of female individuals shall be the same as those required for male individuals, except for those minimum essential adjustments in such standards required because of physiological differences between male and female individuals, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/106/s803/a">section 803(a) of Pub. L. 94–106</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s7442">section 7442 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idab770279-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Secretary To Implement Policy of Expeditious Admission of Women to the Academy</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Secretary to continue to exercise the authority granted under this chapter and chapters 403 and 603 of this title, but such authority to be exercised within a program providing for the orderly and expeditious admission of women to the Academy, consistent with the needs of the services, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/106/s803/c">section 803(c) of Pub. L. 94–106</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s7442">section 7442 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
