<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida8348183-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s948j"><num value="948j">§ 948j.</num><heading> Military judge of a military commission</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8348184-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s948j/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Detail of Military Judge</inline>.—</heading><content>A military judge shall be detailed to each military commission under this chapter. The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations providing for the manner in which military judges are so detailed to military commissions. The military judge shall preside over each military commission to which such military judge has been detailed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8348185-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s948j/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligibility</inline>.—</heading><content>A military judge shall be a commissioned officer of the armed forces who is a member of the bar of a Federal court, or a member of the bar of the highest court of a State, and who is certified to be qualified for duty under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s826">section 826 of this title</ref> (article 26 of the Uniform Code of Military Justice) as a military judge of general courts-martial by the Judge Advocate General of the armed force of which such military judge is a member.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8348186-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s948j/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Ineligibility of Certain Individuals</inline>.—</heading><content>No person is eligible to act as military judge in a case of a military commission under this chapter if such person is the accuser or a witness or has acted as investigator or a counsel in the same case.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8348187-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s948j/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation With Members; Ineligibility to Vote</inline>.—</heading><content>A military judge detailed to a military commission under this chapter may not consult with the members except in the presence of the accused (except as otherwise provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s949d">section 949d of this title</ref>), trial counsel, and defense counsel, nor may such military judge vote with the members.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8348188-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s948j/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other Duties</inline>.—</heading><content>A commissioned officer who is certified to be qualified for duty as a military judge of a military commission under this chapter may perform such other duties as are assigned to such officer by or with the approval of the Judge Advocate General of the armed force of which such officer is a member or the designee of such Judge Advocate General.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida8348189-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s948j/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Prohibition on Evaluation of Fitness by Convening Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The convening authority of a military commission under this chapter may not prepare or review any report concerning the effectiveness, fitness, or efficiency of a military judge detailed to the military commission which relates to such judge’s performance of duty as a military judge on the military commission.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida834818a-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/dA/tXVIII/s1802">Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2577">123 Stat. 2577</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida834818b-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida834818c-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="ida834818d-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 948j, added <ref href="/us/pl/109/366/s3/a/1">Pub. L. 109–366, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2604">120 Stat. 2604</ref>, related to military judges of military commissions, prior to the general amendment of this chapter by <ref href="/us/pl/111/84">Pub. L. 111–84</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
