<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida836ccb4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s949o"><num value="949o">§ 949o.</num><heading> Record of trial</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida836ccb5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s949o/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Record; Authentication</inline>.—</heading><content>Each military commission under this chapter shall keep a separate, verbatim, record of the proceedings in each case brought before it, and the record shall be authenticated by the signature of the military judge. If the record cannot be authenticated by the military judge by reason of death, disability, or absence, it shall be authenticated by the signature of the trial counsel or by a member of the commission if the trial counsel is unable to authenticate it by reason of death, disability, or absence. Where appropriate, and as provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the record of a military commission under this chapter may contain a classified annex.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida836ccb6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s949o/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Complete Record Required</inline>.—</heading><content>A complete record of the proceedings and testimony shall be prepared in every military commission under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida836ccb7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s949o/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Provision of Copy to Accused</inline>.—</heading><content>A copy of the record of the proceedings of the military commission under this chapter shall be given the accused as soon as it is authenticated. If the record contains classified information, or a classified annex, the accused shall receive a redacted version of the record consistent with the requirements of subchapter V of this chapter. Defense counsel shall have access to the unredacted record, as provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida8393bb8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/dA/tXVIII/s1802">Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2590">123 Stat. 2590</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida8393bb9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida8393bba-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="ida8393bbb-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 949<i>o</i>, added <ref href="/us/pl/109/366/s3/a/1">Pub. L. 109–366, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2617">120 Stat. 2617</ref>, related to record of trial, prior to the general amendment of this chapter by <ref href="/us/pl/111/84">Pub. L. 111–84</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
