<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="ida84793ce-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s993"><num value="993">§ 993.</num><heading> Notification of permanent reduction of sizable numbers of members of the armed forces</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida84793cf-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s993/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of the military department concerned shall notify Congress under subsection (b) of a plan to reduce more than 1,000 members of the armed forces assigned at a military installation. In calculating the number of members to be reduced, the Secretary shall take into consideration both direct reductions and indirect reductions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida84793d0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s993/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>No irrevocable action may be taken to effect or implement a reduction described under subsection (a) until—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida84793d1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s993/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of the military department concerned—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida84793d2-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s993/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> submits to Congress a notice of the proposed reduction and the number of military and civilian personnel assignments affected, including reductions in base operations support services and personnel to occur because of the proposed reduction; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="ida84793d3-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s993/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> includes in the notice a justification for the reduction and an evaluation of the costs and benefits of the reduction and of the local economic, strategic, and operational consequences of the reduction; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida84793d4-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s993/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a period of 90 days expires following the day on which the notice is submitted to Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida84793d5-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s993/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida84793d6-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s993/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Base closure process</inline>.—</heading><content>Subsections (a) and (b) do not apply in the case of the realignment of a military installation pursuant to a base closure law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida84793d7-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s993/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">National security or emergency</inline>.—</heading><content>Subsections (a) and (b) do not apply if the President certifies to Congress that the reduction in military personnel at a military installation must be implemented for reasons of national security or a military emergency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="ida84793d8-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s993/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida84793d9-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s993/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “indirect reduction” means subsequent planned reductions or relocations in base operations support services and personnel able to occur due to the direct reductions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="ida84793da-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5" identifier="/us/usc/t10/s993/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “military installation” means a base, camp, post, station, yard, center, homeport facility for any ship, or other activity under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense, including any leased facility, which is located within any of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or Guam. Such term does not include any facility used primarily for civil works, rivers and harbors projects, or flood control projects.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="ida84793db-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/112/81/dB/tXXVIII/s2864/a">Pub. L. 112–81, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2864(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1702">125 Stat. 1702</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dB/tXXVIII/s2851">Pub. L. 112–239, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2851</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2159">126 Stat. 2159</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="ida84793dc-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="ida84793dd-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="ida84793de-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s2851/a">Pub. L. 112–239, § 2851(a)</ref>, inserted at end “In calculating the number of members to be reduced, the Secretary shall take into consideration both direct reductions and indirect reductions.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1) to (3). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s2851/b">Pub. L. 112–239, § 2851(b)</ref>, added pars. (1) and (2) and struck out former pars. (1) to (3), which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(1) the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of the military department concerned notifies the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives of the proposed reduction and the number of personnel assignments affected;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2) submits a justification for the reduction and an evaluation of the local strategic and operational impact of such reduction; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(3) a period of 21 days has expired following submission of the notice and evaluation required under this subsection, or if sooner, a period of 14 days has expired following the date on which an electronic version of the notice and justification has been submitted to such committees.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/s2851/c">Pub. L. 112–239, § 2851(c)</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="ida84793df-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida84793e0-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Special Operations Force Structure</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tX/s1075">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title X, § 1075</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/410">137 Stat. 410</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tX/s1075">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] a report containing an assessment of the optimal force structure for special operations forces. Such report shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> a description of the role of special operations forces in implementing the most recent national defense strategy under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s113/g">section 113(g) of title 10</ref>, United States Code;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> a detailed accounting of the demand for special operations forces by the geographic combatant commands;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> an assessment of current and projected capabilities and capacities of the general purpose forces of the United States Armed Forces, including forces that enable special operations, that could affect force structure capability and capacity requirements of special operations forces;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> an assessment of the size, composition, and organizational structure of the special operations command headquarters of each of the Armed Forces and subordinate headquarters elements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> an assessment of the adequacy of special operations force structure for meeting the goals of the National Military Strategy under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s153/b">section 153(b) of title 10</ref>, United States Code;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> a description of the role of special operations forces in supporting the Joint Concept for Competing; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> any other matters the Secretary of Defense determines relevant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notification Required</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subsection (d), not later than 15 days before making any reduction in the number of special operations forces by more than 1,000 personnel and prior to implementing or announcing such reduction, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees written notification of the decision to make such reduction.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents of Notification</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A notification required under subsection (b) shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> details of the planned changes to force structure and personnel requirements and a justification for the planned changes, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> which units or occupational skills are planned to be reduced or reallocated; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> to which units or capabilities the force structure is planned to be transferred or reallocated;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> an accounting of the personnel planned to be transferred under the force structure change, including which units such personnel are planned to be transferred to and from;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> an analysis of the expected implications of the planned change on the ability of the Department of Defense to carry out operational and campaign plans of combatant commanders, support the Joint Concept for Competing, and meet the goals of the most recent national defense strategy under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s113/g">section 113(g) of title 10</ref>, United States Code; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> any other matters the Secretary of Defense determines relevant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading><content>The notification requirement under subsection (b) shall not apply with respect to a reduction in the number of special operations forces if the Secretary of Defense submits to the congressional defense committees certification that such reduction needs to be implemented expeditiously for reasons of military urgency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The term ‘special operations forces’ means the forces described in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s167/j">section 167(j) of title 10</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> The term ‘force structure’, when used with respect to an organization, means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the mission of the organization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the personnel required to operate the organization; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the equipment required to execute the mission of the organization.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="ida84793e1-3a6f-11f1-a58a-d8db54b14ab5"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Notification of Necessary Assessments or Studies</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tX/s1074/b">Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title X, § 1074(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/870">127 Stat. 870</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tX/s1074/b">“The Secretary of the Army, when making a congressional notification in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s993">section 993 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, shall include the Secretary’s assessment of whether or not the changes covered by the notification require an Environmental Assessment or Environmental Impact Statement in accordance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.), and, if an assessment or study is required, the plan for conducting such assessment or study.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
