<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb09a30dc-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373"><num value="373">§ 373.</num><heading> Repayment of unearned portion of bonus, incentive pay, or similar benefit, and termination of remaining payments, when conditions of payment not met</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb09a30dd-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Repayment and Termination</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subsection (b), a member of the uniformed services who is paid a bonus, incentive pay, or similar benefit, the receipt of which is contingent upon the member’s satisfaction of certain service or eligibility requirements, shall repay to the United States any unearned portion of the bonus, incentive pay, or similar benefit if the member fails to satisfy any such service or eligibility requirement, and the member may not receive any unpaid amounts of the bonus, incentive pay, or similar benefit after the member fails to satisfy such service or eligibility requirement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb09a30de-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb09a30df-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Discretion to provide exception to termination and repayment requirements</inline>.—</heading><content>Pursuant to the regulations prescribed to administer this section, the Secretary concerned may grant an exception to the repayment requirement and requirement to terminate the payment of unpaid amounts of a bonus, incentive pay, or similar benefit if the Secretary concerned determines that the imposition of the repayment and termination requirements with regard to a member of the uniformed services would be contrary to a personnel policy or management objective, would be against equity and good conscience, or would be contrary to the best interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb09a30e0-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special rule for deceased and disabled members</inline>.—</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb09a30e1-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> If a member of the uniformed services dies or is retired or separated with a combat-related disability, the Secretary concerned—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb09a30e2-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/b/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> shall not require repayment by the member or the member’s estate of the unearned portion of any bonus, incentive pay, or similar benefit previously paid to the member; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb09a30e3-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/b/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> shall require the payment to the member or the member’s estate of the remainder of any bonus, incentive pay, or similar benefit that was not yet paid to the member, but to which the member was entitled immediately before the death, retirement, or separation of the member, and would be paid if not for the death, retirement, or separation of the member.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb09a30e4-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Subparagraph (A) does not apply if the death or disability of the member is the result the member’s misconduct.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb09a30e5-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The amount to be paid under subparagraph (A)(ii) shall be equal to the full amount specified by the agreement or contract applicable to the bonus, incentive pay, or similar benefit as if the member continued to be entitled to the bonus, incentive pay, or similar benefit following the death, retirement, or separation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb09a30e6-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Amounts to be paid to a member or the member’s estate under subparagraph (A)(ii) shall be paid in a lump sum not later than 90 days after the date of the death, retirement, or separation of the member, whichever applies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb09a30e7-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/b/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> In this paragraph, the term “combat-related disability” has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s1413a/e">section 1413a(e) of title 10</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb09a30e8-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Special rule for members who receive sole survivorship discharge</inline>.—</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb09a30e9-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> If a member of the uniformed services receives a sole survivorship discharge, the Secretary concerned—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb09a30ea-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/b/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> shall not require repayment by the member of the unearned portion of any bonus, incentive pay, or similar benefit previously paid to the member; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb09a30eb-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/b/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> may grant an exception to the requirement to terminate the payment of any unpaid amounts of a bonus, incentive pay, or similar benefit if the Secretary concerned determines that termination of the payment of the unpaid amounts would be contrary to a personnel policy or management objective, would be against equity and good conscience, or would be contrary to the best interests of the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb09a30ec-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> In this paragraph, the term “sole survivorship discharge” means the separation of a member from the Armed Forces, at the request of the member, pursuant to the Department of Defense policy permitting the early separation of a member who is the only surviving child in a family in which—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb09a30ed-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/b/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> the father or mother or one or more siblings—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb09a30ee-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/b/3/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> served in the Armed Forces; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb09a30ef-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/b/3/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> was killed, died as a result of wounds, accident, or disease, is in a captured or missing in action status, or is permanently 100 percent disabled or hospitalized on a continuing basis (and is not employed gainfully because of the disability or hospitalization); and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb09a30f0-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/b/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the death, status, or disability did not result from the intentional misconduct or willful neglect of the parent or sibling and was not incurred during a period of unauthorized absence.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb09a30f1-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effect of Bankruptcy</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An obligation to repay the United States under this section is, for all purposes, a debt owed the United States. A discharge in bankruptcy under title 11 does not discharge a person from such debt if the discharge order is entered less than five years after—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb09a30f2-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the date of the termination of the agreement or contract on which the debt is based; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb09a30f3-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> in the absence of such an agreement or contract, the date of the termination of the service on which the debt is based.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb09a30f4-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb09a30f5-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “bonus, incentive pay, or similar benefit” means a bonus, incentive pay, special pay, or similar payment, or an educational benefit or stipend, paid to a member of the uniformed services under a provision of law that refers to the repayment requirements of this section or <ref href="/us/usc/t37/s303a/e">section 303a(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb09a30f6-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The term “service”, as used in subsection (c)(2), refers to an obligation willingly undertaken by a member of the uniformed services, in exchange for a bonus, incentive pay, or similar benefit offered by the Secretary concerned—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb09a30f7-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to a member who remains on active duty, in an active status in a reserve component, or in space force active status;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb09a30f8-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to perform duty in a specified skill, with or without a specified qualification or credential;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb09a30f9-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> to perform duty in a specified assignment, location or unit; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb09a30fa-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0" identifier="/us/usc/t37/s373/d/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> to perform duty for a specified period of time.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb09a30fb-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/110/181/dA/tVI/s661/a/2">Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title VI, § 661(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2008-01-28">Jan. 28, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/177">122 Stat. 177</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/110/417">Pub. L. 110–417</ref>, [div. A], title VI, § 651(c)(1), (2)(A), <date date="2008-10-14">Oct. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4496">122 Stat. 4496</ref>, 4497; <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/dA/tVI/s617/b">Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title VI, § 617(b)</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2355">123 Stat. 2355</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tVI/s601/d/2">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title VI, § 601(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/904">139 Stat. 904</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb09a30fc-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb09a30fd-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb09a30fe-2930-11f1-a69d-9cbca84c43f0"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (d)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60">Pub. L. 119–60</ref> substituted “who remains on active duty, in an active status in a reserve component, or in space force active status” for “in a regular or reserve component who remains on active duty or in an active status”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/s617/b/1">Pub. L. 111–84, § 617(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Special rule for deceased and disabled members” for “Mandatory payment of unpaid amounts under certain circumstances; no repayment of unearned amounts” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/111/84/s617/b/2">Pub. L. 111–84, § 617(b)(2)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—<ref href="/us/pl/110/417/s651/c/2/A">Pub. L. 110–417, § 651(c)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “Repayment of unearned portion of bonus, incentive pay, or similar benefit, and termination of remaining payments, when conditions of payment not met” for “Repayment of unearned portion of bonus, incentive pay, or similar benefit when conditions of payment not met” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/110/417/s651/c/1/A">Pub. L. 110–417, § 651(c)(1)(A)</ref>, inserted “and Termination” after “Repayment” in heading and “, and the member may not receive any unpaid amounts of the bonus, incentive pay, or similar benefit after the member fails to satisfy such service or eligibility requirement” in text before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/110/417/s651/c/1/B">Pub. L. 110–417, § 651(c)(1)(B)</ref>, added subsec. (b) and struck out former subsec. (b). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The regulations prescribed to administer this section may specify procedures for determining the circumstances under which an exception to the required repayment may be granted.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
