<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id602f32fc-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1028"><num value="1028">§ 1028.</num><heading> Hot dry rock geothermal energy</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id602f32fd-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1028/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition of enhanced geothermal systems</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “enhanced geothermal systems” has the meaning given the term in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s17191">section 17191 of title 42</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id602f32fe-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1028/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> USGS program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior, acting through the United States Geological Survey, and in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, shall establish a cooperative Government-private sector program with respect to hot dry rock geothermal energy resources on public lands (as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1702/e">section 1702(e) of title 43</ref>) and lands managed by the Department of Agriculture, other than any such public or other lands that are withdrawn from geothermal leasing. Such program shall include, but shall not be limited to, activities to identify, select, and classify those areas throughout the United States that have a high potential for hot dry rock geothermal energy production and activities to develop and disseminate information regarding the utilization of such areas for hot dry rock energy production. Such information may include information regarding field test processes and techniques for assuring that hot dry rock geothermal energy development projects are developed in an economically feasible manner without adverse environmental consequences. Utilizing the information developed by the Secretary, together with information developed in connection with other related programs carried out by other Federal agencies, the Secretary, acting through the United States Geological Survey, may also enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with any public or private entity to provide assistance to any such entity to enable such entity to carry out additional projects with respect to the utilization of hot dry rock geothermal energy resources which will further the purposes of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id602f32ff-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1028/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Update to geothermal resource assessment</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Interior, acting through the United States Geological Survey, and in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, shall update the 2008 United States geothermal resource assessment carried out by the United States Geological Survey, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id602f3300-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1028/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> with respect to areas previously identified by the Department of Energy or the United States Geological Survey as having significant potential for hydrothermal energy or enhanced geothermal systems energy, by focusing on—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id602f3301-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1028/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> improving the resolution of resource potential at systematic temperatures and depths, including temperatures and depths appropriate for power generation and direct use applications;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id602f3302-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1028/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> quantifying the total potential to coproduce geothermal energy and minerals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id602f3303-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1028/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> incorporating data relevant to underground thermal energy storage and exchange, such as aquifer and soil properties; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id602f3304-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1028/c/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> producing high resolution maps, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id602f3305-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1028/c/1/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> maps that indicate key subsurface parameters for electric and direct use resources; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id602f3306-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1028/c/1/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> risk maps for induced seismicity based on geologic, geographic, and operational parameters; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id602f3307-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1028/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to the maximum extent practicable, by coordinating with relevant State officials and institutions of higher education to expand geothermal assessments, including enhanced geothermal systems assessments, to include assessments for the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and the States of Alaska and Hawaii.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id602f3308-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1028/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id602f3309-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tXXV/s2501">Pub. L. 102–486, title XXV, § 2501</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3101">106 Stat. 3101</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dZ/tIII/s3002/m">Pub. L. 116–260, div. Z, title III, § 3002(m)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2496">134 Stat. 2496</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id602f330a-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id602f330b-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id602f330c-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Energy Policy Act of 1992, and not as part of the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id602f330d-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s3002/m/2">Pub. L. 116–260, § 3002(m)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (a). Former subsec. (a) redesignated (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s3002/m/1">Pub. L. 116–260, § 3002(m)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (a) as (b). Former subsec. (b) redesignated (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s3002/m/3">Pub. L. 116–260, § 3002(m)(3)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s3002/m/1">Pub. L. 116–260, § 3002(m)(1)</ref>, (4), redesignated subsec. (b) as (d) and substituted “necessary” for “necesary”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
