<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id60317d6b-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1221"><num value="1221">§ 1221.</num><heading> Authorization of State allotments to institutes</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id60317d6c-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1221/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id60317d6d-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1221/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of the Interior (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Secretary”) funds adequate to provide for each participating State $400,000 for each of the fiscal years ending <date date="1990-09-30">September 30, 1990</date>, through <date date="1994-09-30">September 30, 1994</date>, to assist the States in carrying on the work of a competent and qualified mining and mineral resources research institute or center (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “institute”) at one public college or university in the State which meets the eligibility criteria established in <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1230">section 1230 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id60317d6e-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1221/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id60317d6f-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1221/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Funds appropriated under this section shall be made available for grants to be matched on a basis of no less than 2 non-Federal dollars for each Federal dollar.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id60317d70-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1221/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> If there is more than one such eligible college or university in a State, funds appropriated under this subchapter shall, in the absence of a designation to the contrary by act of the legislature of the State, be granted to one such college or university designated by the Governor of the State.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id60317d71-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1221/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Where a State does not have a public college or university eligible under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1230">section 1230 of this title</ref>, the Committee on Mining and Mineral Resources Research established in <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1229">section 1229 of this title</ref> (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Committee”) may allocate the State’s allotment to one private college or university which it determines to be eligible under such section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id60317d72-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1221/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> It shall be the duty of each institute to plan and conduct, or arrange for a component or components of the college or university with which it is affiliated to conduct research, investigations, demonstrations, and experiments of either, or both, a basic or practical nature in relation to mining and mineral resources, and to provide for the training of mineral engineers and scientists through such research, investigations, demonstrations, and experiments. The subject of such research, investigation, demonstration, experiment, and training may include exploration; extraction; processing; development; production of fuel and nonfuel mineral resources; mining and mineral technology; supply and demand for minerals; conservation and best use of available supplies of minerals; the economic, legal, social, engineering, recreational, biological, geographic, ecological, and other aspects of mining, mineral resources, and mineral reclamation. Such research, investigation, demonstration, experiment and training shall consider the interrelationship with the natural environment, the varying conditions and needs of the respective States, and mining and mineral resources research projects being conducted by agencies of the Federal and State governments and other institutes.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id60317d73-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/409/s1">Pub. L. 98–409, § 1</ref>, <date date="1984-08-29">Aug. 29, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1536">98 Stat. 1536</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/483">Pub. L. 100–483</ref>, §§ 2–4, <date date="1988-10-12">Oct. 12, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2339">102 Stat. 2339</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id60317d74-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id60317d75-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id60317d76-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Mining and Mineral Resources Research Institute Act of 1984, and not as part of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id60317d77-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 1221, <ref href="/us/pl/95/87/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 95–87, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1977-08-03">Aug. 3, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/451">91 Stat. 451</ref>, contained provisions similar to this section covering fiscal years 1978 through 1984.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id60317d78-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/483/s2">Pub. L. 100–483, § 2</ref>, substituted “$400,000 for each of the fiscal years ending <date date="1990-09-30">September 30, 1990</date>, through <date date="1994-09-30">September 30, 1994</date>” for “$300,000 for the fiscal year ending <date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>, and $400,000 to each participating State for each fiscal year thereafter for a total of five years”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/100/483/s3">Pub. L. 100–483, § 3</ref>, amended subpar. (A) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (A) read as follows: “Funds appropriated under this section shall be made available for grants to be matched on a basis of no less than one and one-half non-Federal dollars for each Federal dollar during the fiscal years ending <date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>, and <date date="1986-09-30">September 30, 1986</date>, and no less than two non-Federal dollars for each Federal dollar during the fiscal years ending <date date="1987-09-30">September 30, 1987</date>, <date date="1988-09-30">September 30, 1988</date>, and <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/483/s4">Pub. L. 100–483, § 4</ref>, substituted “production of fuel and nonfuel mineral resources” for “production of mineral resources”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id60317d79-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="id60317d7a-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For short title of <ref href="/us/pl/98/409">Pub. L. 98–409</ref>, which enacted this subchapter, as the Mining and Mineral Resources Institutes Act, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/409/s11">section 11 of Pub. L. 98–409</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1201">section 1201 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
