<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6038a943-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1236"><num value="1236">§ 1236.</num><heading> Reclamation of rural lands</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6038a944-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1236/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Agreements with landowners for conservation treatment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to provide for the control and prevention of erosion and sediment damages from unreclaimed mined lands, and to promote the conservation and development of soil and water resources of unreclaimed mined lands and lands affected by mining, the Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to enter into agreements of not more than ten years with landowners (including owners of water rights), residents, and tenants, and individually or collectively, determined by him to have control for the period of the agreement of lands in question therein, providing for land stabilization, erosion, and sediment control, and reclamation through conservation treatment, including measures for the conservation and development of soil, water (excluding stream channelization), woodland, wildlife, and recreation resources, and agricultural productivity of such lands. Such agreements shall be made by the Secretary with the owners, including owners of water rights, residents, or tenants (collectively or individually) of the lands in question.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6038a945-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1236/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Conservation and development plans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The landowner, including the owner of water rights, resident, or tenant shall furnish to the Secretary of Agriculture a conservation and development plan setting forth the proposed land uses and conservation treatment which shall be mutually agreed by the Secretary of Agriculture and the landowner, including owner of water rights, resident, or tenant to be needed on the lands for which the plan was prepared. In those instances where it is determined that the water rights or water supply of a tenant, landowner, including owner of water rights, resident, or tenant have been adversely affected by a surface or underground coal mine operation which has removed or disturbed a stratum so as to significantly affect the hydrologic balance, such plan may include proposed measures to enhance water quality or quantity by means of joint action with other affected landowners, including owner of water rights, residents, or tenants in consultation with appropriate State and Federal agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6038a946-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1236/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Agreement to effect plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Such plan shall be incorporated in an agreement under which the landowner, including owner of water rights, resident, or tenant shall agree with the Secretary of Agriculture to effect the land uses and conservation treatment provided for in such plan on the lands described in the agreement in accordance with the terms and conditions thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6038a947-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1236/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Financial and other assistance; determination by Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In return for such agreement by the landowner, including owner of water rights, resident, or tenant, the Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to furnish financial and other assistance to such landowner, including owner of water rights, resident, or tenant, in such amounts and subject to such conditions as the Secretary of Agriculture determines are appropriate in the public interest for carrying out the land use and conservation treatment set forth in the agreement. Grants made under this section, depending on the income-producing potential of the land after reclaiming, shall provide up to 80 per centum of the cost of carrying out such land uses and conservation treatment on not more than one hundred and twenty acres of land occupied by such owner, including water rights owners, resident, or tenant, or on not more than one hundred and twenty acres of land which has been purchased jointly by such landowners, including water rights owners, residents, or tenants, under an agreement for the enhancement of water quality or quantity or on land which has been acquired by an appropriate State or local agency for the purpose of implementing such agreement; except the Secretary may reduce the matching cost share where he determines that (1) the main benefits to be derived from the project are related to improving offsite water quality, offsite esthetic values, or other offsite benefits, and (2) the matching share requirement would place a burden on the landowner which would probably prevent him from participating in the program: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the Secretary of Agriculture may allow for land use and conservation treatment on such lands occupied by any such owner in excess of such one hundred and twenty acre limitation up to three hundred and twenty acres, but in such event the amount of the grant to such landowner to carry out such reclamation on such lands shall be reduced proportionately. Notwithstanding any other provision of this section with regard to acreage limitations, the Secretary of Agriculture may carry out reclamation treatment projects to control erosion and improve water quality on all lands within a hydrologic unit, consisting of not more than 25,000 acres, if the Secretary determines that treatment of such lands as a hydrologic unit will achieve greater reduction in the adverse effects of past surface mining practices than would be achieved if reclamation was done on individual parcels of land.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6038a948-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1236/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination of agreements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture may terminate any agreement with a landowner including water rights owners, operator, or occupier by mutual agreement if the Secretary of Agriculture determines that such termination would be in the public interest, and may agree to such modification of agreements previously entered into hereunder as he deems desirable to carry out the purposes of this section or to facilitate the practical administration of the program authorized herein.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6038a949-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1236/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Preservation and surrender of history and allotments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Agriculture, to the extent he deems it desirable to carry out the purposes of this section, may provide in any agreement hereinunder for (1) preservation for a period not to exceed the period covered by the agreement and an equal period thereafter of the cropland, crop acreage, and allotment history applicable to land covered by the agreement for the purpose of any Federal program under which such history is used as a basis for an allotment or other limitation on the production of such crop; or (2) surrender of any such history and allotments.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6038a94a-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1236/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Rules and regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Agriculture shall be authorized to issue such rules and regulations as he determines are necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6038a94b-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1236/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Utilization of Natural Resources Conservation Service</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out the provisions of this section, the Secretary of Agriculture shall utilize the services of the Natural Resources Conservation Service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6038a94c-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1236/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Agriculture, from amounts in the Treasury other than amounts in the fund, such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6038a94d-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/87/tIV/s406">Pub. L. 95–87, title IV, § 406</ref>, <date date="1977-08-03">Aug. 3, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/460">91 Stat. 460</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/tXV/s1551">Pub. L. 97–98, title XV, § 1551</ref>, <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1344">95 Stat. 1344</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tVI">Pub. L. 101–508, title VI</ref>, §§ 6008, 6012(c), (d)(3), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-295">104 Stat. 1388–295</ref>, 1388–298; <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/dC/tII/s204">Pub. L. 109–432, div. C, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3016">120 Stat. 3016</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6038a94e-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6038a94f-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6038a950-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s204/a">Pub. L. 109–432, § 204(a)</ref>, substituted “Natural Resources Conservation Service” for “Soil Conservation Service”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s204/b">Pub. L. 109–432, § 204(b)</ref>, added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s6012/d/3">Pub. L. 101–508, § 6012(d)(3)</ref>, which directed the substitution of “(including owners” for “including owners” was executed the first time that phrase appeared to reflect the probable intent of Congress, because the parenthetical statement concluding with “water rights)” was enacted without an opening parenthesis.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s6008">Pub. L. 101–508, § 6008</ref>, struck out “experimental” before “reclamation treatment projects” in last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s6012/c">Pub. L. 101–508, § 6012(c)</ref>, repealed subsec. (i) which read as follows: “Funds shall be made available to the Secretary of Agriculture for the purposes of this section, as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1231">section 1231 of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/98">Pub. L. 97–98</ref> inserted provisions that notwithstanding any other provision of this section with regard to acreage limitations, the Secretary may carry out experimental reclamation treatment projects to control erosion and improve water quality on all lands within a hydrologic unit, consisting of not more than 25,000 acres, if the Secretary determines that treatment of such lands as a hydrologic unit will achieve greater reduction in the adverse effects of past surface mining practices than would be achieved if reclamation was done on individual parcels of land.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6038a951-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id6038a952-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> effective <date date="1991-10-01">Oct. 1, 1991</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s6014">section 6014 of Pub. L. 101–508</ref> set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1231">section 1231 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id6038a953-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/98">Pub. L. 97–98</ref> effective <date date="1981-12-22">Dec. 22, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/98/s1801">section 1801 of Pub. L. 97–98</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s4301">section 4301 of Title 7</ref>, Agriculture.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
