<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id60470028-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1266"><num value="1266">§ 1266.</num><heading> Surface effects of underground coal mining operations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id60470029-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1266/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Rules and regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall promulgate rules and regulations directed toward the surface effects of underground coal mining operations, embodying the following requirements and in accordance with the procedures established under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1251">section 1251 of this title</ref>: <i>Provided, however</i>, That in adopting any rules and regulations the Secretary shall consider the distinct difference between surface coal mining and underground coal mining. Such rules and regulations shall not conflict with nor supersede any provision of the Federal Coal Mine Health and Safety Act of 1969 [<ref href="/us/usc/t30/s801">30 U.S.C. 801</ref> et seq.] nor any regulation issued pursuant thereto, and shall not be promulgated until the Secretary has obtained the written concurrence of the head of the department which administers such Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6047002a-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1266/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Permit requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each permit issued under any approved State or Federal program pursuant to this chapter and relating to underground coal mining shall require the operator to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6047002b-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1266/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> adopt measures consistent with known technology in order to prevent subsidence causing material damage to the extent technologically and economically feasible, maximize mine stability, and maintain the value and reasonably foreseeable use of such surface lands, except in those instances where the mining technology used requires planned subsidence in a predictable and controlled manner: <i>Provided</i>, That nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prohibit the standard method of room and pillar mining;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6047002c-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1266/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> seal all portals, entryways, drifts, shafts, or other openings between the surface and underground mine working when no longer needed for the conduct of the mining operations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6047002d-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1266/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> fill or seal exploratory holes no longer necessary for mining, maximizing to the extent technologically and economically feasible return of mine and processing waste, tailings, and any other waste incident to the mining operation, to the mine workings or excavations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6047002e-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1266/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> with respect to surface disposal of mine wastes, tailings, coal processing wastes, and other wastes in areas other than the mine workings or excavations, stabilize all waste piles created by the permittee from current operations through construction in compacted layers including the use of incombustible and impervious materials if necessary and assure that the leachate will not degrade below water quality standards established pursuant to applicable Federal and State law surface or ground waters and that the final contour of the waste accumulation will be compatible with natural surroundings and that the site is stabilized and revegetated according to the provisions of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6047002f-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1266/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> design, locate, construct, operate, maintain, enlarge, modify, and remove, or abandon, in accordance with the standards and criteria developed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1265/f">section 1265(f) of this title</ref>, all existing and new coal mine waste piles consisting of mine wastes, tailings, coal processing wastes, or other liquid and solid wastes and used either temporarily or permanently as dams or embankments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60470030-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1266/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> establish on regraded areas and all other lands affected, a diverse and permanent vegetative cover capable of self-regeneration and plant succession and at least equal in extent of cover to the natural vegetation of the area;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60470031-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1266/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> protect offsite areas from damages which may result from such mining operations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60470032-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1266/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> eliminate fire hazards and otherwise eliminate conditions which constitute a hazard to health and safety of the public;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60470033-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1266/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><chapeau> minimize the disturbances of the prevailing hydrologic balance at the minesite and in associated offsite areas and to the quantity of water in surface ground water systems both during and after coal mining operations and during reclamation by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id60470034-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1266/b/9/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> avoiding acid or other toxic mine drainage by such measures as, but not limited to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id60470035-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1266/b/9/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> preventing or removing water from contact with toxic producing deposits;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id60470036-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1266/b/9/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> treating drainage to reduce toxic content which adversely affects downstream water upon being released to water courses;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id60470037-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1266/b/9/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> casing, sealing, or otherwise managing boreholes, shafts, and wells to keep acid or other toxic drainage from entering ground and surface waters; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id60470038-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1266/b/9/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> conducting surface coal mining operations so as to prevent, to the extent possible using the best technology currently available, additional contributions of suspended solids to streamflow or runoff outside the permit area (but in no event shall such contributions be in excess of requirements set by applicable State or Federal law), and avoiding channel deepening or enlargement in operations requiring the discharge of water from mines;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60470039-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1266/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> with respect to other surface impacts not specified in this subsection including the construction of new roads or the improvement or use of existing roads to gain access to the site of such activities and for haulage, repair areas, storage areas, processing areas, shipping areas, and other areas upon which are sited structures, facilities, or other property or materials on the surface, resulting from or incident to such activities, operate in accordance with the standards established under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1265">section 1265 of this title</ref> for such effects which result from surface coal mining operations: <i>Provided</i>, That the Secretary shall make such modifications in the requirements imposed by this paragraph as are necessary to accommodate the distinct difference between surface and underground coal mining;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6047003a-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1266/b/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> to the extent possible using the best technology currently available, minimize disturbances and adverse impacts of the operation on fish, wildlife, and related environmental values, and achieve enhancement of such resources where practicable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6047003b-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1266/b/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> locate openings for all new drift mines working acid-producing or iron-producing coal seams in such a manner as to prevent a gravity discharge of water from the mine.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6047003c-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1266/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Suspension of underground coal mining operations in urbanized areas</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to protect the stability of the land, the regulatory authority shall suspend underground coal mining under urbanized areas, cities, towns, and communities and adjacent to industrial or commercial buildings, major impoundments, or permanent streams if he finds imminent danger to inhabitants of the urbanized areas, cities, towns, and communities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6047003d-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1266/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability of this subchapter to surface operations and surface impacts incident to underground coal mining operations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of this subchapter relating to State and Federal programs, permits, bonds, inspections and enforcement, public review, and administrative and judicial review shall be applicable to surface operations and surface impacts incident to an underground coal mine with such modifications to the permit application requirements, permit approval or denial procedures, and bond requirements as are necessary to accommodate the distinct difference between surface and underground coal mining. The Secretary shall promulgate such modifications in accordance with the rulemaking procedure established in <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1251">section 1251 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6047003e-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/87/tV/s516">Pub. L. 95–87, title V, § 516</ref>, <date date="1977-08-03">Aug. 3, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/495">91 Stat. 495</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6047003f-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id60470040-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id60470041-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Coal Mine Health and Safety Act of 1969, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/91/173">Pub. L. 91–173</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/742">83 Stat. 742</ref>, which was redesignated the Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 1977 by <ref href="/us/pl/95/164/tI/s101">Pub. L. 95–164, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1977-11-09">Nov. 9, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1290">91 Stat. 1290</ref>, and is classified principally to chapter 22 (§ 801 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s801">section 801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
