<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id604971d0-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1277"><num value="1277">§ 1277.</num><heading> Special bituminous coal mines</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id604971d1-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1277/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Issuance of separate regulations; criteria</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The regulatory authority is authorized to issue separate regulations for those special bituminous coal surface mines located west of the 100th meridian west longitude which meet the following criteria:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id604971d2-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1277/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the excavation of the specific mine pit takes place on the same relatively limited site for an extended period of time;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id604971d3-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1277/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the excavation of the specific mine pit follows a coal seam having an inclination of fifteen degrees or more from the horizontal, and continues in the same area proceeding downward with lateral expansion of the pit necessary to maintain stability or as necessary to accommodate the orderly expansion of the total mining operation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id604971d4-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1277/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the excavation of the specific mine pit involves the mining of more than one coal seam and mining has been initiated on the deepest coal seam contemplated to be mined in the current operation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id604971d5-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1277/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the amount of material removed is large in proportion to the surface area disturbed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id604971d6-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1277/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> there is no practicable alternative method of mining the coal involved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id604971d7-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1277/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> there is no practicable method to reclaim the land in the manner required by this chapter; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id604971d8-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1277/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> the specific mine pit has been actually producing coal since <date date="1972-01-01">January 1, 1972</date>, in such manner as to meet the criteria set forth in this section, and, because of past duration of mining, is substantially committed to a mode of operation which warrants exceptions to some provisions of this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id604971d9-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1277/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> New bituminous coal surface mines</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Such separate regulations shall also contain a distinct part to cover and pertain to new bituminous coal surface mines which may be developed after <date date="1977-08-03">August 3, 1977</date>, on lands immediately adjacent to lands upon which are located special bituminous mines existing on <date date="1972-01-01">January 1, 1972</date>. Such new mines shall meet the criteria of subsection (a) except for paragraphs (3) and (7), and all requirements of State law, notwithstanding in whole or part the regulations issued pursuant to subsection (c) of this section. In the event of an amendment or revision to the State’s regulatory program, regulations, or decisions made thereunder governing such mines, the Secretary shall issue such additional regulations as necessary to meet the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id604971da-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1277/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Scope of alternative regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Such alternative regulations may pertain only to the standards governing onsite handling of spoils, elimination of depressions capable of collecting water, creation of impoundments, and regrading to the approximate original contour and shall specify that remaining highwalls are stable. All other performance standards in this subchapter shall apply to such mines.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id604971db-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/87/tV/s527">Pub. L. 95–87, title V, § 527</ref>, <date date="1977-08-03">Aug. 3, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/513">91 Stat. 513</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
