<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id604bbc3c-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1298"><num value="1298">§ 1298.</num><heading> Alaskan surface coal mine study</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id604bbc3d-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1298/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Contract with National Academy of Sciences-National Academy of Engineering</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is directed to contract to such extent or in such amounts as are provided in advance in appropriation Acts with the National Academy of Sciences-National Academy of Engineering for an in-depth study of surface coal mining conditions in the State of Alaska in order to determine which, if any, of the provisions of this chapter should be modified with respect to surface coal mining operations in Alaska.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id604bbc3e-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1298/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Report to President and Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall report on the findings of the study to the President and Congress no later than two years after <date date="1977-08-03">August 3, 1977</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id604bbc3f-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1298/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Draft of legislation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall include in his report a draft of legislation to implement any changes recommended to this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id604bbc40-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1298/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Modification of applicability of environmental protection provisions of this chapter to surface coal mining operations in Alaska; publication in Federal Register; hearing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Until one year after the Secretary has made this report to the President and Congress, or three years after <date date="1977-08-03">August 3, 1977</date>, whichever comes first, the Secretary is authorized to modify the applicability of any environmental protection provision of this chapter, or any regulation issued pursuant thereto, to any surface coal mining operation in Alaska from which coal has been mined during the year preceding <date date="1977-08-03">August 3, 1977</date>, if he determines that it is necessary to insure the continued operation of such surface coal mining operation. The Secretary may exercise this authority only after he has (1) published notice of proposed modification in the Federal Register and in a newspaper of general circulation in the area of Alaska in which the affected surface coal mining operation is located, and (2) held a public hearing on the proposed modification in Alaska.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id604bbc41-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1298/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Interim regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to allow new mines in Alaska to continue orderly development, the Secretary is authorized to issue interim regulations pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1251/b">section 1251(b) of this title</ref> including those modifications to the environmental standards as required based on the special physical, hydrological and climatic conditions in Alaska but with the purpose of protecting the environment to an extent equivalent to those standards for the other coal regions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id604bbc42-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1298/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of this section $250,000: <i>Provided</i>, That no new budget authority is authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 1977.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id604bbc43-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/87/tVII/s708">Pub. L. 95–87, title VII, § 708</ref>, <date date="1977-08-03">Aug. 3, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/521">91 Stat. 521</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
