<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id604e2cb3-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1309a"><num value="1309a">§ 1309a.</num><heading> Subsidence</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id604e2cb4-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1309a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Underground coal mining operations conducted after <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, shall comply with each of the following requirements:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id604e2cb5-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1309a/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Promptly repair, or compensate for, material damage resulting from subsidence caused to any occupied residential dwelling and structures related thereto, or non-commercial building due to underground coal mining operations. Repair of damage shall include rehabilitation, restoration, or replacement of the damaged occupied residential dwelling and structures related thereto, or non-commercial building. Compensation shall be provided to the owner of the damaged occupied residential dwelling and structures related thereto or non-commercial building and shall be in the full amount of the diminution in value resulting from the subsidence. Compensation may be accomplished by the purchase, prior to mining, of a noncancellable premium-prepaid insurance policy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id604e2cb6-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1309a/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Promptly replace any drinking, domestic, or residential water supply from a well or spring in existence prior to the application for a surface coal mining and reclamation permit, which has been affected by contamination, diminution, or interruption resulting from underground coal mining operations.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit or interrupt underground coal mining operations.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id604e2cb7-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1309a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within one year after <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, the Secretary shall, after providing notice and opportunity for public comment, promulgate final regulations to implement subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id604e2cb8-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/87/tVII/s720">Pub. L. 95–87, title VII, § 720</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tXXV/s2504/a/1">Pub. L. 102–486, title XXV, § 2504(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3104">106 Stat. 3104</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id604e2cb9-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id604e2cba-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id604e2cbb-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Review of Existing Requirements and Report to Congress</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tXXV/s2504/a/2">Pub. L. 102–486, title XXV, § 2504(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3104">106 Stat. 3104</ref>, directed Secretary of the Interior to review existing requirements related to underground coal mine subsidence and natural gas and petroleum pipeline safety, submit a report detailing results of review to Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of Senate and Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of House of Representatives within 18 months of <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, and, where appropriate, to commence a rulemaking to address any deficiencies in existing law determined in the review regarding notification, coordination and mitigation.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
