<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id604e2d25-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1326"><num value="1326">§ 1326.</num><heading> Fellowship conditions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id604e2d26-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1326/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> A person awarded a fellowship under the provisions of this subchapter shall continue to receive the payments provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1324/a">section 1324(a) of this title</ref> only during such periods as the Secretary of Energy finds that he is maintaining satisfactory proficiency in, and devoting essentially full time to, study or research in the field in which such fellowship was awarded, in an institution of higher education, and is not engaging in gainful employment other than part-time employment in teaching, research, or similar activities, approved by the Secretary of Energy.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id604e2d27-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1326/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The Secretary of Energy shall require reports containing such information in such forms and to be filed at such times as he determines necessary from each person awarded a fellowship under the provisions of this subchapter. Such reports shall be accompanied by a certificate from an appropriate official at the institution of higher education, library, archive, or other research center approved by the Secretary of Energy, stating that such person is making satisfactory progress in, and is devoting essentially full time to the research for which the fellowship was awarded.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id604e2d28-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/87/tIX/s906">Pub. L. 95–87, title IX, § 906</ref>, <date date="1977-08-03">Aug. 3, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/530">91 Stat. 530</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/91/tIII/s301/a">Pub. L. 95–91, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, title VII, §§ 703, 707, <date date="1977-08-04">Aug. 4, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/577">91 Stat. 577</ref>, 606, 607.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id604e2d29-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id604e2d2a-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id604e2d2b-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Energy” substituted in text for “Administrator”, meaning Administrator of Energy Research and Development Administration, pursuant to sections 301(a), 703, and 707 of <ref href="/us/pl/95/91">Pub. L. 95–91</ref>, which are classified to sections 7151(a), 7293, 7297 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, and which terminated Energy Research and Development Administration and transferred its functions and functions of Administrator thereof (with certain exceptions) to Secretary of Energy.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
