<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id60509d85-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1411"><num value="1411">§ 1411.</num><heading> Prohibited activities by United States citizens</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id60509d86-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1411/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibited activities and exceptions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id60509d87-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1411/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> No United States citizen may engage in any exploration or commercial recovery unless authorized to do so under—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60509d88-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1411/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a license or a permit issued under this subchapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60509d89-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1411/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a license, permit, or equivalent authorization issued by a reciprocating state; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60509d8a-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1411/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> an international agreement which is in force with respect to the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id60509d8b-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1411/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The prohibitions of this subsection shall not apply to any of the following activities:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60509d8c-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1411/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Scientific research, including that concerning hard mineral resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60509d8d-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1411/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Mapping, or the taking of any geophysical, geochemical, oceanographic, or atmospheric measurements or random bottom samplings of the deep seabed, if such taking does not significantly alter the surface or subsurface of the deep seabed or significantly affect the environment.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60509d8e-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1411/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The design, construction, or testing of equipment and facilities which will or may be used for exploration or commercial recovery, if such design, construction, or testing is conducted on shore, or does not involve the recovery of any but incidental hard mineral resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60509d8f-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1411/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The furnishing of machinery, products, supplies, services, or materials for any exploration or commercial recovery conducted under a license or permit issued under this subchapter, a license or permit or equivalent authorization issued by a reciprocating state, or under an international agreement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60509d90-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1411/a/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Activities, other than exploration or commercial recovery activities, of the Federal Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id60509d91-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1411/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Existing exploration</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id60509d92-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1411/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Subsection (a)(1)(A) shall not be deemed to prohibit any United States citizen who is engaged in exploration before <date date="1980-06-28">June 28, 1980</date>, from continuing to engage in such exploration—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60509d93-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1411/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> if such citizen applies for a license under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1413/a">section 1413(a) of this title</ref> with respect to such exploration within such reasonable period of time, after the date on which initial regulations to implement <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1413/a">section 1413(a) of this title</ref> are issued, as the Administrator shall prescribe; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60509d94-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1411/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> until such license is issued to such citizen or a final administrative or judicial determination is made affirming the denial of certification of the application for, or issuance of, such license.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id60509d95-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1411/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1), if the President by Executive order determines that immediate suspension of exploration activities is necessary for the reasons set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1416/a/2/B">section 1416(a)(2)(B) of this title</ref> or the Administrator determines that immediate suspension of activities is necessary to prevent a significant adverse effect on the environment or to preserve the safety of life and property at sea, the Administrator is authorized, notwithstanding any other requirement of this chapter, to issue an emergency order requiring any United States citizen who is engaged in exploration before <date date="1980-06-28">June 28, 1980</date>, to immediately suspend exploration activities. The issuance of such emergency order is subject to judicial review as provided in chapter 7 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id60509d96-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1411/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The timely filing of any application for a license under paragraph (1)(A) shall entitle the applicant to priority of right for the issuance of such license under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1413/b">section 1413(b) of this title</ref>. In any case in which more than one application referred to in paragraph (1) is filed based on exploration plans required by <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1413/a/2">section 1413(a)(2) of this title</ref> which refer to all or part of the same deep seabed area, the Administrator shall, in taking action on such applications, apply principles of equity which take into consideration, among other things, the date on which the applicants or predecessors in interest, or component organizations thereof, commenced exploration activities and the continuity and extent of such exploration and amount of funds expended with respect to such exploration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id60509d97-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1411/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Interference</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No United States citizen may interfere or participate in interference with any activity conducted by any licensee or permittee which is authorized to be undertaken under a license or permit issued by the United States to the licensee or permittee under this chapter or with any activity conducted by the holder of, and authorized to be undertaken under, a license or permit or equivalent authorization issued by a reciprocating state for the exploration or commercial recovery of hard mineral resources. United States citizens shall exercise their rights on the high seas with reasonable regard for the interests of other states in their exercise of the freedoms of the high seas.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id60509d98-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/283/tI/s101">Pub. L. 96–283, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1980-06-28">June 28, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/557">94 Stat. 557</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
