<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6052e83e-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1425"><num value="1425">§ 1425.</num><heading> Relinquishment, surrender, and transfer of licenses and permits</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6052e83f-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1425/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Relinquishment and surrender</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any licensee or permittee may at any time, without penalty—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6052e840-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1425/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> surrender to the Administrator a license or a permit issued to the licensee or permittee; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6052e841-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1425/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> relinquish to the Administrator, in whole or in part, any right to conduct any exploration or commercial recovery activities authorized by the license or permit.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Any licensee or permittee who surrenders a license or permit, or relinquishes any such right, shall remain liable with respect to all violations and penalties incurred, and damage to persons or property caused, by the licensee or permittee as a result of activities engaged in by the licensee or permittee under such license or permit.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6052e842-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1425/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any license or permit, upon written request of the licensee or permittee, may be transferred by the Administrator; except that no such transfer may occur unless the proposed transferee is a United States citizen and until the Administrator determines that (1) the proposed transfer is in the public interest, and (2) the proposed transferee and the exploration or commercial recovery activities the transferee proposes to conduct meet the requirements of this chapter and regulations issued under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6052e843-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/283/tI/s115">Pub. L. 96–283, title I, § 115</ref>, <date date="1980-06-28">June 28, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/572">94 Stat. 572</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
