<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id60555863-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1441"><num value="1441">§ 1441.</num><heading> Declaration of Congressional intent</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the intent of Congress—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60555864-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1441/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> that any international agreement to which the United States becomes a party should, in addition to promoting other national oceans objectives—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id60555865-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1441/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> provide assured and nondiscriminatory access, under reasonable terms and conditions, to the hard mineral resources of the deep seabed for United States citizens, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id60555866-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1441/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provide security of tenure by recognizing the rights of United States citizens who have undertaken exploration or commercial recovery under subchapter I before such agreement enters into force with respect to the United States to continue their operations under terms, conditions, and restrictions which do not impose significant new economic burdens upon such citizens with respect to such operations with the effect of preventing the continuation of such operations on a viable economic basis;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60555867-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1441/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> that the extent to which any such international agreement conforms to the provisions of paragraph (1) should be determined by the totality of the provisions of such agreement, including, but not limited to, the practical implications for the security of investments of any discretionary powers granted to an international regulatory body, the structures and decisionmaking procedures of such body, the availability of impartial and effective procedures for the settlement of disputes, and any features that tend to discriminate against exploration and commercial recovery activities undertaken by United States citizens; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60555868-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1441/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> that this chapter should be transitional pending—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id60555869-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1441/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the adoption of an international agreement at the Third United Nations Conference on the Law of the Sea, and the entering into force of such agreement, or portions thereof, with respect to the United States, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6055586a-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1441/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if such adoption is not forthcoming, the negotiation of a multilateral or other treaty concerning the deep seabed, and the entering into force of such treaty with respect to the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id6055586b-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/283/tII/s201">Pub. L. 96–283, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1980-06-28">June 28, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/575">94 Stat. 575</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
