<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id60555877-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1461"><num value="1461">§ 1461.</num><heading> Prohibited acts</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is unlawful for any person who is a United States citizen, or a foreign national on board a vessel documented or numbered under the laws of the United States, or subject to the jurisdiction of the United States under a reciprocating state agreement negotiated under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1428/e">section 1428(e) of this title</ref>—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60555878-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1461/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to violate any provision of this chapter, any regulation issued under this chapter, or any term, condition, or restriction of any license or permit issued to such person under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60555879-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1461/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to engage in exploration or commercial recovery after the revocation, or during the period of suspension, of an applicable license or permit issued under this chapter, to engage in a particular exploration or commercial recovery activity during the period such activity has been suspended under this chapter, or to fail to modify a particular exploration or commercial recovery activity for which modification was required under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6055587a-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1461/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to refuse to permit any Federal officer or employee authorized to monitor or enforce the provisions of this chapter, as provided in sections 1424 and 1464 of this title, to board a vessel documented or numbered under the laws of the United States, or any vessel for which such boarding is authorized by a treaty or executive agreement, for purposes of conducting any search or inspection in connection with the monitoring or enforcement of this chapter or any regulation, term, condition, or restriction referred to in paragraph (1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6055587b-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1461/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to forcibly assault, resist, oppose, impede, intimidate, or interfere with any such authorized officer or employee in the conduct of any search or inspection described in paragraph (3);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6055587c-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1461/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> to resist a lawful arrest for any act prohibited by this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6055587d-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1461/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> to ship, transport, offer for sale, sell, purchase, import, export, or have custody, control, or possession of any hard mineral resource recovered, processed, or retained in violation of this chapter or any regulation, term, condition, or restriction referred to in paragraph (1); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6055587e-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1461/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> to interfere with, delay, or prevent, by any means, the apprehension or arrest of any other person subject to this section knowing that such other person has committed any act prohibited by this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id6055587f-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/283/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 96–283, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1980-06-28">June 28, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/577">94 Stat. 577</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
