<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6055588a-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1464"><num value="1464">§ 1464.</num><heading> Enforcement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6055588b-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1464/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Responsibility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to the other provisions of this subsection, the Administrator shall enforce the provisions of this chapter. The Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall exercise such other enforcement responsibilities with respect to vessels subject to the provisions of this chapter as are authorized under other provisions of law and may, upon the specific request of the Administrator, assist the Administrator in the enforcement of the provisions of this chapter. The Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall have the exclusive responsibility for enforcement measures which affect the safety of life and property at sea. The Administrator and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may, by agreement, on a reimbursable basis or otherwise, utilize the personnel, services, equipment, including aircraft and vessels, and facilities of any other Federal agency or department, and may authorize officers or employees of other departments or agencies to provide assistance as necessary in carrying out subsection (b). While providing such assistance, these officers and employees shall be under the control, authority, and supervision of the Coast Guard. The Administrator and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may issue regulations jointly or severally as may be necessary and appropriate to carry out their duties under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6055588c-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1464/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Powers of authorized officers</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To enforce this chapter on board any vessel subject to the provisions of this chapter, any officer who is authorized by the Administrator or by the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6055588d-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1464/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> board and inspect any vessel which is subject to the provisions of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6055588e-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1464/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> search any such vessel if the officer has reasonable cause to believe that the vessel has been used or employed in the violation of any provision of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6055588f-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1464/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> arrest any person subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1461">section 1461 of this title</ref> if the officer has reasonable cause to believe that the person has committed a criminal offense under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1463">section 1463 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60555890-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1464/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> seize any such vessel together with its gear, furniture, appurtenances, stores, and cargo, used or employed in, or with respect to which it reasonably appears that such vessel was used or employed in, the violation of any provision of this chapter if such seizure is necessary to prevent evasion of the enforcement of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60555891-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1464/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> seize any hard mineral resource recovered or processed in violation of any provision of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60555892-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1464/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> seize any other evidence related to any violation of any provision of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60555893-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1464/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> execute any warrant or other process issued by any court of competent jurisdiction; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60555894-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1464/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> exercise any other lawful authority.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id60555895-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1464/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “provisions of this chapter” or “provision of this chapter” means (1) any provision of subchapter I or II or this subchapter, (2) any regulation issued under subchapter I, subchapter II, or this subchapter, and (3) any term, condition, or restriction of any license or permit issued under subchapter I.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id60555896-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1464/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Proprietary information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Proprietary and privileged information seized or maintained under this subchapter concerning a person or vessel engaged in exploration or commercial recovery shall not be made available for general or public use or inspection. The Administrator and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall issue regulations to insure the confidentiality of privileged and proprietary information.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id60555897-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/283/tIII/s304">Pub. L. 96–283, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1980-06-28">June 28, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/578">94 Stat. 578</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id60555898-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id60555899-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id6055589a-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
