<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6063b0ca-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1726"><num value="1726">§ 1726.</num><heading> Alternatives for marginal properties</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6063b0cb-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1726/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination of best interests of State concerned and United States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary and the State concerned, acting in the best interests of the United States and the State concerned to promote production, reduce administrative costs, and increase net receipts to the United States and the States, shall jointly determine, on a case by case basis, the amount of what marginal production from a lease or leases or well or wells, or parts thereof, shall be subject to a prepayment under subsection (b) or regulatory relief under subsection (c). If the State concerned does not consent, such prepayments or regulatory relief shall not be made available under this section for such marginal production: <i>Provided</i>, That if royalty payments from a lease or leases, or well or wells are not shared with any State, such determination shall be made solely by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6063b0cc-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1726/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Prepayment of royalty</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6063b0cd-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1726/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding the provisions of any lease to the contrary, for any lease or leases or well or wells identified by the Secretary and the State concerned pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary is authorized to accept a prepayment for royalties in lieu of monthly royalty payments under the lease for the remainder of the lease term if the affected lessee so agrees. Any prepayment agreed to by the Secretary, State concerned and lessee which is less than an average $500 per month in total royalties shall be effectuated under this section not earlier than two years after <date date="1996-08-13">August 13, 1996</date>, and, any prepayment which is greater than an average $500 per month in total royalties shall be effectuated under this section not earlier than three years after <date date="1996-08-13">August 13, 1996</date>. The Secretary and the State concerned may condition their acceptance of the prepayment authorized under this section on the lessee’s agreeing to such terms and conditions as the Secretary and the State concerned deem appropriate and consistent with the purposes of this chapter. Such terms may—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6063b0ce-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1726/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> provide for prepayment that does not result in a loss of revenue to the United States in present value terms;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6063b0cf-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1726/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> include provisions for receiving additional prepayments or royalties for developments in the lease or leases or well or wells that deviate significantly from the assumptions and facts on which the valuation is determined; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id6063b0d0-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1726/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> require the lessee or its designee to provide such periodic production reports as may be necessary to allow the Secretary and the State concerned to monitor production for the purposes of subparagraph (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6063b0d1-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1726/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> State share</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A prepayment under this section shall be shared by the Secretary with any State or other recipient to the same extent as any royalty payment for such lease.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id6063b0d2-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1726/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Satisfaction of obligation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as may be provided in the terms and conditions established by the Secretary under subsection (b), a lessee or its designee who makes a prepayment under this section shall have satisfied in full the lessee’s obligation to pay royalty on the production stream sold from the lease or leases or well or wells.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6063b0d3-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1726/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Alternative accounting and auditing requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within one year after <date date="1996-08-13">August 13, 1996</date>, the Secretary or the delegated State shall provide accounting, reporting, and auditing relief that will encourage lessees to continue to produce and develop properties subject to subsection (a): <i>Provided</i>, That such relief will only be available to lessees in a State that concurs, which concurrence is not required if royalty payments from the lease or leases or well or wells are not shared with any State. Prior to granting such relief, the Secretary and, if appropriate, the State concerned shall agree that the type of marginal wells and relief provided under this paragraph is in the best interest of the United States and, if appropriate, the State concerned.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6063b0d4-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/451/tI/s117">Pub. L. 97–451, title I, § 117</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/104/185/s7/a">Pub. L. 104–185, § 7(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-13">Aug. 13, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1715">110 Stat. 1715</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/104/200/s1/7">Pub. L. 104–200, § 1(7)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-22">Sept. 22, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2421">110 Stat. 2421</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6063b0d5-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6063b0d6-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id6063b0d7-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/185/s4/a">Pub. L. 104–185, § 4(a)</ref>, which directed the addition of this section at the end of the Federal Oil and Gas Royalty Management Act of 1982, was executed by adding this section at the end of title I of that Act to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6063b0d8-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/104/200/s1/7">Pub. L. 104–200, § 1(7)</ref>, substituted “its designee” for “it designee”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6063b0d9-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id6063b0da-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section applicable with respect to production of oil and gas after the first day of the month following <date date="1996-08-13">Aug. 13, 1996</date>, except as provided by this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/185/s11">section 11 of Pub. L. 104–185</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1996 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1701">section 1701 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6063b0db-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Applicability</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section not applicable to any privately owned minerals or with respect to Indian lands, see sections 9 and 10 of <ref href="/us/pl/104/185">Pub. L. 104–185</ref>, set out as an Applicability of 1996 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1701">section 1701 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
