<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6063b0f5-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1733"><num value="1733">§ 1733.</num><heading> Information</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6063b0f6-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1733/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability of confidential information by Secretary pursuant to cooperative agreements; conditions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Trade secrets, proprietary and other confidential information shall be made available by the Secretary, pursuant to a cooperative agreement, to a State or Indian tribe upon request only if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6063b0f7-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1733/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> such State or Indian tribe consents in writing to restrict the dissemination of the information to those who are directly involved in an audit or investigation under this chapter and who have a need to know;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6063b0f8-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1733/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> such State or tribe accepts liability for wrongful disclosure;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6063b0f9-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1733/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> in the case of a State, such State demonstrates that such information is essential to the conduct of an audit or investigation or to litigation under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1734">section 1734 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6063b0fa-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1733/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> in the case of an Indian tribe, such tribe demonstrates that such information is essential to the conduct of an audit or investigation and waives sovereign immunity by express consent for wrongful disclosure by such tribe.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6063b0fb-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1733/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Nonliability of United States for wrongful disclosure</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The United States shall not be liable for the wrongful disclosure by any individual, State, or Indian tribe of any information provided to such individual, State, or Indian tribe pursuant to any cooperative agreement or a delegation, authorized by this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6063b0fc-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1733/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Law governing disclosure</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever any individual, State, or Indian tribe has obtained possession of information pursuant to a cooperative agreement authorized by this section, or any individual or State has obtained possession of information pursuant to a delegation under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1735">section 1735 of this title</ref>, the individual shall be subject to the same provisions of law with respect to the disclosure of such information as would apply to an officer or employee of the United States or of any department or agency thereof and the State or Indian tribe shall be subject to the same provisions of law with respect to the disclosure of such information as would apply to the United States or any department or agency thereof. No State or State officer or employee who receives trade secrets, proprietary information, or other confidential information under this chapter may be required to disclose such information under State law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id6063b0fd-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/451/tII/s203">Pub. L. 97–451, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2458">96 Stat. 2458</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
