<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6063b131-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1736"><num value="1736">§ 1736.</num><heading> Shared civil penalties</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An amount equal to 50 per centum of any civil penalty collected by the Federal Government under this chapter resulting from activities conducted by a State or Indian tribe pursuant to a cooperative agreement under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1732">section 1732 of this title</ref> or a State under a delegation under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1735">section 1735 of this title</ref>, shall be payable to such State or tribe. Any payments under this section shall be reduced by an amount equal to any payments provided or due to such State or Indian tribe under the cooperative agreement or delegation, as applicable, during the fiscal year in which the civil penalty is received, up to the total amount provided or due for that fiscal year.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id6063b132-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/451/tII/s206">Pub. L. 97–451, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2460">96 Stat. 2460</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/76/dG/tI/s121">Pub. L. 113–76, div. G, title I, § 121</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/314">128 Stat. 314</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6063b133-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6063b134-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6063b135-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—<ref href="/us/pl/113/76">Pub. L. 113–76</ref> substituted “Any payments under this section shall be reduced by an amount equal to any payments provided or due to such State or Indian tribe under the cooperative agreement or delegation, as applicable, during the fiscal year in which the civil penalty is received, up to the total amount provided or due for that fiscal year.” for “Such amount shall be deducted from any compensation due such State or Indian tribe under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1732">section 1732 of this title</ref> or such State under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1735">section 1735 of this title</ref>.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
