<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6063b13c-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s1752"><num value="1752">§ 1752.</num><heading> Reports</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall submit to the Congress an annual report on the implementation of this chapter. The information to be included in the report and the format of the report shall be developed by the Secretary after consulting with the Committees on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate. The Secretary shall also report on the progress of the Department in reconciling account balances.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id6063b13d-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/451/tIII/s302">Pub. L. 97–451, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2461">96 Stat. 2461</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/437/s11/a/2">Pub. L. 103–437, § 11(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4589">108 Stat. 4589</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/362/tIX/s901/j/1">Pub. L. 105–362, title IX, § 901(j)(1)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3290">112 Stat. 3290</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6063b13e-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6063b13f-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6063b140-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—<ref href="/us/pl/105/362">Pub. L. 105–362</ref> struck out subsec. (a) designation and struck out subsec. (b) which read as follows: “Commencing with fiscal year 1984, the Inspector General of the Department of the Interior shall conduct a biennial audit of the Federal royalty management system. The Inspector General shall submit the results of such audit to the Secretary and to the Congress.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/437">Pub. L. 103–437</ref> substituted “Natural Resources” for “Interior and Insular Affairs” after “Committees on”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6063b141-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6063b142-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, of provisions of law requiring submittal to Congress of any annual, semiannual, or other regular periodic report listed in House Document No. 103–7 (in which a report required under this section is listed on page 111), see <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id6063b143-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study of the Adequacy of Royalty Management for Minerals on Federal and Indian Lands</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/97/451/tIII/s303">Pub. L. 97–451, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2461">96 Stat. 2461</ref>, directed Secretary to study question of adequacy of royalty management for coal, uranium and other energy and nonenergy minerals on Federal and Indian lands, include proposed legislation if Secretary determined that such legislation was necessary to ensure prompt and proper collection of revenues owed to the United States, the States and Indian tribes or Indian allottees from the sale, lease or other disposal of such minerals, with study to be submitted to Congress not later than one year from <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
