<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5feece68-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s192a"><num value="192a">§ 192a.</num><heading> Cancellation or modification of contracts</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Where, under any existing contract entered into pursuant to the first proviso in the second paragraph of <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s192">section 192 of this title</ref>, any refinery is required to pay a premium price for the purchase of Government royalty oil, such refinery may, at its option, by written notice to the Secretary of the Interior, elect either—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5ff11859-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s192a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to terminate such contract, the termination to take place at the end of the calendar month following the month in which such notice is given; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id5ff1185a-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s192a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to retain such contract with the modifications, that (a) the price, on and after <date date="1949-03-01">March 1, 1949</date>, shall be as defined in the contract, without premium payments, (b) any credit thereby resulting from past premium payments shall be added to the refinery’s account, and (c) the Secretary may, at his option, elect to terminate the contract as so modified, such termination to take place at the end of the third calendar month following the month in which written notice thereof is given by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id5ff1185b-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/act/1949-09-01/ch529/s1">Sept. 1, 1949, ch. 529, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/682">63 Stat. 682</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5ff1185c-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5ff1185d-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id5ff1185e-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was not enacted as part of <ref href="/us/act/1920-02-25/ch85">act Feb. 25, 1920, ch. 85</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/41/437">41 Stat. 437</ref>, known as the Mineral Leasing Act, which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
