<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5fd7014d-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s21a"><num value="21a">§ 21a.</num><heading> National mining and minerals policy; “minerals” defined; execution of policy under other authorized programs</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress declares that it is the continuing policy of the Federal Government in the national interest to foster and encourage private enterprise in (1) the development of economically sound and stable domestic mining, minerals, metal and mineral reclamation industries, (2) the orderly and economic development of domestic mineral resources, reserves, and reclamation of metals and minerals to help assure satisfaction of industrial, security and environmental needs, (3) mining, mineral, and metallurgical research, including the use and recycling of scrap to promote the wise and efficient use of our natural and reclaimable mineral resources, and (4) the study and development of methods for the disposal, control, and reclamation of mineral waste products, and the reclamation of mined land, so as to lessen any adverse impact of mineral extraction and processing upon the physical environment that may result from mining or mineral activities.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of this section “minerals” shall include all minerals and mineral fuels including oil, gas, coal, oil shale and uranium.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be the responsibility of the Secretary of the Interior to carry out this policy when exercising his authority under such programs as may be authorized by law other than this section.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id5fd7014e-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/631/tI/s101">Pub. L. 91–631, title I, § 101</ref>, formerly § 2, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1876">84 Stat. 1876</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/tI/s1081/b">Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1081(b)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/721">109 Stat. 721</ref>; renumbered title I, § 101, <ref href="/us/pl/104/325/s2/1">Pub. L. 104–325, § 2(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3994">110 Stat. 3994</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5fd7014f-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5fd70150-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id5fd70151-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—<ref href="/us/pl/104/66">Pub. L. 104–66</ref> in last par. struck out at end “For this purpose the Secretary of the Interior shall include in his annual report to the Congress a report on the state of the domestic mining, minerals, and mineral reclamation industries, including a statement of the trend in utilization and depletion of these resources, together with such recommendations for legislative programs as may be necessary to implement the policy of this section.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id5fd70152-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="id5fd70153-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/91/631/s1">Pub. L. 91–631, § 1</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1876">84 Stat. 1876</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/91/631/s1">“That this Act [enacting this section] may be cited as the ‘Mining and Minerals Policy Act of 1970’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
