<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5fd7015b-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s23"><num value="23">§ 23.</num><heading> Length of claims on veins or lodes</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Mining claims upon veins or lodes of quartz or other rock in place bearing gold, silver, cinnabar, lead, tin, copper, or other valuable deposits, located prior to <date date="1872-05-10">May 10, 1872</date>, shall be governed as to length along the vein or lode by the customs, regulations, and laws in force at the date of their location. A mining claim located after the 10th day of May 1872, whether located by one or more persons, may equal, but shall not exceed, one thousand five hundred feet in length along the vein or lode; but no location of a mining claim shall be made until the discovery of the vein or lode within the limits of the claim located. No claim shall extend more than three hundred feet on each side of the middle of the vein at the surface, nor shall any claim be limited by any mining regulation to less than twenty-five feet on each side of the middle of the vein at the surface, except where adverse rights existing on the 10th day of May 1872 render such limitation necessary. The end lines of each claim shall be parallel to each other.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id5fd7015c-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(R.S. § 2320.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5fd7015d-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5fd7015e-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id5fd7015f-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">R.S. § 2320 derived from <ref href="/us/act/1872-05-10/ch152/s2">act May 10, 1872, ch. 152, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/17/91">17 Stat. 91</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
