<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5fde05d8-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s35"><num value="35">§ 35.</num><heading> Placer claims; entry and proceedings for patent under provisions applicable to vein or lode claims; conforming entry to legal subdivisions and surveys; limitation of claims; homestead entry of segregated agricultural land</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Claims usually called “placers,” including all forms of deposit, excepting veins of quartz, or other rock in place, shall be subject to entry and patent, under like circumstances and conditions, and upon similar proceedings, as are provided for vein or lode claims; but where the lands have been previously surveyed by the United States, the entry in its exterior limits shall conform to the legal subdivisions of the public lands. And where placer claims are upon surveyed lands, and conform to legal subdivisions, no further survey or plat shall be required, and all placer-mining claims located after the 10th day of May 1872, shall conform as near as practicable with the United States system of public-land surveys, and the rectangular subdivisions of such surveys, and no such location shall include more than twenty acres for each individual claimant; but where placer claims cannot be conformed to legal subdivisions, survey and plat shall be made as on unsurveyed lands; and where by the segregation of mineral land in any legal subdivision a quantity of agricultural land less than forty acres remains, such fractional portion of agricultural land may be entered by any party qualified by law, for homestead purposes.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id5fde05d9-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(R.S. §§ 2329, 2331; <ref href="/us/act/1891-03-03/ch561/s4">Mar. 3, 1891, ch. 561, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/26/1097">26 Stat. 1097</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5fde05da-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id5fde05db-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id5fde05dc-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">R.S. § 2329 derived from <ref href="/us/act/1870-07-09/ch235/s12">act July 9, 1870, ch. 235, § 12</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/16/217">16 Stat. 217</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">R.S. § 2331 derived from <ref href="/us/act/1872-05-10/ch152/s10">act May 10, 1872, ch. 152, § 10</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/17/94">17 Stat. 94</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id5fde05dd-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id5fde05de-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Submerged Lands Act</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions of this section as not amended, modified or repealed by the Submerged Lands Act, see <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1303">section 1303 of Title 43</ref>, Public Lands.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
