<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id5fd48ff6-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s4c"><num value="4c">§ 4c.</num><heading> Investigation of sub-bituminous and lignite coal</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The United States Bureau of Mines, under the general direction of the Secretary of the Interior, is authorized to conduct investigations, studies, and experiments on its own initiative and in cooperation with individuals, State institutions, laboratories, and other organizations, with a view to (1) the development of a commercially practicable carbonization method of processing sub-bituminous and lignite coal so as to convert such coal into an all-purpose fuel, to provide fertilizers, and obtain such other byproducts thereof as may be commercially valuable; (2) the development of efficient methods, equipment, and devices for burning lignite or char therefrom; and (3) determining and developing methods for more efficient utilization of such sub-bituminous and lignite coal for purposes of generating electric power.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id5fd48ff7-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/act/1936-05-15/ch397/s1">May 15, 1936, ch. 397, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/1275">49 Stat. 1275</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/285/s10/b">Pub. L. 102–285, § 10(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-05-18">May 18, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/172">106 Stat. 172</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id5fd48ff8-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id5fd48ff9-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id5fd48ffa-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“United States Bureau of Mines” substituted in text for “Bureau of Mines” pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/102/285/s10/b">section 10(b) of Pub. L. 102–285</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>. For provisions relating to closure and transfer of functions of the United States Bureau of Mines, see Transfer of Functions note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
