<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id60042bc2-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s541a"><num value="541a">§ 541a.</num><heading> Claims located prior to <date date="1955-05-25">May 25, 1955</date>; extra­lateral rights; amended notice of mining location</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any mining claim located in a manner prescribed by the mining laws of the United States upon lands of the character described in <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s541">section 541 of this title</ref>, prior to <date date="1955-05-25">May 25, 1955</date>, if based upon a discovery of valuable source material contained in lignite shall be effective to the same extent as if such lands at the time of location, and at all times thereafter, had not been classified as or known to be valuable for coal subject to disposition under the mineral leasing laws, subject, however, to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s541">section 541 of this title</ref>: <i>Provided</i>, That no extralateral rights shall attach to any mining location validated under this section: <i>And provided further</i>, That the locator or locators of such a mining claim shall, not later than one hundred and eighty days from and after <date date="1955-08-11">August 11, 1955</date>, post on the claim and file for record in the office where the notice or certificate of location is of record, an amended notice of the mining location stating that such amended notice is filed pursuant to the provisions of this chapter and for the purpose of obtaining the benefits thereof; and that a copy of said amended notice is, within the said one-hundred-and-eighty-day period, filed in the land office of the Bureau of Land Management for the State in which the mining location is situated, and the mining locator thereafter complies with the requirements of this chapter.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id60042bc3-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-08-11/ch795/s2">Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 795, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/679">69 Stat. 679</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id60042bc4-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id60042bc5-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id60042bc6-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Extension of Time for Annual Assessment Work</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1956-06-29/ch478">Act June 29, 1956, ch. 478</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/438">70 Stat. 438</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/85/68">Pub. L. 85–68</ref>, <date date="1957-06-29">June 29, 1957</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/71/226">71 Stat. 226</ref>, provided for extension of time for period commencing <date date="1955-07-01">July 1, 1955</date>, to 12 o’clock noon <date date="1958-07-01">July 1, 1958</date>, during which labor must be performed, or improvements made pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s28">section 28 of this title</ref>, or any unpatented mining claim validated under this section and for extension of time for period commencing <date date="1956-07-01">July 1, 1956</date>, to 12 o’clock noon <date date="1958-07-01">July 1, 1958</date>, during which labor must be performed, or improvements made pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s28">section 28 of this title</ref>, on any other unpatented mining claim subject to this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
