<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id60090d6f-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s621"><num value="621">§ 621.</num><heading> Entry to lands reserved for power development</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id60090d70-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s621/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditions of entry</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All public lands belonging to the United States heretofore, now or hereafter withdrawn or reserved for power development or power sites shall be open to entry for location and patent of mining claims and for mining, development, beneficiation, removal, and utilization of the mineral resources of such lands under applicable Federal statutes: <i>Provided</i>, That all power rights to such lands shall be retained by the United States: <i>Provided further</i>, That locations made under this chapter within the revested Oregon and California Railroad and reconveyed Coos Bay Wagon grant lands shall also be subject to the provisions of the Act of <date date="1948-04-08">April 8, 1948</date>, Public Law 477 (Eightieth Congress, second session): <i>And provided further</i>, That nothing contained herein shall be construed to open for the purposes described in this section any lands (1) which are included in any project operating or being constructed under a license or permit issued under the Federal Power Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s791a">16 U.S.C. 791a</ref> et seq.] or other Act of Congress, or (2) which are under examination and survey by a prospective licensee of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, if such prospective licensee holds an uncanceled preliminary permit issued under the Federal Power Act authorizing him to conduct such examination and survey with respect to such lands and such permit has not been renewed in the case of such prospective licensee more than once.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id60090d71-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s621/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Placer claims; notice; hearing; order; rules and regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The locator of a placer claim under this chapter, however, shall conduct no mining operations for a period of sixty days after the filing of a notice of location pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s623">section 623 of this title</ref>. If the Secretary of the Interior, within sixty days from the filing of the notice of location, notifies the locator by registered mail or certified mail of the Secretary’s intention to hold a public hearing to determine whether placer mining operations would substantially interfere with other uses of the land included within the placer claim, mining operations on that claim shall be further suspended until the Secretary has held the hearing and has issued an appropriate order. The order issued by the Secretary of the Interior shall provide for one of the following: (1) a complete prohibition of placer mining; (2) a permission to engage in placer mining upon the condition that the locator shall, following placer operations, restore the surface of the claim to the condition in which it was immediately prior to those operations; or (3) a general permission to engage in placer mining. No order by the Secretary with respect to such operations shall be valid unless a certified copy is filed in the same State or county office in which the locator’s notice of location has been filed in compliance with the United States mining laws.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish such rules and regulations as he deems desirable concerning bonds and deposits with respect to the restoration of lands to their condition prior to placer mining operations. Moneys received from any bond or deposit shall be used for the restoration of the surface of the claim involved, and any money received in excess of the amount needed for the restoration of the surface of that claim shall be refunded.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id60090d72-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s621/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Validity of withdrawals unaffected</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall affect the validity of withdrawals or reservations for purposes other than power development.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id60090d73-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-08-11/ch797/s2">Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 797, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/682">69 Stat. 682</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/507/s1/27">Pub. L. 86–507, § 1(27)</ref>, <date date="1960-06-11">June 11, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/202">74 Stat. 202</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/91/tIV/s402/a/1/A">Pub. L. 95–91, title IV, § 402(a)(1)(A)</ref>, title VII, §§ 703, 707, <date date="1977-08-04">Aug. 4, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/584">91 Stat. 584</ref>, 606, 607.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id60090d74-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id60090d75-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id60090d76-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1948-04-08">April 8, 1948</date>, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1948-04-08/ch179">act Apr. 8, 1948, ch. 179</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/162">62 Stat. 162</ref>, which is not classified to the Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Power Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1920-06-10/ch285">act June 10, 1920, ch. 285</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/41/1063">41 Stat. 1063</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 12 (§ 791a et seq.) of Title 16, Conservation. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s791a">section 791a of Title 16</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id60090d77-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1960—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/86/507">Pub. L. 86–507</ref> inserted “or certified mail” after “registered mail”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="id60090d78-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1955-08-11/ch797/s1">Act Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 797, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/681">69 Stat. 681</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1955-08-11/ch797/s1">“That this Act [enacting this chapter] may be cited as the ‘Mining Claims Rights Restoration Act of 1955’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id60090d79-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id60090d7a-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Federal Energy Regulatory Commission” substituted for “Federal Power Commission” in subsec. (a) pursuant to sections 402(a)(1)(A), 703, and 707 of <ref href="/us/pl/95/91">Pub. L. 95–91</ref>, which are classified to sections 7172(a)(1)(A), 7293, and 7297 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, and which terminated the Federal Power Commission and transferred its functions relating to licensing and permits for dams, reservoirs, or other works for development and improvement of navigation and for development and utilization of power across, along, from, or in navigable waters under part I of Federal Power Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s791a">16 U.S.C. 791a</ref> et seq.) to the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
