<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id600dc86f-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s812"><num value="812">§ 812.</num><heading> Advisory committees</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id600dc870-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s812/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Committee on coal or other mine safety research; establishment; membership; chairman; functions; conflicts of interest</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id600dc871-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s812/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of the Interior shall appoint an advisory committee on coal or other mine safety research composed of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id600dc872-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s812/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Director of the Office of Science and Technology or his delegate, with the consent of the Director;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id600dc873-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s812/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, Department of Commerce, or his delegate, with the consent of the Director;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id600dc874-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s812/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the Director of the National Science Foundation, or his delegate, with the consent of the Director; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id600dc875-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s812/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> such other persons as the Secretary of the Interior may appoint who are knowledgeable in the field of coal or other mine safety research.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary of the Interior shall designate the chairman of the committee.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id600dc876-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s812/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The advisory committee shall consult with, and make recommendations to, the Secretary of the Interior on matters involving or relating to coal or other mine safety research. The Secretary of the Interior shall consult with, and consider the recommendations of, such committee in the conduct of such research, the making of any grants, and the entering into of contracts for such research.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id600dc877-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s812/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The chairman of the committee and a majority of the persons appointed by the Secretary of the Interior pursuant to paragraph (1)(D) shall be individuals who have no economic interests in the coal or other mining industry, and who are not operators, miners, or officers or employees of the Federal Government or any State or local government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id600dc878-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s812/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Committee on coal or other mine health research; establishment; membership; chairman; functions; conflicts of interest</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id600dc879-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s812/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall appoint an advisory committee on coal or other mine health research composed of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id600dc87a-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s812/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Director, United States Bureau of Mines, or his delegate, with the consent of the Director;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id600dc87b-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s812/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Director of the National Science Foundation, or his delegate, with the consent of the Director;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id600dc87c-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s812/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the Director of the National Institutes of Health, or his delegate, with the consent of the Director; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id600dc87d-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s812/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> such other persons as the Secretary of Health and Human Services may appoint who are knowledgeable in the field of coal or other mine health research.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall designate the chairman of the committee.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id600dc87e-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s812/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The advisory committee shall consult with, and make recommendations to, the Secretary of Health and Human Services on matters involving or relating to coal or other mine health research. The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall consult with, and consider the recommendations of, such committee in the conduct of such research, the making of any grants, and the entering into of contracts for such research.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id600dc87f-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s812/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The chairman of the committee and a majority of the persons appointed by the Secretary of Health and Human Services pursuant to paragraph (1)(D) shall be individuals who have no economic interests in the coal or other mining industry, and who are not operators, miners, or officers or employees of the Federal Government or any State or local government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id600dc880-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s812/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional advisory committees; chairman; conflicts of interest</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary or the Secretary of Health and Human Services may appoint other advisory committees as he deems appropriate to advise him in carrying out the provisions of this chapter. The Secretary or the Secretary of Health and Human Services, as the case may be, shall appoint the chairman of each such committee. A majority of the members (including the chairman) of any such advisory committee appointed pursuant to this subsection shall be composed of individuals who have no economic interests in the coal or other mining industry, and who are not operators, miners, or officers or employees of the Federal Government or any State or local government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id600dc881-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s812/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation; travel and subsistence expenses</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Advisory committee members, other than officers or employees of Federal, State, or local governments, shall be, for each day (including traveltime) during which they are performing committee business, entitled to receive compensation at a rate fixed by the appropriate Secretary but not in excess of the maximum rate of pay for grade GS–18 as provided in the General Schedule under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5332">section 5332 of title 5</ref>, and shall, notwithstanding the limitations of sections 5703 and 5704 of title 5, be fully reimbursed for travel, subsistence, and related expenses.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id600dc882-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/173/tI/s102">Pub. L. 91–173, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/747">83 Stat. 747</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/164/tII/s201">Pub. L. 95–164, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1977-11-09">Nov. 9, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1295">91 Stat. 1295</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/tV/s509/b">Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/695">93 Stat. 695</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tV/s5115/c">Pub. L. 100–418, title V, § 5115(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1433">102 Stat. 1433</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/285/s10/b">Pub. L. 102–285, § 10(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-05-18">May 18, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/172">106 Stat. 172</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id600dc883-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id600dc884-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id600dc885-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (c), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/91/173">Pub. L. 91–173</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/742">83 Stat. 742</ref>, known as the Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 1977, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s801">section 801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id600dc886-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/100/418">Pub. L. 100–418</ref> substituted “National Institute of Standards and Technology” for “National Bureau of Standards”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/164">Pub. L. 95–164</ref> expanded the area of coverage for the committee on mine safety research from “coal mines” to “coal or other mines”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/164">Pub. L. 95–164</ref> expanded the area of coverage for the advisory committee on mine health research from “coal mines” to “coal or other mines”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/164">Pub. L. 95–164</ref> struck out “, who shall be an individual who has no economic interest in the coal mining industry, and who is not an operator, miner, or an officer or employee of the Federal Government or any State or local government” after “chairman of each such committee” and inserted “(including the chairman)” after “A majority of the members”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/164">Pub. L. 95–164</ref> reenacted subsec. (d) without change.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id600dc887-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id600dc888-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“United States Bureau of Mines” substituted for “Bureau of Mines” in subsec. (b)(1)(A) pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/102/285/s10/b">section 10(b) of Pub. L. 102–285</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>. For provisions relating to closure and transfer of functions of the United States Bureau of Mines, see Transfer of Functions note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Health and Human Services” substituted for “Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare” in subsecs. (b) and (c) pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/s509/b">section 509(b) of Pub. L. 96–88</ref> which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s3508/b">section 3508(b) of Title 20</ref>, Education.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id600dc889-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1977 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/164">Pub. L. 95–164</ref> effective 120 days after <date date="1977-11-09">Nov. 9, 1977</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/164/s307">section 307 of Pub. L. 95–164</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s801">section 801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id600dc88a-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section operative 90 days after <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, except to the extent an earlier date is specifically provided for in <ref href="/us/pl/91/173">Pub. L. 91–173</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/173/s509">section 509 of Pub. L. 91–173</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s801">section 801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id600dc88b-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Advisory Committees</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Advisory committees in existence on <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period following <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, unless, in the case of a committee established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such committee is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a committee established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided by law. Advisory committees established after <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on the date of their establishment, unless, in the case of a committee established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such committee is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a committee established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided by law. See <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1013">section 1013 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id600dc88c-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Other Laws to GS–16, 17, or 18 Pay Rates</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References in laws to the rates of pay for GS–16, 17, or 18, or to maximum rates of pay under the General Schedule, to be considered references to rates payable under specified sections of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, see section 529 [title I, § 101(c)(1)] of <ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref>, set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5376">section 5376 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id600dc88d-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id600dc88e-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions vested by law in Office of Science and Technology and in Director or Deputy Director of Office of Science and Technology transferred to Director of National Science Foundation, and Office of Science and Technology, including offices of Director and Deputy Director, provided for by sections 1 and 2 of Reorg. Plan No. 2, of 1962, eff. <date date="1962-06-08">June 8, 1962</date>, 27 F.R. 5419, <ref href="/us/stat/76/1253">76 Stat. 1253</ref>, abolished by sections 2 and 3(a)(5) of Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1973, eff. <date date="1973-07-01">July 1, 1973</date>, 38 F.R. 9579, <ref href="/us/stat/87/1089">87 Stat. 1089</ref>, both set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
