<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id601e6a79-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s903"><num value="903">§ 903.</num><heading> Field offices</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id601e6a7a-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s903/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Secretary of Labor shall establish and operate such field offices as may be necessary to assist miners and survivors of miners in the filing and processing of claims under this subchapter. Such field offices shall, to the extent feasible, be reasonably accessible to such miners and survivors. The Secretary, in connection with the establishment and operation of field offices, may enter into arrangements with other Federal departments and agencies, and with State agencies, for the use of existing facilities operated by such departments and agencies. Where the establishment of separate facilities is not feasible the Secretary may enter into such arrangements as he deems necessary with the heads of Federal departments, agencies, and instrumentalities and with State agencies for the use of existing facilities and personnel under their control.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id601e6a7b-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s903/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> There are authorized to be appropriated for the purposes of subsection (a) such sums as may be necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id601e6a7c-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/239/s18">Pub. L. 95–239, § 18</ref>, <date date="1978-03-01">Mar. 1, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/105">92 Stat. 105</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id601e6a7d-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id601e6a7e-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id601e6a7f-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Black Lung Benefits Reform Act of 1977, and not as part of the Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 1977 which comprises this chapter or the Black Lung Benefits Act which comprises this subchapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id601e6a80-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id601e6a81-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1978-03-01">Mar. 1, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/239/s20/a">section 20(a) of Pub. L. 95–239</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1978 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s901">section 901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
