<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id601e6a88-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s921"><num value="921">§ 921.</num><heading> Regulations and presumptions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id601e6a89-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s921/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Promulgation; payment of benefits</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall, in accordance with the provisions of this part, and the regulations promulgated by him under this part, make payments of benefits in respect of total disability of any miner due to pneumoconiosis, and in respect of the death of any miner whose death was due to pneumoconiosis or, except with respect to a claim filed under part C of this subchapter on or after the effective date of the Black Lung Benefits Amendments of 1981, who at the time of his death was totally disabled by pneumoconiosis.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id601e6a8a-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s921/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Promulgation of standards determining total disability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall by regulation prescribe standards for determining for purposes of subsection (a) whether a miner is totally disabled due to pneumoconiosis and for determining whether the death of a miner was due to pneumoconiosis. Regulations required by this subsection shall be promulgated and published in the Federal Register at the earliest practicable date after <date date="1969-12-30">December 30, 1969</date>, and in no event later than the end of the third month following December 1969. Final regulations required for implementation of any amendments to this subchapter shall be promulgated and published in the Federal Register at the earliest practicable date after the date of enactment of such amendments, and in no event later than the end of the fourth month following the month in which such amendments are enacted. Such regulations may be modified or additional regulations promulgated from time to time thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id601e6a8b-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s921/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Presumptions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id601e6a8c-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s921/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If a miner who is suffering or suffered from pneumoconiosis was employed for ten years or more in one or more coal mines there shall be a rebuttable presumption that his pneumoconiosis arose out of such employment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id601e6a8d-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s921/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If a deceased miner was employed for ten years or more in one or more coal mines and died from a respirable disease there shall be a rebuttable presumption that his death was due to pneumoconiosis. The provisions of this paragraph shall not apply with respect to claims filed on or after the effective date of the Black Lung Benefits Amendments of 1981.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id601e6a8e-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s921/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If a miner is suffering or suffered from a chronic dust disease of the lung which (A) when diagnosed by chest roentgenogram, yields one or more large opacities (greater than one centimeter in diameter) and would be classified in category A, B, or C in the International Classification of Radiographs of the Pneumoconioses by the International Labor Organization, (B) when diagnosed by biopsy or autopsy, yields massive lesions in the lung, or (C) when diagnosis is made by other means, would be a condition which could reasonably be expected to yield results described in clause (A) or (B) if diagnosis had been made in the manner prescribed in clause (A) or (B), then there shall be an irrebuttable presumption that he is totally disabled due to pneumoconiosis or that his death was due to pneumoconiosis, or that at the time of his death he was totally disabled by pneumoconiosis.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002039">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002039"><num>1</num> So in original. The period probably should be a comma.</note> as the case may be.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id601e6a8f-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s921/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> if <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002040">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002040"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be capitalized.</note> a miner was employed for fifteen years or more in one or more underground coal mines, and if there is a chest roentgenogram submitted in connection with such miner’s, his widow’s, his child’s, his parent’s, his brother’s, his sister’s, or his dependent’s claim under this subchapter and it is interpreted as negative with respect to the requirements of paragraph (3) of this subsection, and if other evidence demonstrates the existence of a totally disabling respiratory or pulmonary impairment, then there shall be a rebuttable presumption that such miner is totally disabled due to pneumoconiosis, that his death was due to pneumoconiosis, or that at the time of his death he was totally disabled by pneumoconiosis. In the case of a living miner, a wife’s affidavit may not be used by itself to establish the presumption. The Secretary shall not apply all or a portion of the requirement of this paragraph that the miner work in an underground mine where he determines that conditions of a miner’s employment in a coal mine other than an underground mine were substantially similar to conditions in an underground mine. The Secretary may rebut such presumption only by establishing that (A) such miner does not, or did not, have pneumoconiosis, or that (B) his respiratory or pulmonary impairment did not arise out of, or in connection with, employment in a coal mine.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id601e6a90-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s921/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> In the case of a miner who dies on or before <date date="1978-03-01">March 1, 1978</date>, who was employed for 25 years or more in one or more coal mines before <date date="1971-06-30">June 30, 1971</date>, the eligible survivors of such miner shall be entitled to the payment of benefits, at the rate applicable under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s922/a/2">section 922(a)(2) of this title</ref>, unless it is established that at the time of his or her death such miner was not partially or totally disabled due to pneumoconiosis. Eligible survivors shall, upon request by the Secretary, furnish such evidence as is available with respect to the health of the miner at the time of his or her death. The provisions of this paragraph shall not apply with respect to claims filed on or after the day that is 180 days after the effective date of the Black Lung Benefits Amendments of 1981.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id601e6a91-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s921/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability of presumptions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in subsection (c) shall be deemed to affect the applicability of subsection (a) in the case of a claim where the presumptions provided for therein are inapplicable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id601e6a92-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/173/tIV/s411">Pub. L. 91–173, title IV, § 411</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/793">83 Stat. 793</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/303">Pub. L. 92–303</ref>, §§ 3(a), 4(b)(1), (3), (c), (d), <date date="1972-05-19">May 19, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/153">86 Stat. 153</ref>, 154; <ref href="/us/pl/95/239/s3/a">Pub. L. 95–239, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-03-01">Mar. 1, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/96">92 Stat. 96</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/119/tII">Pub. L. 97–119, title II</ref>, §§ 202(b), 203(a)(5), <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1643">95 Stat. 1643</ref>, 1644; <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/tI/s108/i/2">Pub. L. 103–296, title I, § 108(i)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-08-15">Aug. 15, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1488">108 Stat. 1488</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/275/s2/a">Pub. L. 107–275, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1925">116 Stat. 1925</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tI/s1556/a">Pub. L. 111–148, title I, § 1556(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/260">124 Stat. 260</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id601e6a93-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id601e6a94-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id601e6a95-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The effective date of the Black Lung Benefits Amendments of 1981, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (c)(2), (5), is <date date="1982-01-01">Jan. 1, 1982</date>, except as otherwise provided. See <ref href="/us/pl/97/119/s206/a">section 206(a) of Pub. L. 97–119</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1981 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s901">section 901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id601e6a96-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148">Pub. L. 111–148</ref> struck out at end “The provisions of this paragraph shall not apply with respect to claims filed on or after the effective date of the Black Lung Benefits Amendments of 1981.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsecs. (a), (b), (c)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/107/275">Pub. L. 107–275</ref> substituted “Secretary” for “Commissioner of Social Security” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsecs. (a), (b), (c)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/103/296">Pub. L. 103–296</ref> substituted “Commissioner of Social Security” for “Secretary” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/119/s203/a/5">Pub. L. 97–119, § 203(a)(5)</ref>, inserted “, except with respect to a claim filed under part C of this subchapter on or after the effective date of the Black Lung Benefits Amendments of 1981,” after “pneumoconiosis or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/97/119/s202/b/1">Pub. L. 97–119, § 202(b)(1)</ref>, inserted provision that this paragraph not apply with respect to claims filed on or after the effective date of the Black Lung Benefits Amendments of 1981.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/97/119/s202/b/2">Pub. L. 97–119, § 202(b)(2)</ref>, inserted provision that this paragraph not apply with respect to claims filed on or after the day that is 180 days after the effective date of the Black Lung Benefits Amendments of 1981.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/239">Pub. L. 95–239</ref> capitalized and repunctuated the existing paragraphs to change their construction from that of uncapitalized clauses to complete sentences, and added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1972—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/92/303/s4/b/1">Pub. L. 92–303, § 4(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “pneumoconiosis or who at the time of his death was totally disabled by pneumoconiosis” for “pneumoconiosis”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/92/303/s4/d">Pub. L. 92–303, § 4(d)</ref>, inserted provision for the promulgation and publication in the Federal Register of final regulations and their amendments and for time limits for publication.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1), (2). <ref href="/us/pl/92/303/s3/a">Pub. L. 92–303, § 3(a)</ref>, substituted “coal mines” for “underground coal mines”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/92/303/s4/b/3">Pub. L. 92–303, § 4(b)(3)</ref>, inserted presumption that at the time of death the miner was totally disabled by pneumoconiosis.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/92/303/s4/c">Pub. L. 92–303, § 4(c)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id601e6a97-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id601e6a98-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2010 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tI/s1556/c">Pub. L. 111–148, title I, § 1556(c)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/260">124 Stat. 260</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/148/tI/s1556/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s932">section 932 of this title</ref>] shall apply with respect to claims filed under part B or part C of the Black Lung Benefits Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t30/s921">30 U.S.C. 921</ref> et seq., 931 et seq.) after <date date="2005-01-01">January 1, 2005</date>, that are pending on or after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id601e6a99-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2002 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/107/275">Pub. L. 107–275</ref> effective 90 days after <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/275/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 107–275</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s902">section 902 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id601e6a9a-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/296">Pub. L. 103–296</ref> effective <date date="1995-03-31">Mar. 31, 1995</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s110/a">section 110(a) of Pub. L. 103–296</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id601e6a9b-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/119">Pub. L. 97–119</ref> effective <date date="1982-01-01">Jan. 1, 1982</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/119/s206/a">section 206(a) of Pub. L. 97–119</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s901">section 901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id601e6a9c-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/239">Pub. L. 95–239</ref> effective <date date="1978-03-01">Mar. 1, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/239/s20/a">section 20(a) of Pub. L. 95–239</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s901">section 901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id601e6a9d-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1972 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/92/303/s3/a">section 3(a) of Pub. L. 92–303</ref> effective <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/92/303/s3/c">section 3(c) of Pub. L. 92–303</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s901">section 901 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/92/303/s4/g">Pub. L. 92–303, § 4(g)</ref>, <date date="1972-05-19">May 19, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/154">86 Stat. 154</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/92/303/s4/g">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 901, 902, 923, and 931 of this title] shall be effective as of <date date="1969-12-30">December 30, 1969</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id601e6a9e-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Transitional Provisions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/275/s3">Pub. L. 107–275, § 3</ref>, <date date="2002-11-02">Nov. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1926">116 Stat. 1926</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/275/s3">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading><content>This section shall apply to the transfer of all functions relating to the administration of part B of subchapter IV (<ref href="/us/usc/t30/s901">30 U.S.C. 901</ref> et seq.) [probably means <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s921">30 U.S.C. 921</ref> et seq.] from the Commissioner of Social Security (hereinafter in this section referred to as the ‘Commissioner’) to the Secretary of Labor, as provided by this Act [see Short Title of 2002 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s801">section 801 of this title</ref>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transfer of Assets, Liabilities, etc.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The Commissioner shall transfer to the Secretary of Labor all property and records that the Director of the Office of Management and Budget determines relate to the functions transferred to the Secretary of Labor by this Act or amendments made by this Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1531">Section 1531 of title 31</ref>, United States Code, shall apply in carrying out this Act and amendments made by this Act, except that, for purposes of carrying out this Act and amendments made by this Act, the functions of the President under section 1531(b) shall be performed by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget unless otherwise directed by the President.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Continuation of Orders, Determinations, etc.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> This Act shall not affect the validity of any order, determination, rule, regulation, operating procedure (to the extent applicable to the Secretary of Labor), or contract that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> relates to a function transferred by this Act; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> is in effect on the date this Act takes effect [see Effective Date of 2002 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s902">section 902 of this title</ref>].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> Any order, determination, rule, regulation, operating procedure, or contract described in paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> apply on and after the effective date of this Act to the Secretary of Labor; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> continue in effect, according to its terms, until it is modified, superseded, terminated, or otherwise deprived of legal effect by the Secretary of Labor, a court of competent jurisdiction, or operation of law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Continuation of Administrative Proceedings.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Any proceeding before the Commissioner involving the functions transferred by this Act that is pending on the date this Act takes effect shall continue before the Secretary of Labor, except as provided in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> Any proceeding pending before an Administrative Law Judge or the Appeals Council pursuant to part B and the applicable regulations of the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall continue before the Commissioner consistent with the following provisions:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Any proceeding described in this paragraph shall continue as if this Act had not been enacted, and shall include all rights to hearing, administrative review, and judicial review available under part B and the applicable regulations of the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Any decision, order, or other determination issued in any proceeding described in this subsection shall apply to the Secretary of Labor and continue in effect, according to its terms, until it is modified, superseded, terminated, or otherwise deprived of legal effect by the Secretary of Labor, a court of competent jurisdiction, or operation of law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Nothing in this paragraph shall be deemed to prohibit the discontinuance or modification of any such proceeding under the same terms and conditions and to the same extent that such proceeding could have been discontinued or modified if this Act had not been enacted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Any proceeding before the Secretary of Labor involving the functions transferred by this Act shall be subject to the statutory requirements for notice, hearing, action upon the record, administrative review, and judicial review that apply to similar proceedings before the Commissioner conducted prior to the enactment of this Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Continuation of Actions and Causes of Action.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), this Act shall not abrogate, terminate, or otherwise affect any action or cause of action, that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> relates to a function transferred by this Act; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> is pending or otherwise in existence on the date this Act takes effect [see Effective Date of 2002 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s902">section 902 of this title</ref>].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> Any action pending before the Commissioner or any court on the date this Act takes effect that involves a function transferred by this Act shall continue before the Commissioner or court consistent with the following provisions:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Any proceeding described in this paragraph shall continue as if this Act had not been enacted.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Any decision, order, or other determination issued in any proceeding subject to this paragraph shall apply to the Secretary of Labor and continue in effect, according to its terms, until it is modified, superseded, terminated, or otherwise deprived of legal effect by the Secretary of Labor, a court of competent jurisdiction, or operation of law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Any cause of action by or against the Commissioner that exists on the date this Act takes effect and involves any function transferred by this Act may be asserted by or against the Secretary of Labor or the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Continuation of Actions Against Officers</inline>.—</heading><content>No suit, action, or other proceeding commenced by or against any officer in his official capacity as an officer of the Social Security Administration, and relating to a function transferred by this Act, shall abate by reason of the enactment of this Act. No cause of action by or against the Social Security Administration, or by or against any officer thereof in his official capacity, relating to a function transferred by this Act, shall abate by reason of enactment of this Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Preservation of Penalties, etc</inline>.—</heading><content>The transfer of functions under this Act shall not release or extinguish any penalty, forfeiture, liability, prosecution, investigation, or right to initiate a future investigation or prosecution involving any function transferred by this Act.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
