<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id60234bf4-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s931"><num value="931">§ 931.</num><heading> Benefits under State workmen’s compensation laws</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id60234bf5-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s931/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Filing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">On and after <date date="1974-01-01">January 1, 1974</date>, any claim for benefits for death or total disability due to pneumoconiosis shall be filed pursuant to the applicable State workmen’s compensation law, except that during any period when miners or their surviving widows, children, parents, brothers, or sisters, as the case may be, are not covered by a State workmen’s compensation law which provides adequate coverage for pneumoconiosis, and in any case in which benefits based upon eligibility under paragraph (5) of <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s921/c">section 921(c) of this title</ref> are involved.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002041">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002041"><num>1</num> So in original. The period probably should be a comma.</note> they shall be entitled to claim benefits under this part.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id60234bf6-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s931/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Adequacy of compensation; listing of States providing adequate compensation; requisites for listing</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id60234bf7-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s931/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> For purposes of this section, a State workmen’s compensation law shall not be deemed to provide adequate coverage for pneumoconiosis during any period unless it is included in the list of State laws found by the Secretary to provide such adequate coverage during such period. The Secretary shall, no later than <date date="1972-10-01">October 1, 1972</date>, publish in the Federal Register a list of State workmen’s compensation laws which provide adequate coverage for pneumoconiosis and shall revise and republish in the Federal Register such list from time to time, as may be appropriate to reflect changes in such State laws due to legislation or judicial or administrative interpretation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id60234bf8-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s931/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall include a State workmen’s compensation law on such list during any period only if he finds that during such period under such law—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60234bf9-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s931/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> benefits must be paid for total disability or death of a miner due to pneumoconiosis, except that (i) such law shall not be required to provide such benefits where the miner’s last employment in a coal mine terminated before the Secretary’s approval of the State law pursuant to this section; and (ii) each operator of a coal mine shall secure the payment of benefits pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s933">section 933 of this title</ref> with respect to any miner whose last employment in a coal mine terminated before the Secretary’s approval of the State law pursuant to this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60234bfa-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s931/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the amount of such cash benefits is substantially equivalent to or greater than the amount of benefits prescribed by <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s922/a">section 922(a) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60234bfb-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s931/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the standards for determining death or total disability due to pneumoconiosis are substantially equivalent to <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s902/f">section 902(f) of this title</ref> and to those standards established under this part, and by the regulations of the Secretary promulgated under this part;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60234bfc-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s931/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> any claim for benefits on account of total disability of a miner due to pneumoconiosis is deemed to be timely filed if such claim is filed within three years after a medical determination of total disability due to pneumoconiosis;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60234bfd-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s931/b/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> there are in effect provisions with respect to prior and successor operators which are substantially equivalent to the provisions contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s932/i">section 932(i) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60234bfe-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s931/b/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> there are applicable such other provisions, regulations or interpretations, which are consistent with the provisions contained in Public Law 803, 69th Congress (<ref href="/us/stat/44/1424">44 Stat. 1424</ref>, approved <date date="1927-03-04">March 4, 1927</date>), as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s901">33 U.S.C. 901</ref> et seq.], which are applicable under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s932/a">section 932(a) of this title</ref>, but are not inconsistent with any of the criteria set forth in subparagraphs (A) through (E) of this paragraph, as the Secretary, in accordance with regulations promulgated by him, determines to be necessary or appropriate to assure adequate compensation for total disability or death due to pneumoconiosis.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The action of the Secretary in including or failing to include any State workmen’s compensation law on such list shall be subject to judicial review exclusively in the United States court of appeals for the circuit in which the State is located or the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id60234bff-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s931/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Publication in Federal Register; review of listings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Final regulations required for implementation of any amendments to this part shall be promulgated and published in the Federal Register at the earliest practicable date after the date of enactment of such amendments, and in no event later than the end of the sixth month following the month in which such amendments are enacted.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id60234c00-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/173/tIV/s421">Pub. L. 91–173, title IV, § 421</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/795">83 Stat. 795</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/303">Pub. L. 92–303</ref>, §§ 1(c)(1), 4(e), 5(3), (5), <date date="1972-05-19">May 19, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/151">86 Stat. 151</ref>, 154, 155; <ref href="/us/pl/95/239">Pub. L. 95–239</ref>, §§ 3(b)(3), 6, <date date="1978-03-01">Mar. 1, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/97">92 Stat. 97</ref>, 98.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id60234c01-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id60234c02-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id60234c03-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Public Law 803, 69th Congress, referred to in subsec. (b)(2)(F), is <ref href="/us/act/1927-03-04/ch509">act Mar. 4, 1927, ch. 509</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/1424">44 Stat. 1424</ref>, popularly known as the Longshore and Harbor Workers’ Compensation Act, which is classified generally to chapter 18 (§ 901 et seq.) of Title 33, Navigation and Navigable Waters. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s901">section 901 of Title 33</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id60234c04-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/239/s3/b/3">Pub. L. 95–239, § 3(b)(3)</ref>, inserted reference to cases in which benefits based upon eligibility under par. (5) of <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s921/c">section 921(c) of this title</ref> are involved.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/95/239/s6/a">Pub. L. 95–239, § 6(a)</ref>, added the exceptions set out in cls. (i) and (ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/95/239/s6/b">Pub. L. 95–239, § 6(b)</ref>, substituted “established under this part, and by the regulations of the Secretary promulgated under this part” for “established under part B of this subchapter, and by the regulations of the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare promulgated thereunder”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/95/239/s6/c">Pub. L. 95–239, § 6(c)</ref>, substituted “total disability of a miner due to pneumoconiosis is deemed to be timely filed if such claim is filed within three years after a medical determination of total disability due to pneumoconiosis” for “total disability or death of a miner due to pneumoconiosis is deemed to be timely filed if such claim is filed within three years of the discovery of total disability due to pneumoconiosis, or the date of such death, as the case may be”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1972—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/92/303">Pub. L. 92–303</ref>, §§ 1(c)(1), 5(3), substituted “widows, children, parents, brothers, or sisters, as the case may be,” for “widows” and “1974” for “1973”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/92/303/s4/e">Pub. L. 92–303, § 4(e)</ref>, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t30/s902/f">section 902(f) of this title</ref> and to those standards established under part B of this subchapter” for “those established by <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s921">section 921 of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/92/303/s5/5">Pub. L. 92–303, § 5(5)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id60234c05-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id60234c06-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/239">Pub. L. 95–239</ref> effective <date date="1978-03-01">Mar. 1, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/239/s20/a">section 20(a) of Pub. L. 95–239</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s901">section 901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id60234c07-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1972 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/92/303/s4/e">section 4(e) of Pub. L. 92–303</ref> effective <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/92/303/s4/g">section 4(g) of Pub. L. 92–303</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s921">section 921 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
