<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id6025969b-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943"><num value="943">§ 943.</num><heading> Black lung insurance program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6025969c-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization to establish and carry out</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to establish and carry out a black lung insurance program which will enable operators of coal mines to purchase insurance covering their obligations under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s932">section 932 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6025969d-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Non-availability of other insurance coverage</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may exercise his or her authority under this section only if, and to the extent that, insurance coverage is not otherwise available, at reasonable cost, to operators of coal mines.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id6025969e-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Agreements with coal mine operators; reinsurance agreements</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id6025969f-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary may enter into agreements with operators of coal mines who may be liable for the payment of benefits under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s932">section 932 of this title</ref>, under which the Black Lung Compensation Insurance Fund established under subsection (a) (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “insurance fund”) shall assume all or part of the liability of such operator in return for the payment of premiums to the insurance fund, and on such terms and conditions as will fully protect the financial solvency of the insurance fund. During any period in which such agreement is in effect the operator shall be deemed in compliance with the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s933">section 933 of this title</ref> with respect to the risks covered by such agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id602596a0-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary may also enter into reinsurance agreements with one or more insurers or pools of insurers under which, in return for the payment of premiums to the insurance fund, and on such terms and conditions as will fully protect the financial solvency of the insurance fund, the insurance fund shall provide reinsurance coverage for benefits required to be paid under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s932">section 932 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id602596a1-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Terms and conditions of insurability</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may by regulation provide for general terms and conditions of insurability as applicable to operators of coal mines or insurers eligible for insurance or reinsurance under this section, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id602596a2-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the types, classes, and locations of operators or facilities which shall be eligible for such insurance or reinsurance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id602596a3-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the classification, limitation, and rejection of any operator or facility which may be advisable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id602596a4-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> appropriate premiums for different classifications of operators or facilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id602596a5-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> appropriate loss deductibles;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id602596a6-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> experience rating; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id602596a7-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> any other terms and conditions relating to insurance or reinsurance coverage or exclusion which may be appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id602596a8-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Premium schedule studies and investigations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may undertake and carry out such studies and investigations, and receive or exchange such information, as may be necessary to formulate a premium schedule which will enable the insurance and reinsurance authorized by this section to be provided on a basis which is (1) in accordance with accepted actuarial principles; and (2) fair and equitable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id602596a9-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations relating to premium rates</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id602596aa-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> On the basis of estimates made by the Secretary in formulating a premium schedule under subsection (e), and such other information as may be available, the Secretary shall from time to time prescribe by regulation the chargeable premium rates for types and classes of insurers, operators of coal mines, and facilities for which insurance or reinsurance coverage shall be available under this section and the terms and conditions under which, and the area within which, such insurance or reinsurance shall be available and such rates shall apply.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id602596ab-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Such premium rates shall be (A) based on a consideration of the risks involved, taking into account differences, if any, in risks based on location, type of operations, facilities, type of coal, experience, and any other matter which may be considered under accepted actuarial principles; and (B) adequate, on the basis of accepted actuarial principles, to provide reserves for anticipated losses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id602596ac-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> All premiums received by the Secretary shall be paid into the insurance fund.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id602596ad-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Black Lung Compensation Insurance Fund</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id602596ae-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary may establish in the Department of Labor a Black Lung Compensation Insurance Fund which shall be available, without fiscal year limitation—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id602596af-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to pay claims of miners for benefits covered by insurance or reinsurance issued under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id602596b0-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to pay the administrative expenses of carrying out the black lung compensation insurance program under this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id602596b1-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/g/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> to repay to the Secretary of the Treasury such sums as may be borrowed in accordance with the authority provided in subsection (i).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id602596b2-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The insurance fund shall be credited with—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id602596b3-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/g/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> premiums, fees, or other charges which may be collected in connection with insurance or reinsurance coverage provided under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id602596b4-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/g/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such amounts as may be advanced to the insurance fund from appropriations in order to maintain the insurance fund in an operative condition adequate to meet its liabilities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id602596b5-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/g/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> income which may be earned on investments of the insurance fund pursuant to paragraph (3).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id602596b6-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If, after all outstanding current obligations of the insurance fund have been liquidated and any outstanding amounts which may have been advanced to the insurance fund from appropriations authorized under subsection (i) have been credited to the appropriation from which advanced, the Secretary determines that the moneys of the insurance fund are in excess of current needs, he or she may request the investment of such amounts as he or she deems advisable by the Secretary of the Treasury in public debt securities with maturities suitable for the needs of the insurance fund and bearing interest at prevailing market rates.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id602596b7-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id602596b8-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s943/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the insurance fund, as repayable advances, such sums as may be necessary to meet obligations incurred under subsection (g). All such sums shall remain available without fiscal year limitation. Advances made pursuant to this subsection shall be repaid, with interest, to the general fund of the Treasury when the Secretary determines that moneys are available in the insurance fund for such repayments. Interest on such advances shall be computed in the same manner as provided in subsection (b)(2) of section 934a <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002048">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002048"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id602596b9-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/173/tIV/s433">Pub. L. 91–173, title IV, § 433</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/95/239/s13">Pub. L. 95–239, § 13</ref>, <date date="1978-03-01">Mar. 1, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/101">92 Stat. 101</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id602596ba-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id602596bb-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id602596bc-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t30/s934a">Section 934a of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (i), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/97/119/tI/s103/b">Pub. L. 97–119, title I, § 103(b)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1638">95 Stat. 1638</ref>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s9501/c">section 9501(c) of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id602596bd-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h) of this section, which required the Secretary to report to Congress not later than April 1 of each year on the financial condition and operation of the insurance fund, terminated, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance. See, also, page 124 of House Document No. 103–7.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id602596be-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id602596bf-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1978-03-01">Mar. 1, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/239/s20/a">section 20(a) of Pub. L. 95–239</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1978 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s901">section 901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
