<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id60280704-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s953"><num value="953">§ 953.</num><heading> Assistance to States</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id60280705-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s953/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Development and enforcement of health and safety regulations; improvement of workmen’s compensation and occupational disease laws; promotion of Federal-State coordination in mine safety</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of the Interior, is authorized to make grants in accordance with an application approved under this section to any State in which coal or other mining takes place—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60280706-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s953/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to assist such State in developing and enforcing effective coal or other mine health and safety laws and regulations consistent with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s955">section 955 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60280707-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s953/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to improve State workmen’s compensation and occupational disease laws and programs related to coal or other mine employment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60280708-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s953/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to promote Federal-State coordination and cooperation in improving the health and safety conditions in the coal or other mines.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id60280709-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s953/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Application for grants; contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall approve any application or any modification thereof, submitted under this section by a State, through its official coal or other mine inspection or safety agency, which—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6028070a-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s953/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> sets forth the programs, policies, and methods to be followed in carrying out the application in accordance with the purposes of subsection (a) of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6028070b-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s953/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> provides research and planning studies to carry out plans designed to improve State workmen’s compensation and occupational disease laws and programs, as they relate to compensation to miners for occupationally caused diseases and injuries arising out of employment in any coal or other mine;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6028070c-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s953/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> designates such State coal or other mine inspection or safety agency as the sole agency responsible for administering grants under this section throughout the State, and contains satisfactory evidence that such agency will have the authority to carry out the purposes of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6028070d-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s953/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> gives assurances that such agency has or will employ an adequate and competent staff of trained inspectors qualified under the laws of such State to make coal or other mine inspections within such State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6028070e-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s953/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> provides for the extension and improvement of the State program for the improvement of coal or other mine health and safety in the State, and provides that no advance notice of an inspection will be provided anyone;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id6028070f-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s953/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> provides such fiscal control and fund accounting procedures as may be appropriate to assure proper disbursement and accounting of grants made to the States under this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60280710-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s953/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> provides that the designated agency will make such reports to the Secretary in such form and containing such information as the Secretary may from time to time require;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60280711-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s953/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> contains assurances that grants provided under this section will supplement, not supplant, existing State coal or other mine health and safety programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id60280712-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s953/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> meets additional conditions which the Secretary may prescribe in furtherance of, and consistent with, the purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id60280713-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s953/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Approval by Secretary; notice and hearing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall not finally disapprove any State application or modification thereof without first affording the State agency reasonable notice and opportunity for a public hearing.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id60280714-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s953/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Review by Court of Appeals; conclusiveness of findings of Secretary; filing of petition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any State aggrieved by a decision of the Secretary under subsection (b) or (c) of this section may file within thirty days from the date of such decision with the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia a petition praying that such action be modified or set aside in whole or in part. The court shall hear such appeal on the record made before the Secretary. The decision of the Secretary incorporating his findings of fact therein, if supported by substantial evidence on the record considered as a whole, shall be conclusive. The court may affirm, vacate, or remand the proceedings to the Secretary for such further action as it directs. The filing of a petition under this subsection shall not stay the application of the decision of the Secretary, unless the court so orders. The provisions of section 816(a), (b), and (c) of this title shall not be applicable to this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id60280715-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s953/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Programs to train State inspectors</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any State application or modification thereof submitted to the Secretary under this section may include a program to train State inspectors.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id60280716-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s953/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Cooperation in implementation of programs; exchange of reports between States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall cooperate with such State in carrying out the application or modification thereof and shall, as appropriate, develop and, where appropriate, construct facilities for, and finance a program of, training of Federal and State inspectors jointly. The Secretary shall also cooperate with such State in establishing a system by which State and Federal inspection reports of coal or other mines located in the State are exchanged for the purpose of improving health and safety conditions in such mines.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id60280717-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s953/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on grants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The amount granted to any coal or other mining State for a fiscal year under this section shall not exceed 80 per centum of the amount expended by such State in such year for carrying out such application.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id60280718-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58" identifier="/us/usc/t30/s953/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated $3,000,000 for fiscal year 1970, and $10,000,000 annually in each succeeding fiscal year to carry out the provisions of this section, which shall remain available until expended. The Secretary shall provide for an equitable distribution of sums appropriated for grants under this section to the States where there is an approved application, except that no less than one-half of such sum shall be allocated to coal-producing States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id60280719-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/173/tV/s503">Pub. L. 91–173, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/800">83 Stat. 800</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/164/tIII/s303/c">Pub. L. 95–164, title III, § 303(c)</ref>, <date date="1977-11-09">Nov. 9, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1320">91 Stat. 1320</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/tV/s509/b">Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/695">93 Stat. 695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id6028071a-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id6028071b-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id6028071c-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/164/s303/c/1">Pub. L. 95–164, § 303(c)(1)</ref>, inserted reference to mines and mining other than coal mines and coal mining and substituted “Secretary of the Interior” for “Secretary of Labor”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b), (f), (g). <ref href="/us/pl/95/164/s303/c/1">Pub. L. 95–164, § 303(c)(1)</ref>, inserted references to mines and mining other than coal mines and coal mining.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/95/164/s303/c/2">Pub. L. 95–164, § 303(c)(2)</ref>, substituted “$10,000,000” for “$5,000,000” and inserted requirement that no less than one-half of sums appropriated for grants be allocated to coal-producing States.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id6028071d-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id6028071e-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Health and Human Services” substituted for “Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare” in subsec. (a) pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/s509/b">section 509(b) of Pub. L. 96–88</ref> which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s3508/b">section 3508(b) of Title 20</ref>, Education.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id6028071f-3a70-11f1-83b4-f01f82055b58"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1977 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/164">Pub. L. 95–164</ref> effective 120 days after <date date="1977-11-09">Nov. 9, 1977</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/164/s307">section 307 of Pub. L. 95–164</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s801">section 801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
