<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0ce4df41-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11"><num value="1070a–11">§ 1070a–11.</num><heading> Program authority; authorization of appropriations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df42-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Grants and contracts authorized</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall, in accordance with the provisions of this division, carry out a program of making grants and contracts designed to identify qualified individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds, to prepare them for a program of postsecondary education, to provide support services for such students who are pursuing programs of postsecondary education, to motivate and prepare students for doctoral programs, and to train individuals serving or preparing for service in programs and projects so designed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df43-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Recipients, duration, and size</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df44-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Recipients</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For the purposes described in subsection (a), the Secretary is authorized, without regard to <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>, to make grants to, and contracts with, institutions of higher education, public and private agencies and organizations, including community-based organizations with experience in serving disadvantaged youth, combinations of such institutions, agencies and organizations, and, as appropriate to the purposes of the program, secondary schools, for planning, developing, or carrying out one or more of the services assisted under this division.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df45-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Duration</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Grants or contracts made under this division shall be awarded for a period of 5 years, except that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0ce4df46-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in order to synchronize the awarding of grants for programs under this division, the Secretary may, under such terms as are consistent with the purposes of this division, provide a one-time, limited extension of the length of such an award;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0ce4df47-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> grants made under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–17">section 1070a–17 of this title</ref> shall be awarded for a period of 2 years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0ce4df48-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> grants under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–18">section 1070a–18 of this title</ref> shall be awarded for a period determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df49-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Minimum grants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Unless the institution or agency requests a smaller amount, an individual grant authorized under this division shall be awarded in an amount that is not less than $200,000, except that an individual grant authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–17">section 1070a–17 of this title</ref> shall be awarded in an amount that is not less than $170,000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df4a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedures for awarding grants and contracts</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df4b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Application requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">An eligible entity that desires to receive a grant or contract under this division shall submit an application to the Secretary in such manner and form, and containing such information and assurances, as the Secretary may reasonably require.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df4c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df4d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Prior experience</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In making grants under this division, the Secretary shall consider each applicant’s prior experience of high quality service delivery, as determined under subsection (f), under the particular program for which funds are sought. The level of consideration given the factor of prior experience shall not vary from the level of consideration given such factor during fiscal years 1994 through 1997, except that grants made under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–18">section 1070a–18 of this title</ref> shall not be given prior experience consideration.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df4e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Participant need</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In making grants under this division, the Secretary shall consider the number, percentages, and needs of eligible participants in the area, institution of higher education, or secondary school to be served to aid such participants in preparing for, enrolling in, or succeeding in postsecondary education, as appropriate to the particular program for which the eligible entity is applying.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df4f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Order of awards; program fraud</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0ce4df50-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Except with respect to grants made under sections 1070a–17 and 1070a–18 of this title and as provided in subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall award grants and contracts under this division in the order of the scores received by the application for such grant or contract in the peer review process required under paragraph (4) and adjusted for prior experience in accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0ce4df51-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary shall not provide assistance to a program otherwise eligible for assistance under this division, if the Secretary has determined that such program has involved the fraudulent use of funds under this division.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df52-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Peer review process</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0ce4df53-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary shall ensure that, to the extent practicable, members of groups underrepresented in higher education, including African Americans, Hispanics, Native Americans, Alaska Natives, Asian Americans, and Native American Pacific Islanders (including Native Hawaiians), are represented as readers of applications submitted under this division. The Secretary shall also ensure that persons from urban and rural backgrounds are represented as readers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0ce4df54-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary shall ensure that each application submitted under this division is read by at least three readers who are not employees of the Federal Government (other than as readers of applications).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df55-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Number of applications for grants and contracts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall not limit the number of applications submitted by an entity under any program authorized under this division if the additional applications describe programs serving different populations or different campuses.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df56-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination with other programs for disadvantaged students</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall encourage coordination of programs assisted under this division with other programs for disadvantaged students operated by the sponsoring institution or agency, regardless of the funding source of such programs. The Secretary shall not limit an entity’s eligibility to receive funds under this division because such entity sponsors a program similar to the program to be assisted under this division, regardless of the funding source of such program. The Secretary shall permit the Director of a program receiving funds under this division to administer one or more additional programs for disadvantaged students operated by the sponsoring institution or agency, regardless of the funding sources of such programs. The Secretary shall, as appropriate, require each applicant for funds under the programs authorized by this division to identify and make available services under such program, including mentoring, tutoring, and other services provided by such program, to foster care youth (including youth in foster care and youth who have left foster care after reaching age 13) or to homeless children and youths as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s11434a">section 11434a of title 42</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df57-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Application status</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall inform each entity operating programs under this division regarding the status of their application for continued funding at least 8 months prior to the expiration of the grant or contract. The Secretary, in the case of an entity that is continuing to operate a successful program under this division, shall ensure that the start-up date for a new grant or contract for such program immediately follows the termination of the preceding grant or contract so that no interruption of funding occurs for such successful reapplicants. The Secretary shall inform each entity requesting assistance under this division for a new program regarding the status of their application at least 8 months prior to the proposed startup date of such program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df58-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Review and notification by the Secretary</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df59-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Guidance</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2008-08-14">August 14, 2008</date>, the Secretary shall issue nonregulatory guidance regarding the rights and responsibilities of applicants with respect to the application and evaluation process for programs and projects assisted under this division, including applicant access to peer review comments. The guidance shall describe the procedures for the submission, processing, and scoring of applications for grants under this division, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4df5a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the responsibility of applicants to submit materials in a timely manner and in accordance with the processes established by the Secretary under the authority of the General Education Provisions Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1221">20 U.S.C. 1221</ref> et seq.];</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4df5b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> steps the Secretary will take to ensure that the materials submitted by applicants are processed in a proper and timely manner;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4df5c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> steps the Secretary will take to ensure that prior experience points for high quality service delivery are awarded in an accurate and transparent manner;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4df5d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> steps the Secretary will take to ensure the quality and integrity of the peer review process, including assurances that peer reviewers will consider applications for grants under this division in a thorough and complete manner consistent with applicable Federal law; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4df5e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> steps the Secretary will take to ensure that the final score of an application, including prior experience points for high quality service delivery and points awarded through the peer review process, is determined in an accurate and transparent manner.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df5f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Updated guidance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 45 days before the date of the commencement of each competition for a grant under this division that is held after the expiration of the 180-day period described in subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall update and publish the guidance described in such subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df60-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Review</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df61-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">With respect to any competition for a grant under this division, an applicant may request a review by the Secretary if the applicant—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0ce4df62-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> has evidence of a specific technical, administrative, or scoring error made by the Department, an agent of the Department, or a peer reviewer, with respect to the scoring or processing of a submitted application; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0ce4df63-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> has otherwise met all of the requirements for submission of the application.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df64-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Technical or administrative error</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In the case of evidence of a technical or administrative error listed in clause (i)(I), the Secretary shall review such evidence and provide a timely response to the applicant. If the Secretary determines that a technical or administrative error was made by the Department or an agent of the Department, the application of the applicant shall be reconsidered in the peer review process for the applicable grant competition.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df65-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/C/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Scoring error</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In the case of evidence of a scoring error listed in clause (i)(I), when the error relates to either prior experience points for high quality service delivery or to the final score of an application, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0ce4df66-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/C/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> review such evidence and provide a timely response to the applicant; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0ce4df67-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/C/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> if the Secretary determines that a scoring error was made by the Department or a peer reviewer, adjust the prior experience points or final score of the application appropriately and quickly, so as not to interfere with the timely awarding of grants for the applicable grant competition.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df68-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/C/iv"><num value="iv" class="bold">(iv)</num><heading class="bold"> Error in peer review process</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df69-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/C/iv/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> Referral to secondary review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">In the case of a peer review process error listed in clause (i)(I), if the Secretary determines that points were withheld for criteria not required in Federal statute, regulation, or guidance governing a program assisted under this division or the application for a grant for such program, or determines that information pertaining to selection criteria was wrongly determined to be missing from an application by a peer reviewer, then the Secretary shall refer the application to a secondary review panel.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df6a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/C/iv/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Timely review; replacement score</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The secondary review panel described in subclause (I) shall conduct a secondary review in a timely fashion, and the score resulting from the secondary review shall replace the score from the initial peer review.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df6b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/C/iv/III"><num value="III" class="bold">(III)</num><heading class="bold"> Composition of secondary review panel</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The secondary review panel shall be composed of reviewers each of whom—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id0ce4df6c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/C/iv/III/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> did not review the application in the original peer review;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id0ce4df6d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/C/iv/III/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> is a member of the cohort of peer reviewers for the grant program that is the subject of such secondary review; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id0ce4df6e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/C/iv/III/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content> to extent practicable, has conducted peer reviews in not less than two previous competitions for the grant program that is the subject of such secondary review.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df6f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/C/iv/IV"><num value="IV" class="bold">(IV)</num><heading class="bold"> Final score</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The final peer review score of an application subject to a secondary review under this clause shall be adjusted appropriately and quickly using the score awarded by the secondary review panel, so as not to interfere with the timely awarding of grants for the applicable grant competition.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df70-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/C/iv/V"><num value="V" class="bold">(V)</num><heading class="bold"> Qualification for secondary review</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">To qualify for a secondary review under this clause, an applicant shall have evidence of a scoring error and demonstrate that—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id0ce4df71-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/C/iv/V/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> points were withheld for criteria not required in statute, regulation, or guidance governing the Federal TRIO programs or the application for a grant for such programs; or</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id0ce4df72-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/C/iv/V/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> information pertaining to selection criteria was wrongly determined to be missing from the application.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df73-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/C/v"><num value="v" class="bold">(v)</num><heading class="bold"> Finality</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df74-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/C/v/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">A determination by the Secretary under clause (i), (ii), or (iii) shall not be reviewable by any officer or employee of the Department.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df75-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/C/v/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Scoring</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The score awarded by a secondary review panel under clause (iv) shall not be reviewable by any officer or employee of the Department other than the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df76-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/c/8/C/vi"><num value="vi" class="bold">(vi)</num><heading class="bold"> Funding of applications with certain adjusted scores</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">To the extent feasible based on the availability of appropriations, the Secretary shall fund applications with scores that are adjusted upward under clauses (ii), (iii), and (iv) to equal or exceed the minimum cut off score for the applicable grant competition.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df77-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Outreach</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df78-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall conduct outreach activities to ensure that entities eligible for assistance under this division submit applications proposing programs that serve geographic areas and eligible populations which have been underserved by the programs assisted under this division.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df79-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In carrying out the provisions of paragraph (1), the Secretary shall notify the entities described in subsection (b) of the availability of assistance under this subsection not less than 120 days prior to the deadline for submission of applications under this division and shall consult national, State, and regional organizations about candidates for notification.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df7a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Technical assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall provide technical training to applicants for projects and programs authorized under this division. The Secretary shall give priority to serving programs and projects that serve geographic areas and eligible populations which have been underserved by the programs assisted under this division. Technical training activities shall include the provision of information on authorizing legislation, goals and objectives of the program, required activities, eligibility requirements, the application process and application deadlines, and assistance in the development of program proposals and the completion of program applications. Such training shall be furnished at conferences, seminars, and workshops to be conducted at not less than 10 sites throughout the United States to ensure that all areas of the United States with large concentrations of eligible participants are served.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df7b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rule</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may contract with eligible entities to conduct the outreach activities described in this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df7c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Documentation of status as a low-income individual</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0ce4df7d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Except in the case of an independent student, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1087vv/d">section 1087vv(d) of this title</ref>, documentation of an individual’s status pursuant to subsection (h)(4) shall be made by providing the Secretary with—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0ce4df7e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a signed statement from the individual’s parent or legal guardian;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0ce4df7f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> verification from another governmental source;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0ce4df80-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a signed financial aid application; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0ce4df81-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/e/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> a signed United States or Puerto Rico income tax return.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0ce4df82-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> In the case of an independent student, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1087vv/d">section 1087vv(d) of this title</ref>, documentation of an individual’s status pursuant to subsection (h)(4) shall be made by providing the Secretary with—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0ce4df83-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a signed statement from the individual;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0ce4df84-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> verification from another governmental source;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0ce4df85-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a signed financial aid application; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0ce4df86-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/e/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> a signed United States or Puerto Rico income tax return.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0ce4df87-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Notwithstanding this subsection and subsection (h)(4), individuals who are foster care youth (including youth in foster care and youth who have left foster care after reaching age 13), or homeless children and youths as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s11434a">section 11434a of title 42</ref>, shall be eligible to participate in programs under sections 1070a–12, 1070a–13, 1070a–14, and 1070a–16 of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df88-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Outcome criteria</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df89-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Use for prior experience determination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For competitions for grants under this division that begin on or after <date date="2009-01-01">January 1, 2009</date>, the Secretary shall determine an eligible entity’s prior experience of high quality service delivery, as required under subsection (c)(2), based on the outcome criteria described in paragraphs (2) and (3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df8a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Disaggregation of relevant data</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The outcome criteria under this subsection shall be disaggregated by low-income students, first generation college students, and individuals with disabilities, in the schools and institutions of higher education served by the program to be evaluated.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4df8b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents of outcome criteria</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The outcome criteria under this subsection shall measure, annually and for longer periods, the quality and effectiveness of programs authorized under this division and shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0ce4df8c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> For programs authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–12">section 1070a–12 of this title</ref>, the extent to which the eligible entity met or exceeded the entity’s objectives established in the entity’s application for such program regarding—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4df8d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the delivery of service to a total number of students served by the program;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4df8e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the continued secondary school enrollment of such students;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4df8f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the graduation of such students from secondary school with a regular secondary school diploma in the standard number of years;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4df90-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the completion by such students of a rigorous secondary school program of study that will make such students eligible for programs such as the Academic Competitiveness Grants Program;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4df91-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> the enrollment of such students in an institution of higher education; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4df92-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/A/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> to the extent practicable, the postsecondary education completion of such students.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0ce4df93-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> For programs authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–13">section 1070a–13 of this title</ref>, the extent to which the eligible entity met or exceeded the entity’s objectives for such program regarding—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4df94-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the delivery of service to a total number of students served by the program, as agreed upon by the entity and the Secretary for the period;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4df95-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> such students’ school performance, as measured by the grade point average, or its equivalent;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4df96-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> such students’ academic performance, as measured by standardized tests, including tests required by the students’ State;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4df97-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the retention in, and graduation from, secondary school of such students;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4df98-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> the completion by such students of a rigorous secondary school program of study that will make such students eligible for programs such as the Academic Competitiveness Grants Program;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4df99-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/B/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> the enrollment of such students in an institution of higher education; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4df9a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/B/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> to the extent practicable, the postsecondary education completion of such students.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0ce4df9b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> For programs authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–14">section 1070a–14 of this title</ref>—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4df9c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the extent to which the eligible entity met or exceeded the entity’s objectives regarding the retention in postsecondary education of the students served by the program;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4df9d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4df9e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/C/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> in the case of an entity that is an institution of higher education offering a baccalaureate degree, the extent to which the entity met or exceeded the entity’s objectives regarding the percentage of such students’ completion of the degree programs in which such students were enrolled; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4df9f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/C/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><chapeau> in the case of an entity that is an institution of higher education that does not offer a baccalaureate degree, the extent to which such students met or exceeded the entity’s objectives regarding—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0ce4dfa0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/C/ii/II/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> the completion of a degree or certificate by such students; and</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0ce4dfa1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/C/ii/II/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> the transfer of such students to institutions of higher education that offer baccalaureate degrees;</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4dfa2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the extent to which the entity met or exceeded the entity’s objectives regarding the delivery of service to a total number of students, as agreed upon by the entity and the Secretary for the period; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4dfa3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the extent to which the entity met or exceeded the entity’s objectives regarding the students served under the program who remain in good academic standing.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0ce4dfa4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> For programs authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–15">section 1070a–15 of this title</ref>, the extent to which the entity met or exceeded the entity’s objectives for such program regarding—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4dfa5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the delivery of service to a total number of students served by the program, as agreed upon by the entity and the Secretary for the period;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4dfa6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the provision of appropriate scholarly and research activities for the students served by the program;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4dfa7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the acceptance and enrollment of such students in graduate programs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4dfa8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/D/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the continued enrollment of such students in graduate study and the attainment of doctoral degrees by former program participants.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0ce4dfa9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><chapeau> For programs authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–16">section 1070a–16 of this title</ref>, the extent to which the entity met or exceeded the entity’s objectives for such program regarding—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4dfaa-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the enrollment of students without a secondary school diploma or its recognized equivalent, who were served by the program, in programs leading to such diploma or equivalent;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4dfab-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the enrollment of secondary school graduates who were served by the program in programs of postsecondary education;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4dfac-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/E/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the delivery of service to a total number of students served by the program, as agreed upon by the entity and the Secretary for the period; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0ce4dfad-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/3/E/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the provision of assistance to students served by the program in completing financial aid applications and college admission applications.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4dfae-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/f/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Measurement of progress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In order to determine the extent to which each outcome criterion described in paragraph (2) or (3) is met or exceeded, the Secretary shall compare the agreed upon target for the criterion, as established in the eligible entity’s application approved by the Secretary, with the results for the criterion, measured as of the last day of the applicable time period for the determination for the outcome criterion.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4dfaf-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of making grants and contracts under this division, there are authorized to be appropriated $900,000,000 for fiscal year 2009 and such sums as may be necessary for each of the five succeeding fiscal years. Of the amount appropriated under this division, the Secretary may use no more than ½ of 1 percent of such amount to obtain additional qualified readers and additional staff to review applications, to increase the level of oversight monitoring, to support impact studies, program assessments and reviews, and to provide technical assistance to potential applicants and current grantees. In expending these funds, the Secretary shall give priority to the additional administrative requirements provided in the Higher Education Amendments of 1992, to outreach activities, and to obtaining additional readers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4dfb0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of this division:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4dfb1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Different campus</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “different campus” means a site of an institution of higher education that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0ce4dfb2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is geographically apart from the main campus of the institution;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0ce4dfb3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is permanent in nature; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0ce4dfb4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/h/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> offers courses in educational programs leading to a degree, certificate, or other recognized educational credential.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce4dfb5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Different population</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “different population” means a group of individuals that an eligible entity desires to serve through an application for a grant under this division, and that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0ce4dfb6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is separate and distinct from any other population that the entity has applied for a grant under this division to serve; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0ce74fb7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> while sharing some of the same needs as another population that the eligible entity has applied for a grant under this division to serve, has distinct needs for specialized services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce74fb8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/h/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> First generation college student</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “first generation college student” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0ce74fb9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/h/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an individual both of whose parents did not complete a baccalaureate degree; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0ce74fba-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/h/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case of any individual who regularly resided with and received support from only one parent, an individual whose only such parent did not complete a baccalaureate degree.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce74fbb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/h/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Low-income individual</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “low-income individual” means an individual from a family whose taxable income for the preceding year did not exceed 150 percent of an amount equal to the poverty level determined by using criteria of poverty established by the Bureau of the Census.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce74fbc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/h/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Veteran eligibility</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">No veteran shall be deemed ineligible to participate in any program under this division by reason of such individual’s age who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0ce74fbd-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/h/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> served on active duty for a period of more than 180 days and was discharged or released therefrom under conditions other than dishonorable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0ce74fbe-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/h/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> served on active duty and was discharged or released therefrom because of a service connected disability;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0ce74fbf-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/h/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> was a member of a reserve component of the Armed Forces called to active duty for a period of more than 30 days; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0ce74fc0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/h/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> was a member of a reserve component of the Armed Forces who served on active duty in support of a contingency operation (as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101/a/13">section 101(a)(13) of title 10</ref>) on or after <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0ce74fc1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11/h/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may waive the service requirements in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of paragraph (5) if the Secretary determines the application of the service requirements to a veteran will defeat the purpose of a program under this division.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0ce74fc2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/329/tIV/s402A">Pub. L. 89–329, title IV, § 402A</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/102/325/tIV/s402/a/4">Pub. L. 102–325, title IV, § 402(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1992-07-23">July 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/482">106 Stat. 482</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/208/s2/b/6">Pub. L. 103–208, § 2(b)(6)</ref>–(9), <date date="1993-12-20">Dec. 20, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2458">107 Stat. 2458</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/244/tI/s102/b/1">Pub. L. 105–244, title I, § 102(b)(1)</ref>, title IV, § 402(a), <date date="1998-10-07">Oct. 7, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1622">112 Stat. 1622</ref>, 1652; <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/tIV/s403/a">Pub. L. 110–315, title IV, § 403(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3191">122 Stat. 3191</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/39/tIV/s401/a/4">Pub. L. 111–39, title IV, § 401(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="2009-07-01">July 1, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1938">123 Stat. 1938</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0ce74fc3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0ce74fc4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id0ce74fc5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The General Education Provisions Act, referred to in subsec. (c)(8)(A)(i), is title IV of <ref href="/us/pl/90/247">Pub. L. 90–247</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/814">81 Stat. 814</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 31 (§ 1221 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1221">section 1221 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Higher Education Amendments of 1992, referred to in subsec. (g), is <ref href="/us/pl/102/325">Pub. L. 102–325</ref>, <date date="1992-07-23">July 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/448">106 Stat. 448</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1992 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">section 1001 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id0ce74fc6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (b)(1), “<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>” substituted for “section 3709 of the Revised Statutes (<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s5">41 U.S.C. 5</ref>)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s6/c">Pub. L. 111–350, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3854">124 Stat. 3854</ref>, which Act enacted Title 41, Public Contracts.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id0ce74fc7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/39/s401/a/4/A">Pub. L. 111–39, § 401(a)(4)(A)</ref>, substituted “organizations, including” for “organizations including”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(8)(C)(iv)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/111/39/s401/a/4/B">Pub. L. 111–39, § 401(a)(4)(B)</ref>, inserted “to be” after “determined”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s403/a/1/A">Pub. L. 110–315, § 403(a)(1)(A)</ref>, inserted “including community-based organizations with experience in serving disadvantaged youth” after “private agencies and organizations” and substituted “, as appropriate to the purposes of the program” for “in exceptional circumstances”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s403/a/1/B/i">Pub. L. 110–315, § 403(a)(1)(B)(i)</ref>, substituted “5 years” for “4 years” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s403/a/1/B/ii">Pub. L. 110–315, § 403(a)(1)(B)(ii)</ref>, amended subpar. (A) generally. Prior to amendment subpar. (A) read as follows: “the Secretary shall award such grants or contracts for 5 years to applicants whose peer review scores were in the highest 10 percent of scores of all applicants receiving grants or contracts in each program competition for the same award year;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s403/a/1/C">Pub. L. 110–315, § 403(a)(1)(C)</ref>, added par. (3) and struck out former par. (3). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Unless the institution or agency requests a smaller amount, individual grants under this division shall be no less than—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) $170,000 for programs authorized by sections 1070a–14 and 1070a–17 of this title;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) $180,000 for programs authorized by sections 1070a–12 and 1070a–16 of this title; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) $190,000 for programs authorized by sections 1070a–13 and 1070a–15 of this title.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s403/a/2/A">Pub. L. 110–315, § 403(a)(2)(A)</ref>, inserted par. heading, designated former par. heading as subpar. (A) heading and existing provisions as subpar. (A), substituted “high quality service delivery, as determined under subsection (f),” for “service delivery”, and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s403/a/2/B">Pub. L. 110–315, § 403(a)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “shall not” for “is not required to”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s403/a/2/C">Pub. L. 110–315, § 403(a)(2)(C)</ref>, substituted “different campuses” for “campuses”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s403/a/2/D">Pub. L. 110–315, § 403(a)(2)(D)</ref>, inserted at end “The Secretary shall, as appropriate, require each applicant for funds under the programs authorized by this division to identify and make available services under such program, including mentoring, tutoring, and other services provided by such program, to foster care youth (including youth in foster care and youth who have left foster care after reaching age 13) or to homeless children and youths as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s11434a">section 11434a of title 42</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s403/a/2/E">Pub. L. 110–315, § 403(a)(2)(E)</ref>, added par. (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1), (2). <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s403/a/3/A">Pub. L. 110–315, § 403(a)(3)(A)</ref>, substituted “subsection (h)(4)” for “subsection (g)(2)” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s403/a/3/B">Pub. L. 110–315, § 403(a)(3)(B)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s403/a/5">Pub. L. 110–315, § 403(a)(5)</ref>, added subsec. (f). Former subsec. (f) redesignated (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s403/a/6">Pub. L. 110–315, § 403(a)(6)</ref>, substituted “$900,000,000 for fiscal year 2009 and such sums as may be necessary for each of the five succeeding fiscal years” for “$700,000,000 for fiscal year 1999, and such sums as may be necessary for each of the 4 succeeding fiscal years” and struck out last sentence which read as follows: “The Secretary shall report to Congress by <date date="1994-10-01">October 1, 1994</date>, on the use of these funds.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s403/a/4">Pub. L. 110–315, § 403(a)(4)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (f) as (g). Former subsec. (g) redesignated (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s403/a/7/A">Pub. L. 110–315, § 403(a)(7)(A)</ref>, (B), added pars. (1) and (2) and redesignated former pars. (1) to (4) as (3) to (6), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s403/a/4">Pub. L. 110–315, § 403(a)(4)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (g) as (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(5)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s403/a/7/C/i">Pub. L. 110–315, § 403(a)(7)(C)(i)</ref>, struck out “, any part of which occurred after <date date="1955-01-31">January 31, 1955</date>,” after “more than 180 days” and “or” after semicolon.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(5)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s403/a/7/C/ii">Pub. L. 110–315, § 403(a)(7)(C)(ii)</ref>, struck out “after <date date="1955-01-31">January 31, 1955</date>,” after “active duty” and substituted a semicolon for period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(5)(C), (D). <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s403/a/7/C/iii">Pub. L. 110–315, § 403(a)(7)(C)(iii)</ref>, added subpars. (C) and (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s403/a/7/D">Pub. L. 110–315, § 403(a)(7)(D)</ref>, substituted “subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of paragraph (5)” for “subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (3)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (b)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/105/244/s402/a/1">Pub. L. 105–244, § 402(a)(1)</ref>, added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/244/s402/a/2">Pub. L. 105–244, § 402(a)(2)</ref>, amended heading and text of par. (3) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “In any year in which the appropriations authorized under this division exceed the prior year appropriation as adjusted for inflation, the Secretary shall use 80 percent of the amount appropriated above the current services level to bring each award up to the minimum grant level or the amount requested by the institution or agency, whichever is less. The minimum grant level (A) for programs authorized under section 1070a–14 or 1070a–17 of this title, shall not be less than $170,000 for fiscal year 1993; (B) for programs authorized under section 1070a–12 or 1070a–16 of this title shall not be less than $180,000 for fiscal year 1994; and (C) for programs authorized under section 1070a–13 or 1070a–15 of this title shall not be less than $190,000 for fiscal year 1995.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/105/244/s402/a/3">Pub. L. 105–244, § 402(a)(3)</ref>, amended subsec. (c) generally, revising and restating former pars. (1) to (6), relating to procedures for awarding grants and contracts, as pars. (1) to (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/244/s102/b/1">Pub. L. 105–244, § 102(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “section 1011g” for “section 1145d–1”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/105/244/s402/a/4">Pub. L. 105–244, § 402(a)(4)</ref>, substituted “$700,000,000 for fiscal year 1999” for “$650,000,000 for fiscal year 1993”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/105/244/s402/a/5">Pub. L. 105–244, § 402(a)(5)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/208/s2/b/6">Pub. L. 103–208, § 2(b)(6)</ref>, added par. (2) and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows: “Grants or contracts made under this division shall be awarded for a period of 4 years, except that the Secretary shall award such grants or contracts for 5 years to applicants whose peer review scores were in the highest 10 percent of scores of all applicants receiving grants or contracts in each program competition for the same award year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/208/s2/b/7">Pub. L. 103–208, § 2(b)(7)</ref>, inserted before period at end of second sentence “, except that in the case of the programs authorized in sections 1070a–15 and 1070a–17 of this title, the level of consideration given to prior experience shall be the same as the level of consideration given this factor in the other programs authorized in this division”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/103/208/s2/b/8">Pub. L. 103–208, § 2(b)(8)</ref>, inserted “with respect to grants made under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–17">section 1070a–17 of this title</ref>, and” after “Except”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/103/208/s2/b/9">Pub. L. 103–208, § 2(b)(9)</ref>, amended subsec. (e) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (e) read as follows: “Documentation of an individual’s status pursuant to subsection (g)(2) of this section shall be made—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) in the case of an individual who is eighteen years of age or younger or a dependent student by providing the Secretary with a signed statement from the parent or legal guardian, verification from another governmental source, a signed financial aid application, or a signed United States or Puerto Rican income tax return; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) in the case of an individual who is age 18 or older or who is an independent student, by providing the Secretary with a signed statement from the individual, verification from another governmental source, a signed financial aid form, or a signed United States or Puerto Rican income tax return.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0ce74fc8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0ce74fc9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2009 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/39">Pub. L. 111–39</ref> effective as if enacted on the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/110/315">Pub. L. 110–315</ref> (<date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>), see <ref href="/us/pl/111/39/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 111–39</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">section 1001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0ce74fca-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/244">Pub. L. 105–244</ref> effective <date date="1998-10-01">Oct. 1, 1998</date>, except as otherwise provided in <ref href="/us/pl/105/244">Pub. L. 105–244</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/244/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 105–244</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">section 1001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0ce74fcb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1993 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 2(b)(6), (8), (9) of <ref href="/us/pl/103/208">Pub. L. 103–208</ref> effective as if included in the Higher Education Amendments of 1992, <ref href="/us/pl/102/325">Pub. L. 102–325</ref>, except as otherwise provided, and amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/208/s2/b/7">section 2(b)(7) of Pub. L. 103–208</ref> effective on and after <date date="1993-12-20">Dec. 20, 1993</date>, see section 5(a), (b)(2) of <ref href="/us/pl/103/208">Pub. L. 103–208</ref> set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1051">section 1051 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0ce74fcc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Advanced Placement Fee Payment Program</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/244/tVIII/s810">Pub. L. 105–244, title VIII, § 810</ref>, <date date="1998-10-07">Oct. 7, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1808">112 Stat. 1808</ref>, which authorized grants to States to enable States to reimburse low-income individuals to cover part or all of the cost of advanced placement test fees, required dissemination of information regarding availability of payments, set forth requirements for approval of applications and funding rules, authorized regulations, required annual report, defined terms, and authorized appropriations, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/107/110/tX/s1011/2">Pub. L. 107–110, title X, § 1011(2)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1986">115 Stat. 1986</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Similar provisions were contained in <ref href="/us/pl/102/325/tXV/s1545">Pub. L. 102–325, title XV, § 1545</ref>, <date date="1992-07-23">July 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/837">106 Stat. 837</ref>, which was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/107/110/tX/s1011/1">Pub. L. 107–110, title X, § 1011(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1986">115 Stat. 1986</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0ce74fcd-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References to Subpart 2, 3, or 4 of This Part Deemed To Refer to Subpart 3, 4, or 2 of This Part</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/325/tIV/s402/b">Pub. L. 102–325, title IV, § 402(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-07-23">July 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/505">106 Stat. 505</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/325/tIV/s402/b">“Reference in any provision of law (other than the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</ref> et seq.]) to subpart 2, 3, or 4 of part A of title IV of the Act shall, after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1992-07-23">July 23, 1992</date>], be deemed to refer to subpart 3 [<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070b">20 U.S.C. 1070b</ref> et seq.], 4 [<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070c">20 U.S.C. 1070c</ref> et seq.], or 2 [<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11">20 U.S.C. 1070a–11</ref> et seq.] of such part, respectively.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
