<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0d3ac821-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1087kk"><num value="1087kk">§ 1087kk.</num><heading> Amount of need</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided therein, for award year 2024–2025 and each subsequent award year, the amount of need of any student for financial assistance under this subchapter (except subpart 1 or 2 of part A) is equal to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0d3ac822-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1087kk/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the cost of attendance of such student, minus</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0d3ac823-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1087kk/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the student aid index (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1087mm">section 1087mm of this title</ref>) for such student, minus</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0d3ac824-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1087kk/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> other financial assistance not received under this subchapter (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1087vv/i">section 1087vv(i) of this title</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id0d3ac825-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/329/tIV/s471">Pub. L. 89–329, title IV, § 471</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/498/tIV/s406/a">Pub. L. 99–498, title IV, § 406(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1454">100 Stat. 1454</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/325/tIV/s471/a">Pub. L. 102–325, title IV, § 471(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-07-23">July 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/585">106 Stat. 585</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/244/tIV/s480/a">Pub. L. 105–244, title IV, § 480(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-07">Oct. 7, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1732">112 Stat. 1732</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dFF/tVII/s702/a/1">Pub. L. 116–260, div. FF, title VII, § 702(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3138">134 Stat. 3138</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dR/s102/b/2">Pub. L. 117–103, div. R, § 102(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/819">136 Stat. 819</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0d3ac826-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0d3ac827-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id0d3ac828-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—<ref href="/us/pl/117/103">Pub. L. 117–103</ref> substituted “award year 2024–2025” for “award year 2023–2024” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—<ref href="/us/pl/116/260">Pub. L. 116–260</ref> amended section generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Except as otherwise provided therein, the amount of need of any student for financial assistance under this subchapter (except subparts 1 or 2 of part A of this subchapter) is equal to—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) the cost of attendance of such student, minus</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) the expected family contribution for such student, minus</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(3) estimated financial assistance not received under this subchapter (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1087vv/j">section 1087vv(j) of this title</ref>).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—<ref href="/us/pl/105/244">Pub. L. 105–244</ref> substituted “or 2” for “or 4” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—<ref href="/us/pl/102/325">Pub. L. 102–325</ref> amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section read as follows: “Except as otherwise provided therein, the amount of need of any student for financial assistance under this subchapter (except subparts 1 and 3 of part A of this subchapter) is equal to the cost of attendance of such student minus the expected family contribution for such student.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0d3ac829-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0d3ac82a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2020 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/260">Pub. L. 116–260</ref> effective <date date="2024-07-01">July 1, 2024</date>, except as otherwise expressly provided, and applicable with respect to award year 2024–2025 and each subsequent award year, as determined under this chapter, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s701/b">section 701(b) of Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">section 1001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0d3ac82b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/244/tIV/s480A">Pub. L. 105–244, title IV, § 480A</ref>, <date date="1998-10-07">Oct. 7, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1732">112 Stat. 1732</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/244/tIV/s480A">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subsection (b), the amendments made by this part [part F (§§ 471–480A) of title IV of <ref href="/us/pl/105/244">Pub. L. 105–244</ref>, amending this section and sections 1087<i>ll</i> to 1087tt and 1087vv of this title] are effective on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-10-07">Oct. 7, 1998</date>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Provisions Effective for Academic Year</inline> 2000–2001, <inline class="small-caps">and Thereafter</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendments made by sections 472, 473, 474, and 475 [amending sections 1087nn to 1087qq of this title] shall apply with respect to determinations of need under part F of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 [this part] for academic years beginning on or after <date date="2000-07-01">July 1, 2000</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0d3ac82c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/325/tIV/s471/b">Pub. L. 102–325, title IV, § 471(b)</ref>, <date date="1992-07-23">July 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/609">106 Stat. 609</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/325/tIV/s471/b">“The changes made in part F of title IV of the Act [this part] by the amendment made by this section [amending sections 1087kk to 1087vv of this title] shall apply with respect to determinations of need under such part F for award years beginning on or after <date date="1993-07-01">July 1, 1993</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id0d3ac82d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/498/tIV/s406/b/1">Pub. L. 99–498, title IV, § 406(b)(1)</ref>–(3), <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1475">100 Stat. 1475</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/50/s22/e/1">Pub. L. 100–50, § 22(e)(1)</ref>, (3), <date date="1987-06-03">June 3, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/361">101 Stat. 361</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/50/s22/e/1">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in paragraphs (2) through (4)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> part F of title IV of the Act [this part] shall apply with respect to determinations of need under such title for academic years beginning with academic year 1988–1989 and succeeding academic years; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> for any preceding academic year, determinations of need shall be made in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Education in accordance with the Student Financial Assistance Technical Amendments Act of 1982 [<ref href="/us/pl/97/301">Pub. L. 97–301</ref>, see Short Title of 1982 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">section 1001 of this title</ref>].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> With respect to an application filed after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>] for a loan under part B of such title [part B of this subchapter] for any academic year preceding academic year 1988–1989, any determination of expected family contribution shall be made using the system of financial need analysis approved by the Secretary of Education for use under subpart 2 of part A and parts C and E of such title [subpart 2 of part A of this subchapter and parts C and E of this subchapter].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> For purposes of sections 413D(d)(2)(B) [now 413D(c)(2)(B)], 442(d)(2)(B) and 462(d)(2)(B) [<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070b–3/c/2/B">20 U.S.C. 1070b–3(c)(2)(B)</ref>, 1087–52(d)(2)(B), 1087bb(d)(2)(B)] for any academic year preceding academic year 1988–1989, the Secretary shall, in lieu of average expected family contribution, use the procedures for sampling expected family contribution within income categories that was employed for academic year 1986–1987, adjusted to reflect changes in data.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Section 479B of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1087uu">20 U.S.C. 1087uu</ref>] (as so added) shall apply with respect to financial assistance provided for any academic year beginning after such date of enactment [<date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>].”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[References to subpart 2 of part A of title IV of <ref href="/us/pl/89/329">Pub. L. 89–329</ref> deemed, after <date date="1992-07-23">July 23, 1992</date>, to refer to subpart 3 of such part, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/325/s402/b">section 402(b) of Pub. L. 102–325</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070a–11">section 1070a–11 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0d3d111e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Special Study of Simplification of Need Analysis and Application for Title IV Aid</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/199/dE/tIII/s305">Pub. L. 108–199, div. E, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/263">118 Stat. 263</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/199/dE/tIII/s305">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study Required</inline>.—</heading><content>The Advisory Committee on Student Financial Assistance established by section 491 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1098">20 U.S.C. 1098</ref>), hereafter in this section referred to as ‘the Advisory Committee’, shall conduct a thorough study of the feasibility of simplifying the need analysis methodology for all Federal student financial assistance programs and the process of applying for such assistance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Required Subjects of Study</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In performing the study, the Advisory Committee shall, at a minimum, examine the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> whether the methodology used to calculate the expected family contribution can be simplified without significant adverse effects on program intent, costs, integrity, delivery, and distribution of awards;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> whether the number of data elements, and, accordingly, the number and complexity of questions asked of students and families, used to calculate the expected family contribution can be reduced without such adverse effects;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> whether the procedures for determining such data elements, including determining and updating offsets and allowances, is the most efficient, effective, and fair means to determine a family’s available income and assets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> whether the methodology used to calculate the expected family contribution, specifically the consideration of income earned by a dependent student and its effect on Pell grant eligibility, is an effective and fair means to determine a family’s available income and a student’s need;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> whether the nature and timing of the application required in section 483 (a)(1) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1090/a/1">20 U.S.C. 1090(a)(1)</ref>), eligibility and award determination, financial aid processing, and funds delivery can be streamlined further for students and families, institutions, and States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> whether it is feasible to allow students to complete only those limited sections of the financial aid application that apply to their specific circumstances and the State in which they reside;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> whether a widely disseminated printed form, or the use of an Internet or other electronic means, can be developed to notify individuals of an estimation of their approximate eligibility for grant, work-study, and loan assistance upon completion and verification of the simplified application form;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> whether information provided on other Federal forms (such as the form applying for supplemental security income under title XVI of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1381">42 U.S.C. 1381</ref> et seq.], the form for applying for food stamps under the Food Stamp Act of 1977 [now the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008, <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2011">7 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et seq.], and the schedule for applying for the earned income tax credit under section 32 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [<ref href="/us/usc/t26/s32">26 U.S.C. 32</ref>]) that are designed to determine eligibility for various Federal need-based assistance programs could be used to qualify potential students for the simplified needs test; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> whether any proposed changes to data elements collected, in addition to those used to calculate expected family contribution, or any proposed changes to the form’s design or the process of applying for aid, may have adverse effects on program costs, integrity, delivery, or distribution of awards, as well as, application development or application processing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional Considerations</inline>.—</heading><content>In conducting the feasibility study, the Advisory Committee’s primary objective under this subsection shall be simplifying the financial aid application forms and process and obtaining a substantial reduction in the number of required data items. In carrying out that objective, the Advisory Committee shall pay special attention to the needs of low-income and moderate-income students and families.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Advisory Committee shall consult with a broad range of interested parties in higher education, including parents and students, high school guidance counselors, financial aid and other campus administrators, appropriate State administrators, administrators of intervention and outreach programs, and appropriate officials from the Department of Education.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Forms design expert</inline>.—</heading><content>With the goal of making significant changes to the form to make the questions more easily understandable, the Advisory Committee shall consult a forms design expert to ensure that its recommendations for revision of the application form would assist in making the form easily readable and understood by parents, students, and other members of the public.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Congressional consultation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Advisory Committee shall consult on a regular basis with the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate in carrying out the feasibility study required by this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Departmental consultation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Education shall provide such assistance to the Advisory Committee as is requested and practicable in conducting the study required by this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Interim report</inline>.—</heading><content>The Advisory Committee shall, not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>], prepare and submit an interim report containing any such legislative changes as the Advisory Committee recommends to reform and simplify the needs analysis under part F of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1087kk">20 U.S.C. 1087kk</ref> et seq.) and forms and other requirements under such title to the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, and the Secretary of Education.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Final report</inline>.—</heading><content>The Advisory Committee shall, not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, prepare and submit a full final report on the study, including recommendations for regulatory and administrative changes required by this section, to the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, and the Secretary of Education.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Education shall consult with the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and shall subsequently initiate a redesign of the form required by section 483 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1090">20 U.S.C. 1090</ref>). Such redesign shall include the testing of alternative simplified versions of the free Federal form. The Secretary shall keep the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate fully and currently informed on the progress of these efforts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Postponement of Tax Table Update Pending Report and Implementation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Education shall not implement or enforce for the award year 2004–2005 the annual update to the allowances for State and other taxes in the tables used in the Federal needs analysis methodology, as prescribed by the Secretary on <date date="2003-05-30">May 30, 2003</date> (68 Fed. Reg. 32473).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
