<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0d97b4fb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1234b"><num value="1234b">§ 1234b.</num><heading> Measure of recovery</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0d97b4fc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1234b/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount returned proportionate to extent of harm violation caused to an identifiable Federal interest; reduction; determination of identifiable Federal interest</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0d97b4fd-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1234b/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A recipient determined to have made an unallowable expenditure, or to have otherwise failed to discharge its responsibility to account properly for funds, shall be required to return funds in an amount that is proportionate to the extent of the harm its violation caused to an identifiable Federal interest associated with the program under which the recipient received the award. Such amount shall be reduced in whole or in part by an amount that is proportionate to the extent the mitigating circumstances caused the violation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0d97b4fe-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1234b/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> For the purpose of paragraph (1), an identifiable Federal interest includes, but is not limited to, serving only eligible beneficiaries; providing only authorized services or benefits; complying with expenditure requirements and conditions (such as set-aside, excess cost, maintenance of effort, comparability, supplement-not-supplant, and matching requirements); preserving the integrity of planning, application, recordkeeping, and reporting requirements; and maintaining accountability for the use of funds.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0d97b4ff-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1234b/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Reduction or waiver of amount based on mitigating circumstances; burden of proof; determination of mitigating circumstances; weight, etc., of written request for guidance</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0d97b500-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1234b/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> When a State or local educational agency is determined to have made an unallowable expenditure, or to have otherwise failed to discharge its responsibility to account properly for funds, and mitigating circumstances exist, as described in paragraph (2), the judge shall reduce such amount by an amount that is proportionate to the extent the mitigating circumstances caused the violation. Furthermore, the judge is authorized to determine that no recovery is justified when mitigating circumstances warrant. The burden of demonstrating the existence of mitigating circumstances shall be upon the State or local educational agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0d97b501-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1234b/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> For the purpose of paragraph (1), mitigating circumstances exist only when it would be unjust to compel the recovery of funds because the State or local educational agency—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0d97b502-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1234b/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> actually and reasonably relied upon erroneous written guidance provided by the Department;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0d97b503-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1234b/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> made an expenditure or engaged in a practice after—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0d97b504-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1234b/b/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the State or local educational agency submitted to the Secretary, in good faith, a written request for guidance with respect to the expenditure or practice at issue, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0d97b505-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1234b/b/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a Department official did not respond within 90 days of receipt by the Department of such request; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0d97b506-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1234b/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> actually and reasonably relied upon a judicial decree issued to the recipient.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0d97b507-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1234b/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A written request for guidance as described in paragraph (2) sent by certified mail (return receipt requested) shall be conclusive proof of receipt by the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0d97b508-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1234b/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> If the Secretary responds to a written request for guidance described in paragraph (2)(B) more than 90 days after its receipt, the State or local educational agency that submitted the request shall comply with the guidance received at the earliest practicable time.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0d97b509-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1234b/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> In order to demonstrate the existence of the mitigating circumstances described in paragraph (2)(B), the State or local educational agency shall demonstrate that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0d97b50a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1234b/b/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the written request for guidance accurately described the proposed expenditure or practice and included the facts necessary for a determination of its legality; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0d97b50b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1234b/b/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the written request for guidance contained a certification by the chief legal officer of the State educational agency that such officer had examined the proposed expenditure or practice and believed the proposed expenditure or practice was permissible under then applicable State and Federal law; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0d97b50c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1234b/b/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the State or local educational agency reasonably believed that the proposed expenditure or practice was permissible under then applicable State and Federal law.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0d97b50d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1234b/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The Secretary shall disseminate to State educational agencies responses to written requests for guidance, described in paragraph (5), that reflect significant interpretations of applicable law or policy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0d97b50e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1234b/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Review of written requests for guidance on periodic basis</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall periodically review the written requests for guidance submitted under this section to determine the need for new or supplementary regulatory or other guidance under applicable programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0d97b50f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/247/tIV/s453">Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 453</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/95/561/tXII/s1232">Pub. L. 95–561, title XII, § 1232</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2349">92 Stat. 2349</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/297/tIII/s3501/a">Pub. L. 100–297, title III, § 3501(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/353">102 Stat. 353</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0d97b510-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0d97b511-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id0d97b512-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/297">Pub. L. 100–297</ref> amended section generally, substituting provisions relating to measure of recovery for provisions relating to withholdings. See <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1234d">section 1234d of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0d97b513-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0d97b514-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/297">Pub. L. 100–297</ref> effective 180 days after <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, but not applicable to recipients receiving written notice to return funds prior to that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/297/s3501/b">section 3501(b) of Pub. L. 100–297</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1234">section 1234 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
