<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0d9ee06a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412"><num value="1412">§ 1412.</num><heading> State eligibility</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee06b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A State is eligible for assistance under this subchapter for a fiscal year if the State submits a plan that provides assurances to the Secretary that the State has in effect policies and procedures to ensure that the State meets each of the following conditions:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee06c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Free appropriate public education</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee06d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A free appropriate public education is available to all children with disabilities residing in the State between the ages of 3 and 21, inclusive, including children with disabilities who have been suspended or expelled from school.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee06e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The obligation to make a free appropriate public education available to all children with disabilities does not apply with respect to children—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0d9ee06f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> aged 3 through 5 and 18 through 21 in a State to the extent that its application to those children would be inconsistent with State law or practice, or the order of any court, respecting the provision of public education to children in those age ranges; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0d9ee070-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> aged 18 through 21 to the extent that State law does not require that special education and related services under this subchapter be provided to children with disabilities who, in the educational placement prior to their incarceration in an adult correctional facility—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0d9ee071-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/1/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> were not actually identified as being a child with a disability under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1401">section 1401 of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0d9ee072-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/1/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> did not have an individualized education program under this subchapter.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee073-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/1/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> State flexibility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A State that provides early intervention services in accordance with subchapter III to a child who is eligible for services under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1419">section 1419 of this title</ref>, is not required to provide such child with a free appropriate public education.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee074-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Full educational opportunity goal</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The State has established a goal of providing full educational opportunity to all children with disabilities and a detailed timetable for accomplishing that goal.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee075-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Child find</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee076-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">All children with disabilities residing in the State, including children with disabilities who are homeless children or are wards of the State and children with disabilities attending private schools, regardless of the severity of their disabilities, and who are in need of special education and related services, are identified, located, and evaluated and a practical method is developed and implemented to determine which children with disabilities are currently receiving needed special education and related services.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee077-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Nothing in this chapter requires that children be classified by their disability so long as each child who has a disability listed in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1401">section 1401 of this title</ref> and who, by reason of that disability, needs special education and related services is regarded as a child with a disability under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee078-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Individualized education program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">An individualized education program, or an individualized family service plan that meets the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1436/d">section 1436(d) of this title</ref>, is developed, reviewed, and revised for each child with a disability in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1414/d">section 1414(d) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee079-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Least restrictive environment</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee07a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">To the maximum extent appropriate, children with disabilities, including children in public or private institutions or other care facilities, are educated with children who are not disabled, and special classes, separate schooling, or other removal of children with disabilities from the regular educational environment occurs only when the nature or severity of the disability of a child is such that education in regular classes with the use of supplementary aids and services cannot be achieved satisfactorily.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee07b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional requirement</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee07c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/5/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">A State funding mechanism shall not result in placements that violate the requirements of subparagraph (A), and a State shall not use a funding mechanism by which the State distributes funds on the basis of the type of setting in which a child is served that will result in the failure to provide a child with a disability a free appropriate public education according to the unique needs of the child as described in the child’s IEP.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee07d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/5/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Assurance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If the State does not have policies and procedures to ensure compliance with clause (i), the State shall provide the Secretary an assurance that the State will revise the funding mechanism as soon as feasible to ensure that such mechanism does not result in such placements.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee07e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedural safeguards</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee07f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/6/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Children with disabilities and their parents are afforded the procedural safeguards required by <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1415">section 1415 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee080-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/6/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional procedural safeguards</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Procedures to ensure that testing and evaluation materials and procedures utilized for the purposes of evaluation and placement of children with disabilities for services under this chapter will be selected and administered so as not to be racially or culturally discriminatory. Such materials or procedures shall be provided and administered in the child’s native language or mode of communication, unless it clearly is not feasible to do so, and no single procedure shall be the sole criterion for determining an appropriate educational program for a child.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee081-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Evaluation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Children with disabilities are evaluated in accordance with subsections (a) through (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1414">section 1414 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee082-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Confidentiality</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Agencies in the State comply with <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1417/c">section 1417(c) of this title</ref> (relating to the confidentiality of records and information).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee083-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Transition from subchapter III to preschool programs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Children participating in early intervention programs assisted under subchapter III, and who will participate in preschool programs assisted under this subchapter, experience a smooth and effective transition to those preschool programs in a manner consistent with <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1437/a/9">section 1437(a)(9) of this title</ref>. By the third birthday of such a child, an individualized education program or, if consistent with sections 1414(d)(2)(B) and 1436(d) of this title, an individualized family service plan, has been developed and is being implemented for the child. The local educational agency will participate in transition planning conferences arranged by the designated lead agency under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1435/a/10">section 1435(a)(10) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee084-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10"><num value="10" class="bold">(10)</num><heading class="bold"> Children in private schools</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee085-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Children enrolled in private schools by their parents</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee086-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">To the extent consistent with the number and location of children with disabilities in the State who are enrolled by their parents in private elementary schools and secondary schools in the school district served by a local educational agency, provision is made for the participation of those children in the program assisted or carried out under this subchapter by providing for such children special education and related services in accordance with the following requirements, unless the Secretary has arranged for services to those children under subsection (f):</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0d9ee087-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> Amounts to be expended for the provision of those services (including direct services to parentally placed private school children) by the local educational agency shall be equal to a proportionate amount of Federal funds made available under this subchapter.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0d9ee088-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> In calculating the proportionate amount of Federal funds, the local educational agency, after timely and meaningful consultation with representatives of private schools as described in clause (iii), shall conduct a thorough and complete child find process to determine the number of parentally placed children with disabilities attending private schools located in the local educational agency.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0d9ee089-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> Such services to parentally placed private school children with disabilities may be provided to the children on the premises of private, including religious, schools, to the extent consistent with law.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0d9ee08a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/i/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> State and local funds may supplement and in no case shall supplant the proportionate amount of Federal funds required to be expended under this subparagraph.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0d9ee08b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/i/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> Each local educational agency shall maintain in its records and provide to the State educational agency the number of children evaluated under this subparagraph, the number of children determined to be children with disabilities under this paragraph, and the number of children served under this paragraph.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee08c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Child find requirement</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee08d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/ii/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The requirements of paragraph (3) (relating to child find) shall apply with respect to children with disabilities in the State who are enrolled in private, including religious, elementary schools and secondary schools.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee08e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/ii/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Equitable participation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The child find process shall be designed to ensure the equitable participation of parentally placed private school children with disabilities and an accurate count of such children.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee08f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/ii/III"><num value="III" class="bold">(III)</num><heading class="bold"> Activities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">In carrying out this clause, the local educational agency, or where applicable, the State educational agency, shall undertake activities similar to those activities undertaken for the agency’s public school children.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee090-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/ii/IV"><num value="IV" class="bold">(IV)</num><heading class="bold"> Cost</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The cost of carrying out this clause, including individual evaluations, may not be considered in determining whether a local educational agency has met its obligations under clause (i).</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee091-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/ii/V"><num value="V" class="bold">(V)</num><heading class="bold"> Completion period</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">Such child find process shall be completed in a time period comparable to that for other students attending public schools in the local educational agency.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee092-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">To ensure timely and meaningful consultation, a local educational agency, or where appropriate, a State educational agency, shall consult with private school representatives and representatives of parents of parentally placed private school children with disabilities during the design and development of special education and related services for the children, including regarding—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0d9ee093-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the child find process and how parentally placed private school children suspected of having a disability can participate equitably, including how parents, teachers, and private school officials will be informed of the process;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0d9ee094-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the determination of the proportionate amount of Federal funds available to serve parentally placed private school children with disabilities under this subparagraph, including the determination of how the amount was calculated;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0d9ee095-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/iii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the consultation process among the local educational agency, private school officials, and representatives of parents of parentally placed private school children with disabilities, including how such process will operate throughout the school year to ensure that parentally placed private school children with disabilities identified through the child find process can meaningfully participate in special education and related services;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0d9ee096-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/iii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> how, where, and by whom special education and related services will be provided for parentally placed private school children with disabilities, including a discussion of types of services, including direct services and alternate service delivery mechanisms, how such services will be apportioned if funds are insufficient to serve all children, and how and when these decisions will be made; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0d9ee097-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/iii/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> how, if the local educational agency disagrees with the views of the private school officials on the provision of services or the types of services, whether provided directly or through a contract, the local educational agency shall provide to the private school officials a written explanation of the reasons why the local educational agency chose not to provide services directly or through a contract.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee098-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/iv"><num value="iv" class="bold">(iv)</num><heading class="bold"> Written affirmation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">When timely and meaningful consultation as required by clause (iii) has occurred, the local educational agency shall obtain a written affirmation signed by the representatives of participating private schools, and if such representatives do not provide such affirmation within a reasonable period of time, the local educational agency shall forward the documentation of the consultation process to the State educational agency.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee099-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/v"><num value="v" class="bold">(v)</num><heading class="bold"> Compliance</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee09a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/v/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">A private school official shall have the right to submit a complaint to the State educational agency that the local educational agency did not engage in consultation that was meaningful and timely, or did not give due consideration to the views of the private school official.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee09b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/v/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedure</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">If the private school official wishes to submit a complaint, the official shall provide the basis of the noncompliance with this subparagraph by the local educational agency to the State educational agency, and the local educational agency shall forward the appropriate documentation to the State educational agency. If the private school official is dissatisfied with the decision of the State educational agency, such official may submit a complaint to the Secretary by providing the basis of the noncompliance with this subparagraph by the local educational agency to the Secretary, and the State educational agency shall forward the appropriate documentation to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee09c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/vi"><num value="vi" class="bold">(vi)</num><heading class="bold"> Provision of equitable services</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee09d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/vi/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> Directly or through contracts</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The provision of services pursuant to this subparagraph shall be provided—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id0d9ee09e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/vi/I/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> by employees of a public agency; or</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id0d9ee09f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/vi/I/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> through contract by the public agency with an individual, association, agency, organization, or other entity.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee0a0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/vi/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Secular, neutral, nonideological</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">Special education and related services provided to parentally placed private school children with disabilities, including materials and equipment, shall be secular, neutral, and nonideological.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee0a1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/A/vii"><num value="vii" class="bold">(vii)</num><heading class="bold"> Public control of funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The control of funds used to provide special education and related services under this subparagraph, and title to materials, equipment, and property purchased with those funds, shall be in a public agency for the uses and purposes provided in this chapter, and a public agency shall administer the funds and property.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee0a2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Children placed in, or referred to, private schools by public agencies</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee0a3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Children with disabilities in private schools and facilities are provided special education and related services, in accordance with an individualized education program, at no cost to their parents, if such children are placed in, or referred to, such schools or facilities by the State or appropriate local educational agency as the means of carrying out the requirements of this subchapter or any other applicable law requiring the provision of special education and related services to all children with disabilities within such State.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee0a4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Standards</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">In all cases described in clause (i), the State educational agency shall determine whether such schools and facilities meet standards that apply to State educational agencies and local educational agencies and that children so served have all the rights the children would have if served by such agencies.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee0a5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment for education of children enrolled in private schools without consent of or referral by the public agency</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee0a6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Subject to subparagraph (A), this subchapter does not require a local educational agency to pay for the cost of education, including special education and related services, of a child with a disability at a private school or facility if that agency made a free appropriate public education available to the child and the parents elected to place the child in such private school or facility.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee0a7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Reimbursement for private school placement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If the parents of a child with a disability, who previously received special education and related services under the authority of a public agency, enroll the child in a private elementary school or secondary school without the consent of or referral by the public agency, a court or a hearing officer may require the agency to reimburse the parents for the cost of that enrollment if the court or hearing officer finds that the agency had not made a free appropriate public education available to the child in a timely manner prior to that enrollment.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee0a8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/C/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on reimbursement</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The cost of reimbursement described in clause (ii) may be reduced or denied—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0d9ee0a9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/C/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><chapeau> if—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id0d9ee0aa-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/C/iii/I/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> at the most recent IEP meeting that the parents attended prior to removal of the child from the public school, the parents did not inform the IEP Team that they were rejecting the placement proposed by the public agency to provide a free appropriate public education to their child, including stating their concerns and their intent to enroll their child in a private school at public expense; or</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id0d9ee0ab-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/C/iii/I/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> 10 business days (including any holidays that occur on a business day) prior to the removal of the child from the public school, the parents did not give written notice to the public agency of the information described in item (aa);</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0d9ee0ac-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/C/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> if, prior to the parents’ removal of the child from the public school, the public agency informed the parents, through the notice requirements described in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1415/b/3">section 1415(b)(3) of this title</ref>, of its intent to evaluate the child (including a statement of the purpose of the evaluation that was appropriate and reasonable), but the parents did not make the child available for such evaluation; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0d9ee0ad-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/C/iii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> upon a judicial finding of unreasonableness with respect to actions taken by the parents.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee0ae-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/C/iv"><num value="iv" class="bold">(iv)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Notwithstanding the notice requirement in clause (iii)(I), the cost of reimbursement—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0d9ee0af-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/C/iv/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><chapeau> shall not be reduced or denied for failure to provide such notice if—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id0d9ee0b0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/C/iv/I/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> the school prevented the parent from providing such notice;</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id0d9ee0b1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/C/iv/I/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> the parents had not received notice, pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1415">section 1415 of this title</ref>, of the notice requirement in clause (iii)(I); or</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id0d9ee0b2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/C/iv/I/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content> compliance with clause (iii)(I) would likely result in physical harm to the child; and</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0d9ee0b3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/C/iv/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><chapeau> may, in the discretion of a court or a hearing officer, not be reduced or denied for failure to provide such notice if—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id0d9ee0b4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/C/iv/II/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> the parent is illiterate or cannot write in English; or</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id0d9ee0b5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/10/C/iv/II/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> compliance with clause (iii)(I) would likely result in serious emotional harm to the child.</content>
</item>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee0b6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/11"><num value="11" class="bold">(11)</num><heading class="bold"> State educational agency responsible for general supervision</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee0b7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/11/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The State educational agency is responsible for ensuring that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0d9ee0b8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/11/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the requirements of this subchapter are met;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0d9ee0b9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/11/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> all educational programs for children with disabilities in the State, including all such programs administered by any other State agency or local agency—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0d9ee0ba-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/11/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> are under the general supervision of individuals in the State who are responsible for educational programs for children with disabilities; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0d9ee0bb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/11/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> meet the educational standards of the State educational agency; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0d9ee0bc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/11/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> in carrying out this subchapter with respect to homeless children, the requirements of subtitle B of title VII of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s11431">42 U.S.C. 11431</ref> et seq.) are met.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee0bd-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/11/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subparagraph (A) shall not limit the responsibility of agencies in the State other than the State educational agency to provide, or pay for some or all of the costs of, a free appropriate public education for any child with a disability in the State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee0be-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/11/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding subparagraphs (A) and (B), the Governor (or another individual pursuant to State law), consistent with State law, may assign to any public agency in the State the responsibility of ensuring that the requirements of this subchapter are met with respect to children with disabilities who are convicted as adults under State law and incarcerated in adult prisons.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee0bf-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/12"><num value="12" class="bold">(12)</num><heading class="bold"> Obligations related to and methods of ensuring services</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee0c0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/12/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishing responsibility for services</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Chief Executive Officer of a State or designee of the officer shall ensure that an interagency agreement or other mechanism for interagency coordination is in effect between each public agency described in subparagraph (B) and the State educational agency, in order to ensure that all services described in subparagraph (B)(i) that are needed to ensure a free appropriate public education are provided, including the provision of such services during the pendency of any dispute under clause (iii). Such agreement or mechanism shall include the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee0c1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/12/A/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Agency financial responsibility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">An identification of, or a method for defining, the financial responsibility of each agency for providing services described in subparagraph (B)(i) to ensure a free appropriate public education to children with disabilities, provided that the financial responsibility of each public agency described in subparagraph (B), including the State medicaid agency and other public insurers of children with disabilities, shall precede the financial responsibility of the local educational agency (or the State agency responsible for developing the child’s IEP).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee0c2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/12/A/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditions and terms of reimbursement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The conditions, terms, and procedures under which a local educational agency shall be reimbursed by other agencies.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee0c3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/12/A/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Interagency disputes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Procedures for resolving interagency disputes (including procedures under which local educational agencies may initiate proceedings) under the agreement or other mechanism to secure reimbursement from other agencies or otherwise implement the provisions of the agreement or mechanism.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee0c4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/12/A/iv"><num value="iv" class="bold">(iv)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination of services procedures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Policies and procedures for agencies to determine and identify the interagency coordination responsibilities of each agency to promote the coordination and timely and appropriate delivery of services described in subparagraph (B)(i).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee0c5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/12/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Obligation of public agency</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0d9ee0c6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/12/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If any public agency other than an educational agency is otherwise obligated under Federal or State law, or assigned responsibility under State policy pursuant to subparagraph (A), to provide or pay for any services that are also considered special education or related services (such as, but not limited to, services described in section 1401(1) relating to assistive technology devices, 1401(2) relating to assistive technology services, 1401(26) relating to related services, 1401(33) relating to supplementary aids and services, and 1401(34) of this title relating to transition services) that are necessary for ensuring a free appropriate public education to children with disabilities within the State, such public agency shall fulfill that obligation or responsibility, either directly or through contract or other arrangement pursuant to subparagraph (A) or an agreement pursuant to subparagraph (C).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151c7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/12/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Reimbursement for services by public agency</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If a public agency other than an educational agency fails to provide or pay for the special education and related services described in clause (i), the local educational agency (or State agency responsible for developing the child’s IEP) shall provide or pay for such services to the child. Such local educational agency or State agency is authorized to claim reimbursement for the services from the public agency that failed to provide or pay for such services and such public agency shall reimburse the local educational agency or State agency pursuant to the terms of the interagency agreement or other mechanism described in subparagraph (A)(i) according to the procedures established in such agreement pursuant to subparagraph (A)(ii).</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151c8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/12/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rule</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The requirements of subparagraph (A) may be met through—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da151c9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/12/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> State statute or regulation;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da151ca-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/12/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> signed agreements between respective agency officials that clearly identify the responsibilities of each agency relating to the provision of services; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da151cb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/12/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> other appropriate written methods as determined by the Chief Executive Officer of the State or designee of the officer and approved by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151cc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/13"><num value="13" class="bold">(13)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedural requirements relating to local educational agency eligibility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The State educational agency will not make a final determination that a local educational agency is not eligible for assistance under this subchapter without first affording that agency reasonable notice and an opportunity for a hearing.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151cd-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/14"><num value="14" class="bold">(14)</num><heading class="bold"> Personnel qualifications</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151ce-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/14/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The State educational agency has established and maintains qualifications to ensure that personnel necessary to carry out this subchapter are appropriately and adequately prepared and trained, including that those personnel have the content knowledge and skills to serve children with disabilities.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151cf-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/14/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Related services personnel and paraprofessionals</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The qualifications under subparagraph (A) include qualifications for related services personnel and paraprofessionals that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da151d0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/14/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> are consistent with any State-approved or State-recognized certification, licensing, registration, or other comparable requirements that apply to the professional discipline in which those personnel are providing special education or related services;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da151d1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/14/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> ensure that related services personnel who deliver services in their discipline or profession meet the requirements of clause (i) and have not had certification or licensure requirements waived on an emergency, temporary, or provisional basis; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da151d2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/14/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> allow paraprofessionals and assistants who are appropriately trained and supervised, in accordance with State law, regulation, or written policy, in meeting the requirements of this subchapter to be used to assist in the provision of special education and related services under this subchapter to children with disabilities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151d3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/14/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Qualifications for special education teachers</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The qualifications described in subparagraph (A) shall ensure that each person employed as a special education teacher in the State who teaches elementary school, middle school, or secondary school—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da151d4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/14/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> has obtained full State certification as a special education teacher (including participating in an alternate route to certification as a special educator, if such alternate route meets minimum requirements described in section 2005.56(a)(2)(ii) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002124">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002124"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “200.56(a)(2)(ii)”.</note> of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations, as such section was in effect on <date date="2008-11-28">November 28, 2008</date>), or passed the State special education teacher licensing examination, and holds a license to teach in the State as a special education teacher, except with respect to any teacher teaching in a public charter school who shall meet the requirements set forth in the State’s public charter school law;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da151d5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/14/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> has not had special education certification or licensure requirements waived on an emergency, temporary, or provisional basis; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da151d6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/14/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> holds at least a bachelor’s degree..<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002125">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002125"><num>2</num> So in original.</note></content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151d7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/14/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Policy</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In implementing this section, a State shall adopt a policy that includes a requirement that local educational agencies in the State take measurable steps to recruit, hire, train, and retain personnel who meet the applicable requirements described in this paragraph to provide special education and related services under this subchapter to children with disabilities.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151d8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/14/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding any other individual right of action that a parent or student may maintain under this subchapter, nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to create a right of action on behalf of an individual student for the failure of a particular State educational agency or local educational agency staff person to meet the applicable requirements described in this paragraph, or to prevent a parent from filing a complaint about staff qualifications with the State educational agency as provided for under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151d9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/15"><num value="15" class="bold">(15)</num><heading class="bold"> Performance goals and indicators</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The State—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0da151da-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/15/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> has established goals for the performance of children with disabilities in the State that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da151db-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/15/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> promote the purposes of this chapter, as stated in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1400/d">section 1400(d) of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da151dc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/15/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> are the same as the State’s long-term goals and measurements of interim progress for children with disabilities under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6311/c/4/A/i">section 6311(c)(4)(A)(i) of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da151dd-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/15/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> address graduation rates and dropout rates, as well as such other factors as the State may determine; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da151de-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/15/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> are consistent, to the extent appropriate, with any other goals and standards for children established by the State;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0da151df-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/15/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> has established performance indicators the State will use to assess progress toward achieving the goals described in subparagraph (A), including measurements of interim progress for children with disabilities under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6311/c/4/A/i">section 6311(c)(4)(A)(i) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0da151e0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/15/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> will annually report to the Secretary and the public on the progress of the State, and of children with disabilities in the State, toward meeting the goals established under subparagraph (A), which may include elements of the reports required under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6311/h">section 6311(h) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151e1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/16"><num value="16" class="bold">(16)</num><heading class="bold"> Participation in assessments</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151e2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/16/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">All children with disabilities are included in all general State and districtwide assessment programs, including assessments described under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6311">section 6311 of this title</ref>, with appropriate accommodations and alternate assessments where necessary and as indicated in their respective individualized education programs.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151e3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/16/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Accommodation guidelines</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The State (or, in the case of a districtwide assessment, the local educational agency) has developed guidelines for the provision of appropriate accommodations.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151e4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/16/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Alternate assessments</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151e5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/16/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The State (or, in the case of a districtwide assessment, the local educational agency) has developed and implemented guidelines for the participation of children with disabilities in alternate assessments for those children who cannot participate in regular assessments under subparagraph (A) with accommodations as indicated in their respective individualized education programs.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151e6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/16/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements for alternate assessments</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The guidelines under clause (i) shall provide for alternate assessments that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0da151e7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/16/C/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> are aligned with the challenging State academic content standards under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6311/b/1">section 6311(b)(1) of this title</ref> and alternate academic achievement standards under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6311/b/1/E">section 6311(b)(1)(E) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0da151e8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/16/C/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> if the State has adopted alternate academic achievement standards permitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6311/b/1/E">section 6311(b)(1)(E) of this title</ref>, measure the achievement of children with disabilities against those standards.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151e9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/16/C/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Conduct of alternate assessments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The State conducts the alternate assessments described in this subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151ea-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/16/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The State educational agency (or, in the case of a districtwide assessment, the local educational agency) makes available to the public, and reports to the public with the same frequency and in the same detail as it reports on the assessment of nondisabled children, the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da151eb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/16/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The number of children with disabilities participating in regular assessments, and the number of those children who were provided accommodations in order to participate in those assessments.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da151ec-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/16/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The number of children with disabilities participating in alternate assessments described in subparagraph (C)(ii)(I).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da151ed-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/16/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> The number of children with disabilities participating in alternate assessments described in subparagraph (C)(ii)(II).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da151ee-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/16/D/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> The performance of children with disabilities on regular assessments and on alternate assessments (if the number of children with disabilities participating in those assessments is sufficient to yield statistically reliable information and reporting that information will not reveal personally identifiable information about an individual student), compared with the achievement of all children, including children with disabilities, on those assessments.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151ef-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/16/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Universal design</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The State educational agency (or, in the case of a districtwide assessment, the local educational agency) shall, to the extent feasible, use universal design principles in developing and administering any assessments under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151f0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/17"><num value="17" class="bold">(17)</num><heading class="bold"> Supplementation of State, local, and other Federal funds</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151f1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/17/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Expenditures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Funds paid to a State under this subchapter will be expended in accordance with all the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151f2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/17/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition against commingling</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Funds paid to a State under this subchapter will not be commingled with State funds.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151f3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/17/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition against supplantation and conditions for waiver by Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Except as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1413">section 1413 of this title</ref>, funds paid to a State under this subchapter will be used to supplement the level of Federal, State, and local funds (including funds that are not under the direct control of State or local educational agencies) expended for special education and related services provided to children with disabilities under this subchapter and in no case to supplant such Federal, State, and local funds, except that, where the State provides clear and convincing evidence that all children with disabilities have available to them a free appropriate public education, the Secretary may waive, in whole or in part, the requirements of this subparagraph if the Secretary concurs with the evidence provided by the State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151f4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/18"><num value="18" class="bold">(18)</num><heading class="bold"> Maintenance of State financial support</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151f5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/18/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The State does not reduce the amount of State financial support for special education and related services for children with disabilities, or otherwise made available because of the excess costs of educating those children, below the amount of that support for the preceding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151f6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/18/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Reduction of funds for failure to maintain support</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall reduce the allocation of funds under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1411">section 1411 of this title</ref> for any fiscal year following the fiscal year in which the State fails to comply with the requirement of subparagraph (A) by the same amount by which the State fails to meet the requirement.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151f7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/18/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Waivers for exceptional or uncontrollable circumstances</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary may waive the requirement of subparagraph (A) for a State, for 1 fiscal year at a time, if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da151f8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/18/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> granting a waiver would be equitable due to exceptional or uncontrollable circumstances such as a natural disaster or a precipitous and unforeseen decline in the financial resources of the State; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da151f9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/18/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the State meets the standard in paragraph (17)(C) for a waiver of the requirement to supplement, and not to supplant, funds received under this subchapter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151fa-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/18/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Subsequent years</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If, for any year, a State fails to meet the requirement of subparagraph (A), including any year for which the State is granted a waiver under subparagraph (C), the financial support required of the State in future years under subparagraph (A) shall be the amount that would have been required in the absence of that failure and not the reduced level of the State’s support.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151fb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/19"><num value="19" class="bold">(19)</num><heading class="bold"> Public participation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Prior to the adoption of any policies and procedures needed to comply with this section (including any amendments to such policies and procedures), the State ensures that there are public hearings, adequate notice of the hearings, and an opportunity for comment available to the general public, including individuals with disabilities and parents of children with disabilities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151fc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/20"><num value="20" class="bold">(20)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In complying with paragraphs (17) and (18), a State may not use funds paid to it under this subchapter to satisfy State-law mandated funding obligations to local educational agencies, including funding based on student attendance or enrollment, or inflation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151fd-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/21"><num value="21" class="bold">(21)</num><heading class="bold"> State advisory panel</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151fe-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/21/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The State has established and maintains an advisory panel for the purpose of providing policy guidance with respect to special education and related services for children with disabilities in the State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da151ff-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/21/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Membership</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Such advisory panel shall consist of members appointed by the Governor, or any other official authorized under State law to make such appointments, be representative of the State population, and be composed of individuals involved in, or concerned with, the education of children with disabilities, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da15200-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/21/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> parents of children with disabilities (ages birth through 26);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da15201-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/21/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> individuals with disabilities;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da15202-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/21/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> teachers;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da15203-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/21/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> representatives of institutions of higher education that prepare special education and related services personnel;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da15204-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/21/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> State and local education officials, including officials who carry out activities under subtitle B of title VII of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s11431">42 U.S.C. 11431</ref> et seq.);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da15205-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/21/B/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> administrators of programs for children with disabilities;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da15206-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/21/B/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> representatives of other State agencies involved in the financing or delivery of related services to children with disabilities;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da15207-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/21/B/viii"><num value="viii">(viii)</num><content> representatives of private schools and public charter schools;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da15208-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/21/B/ix"><num value="ix">(ix)</num><content> not less than 1 representative of a vocational, community, or business organization concerned with the provision of transition services to children with disabilities;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da15209-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/21/B/x"><num value="x">(x)</num><content> a representative from the State child welfare agency responsible for foster care; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da1520a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/21/B/xi"><num value="xi">(xi)</num><content> representatives from the State juvenile and adult corrections agencies.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da1520b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/21/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rule</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A majority of the members of the panel shall be individuals with disabilities or parents of children with disabilities (ages birth through 26).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da1520c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/21/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The advisory panel shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da1520d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/21/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> advise the State educational agency of unmet needs within the State in the education of children with disabilities;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da1520e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/21/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> comment publicly on any rules or regulations proposed by the State regarding the education of children with disabilities;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da1520f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/21/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> advise the State educational agency in developing evaluations and reporting on data to the Secretary under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1418">section 1418 of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da15210-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/21/D/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> advise the State educational agency in developing corrective action plans to address findings identified in Federal monitoring reports under this subchapter; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da15211-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/21/D/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> advise the State educational agency in developing and implementing policies relating to the coordination of services for children with disabilities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0da15212-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/22"><num value="22" class="bold">(22)</num><heading class="bold"> Suspension and expulsion rates</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da15213-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/22/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The State educational agency examines data, including data disaggregated by race and ethnicity, to determine if significant discrepancies are occurring in the rate of long-term suspensions and expulsions of children with disabilities—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da15214-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/22/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> among local educational agencies in the State; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da15215-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/22/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> compared to such rates for nondisabled children within such agencies.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da15216-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/22/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Review and revision of policies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If such discrepancies are occurring, the State educational agency reviews and, if appropriate, revises (or requires the affected State or local educational agency to revise) its policies, procedures, and practices relating to the development and implementation of IEPs, the use of positive behavioral interventions and supports, and procedural safeguards, to ensure that such policies, procedures, and practices comply with this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0da15217-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/23"><num value="23" class="bold">(23)</num><heading class="bold"> Access to instructional materials</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da15218-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/23/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The State adopts the National Instructional Materials Accessibility Standard for the purposes of providing instructional materials to blind persons or other persons with print disabilities, in a timely manner after the publication of the National Instructional Materials Accessibility Standard in the Federal Register.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da15219-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/23/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Rights of State educational agency</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to require any State educational agency to coordinate with the National Instructional Materials Access Center. If a State educational agency chooses not to coordinate with the National Instructional Materials Access Center, such agency shall provide an assurance to the Secretary that the agency will provide instructional materials to blind persons or other persons with print disabilities in a timely manner.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da1521a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/23/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Preparation and delivery of files</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If a State educational agency chooses to coordinate with the National Instructional Materials Access Center, not later than 2 years after <date date="2004-12-03">December 3, 2004</date>, the agency, as part of any print instructional materials adoption process, procurement contract, or other practice or instrument used for purchase of print instructional materials, shall enter into a written contract with the publisher of the print instructional materials to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da1521b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/23/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> require the publisher to prepare and, on or before delivery of the print instructional materials, provide to the National Instructional Materials Access Center electronic files containing the contents of the print instructional materials using the National Instructional Materials Accessibility Standard; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da1521c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/23/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> purchase instructional materials from the publisher that are produced in, or may be rendered in, specialized formats.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da1521d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/23/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Assistive technology</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In carrying out this paragraph, the State educational agency, to the maximum extent possible, shall work collaboratively with the State agency responsible for assistive technology programs.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da1521e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/23/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In this paragraph:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0da1521f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/23/E/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> National Instructional Materials Access Center</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The term “National Instructional Materials Access Center” means the center established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1474/e">section 1474(e) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0da15220-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/23/E/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> National Instructional Materials Accessibility Standard</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The term “National Instructional Materials Accessibility Standard” has the meaning given the term in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1474/e/3/A">section 1474(e)(3)(A) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0da15221-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/23/E/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Specialized formats</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The term “specialized formats” has the meaning given the term in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1474/e/3/D">section 1474(e)(3)(D) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0da15222-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/24"><num value="24" class="bold">(24)</num><heading class="bold"> Overidentification and disproportionality</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The State has in effect, consistent with the purposes of this chapter and with <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1418/d">section 1418(d) of this title</ref>, policies and procedures designed to prevent the inappropriate overidentification or disproportionate representation by race and ethnicity of children as children with disabilities, including children with disabilities with a particular impairment described in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1401">section 1401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0da15223-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/25"><num value="25" class="bold">(25)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition on mandatory medication</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da15224-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/25/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The State educational agency shall prohibit State and local educational agency personnel from requiring a child to obtain a prescription for a substance covered by the Controlled Substances Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s801">21 U.S.C. 801</ref> et seq.) as a condition of attending school, receiving an evaluation under subsection (a) or (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1414">section 1414 of this title</ref>, or receiving services under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da15225-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/a/25/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Nothing in subparagraph (A) shall be construed to create a Federal prohibition against teachers and other school personnel consulting or sharing classroom-based observations with parents or guardians regarding a student’s academic and functional performance, or behavior in the classroom or school, or regarding the need for evaluation for special education or related services under paragraph (3).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0da15226-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> State educational agency as provider of free appropriate public education or direct services</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the State educational agency provides free appropriate public education to children with disabilities, or provides direct services to such children, such agency—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0da15227-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> shall comply with any additional requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1413/a">section 1413(a) of this title</ref>, as if such agency were a local educational agency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0da15228-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> may use amounts that are otherwise available to such agency under this subchapter to serve those children without regard to <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1413/a/2/A/i">section 1413(a)(2)(A)(i) of this title</ref> (relating to excess costs).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0da15229-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception for prior State plans</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0da1522a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If a State has on file with the Secretary policies and procedures that demonstrate that such State meets any requirement of subsection (a), including any policies and procedures filed under this subchapter as in effect before the effective date of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Improvement Act of 2004, the Secretary shall consider such State to have met such requirement for purposes of receiving a grant under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0da1522b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Modifications made by State</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (3), an application submitted by a State in accordance with this section shall remain in effect until the State submits to the Secretary such modifications as the State determines necessary. This section shall apply to a modification to an application to the same extent and in the same manner as this section applies to the original plan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0da1522c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Modifications required by the Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If, after the effective date of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Improvement Act of 2004, the provisions of this chapter are amended (or the regulations developed to carry out this chapter are amended), there is a new interpretation of this chapter by a Federal court or a State’s highest court, or there is an official finding of noncompliance with Federal law or regulations, then the Secretary may require a State to modify its application only to the extent necessary to ensure the State’s compliance with this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0da1522d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Approval by the Secretary</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0da1522e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Secretary determines that a State is eligible to receive a grant under this subchapter, the Secretary shall notify the State of that determination.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0da1522f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice and hearing</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall not make a final determination that a State is not eligible to receive a grant under this subchapter until after providing the State—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0da15230-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> with reasonable notice; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0da15231-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> with an opportunity for a hearing.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0da15232-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Assistance under other Federal programs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter permits a State to reduce medical and other assistance available, or to alter eligibility, under titles V and XIX of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s701">42 U.S.C. 701</ref> et seq., 1396 et seq.] with respect to the provision of a free appropriate public education for children with disabilities in the State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0da15233-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> By-pass for children in private schools</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0da15234-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If, on <date date="1983-12-02">December 2, 1983</date>, a State educational agency was prohibited by law from providing for the equitable participation in special programs of children with disabilities enrolled in private elementary schools and secondary schools as required by subsection (a)(10)(A), or if the Secretary determines that a State educational agency, local educational agency, or other entity has substantially failed or is unwilling to provide for such equitable participation, then the Secretary shall, notwithstanding such provision of law, arrange for the provision of services to such children through arrangements that shall be subject to the requirements of such subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0da15235-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Payments</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da15236-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/f/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination of amounts</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the Secretary arranges for services pursuant to this subsection, the Secretary, after consultation with the appropriate public and private school officials, shall pay to the provider of such services for a fiscal year an amount per child that does not exceed the amount determined by dividing—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da15237-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/f/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the total amount received by the State under this subchapter for such fiscal year; by</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0da15238-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/f/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the number of children with disabilities served in the prior year, as reported to the Secretary by the State under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1418">section 1418 of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da15239-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/f/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Withholding of certain amounts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Pending final resolution of any investigation or complaint that may result in a determination under this subsection, the Secretary may withhold from the allocation of the affected State educational agency the amount the Secretary estimates will be necessary to pay the cost of services described in subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da1523a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/f/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Period of payments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The period under which payments are made under subparagraph (A) shall continue until the Secretary determines that there will no longer be any failure or inability on the part of the State educational agency to meet the requirements of subsection (a)(10)(A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0da1523b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice and hearing</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da1523c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/f/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall not take any final action under this subsection until the State educational agency affected by such action has had an opportunity, for not less than 45 days after receiving written notice thereof, to submit written objections and to appear before the Secretary or the Secretary’s designee to show cause why such action should not be taken.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da1523d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/f/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Review of action</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If a State educational agency is dissatisfied with the Secretary’s final action after a proceeding under subparagraph (A), such agency may, not later than 60 days after notice of such action, file with the United States court of appeals for the circuit in which such State is located a petition for review of that action. A copy of the petition shall be forthwith transmitted by the clerk of the court to the Secretary. The Secretary thereupon shall file in the court the record of the proceedings on which the Secretary based the Secretary’s action, as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s2112">section 2112 of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da1523e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/f/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Review of findings of fact</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The findings of fact by the Secretary, if supported by substantial evidence, shall be conclusive, but the court, for good cause shown, may remand the case to the Secretary to take further evidence, and the Secretary may thereupon make new or modified findings of fact and may modify the Secretary’s previous action, and shall file in the court the record of the further proceedings. Such new or modified findings of fact shall likewise be conclusive if supported by substantial evidence.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0da1523f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1412/f/3/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction of court of appeals; review by United States Supreme Court</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Upon the filing of a petition under subparagraph (B), the United States court of appeals shall have jurisdiction to affirm the action of the Secretary or to set it aside, in whole or in part. The judgment of the court shall be subject to review by the Supreme Court of the United States upon certiorari or certification as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1254">section 1254 of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0da15240-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/230/tVI/s612">Pub. L. 91–230, title VI, § 612</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/108/446/tI/s101">Pub. L. 108–446, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="2004-12-03">Dec. 3, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/2676">118 Stat. 2676</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/tIX">Pub. L. 114–95, title IX</ref>, §§ 9214(d)(2), 9215(ss)(3), <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/2164">129 Stat. 2164</ref>, 2182.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0da15241-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0da15242-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id0da15243-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(11)(A)(iii), (21)(B)(v), is <ref href="/us/pl/100/77">Pub. L. 100–77</ref>, <date date="1987-07-22">July 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/482">101 Stat. 482</ref>. Subtitle B of title VII of the Act is classified generally to part B (§ 11431 et seq.) of subchapter VI of chapter 119 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s11301">section 11301 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Controlled Substances Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(25)(A), is title II of <ref href="/us/pl/91/513">Pub. L. 91–513</ref>, <date date="1970-10-27">Oct. 27, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1242">84 Stat. 1242</ref>, which is classified principally to subchapter I (§ 801 et seq.) of chapter 13 of Title 21, Food and Drugs. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s801">section 801 of Title 21</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For the effective date of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Improvement Act of 2004, referred to in subsec. (c)(1), (3), see section 302(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/108/446">Pub. L. 108–446</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1400">section 1400 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Social Security Act, referred to in subsec. (e), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/620">49 Stat. 620</ref>, as amended. Titles V and XIX of the Act are classified generally to subchapters V (§ 701 et seq.) and XIX (§ 1396 et seq.), respectively, of chapter 7 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1305">section 1305 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id0da15244-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 1412, <ref href="/us/pl/91/230/tVI/s612">Pub. L. 91–230, title VI, § 612</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/105/17/tI/s101">Pub. L. 105–17, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1997-06-04">June 4, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/60">111 Stat. 60</ref>, related to State eligibility for assistance, prior to the general amendment of subchapters I to IV of this chapter by <ref href="/us/pl/108/446">Pub. L. 108–446</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another prior section 1412, <ref href="/us/pl/91/230/tVI/s612">Pub. L. 91–230, title VI, § 612</ref>, <date date="1970-04-13">Apr. 13, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/178">84 Stat. 178</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/318/tIV/s421/b/1/C">Pub. L. 92–318, title IV, § 421(b)(1)(C)</ref>, <date date="1972-06-23">June 23, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/341">86 Stat. 341</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/380/tVI">Pub. L. 93–380, title VI</ref>, §§ 614(b), (f)(1), 615(a), title VIII, § 843(b), <date date="1974-08-21">Aug. 21, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/581">88 Stat. 581</ref>, 582, 611; <ref href="/us/pl/94/142">Pub. L. 94–142</ref>, §§ 2(a)(4), (c), (d), 5(a), <date date="1975-11-29">Nov. 29, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/773">89 Stat. 773</ref>, 774, 780; <ref href="/us/pl/98/199/s3/b">Pub. L. 98–199, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1983-12-02">Dec. 2, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1358">97 Stat. 1358</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/457/tII/s203/a">Pub. L. 99–457, title II, § 203(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-08">Oct. 8, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1158">100 Stat. 1158</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/630/tI/s102/b">Pub. L. 100–630, title I, § 102(b)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-07">Nov. 7, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3291">102 Stat. 3291</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/476/tIX/s901/b/33">Pub. L. 101–476, title IX, § 901(b)(33)</ref>–(46), (c), <date date="1990-10-30">Oct. 30, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1143">104 Stat. 1143</ref>, 1144, 1151; <ref href="/us/pl/102/119/s25/a/5">Pub. L. 102–119, § 25(a)(5)</ref>, (b), <date date="1991-10-07">Oct. 7, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/606">105 Stat. 606</ref>, 607, related to eligibility requirements, prior to the general amendment of subchapters I to IV of this chapter by <ref href="/us/pl/105/17">Pub. L. 105–17</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id0da15245-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (a)(14)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s9214/d/2/A">Pub. L. 114–95, § 9214(d)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “secondary school—” for “secondary school is highly qualified by the deadline established in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6319/a/2">section 6319(a)(2) of this title</ref>” and added cls. (i) to (iii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(14)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s9214/d/2/B">Pub. L. 114–95, § 9214(d)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “personnel who meet the applicable requirements described in this paragraph” for “highly qualified personnel”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(14)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s9214/d/2/C">Pub. L. 114–95, § 9214(d)(2)(C)</ref>, substituted “staff person to meet the applicable requirements described in this paragraph” for “staff person to be highly qualified”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(15)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s9215/ss/3/A/i">Pub. L. 114–95, § 9215(ss)(3)(A)(i)</ref>, added cl. (ii) and struck out former cl. (ii) which read as follows: “are the same as the State’s definition of adequate yearly progress, including the State’s objectives for progress by children with disabilities, under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6311/b/2/C">section 6311(b)(2)(C) of this title</ref>;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(15)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s9215/ss/3/A/ii">Pub. L. 114–95, § 9215(ss)(3)(A)(ii)</ref>, which directed substitution of “including measurements of interim progress for children with disabilities under section 6311(c)(4)(A)(i)” for “including measurable annual objectives for progress by children with disabilities under section 6311(b)(2)(C)(v)(II)”, was executed by making the substitution for “including measurable annual objectives for progress by children with disabilities under section 6311(b)(2)(C)(v)(II)(cc)”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(16)(C)(ii)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s9215/ss/3/B/i">Pub. L. 114–95, § 9215(ss)(3)(B)(i)</ref>, substituted “challenging State academic content standards under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6311/b/1">section 6311(b)(1) of this title</ref> and alternate academic achievement standards under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6311/b/1/E">section 6311(b)(1)(E) of this title</ref>” for “State’s challenging academic content standards and challenging student academic achievement standards”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(16)(C)(ii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s9215/ss/3/B/ii">Pub. L. 114–95, § 9215(ss)(3)(B)(ii)</ref>, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6311/b/1/E">section 6311(b)(1)(E) of this title</ref>,” for “the regulations promulgated to carry out <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6311/b/1">section 6311(b)(1) of this title</ref>,”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0da15246-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0da15247-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2015 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/114/95">Pub. L. 114–95</ref> effective <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, except with respect to certain noncompetitive programs and competitive programs, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s5">section 5 of Pub. L. 114–95</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6301">section 6301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
