<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0db463d3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s1682"><num value="1682">§ 1682.</num><heading> Federal administrative enforcement; report to Congressional committees</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each Federal department and agency which is empowered to extend Federal financial assistance to any education program or activity, by way of grant, loan, or contract other than a contract of insurance or guaranty, is authorized and directed to effectuate the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1681">section 1681 of this title</ref> with respect to such program or activity by issuing rules, regulations, or orders of general applicability which shall be consistent with achievement of the objectives of the statute authorizing the financial assistance in connection with which the action is taken. No such rule, regulation, or order shall become effective unless and until approved by the President. Compliance with any requirement adopted pursuant to this section may be effected (1) by the termination of or refusal to grant or to continue assistance under such program or activity to any recipient as to whom there has been an express finding on the record, after opportunity for hearing, of a failure to comply with such requirement, but such termination or refusal shall be limited to the particular political entity, or part thereof, or other recipient as to whom such a finding has been made, and shall be limited in its effect to the particular program, or part thereof, in which such noncompliance has been so found, or (2) by any other means authorized by law: <i>Provided, however</i>, That no such action shall be taken until the department or agency concerned has advised the appropriate person or persons of the failure to comply with the requirement and has determined that compliance cannot be secured by voluntary means. In the case of any action terminating, or refusing to grant or continue, assistance because of failure to comply with a requirement imposed pursuant to this section, the head of the Federal department or agency shall file with the committees of the House and Senate having legislative jurisdiction over the program or activity involved a full written report of the circumstances and the grounds for such action. No such action shall become effective until thirty days have elapsed after the filing of such report.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id0db463d4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/92/318/tIX/s902">Pub. L. 92–318, title IX, § 902</ref>, <date date="1972-06-23">June 23, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/374">86 Stat. 374</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0db463d5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id0db463d6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id0db463d7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of President relating to approval of rules, regulations, and orders of general applicability under this section, delegated to Attorney General, see section 1–102 of Ex. Ord. No. 12250, <date date="1980-11-02">Nov. 2, 1980</date>, 45 F.R. 72995, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000d–1">section 2000d–1 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
