<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0c9623a6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s226"><num value="226">§ 226.</num><heading> Cooperative public and private sector program for providing scholarships to students from the Caribbean and Central America</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c9623a7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s226/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Statement of purpose</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the purpose of this section to encourage the establishment of partnerships between State governments, universities, community colleges, and businesses to support scholarships for talented socially and economically disadvantaged students from eligible countries in the Caribbean and Central America to study in the United States in order to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0c9623a8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s226/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> improve the diversity and quality of educational opportunities for such students;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0c9623a9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s226/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> assist the development efforts of eligible countries by providing training and educational assistance to persons who can help address the social and economic needs of these countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0c9623aa-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s226/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> expand opportunities for cross-cultural studies and exchanges and improve the exchange of understanding and principles of democracy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0c9623ab-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s226/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> promote positive and productive relationships between the United States and its neighbor countries in the Caribbean and Central American regions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0c9623ac-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s226/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> give added visibility and focus to the “scholarship diplomacy” efforts of the United States Government by leveraging the monies available for this purpose through the development of partnerships among Federal, State, and local governments and the business and academic communities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0c9623ad-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s226/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> promote community involvement with the scholarship program as a tool for broadening and strengthening the “American experience” for foreign students.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c9623ae-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s226/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of scholarship program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator of the Agency for International Development shall establish and administer a program of scholarship assistance, in cooperation with State governments, universities, community colleges, and businesses, to provide scholarships to enable socially and economically disadvantaged students from eligible countries in the Caribbean and Central America to study in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c9623af-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s226/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Grants to States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out this section, the Administrator may make grants to States to provide scholarship assistance for undergraduate degree programs and for training programs of one year or longer in study areas related to the critical development needs of the students’ respective countries.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c9623b0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s226/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Agreement with States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator and each participating State shall agree on a program regarding the educational opportunities available within the State, the selection and assignment of scholarship recipients, and related issues. To the maximum extent practicable, each State shall be given flexibility in designing its program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c9623b1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s226/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Federal share for each year for which a State receives payments under this section shall be not less than 50 percent.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c9623b2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s226/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Non-Federal share</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The non-Federal share of payments under this section may be in cash, including the waiver of tuition or the offering of in-State tuition or housing waivers or subsidies, or in-kind fairly evaluated, including the provision of books or supplies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c9623b3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s226/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Forgiveness of scholarship assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The obligation of any recipient to reimburse any entity for any or all scholarship assistance provided under this section shall be forgiven upon the recipient’s prompt return to his or her country of domicile for a period which is at least one year longer than the period spent studying in the United States with scholarship assistance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c9623b4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s226/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Private sector participation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To the maximum extent practicable, each participating State shall enlist the assistance of the private sector to enable the State to meet the non-Federal share of payments under this section. Wherever appropriate, each participating State shall encourage the private sector to offer internships or other opportunities consistent with the purposes of this section to students receiving scholarships under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c9623b5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s226/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Funding</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any funds used in carrying out this section shall be derived from funds allocated for Latin American and Caribbean regional programs under chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2346">22 U.S.C. 2346</ref> and following; relating to the economic support fund).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c9623b6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s226/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0c9623b7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s226/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The term “eligible country” means any country—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0c9623b8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s226/j/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> which is receiving assistance under chapter 1 of part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> and following; relating to development assistance) or chapter 4 of part II of that Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2346">22 U.S.C. 2346</ref> and following; relating to the economic support fund); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0c9623b9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s226/j/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> which is designated by the President as a beneficiary country pursuant to the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2701">19 U.S.C. 2701</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0c9623ba-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s226/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0c9623bb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/382/tII/s231">Pub. L. 101–382, title II, § 231</ref>, <date date="1990-08-20">Aug. 20, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/661">104 Stat. 661</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0c9623bc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0c9623bd-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id0c9623be-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, referred to in subsecs. (i) and (j)(1)(A), is <ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, <date date="1961-09-04">Sept. 4, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/424">75 Stat. 424</ref>. Chapter 1 of part I and chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 are classified generally to part I (§ 2151 et seq.) of subchapter I and part IV (§ 2346 et seq.) of subchapter II, respectively, of chapter 32 of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse. For provisions deeming references to part I of subchapter I to include a reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2293">section 2293 of Title 22</ref>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2293/d/1">section 2293(d)(1) of Title 22</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">section 2151 of Title 22</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act, referred to in subsec. (j)(1)(B), is title II of <ref href="/us/pl/98/67">Pub. L. 98–67</ref>, <date date="1983-08-05">Aug. 5, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/384">97 Stat. 384</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 15 (§ 2701 et seq.) of Title 19, Customs Duties. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2701">section 2701 of Title 19</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id0c9623bf-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0c9623c0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, see note set out preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1681">section 1681 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
