<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0dc777a8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s2504"><num value="2504">§ 2504.</num><heading> Prerequisites for State participation</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any State desiring to receive the amount for which it is eligible for any fiscal year pursuant to this subchapter shall agree to submit to the Secretary of Education by <date date="1978-12-31">December 31, 1978</date>, a report on any planning undertaken pursuant to this subchapter. Such report shall be in such form as the State may desire, and may include planning proposals for—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dc777a9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s2504/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> extending career education and career development programs and services to all individuals in the State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dc777aa-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s2504/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> extending the concept of the education process beyond the school into the area of employment and community affairs, and relating the subject matter curriculums of schools to the needs of individuals to function in society;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dc777ab-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s2504/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the implementation of new concepts in career education and career development and for the replication of concepts which have demonstrated success;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dc777ac-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s2504/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the development of training programs, including inservice training programs, for teachers, counselors, other educators, and administrators;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dc777ad-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s2504/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> fostering cooperative arrangements with such community groups and agencies as the public employment services, vocational rehabilitation service, community mental health agencies, education opportunity centers, and other community resources concerned with vocational development guidance and counseling, in order to avoid unnecessary duplication in the provision of services in the community or area to be served; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dc777ae-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s2504/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> inventories of State, local, and private resources available for the development of career education and career development programs and services.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id0dc777af-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/482/tIII/s334">Pub. L. 94–482, title III, § 334</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2222">90 Stat. 2222</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/tIII/s301/a/1">Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, title V, § 507, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/677">93 Stat. 677</ref>, 692.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0dc777b0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0dc777b1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id0dc777b2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 30 days after <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, except either as specifically otherwise provided or, if not so specifically otherwise provided, effective <date date="1976-07-01">July 1, 1976</date>, where section provides for authorization of appropriations, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/482/s532">section 532 of Pub. L. 94–482</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1976 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">section 1001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id0dc777b3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Education” substituted in text for “Commissioner” pursuant to sections 301(a)(1) and 507 of <ref href="/us/pl/96/88">Pub. L. 96–88</ref>, which are classified to sections 3441(a)(1) and 3507 of this title and which transferred functions of Commissioner of Education to Secretary of Education.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
