<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0dc9c0e4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s2534"><num value="2534">§ 2534.</num><heading> Contracts and grants to States, educational agencies, etc.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0dc9c0e5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s2534/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Implementation of programs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Education is authorized, on a competitive basis, to enter into contracts and make grants to State and local educational agencies, to institutions of higher education, and to private nonprofit organizations to assist them in conducting institutes, work shops, and seminars designed to improve the professional guidance qualifications of teachers and counselors in State and local educational agencies and nonpublic elementary and secondary school systems, including opportunities for teachers and guidance counselors in such agencies and systems to obtain experience in business and industry, the professions, and other occupational pursuits, and including, for the purpose of such improvement, such programs, services, or activities which bring individuals with experience in such pursuits into schools as counselors or advisors for students, and which bring students into the workplaces of such pursuits to acquaint students with the nature of the work and to provide training for supervisory and technical personnel in such agencies and systems having responsibilities for guidance and counseling, and to improve supervisory services in the field of guidance and counseling.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0dc9c0e6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s2534/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination of programs of guidance and counseling</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Education is authorized to make grants to States to assist them in carrying out programs to coordinate new and existing programs of guidance and counseling in the States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0dc9c0e7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/482/tIII/s344">Pub. L. 94–482, title III, § 344</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2225">90 Stat. 2225</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/tIII/s301/a/1">Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, title V, § 507, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/677">93 Stat. 677</ref>, 692.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0dc9c0e8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0dc9c0e9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id0dc9c0ea-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 30 days after <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, except either as specifically otherwise provided or, if not so specifically otherwise provided, effective <date date="1976-07-01">July 1, 1976</date>, where section provides for authorization of appropriations, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/482/s532">section 532 of Pub. L. 94–482</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1976 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">section 1001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id0dc9c0eb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Education” substituted in text for “Commissioner” pursuant to sections 301(a)(1) and 507 of <ref href="/us/pl/96/88">Pub. L. 96–88</ref>, which are classified to sections 3441(a)(1) and 3507 of this title and which transferred functions of Commissioner of Education to Secretary of Education.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
