<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0dd35d8e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3402"><num value="3402">§ 3402.</num><heading> Congressional declaration of purpose</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress declares that the establishment of a Department of Education is in the public interest, will promote the general welfare of the United States, will help ensure that education issues receive proper treatment at the Federal level, and will enable the Federal Government to coordinate its education activities more effectively. Therefore, the purposes of this chapter are—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dd35d8f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3402/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to strengthen the Federal commitment to ensuring access to equal educational opportunity for every individual;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dd35d90-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3402/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to supplement and complement the efforts of States, the local school systems and other instrumentalities of the States, the private sector, public and private educational institutions, public and private nonprofit educational research institutions, community-based organizations, parents, and students to improve the quality of education;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dd35d91-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3402/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to encourage the increased involvement of the public, parents, and students in Federal education programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dd35d92-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3402/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to promote improvements in the quality and usefulness of education through federally supported research, evaluation, and sharing of information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dd35d93-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3402/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> to improve the coordination of Federal education programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dd35d94-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3402/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> to improve the management and efficiency of Federal education activities, especially with respect to the process, procedures, and administrative structures for the dispersal of Federal funds, as well as the reduction of unnecessary and duplicative burdens and constraints, including unnecessary paperwork, on the recipients of Federal funds; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dd35d95-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3402/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> to increase the accountability of Federal education programs to the President, the Congress, and the public.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id0dd35d96-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/88/tI/s102">Pub. L. 96–88, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/670">93 Stat. 670</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0dd35d97-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0dd35d98-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id0dd35d99-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/96/88">Pub. L. 96–88</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/668">93 Stat. 668</ref>, known as the Department of Education Organization Act, which enacted this chapter, amended sections 928, former 929, 1102, 2390, 2711, and 3012 of this title, <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s19">section 19 of Title 3</ref>, The President, sections 101, 5312, and 5314 to 5316 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, sections 2, 9, and 11 of the Inspector General Act of 1978, formerly set out in the Appendix to Title 5 (see <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s402">5 U.S.C. 402</ref>, 422, 424), <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s1004">section 1004 of Title 21</ref>, Food and Drugs, and sections 761b, 794c, 821, 829, 873, 879, 882, 914, and 952 of Title 29, Labor, and enacted provisions set out as notes under sections 1102 and 3401 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s3401">section 3401 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
