<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0dda8a1e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3461"><num value="3461">§ 3461.</num><heading> Officers and employees</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0dda8a1f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3461/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment and compensation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to appoint and fix the compensation of such officers and employees, including attorneys, as may be necessary to carry out the functions of the Secretary and the Department. Except as otherwise provided by law, such officers and employees shall be appointed in accordance with the civil service laws and their compensation fixed in accordance with title 5.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0dda8a20-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3461/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability of General Schedule; termination of authority; exemption from limitations on executive positions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0dda8a21-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3461/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> At the request of the Secretary, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall, under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5108">section 5108 of title 5</ref>, provide for the establishment in each of the grade levels GS–16, GS–17, and GS–18 of a number of positions in the Department equal to the number of positions in that grade level which were used primarily for the performance of functions and offices transferred under this chapter and which were assigned and filled on the day before <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0dda8a22-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3461/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/107/279/tIV/s403/3">Pub. L. 107–279, title IV, § 403(3)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-05">Nov. 5, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1985">116 Stat. 1985</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0dda8a23-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3461/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Appointments to positions provided for under this subsection may be made without regard to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3324">section 3324 of title 5</ref>, if the individual appointed in such position is an individual who is transferred in connection with the transfer of functions and offices under this chapter and, on the day preceding <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>, holds a position and has duties comparable to those of the position to which appointed hereunder.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0dda8a24-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3461/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The authority under this subsection with respect to any position shall terminate when the person first appointed to fill such position ceases to hold such position.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0dda8a25-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3461/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> For purposes of section 414(a)(3)(A) of the Civil Service Reform Act of 1978, an individual appointed under this subsection shall be deemed to occupy the same position as the individual occupied on the day preceding <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0dda8a26-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3461/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/99/498/tXIV/s1401/d">Pub. L. 99–498, title XIV, § 1401(d)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1597">100 Stat. 1597</ref></heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0dda8a27-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3461/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Senior Executive Service</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall establish positions within the Senior Executive Service for 15 limited-term appointees. The Secretary shall appoint individuals to such positions as provided by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3394">section 3394 of title 5</ref>. Such positions shall expire on the later of three years after <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>, or three years after the initial appointment to each position. Positions in effect under this subsection shall be taken into account in applying the limitations on positions prescribed under section 3134(e) and section 5108 of such title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0dda8a28-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3461/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Indian preference laws</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to prevent the application of any Indian preference law in effect on the day before <date date="1979-10-17">October 17, 1979</date>, to any function or office transferred by this chapter and subject to any such law on the day before <date date="1979-10-17">October 17, 1979</date>. Any function or office transferred by this chapter and subject to any such law shall continue to be subject to any such law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0dda8a29-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/88/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 96–88, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/681">93 Stat. 681</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/145/tXII/s1204/a/1">Pub. L. 99–145, title XII, § 1204(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/720">99 Stat. 720</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/498/tXIV/s1401/d">Pub. L. 99–498, title XIV, § 1401(d)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1597">100 Stat. 1597</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/382/tII/s271/a/3/A">Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 271(a)(3)(A)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3929">108 Stat. 3929</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/279/tIV/s403/3">Pub. L. 107–279, title IV, § 403(3)</ref>, <date date="2002-11-05">Nov. 5, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1985">116 Stat. 1985</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0dda8a2a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0dda8a2b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id0dda8a2c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 414(a)(3)(A) of the Civil Service Reform Act of 1978, referred to in subsec. (b)(5), is <ref href="/us/pl/95/454/s414/a/3/A">section 414(a)(3)(A) of Pub. L. 95–454</ref>, title IV, <date date="1978-10-13">Oct. 13, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1178">92 Stat. 1178</ref>, which is set out as a note under sections 3104 and 5108 of Title 5.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id0dda8a2d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsecs. (a) and (d), “<date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>” substituted for “the effective date of this chapter” pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/s601">section 601 of Pub. L. 96–88</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s3401">section 3401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id0dda8a2e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/107/279">Pub. L. 107–279</ref> struck out par. (2) which read as follows: “At the request of the Secretary, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall, under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3104">section 3104 of title 5</ref>, provide for the establishment in the Office created by <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s3419">section 3419 of this title</ref> of a number of scientific, professional, and technical positions outside of the General Schedule equal to the number of such positions which were used primarily for the performance of functions and offices transferred under this chapter and which were assigned and filled on the day before <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/382">Pub. L. 103–382</ref> made technical amendment to reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s3419">section 3419 of this title</ref> to reflect renumbering of corresponding section of original act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/498">Pub. L. 99–498</ref> struck out subsec. (c) which read as follows: “The Secretary may appoint, without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointment in the competitive service, up to 175 scientific, technical, or professional employees of the Office created by <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s3419">section 3419 of this title</ref> and may compensate employees so appointed without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5 relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates. The rate of basic compensation for such employees shall not be equal to or in excess of the minimum rate of pay currently paid for GS–16 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of such title.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/99/145">Pub. L. 99–145</ref> struck out subsec. (f) which deemed any reference to “civilian component” as including a reference to overseas personnel of the overseas dependents’ education system for purposes of any status of forces agreement between the United States and any other country or any international organization.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0dda8a2f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0dda8a30-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Other Laws to GS–16, 17, or 18 Pay Rates</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References in laws to the rates of pay for GS–16, 17, or 18, or to maximum rates of pay under the General Schedule, to be considered references to rates payable under specified sections of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, see section 529 [title I, § 101(c)(1)] of <ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref>, set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5376">section 5376 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
