<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0dda8a3c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3463"><num value="3463">§ 3463.</num><heading> Personnel reduction and annual limitations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0dda8a3d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3463/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Work-years limitation; allocations; adjustments</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0dda8a3e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3463/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, there shall be included in each appropriation Act containing appropriations for the administration of the Department for any fiscal year beginning after <date date="1981-09-30">September 30, 1981</date> (other than an appropriation Act containing only supplemental appropriations for the Department), an annual limitation on the total number of work-years for the personnel of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0dda8a3f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3463/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall prescribe the allocation of the work-years available under paragraph (1) among the organizational units and components of the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0dda8a40-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3463/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If the President transmits any reorganization plan under chapter 9 of title 5 which would result in the transfer of functions or offices to the Secretary or the Department, the message transmitting the plan shall include any adjustments which may be necessary in a work-year limitation established under paragraph (1) to reflect changes in the work-years required as a result of such plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0dda8a41-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3463/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Full-time equivalent personnel reductions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than the end of the first fiscal year beginning after <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>, the number of full-time equivalent personnel positions available for performing functions transferred to the Secretary or the Department by this chapter shall be reduced by 500.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0dda8a42-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3463/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Personnel computations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0dda8a43-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3463/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Computations required to be made for purposes of this section shall be made on the basis of all personnel employed by the Department, including experts and consultants employed under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3109">section 3109 of title 5</ref> and all other part-time and full-time personnel employed to perform functions of the Secretary or the Department, except personnel employed under special programs for students and disadvantaged youth (including temporary summer employment).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0dda8a44-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3463/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall, by rule, establish a method for computing work-years for personnel of the Department as described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0dda8a45-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3463/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Report on effects of reorganization on employees</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall, as soon as practicable, but not later than one year after <date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>, prepare and transmit to the Congress a report on the effects on employees of the reorganization under this chapter, which shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dda8a46-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3463/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an identification of any position within the Department or elsewhere in the executive branch, which it considers unnecessary due to consolidation of functions under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dda8a47-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3463/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a statement of the number of employees entitled to pay savings by reason of the organization under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dda8a48-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3463/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a statement of the number of employees who are voluntarily or involuntarily separated by reason of such reorganization;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dda8a49-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3463/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> an estimate of the personnel costs associated with such reorganization;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dda8a4a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3463/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the effects of such reorganization on labor management relations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dda8a4b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3463/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> such legislative and administrative recommendations for improvements in personnel management within the Department as the Director considers necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0dda8a4c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/88/tIV/s403">Pub. L. 96–88, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/682">93 Stat. 682</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/tI/s1041/a">Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1041(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/714">109 Stat. 714</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0dda8a4d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0dda8a4e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id0dda8a4f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsecs. (a) and (d), “<date date="1980-05-04">May 4, 1980</date>” substituted for “the effective date of this chapter” pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/s601">section 601 of Pub. L. 96–88</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s3401">section 3401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id0dda8a50-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/66">Pub. L. 104–66</ref> struck out before period at end “and shall, within 120 days after the enactment of an appropriation Act containing a work-year limitation, prepare and transmit to the Congress a report on such allocation. Such report shall include explanations and justifications for the allocations made by the Secretary and shall indicate the necessary personnel actions which will be required as a consequence of such allocation. Not later than 120 days after the conclusion of any fiscal year to which a work-year limitation established under paragraph (1) applies, the Secretary shall prepare and transmit to the Congress a report on compliance with such limitation indicating the total work-years actually expended by the Department and by the organizational units and components to which such work-years were allocated”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
