<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0dda8ac0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3483a"><num value="3483a">§ 3483a.</num><heading> Department of Education Nonrecurring Expenses Fund</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as the “Department of Education Nonrecurring Expenses Fund” (the Fund): <i>Provided</i>, That unobligated balances of expired discretionary funds appropriated for this or any succeeding fiscal year from the General Fund of the Treasury to the Department of Education by this or any other Act may be transferred (not later than the end of the fifth fiscal year after the last fiscal year for which such funds are available for the purposes for which appropriated) into the Fund: <i>Provided further</i>, That amounts deposited in the Fund shall be available until expended, and in addition to such other funds as may be available for such purposes, for information and business technology system modernization and facilities infrastructure improvements necessary for the operation of the Department, subject to approval by the Office of Management and Budget: <i>Provided further</i>, That amounts in the Fund may be obligated only after the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate are notified at least 30 days in advance of the specific information and business technology system modernization project or facility infrastructure improvement obligations planned for such amounts.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id0dda8ac1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dH/tIII/s313">Pub. L. 116–260, div. H, title III, § 313</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/1609">134 Stat. 1609</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0dda8ac2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0dda8ac3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id0dda8ac4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in text, is div. H of <ref href="/us/pl/116/260">Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/1547">134 Stat. 1547</ref>, known as the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2021. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id0dda8ac5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Department of Education Appropriations Act, 2021, and not as part of the Department of Education Organization Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
