<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0ddf45cf-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3913"><num value="3913">§ 3913.</num><heading> Teacher institutes</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0ddf45d0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3913/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization to make competitive grants; covered institutions, businesses, etc.; purpose</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Foundation shall, in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter, make competitive grants to institutions of higher education, businesses, nonprofit private organizations (including schools), local education agencies, professional engineering and scientific associations, museums, libraries, public broadcasting entities (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s397/11">section 397(11) of title 47</ref>), and appropriate State agencies to support institutes and workshops for supervisors and teachers in public and private elementary and secondary schools for the purpose of improving the subject knowledge and teaching skills of such teachers in the areas of mathematics and science.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0ddf45d1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3913/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Equitable distribution of grants; awards in each State</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In making grants under this section, the Foundation shall assure that there is an equitable distribution among States of institutes established and operated with funds made available under this section. The Foundation shall award not less than one institute in each State, except that the Foundation may waive this requirement if there is no proposal from a State which meets the requirements of this subchapter. Proposals which exceed $300,000 in any fiscal year incorporating the services or resources of more than two entities in the design and operation of the institute, may be funded at the discretion of the Director of the Foundation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0de18ec2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3913/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Cooperation of advanced technology businesses and other businesses</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Institutes assisted under this subchapter may, to the extent possible, involve the cooperation of advanced technology businesses and other businesses which are able to supply assistance in the teaching of mathematics and science.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0de18ec3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s3913/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement of involvement in planning and development</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In making grants under this subchapter, the Foundation shall require assurances that local education agencies will be involved in the planning and development of the institute in the case of applications submitted by other eligible applicants described in subsection (a) of this section, or that one or more such applicants will be involved in the planning and development of the institute in the case of applications submitted by State or local education agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0de18ec4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/377/tI/s103">Pub. L. 98–377, title I, § 103</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/159/tII/s201">Pub. L. 99–159, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1985-11-22">Nov. 22, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/894">99 Stat. 894</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0de18ec5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0de18ec6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id0de18ec7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 3913, <ref href="/us/pl/98/377/tI/s113">Pub. L. 98–377, title I, § 113</ref>, Aug., 11, 1984, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1269">98 Stat. 1269</ref>, related to distribution of assistance and limitation on grants, prior to the general revision of this subchapter by <ref href="/us/pl/99/159/s201">section 201 of Pub. L. 99–159</ref>. See subsec. (b) of this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
