<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0de40056-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4016"><num value="4016">§ 4016.</num><heading> Annual report</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">During each calendar year until 1999, the Administrator shall prepare and submit, not later than June 1 of each year, to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report on the loan and grant program authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s4014">section 4014 of this title</ref>.</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0de40057-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4016/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> describe the number of applications received;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0de40058-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4016/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> describe the number of loans and grants made in the preceding calendar year and specify each applicant for and recipient of a loan or grant;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0de40059-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4016/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> specify the number of loan or grant applications which were disapproved during the preceding calendar year and describe the reasons for such disapprovals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0de4005a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4016/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> describe the types of programs for which loans or grants were made;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0de4005b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4016/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> specify the estimated total costs of such programs to the recipients of loans or grants and specify the amount of loans or grants made under the program authorized by this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0de4005c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4016/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> estimate the number of schools still in need of assistance and the amount of resources needed by such schools, categorized by State, to abate all remaining asbestos hazards.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id0de4005d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/377/tV/s507">Pub. L. 98–377, title V, § 507</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1293">98 Stat. 1293</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/637">Pub. L. 101–637</ref>, §§ 8, 14(a)(7), <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4592">104 Stat. 4592</ref>, 4594.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0de4005e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0de4005f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id0de40060-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—<ref href="/us/pl/101/637/s14/a/7">Pub. L. 101–637, § 14(a)(7)</ref>, made technical amendment to section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/637/s8/a">Pub. L. 101–637, § 8(a)</ref>, amended first sentence generally. Prior to amendment, first sentence read as follows: “During each of the ten calendar years after 1984, the Administrator shall prepare and submit not later than February 1 of each year a report to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the United States Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the United States House of Representatives on the loan and grant program authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s4014">section 4014 of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (6). <ref href="/us/pl/101/637/s8/b">Pub. L. 101–637, § 8(b)</ref>, inserted before period at end “and the amount of resources needed by such schools, categorized by State, to abate all remaining asbestos hazards”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0de40061-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id0de40062-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Commerce of House of Representatives by <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/a">section 1(a) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress. Committee on Commerce of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives, and jurisdiction over matters relating to securities and exchanges and insurance generally transferred to Committee on Financial Services of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Seventh Congress, <date date="2001-01-03">Jan. 3, 2001</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
