<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0de40097-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4021"><num value="4021">§ 4021.</num><heading> Authorization</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0de40098-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4021/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount; availability until expended</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0de40099-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4021/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> There are hereby authorized to be appropriated for the asbestos abatement program not more than $200,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1991, 1992, 1993, 1994, and 1995. In addition, for such purposes and for each of such fiscal years there are authorized to be appropriated out of the Asbestos Trust Fund established by <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s4022">section 4022 of this title</ref> such sums as are contained in such trust fund in each of such fiscal years.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0de4009a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4021/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The sums appropriated under this subchapter shall remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0de4009b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4021/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Minimum State amount; fiscal year obligation requirement; reserved funds for administration and asbestos abatement oriented program expenditures; appropriations out of Asbestos Trust Fund</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0de4009c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4021/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A State with qualified applicants shall receive no less than one-half of 1 per centum of the sums appropriated under this subchapter or the total of the amounts requested by such applicants, whichever is less. Those amounts available in each fiscal year under this paragraph shall be obligated before the end of that fiscal year. For the purposes of this paragraph the term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Bureau of Indian Affairs and, taken together, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the Northern Mariana Islands, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0de4009d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4021/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Of those sums appropriated for the implementation of this subchapter, not more than 5 percent may be reserved during each fiscal year for the administration of this subchapter and for programs including (but not limited to) the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0de4009e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4021/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The establishment of training centers for contractors, engineers, school employees, parents, and other personnel to provide instruction, in accordance with title II of the Toxic Substances Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2641">15 U.S.C. 2641</ref> et seq.), on asbestos assessment and abatement.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0de4009f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4021/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The development and dissemination of abatement guidance documents to assist in evaluation of potential hazards and the determination of proper abatement programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0de400a0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4021/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The development of rules and regulations regarding inspection, reporting, and recordkeeping.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0de400a1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4021/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The development of a comprehensive testing and technical assistance program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0de400a2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4021/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Of those sums appropriated for any fiscal year for the implementation of this subchapter, the Administrator may use not more than 5 percent to provide grants to States for the following purposes:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0de400a3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4021/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Assisting local educational agencies in performing the periodic reinspections and training activities required under title II of the Toxic Substances Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2641">15 U.S.C. 2641</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0de400a4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4021/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Establishing and maintaining programs to accredit personnel performing asbestos inspections and response actions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0de400a5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/377/tV/s512">Pub. L. 98–377, title V, § 512</ref>, <date date="1984-08-11">Aug. 11, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1295">98 Stat. 1295</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/519/s4/a">Pub. L. 99–519, § 4(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2989">100 Stat. 2989</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/368/s6/a">Pub. L. 100–368, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-07-18">July 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/833">102 Stat. 833</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/637">Pub. L. 101–637</ref>, §§ 11, 14(a)(12), <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4592">104 Stat. 4592</ref>, 4595.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0de400a6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0de400a7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id0de400a8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Toxic Substances Control Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(2)(A), (3)(A), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/469">Pub. L. 94–469</ref>, <date date="1976-10-11">Oct. 11, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2003">90 Stat. 2003</ref>. Title II of the Act, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/99/519/s2">Pub. L. 99–519, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2970">100 Stat. 2970</ref>, is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 2641 et seq.) of chapter 53 of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s2601">section 2601 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id0de400a9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—<ref href="/us/pl/101/637/s14/a/12">Pub. L. 101–637, § 14(a)(12)</ref>, inserted section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/637/s11/a">Pub. L. 101–637, § 11(a)</ref>, amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “There are hereby authorized to be appropriated for the asbestos abatement program not more than $50,000,000 for the fiscal year ending on <date date="1984-09-30">September 30, 1984</date>, $50,000,000 for the fiscal year ending on <date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>, and $100,000,000 for each of the five succeeding fiscal years. In addition, for such purposes there are authorized to be appropriated out of the Asbestos Trust Fund established by <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s4022">section 4022 of this title</ref> $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1987, 1988, 1989, and 1990.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/637/s11/b">Pub. L. 101–637, § 11(b)</ref>, added par. (2) and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows: “Of those sums appropriated for the implementation of this subchapter, up to 10 per centum shall be reserved during the fiscal year ending <date date="1984-09-30">September 30, 1984</date>, and up to 5 per centum for the fiscal year ending <date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>, for the administration of this subchapter and for programs including, but not limited to, the following:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) the establishment of a training center for contractors, engineers, school employees, parents and other personnel to provide instruction on asbestos assessment and abatement;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) the development and dissemination of abatement guidance documents to assist in evaluation of potential hazards, and the determination of proper abatement programs;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) the development of rules and regulations regarding inspection, reporting and record-keeping; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(D) the development of a comprehensive testing and technical assistance program.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/101/637/s11/b">Pub. L. 101–637, § 11(b)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/368">Pub. L. 100–368</ref> moved last sentence (as added by <ref href="/us/pl/98/377">Pub. L. 98–377</ref>) to end of subsec. (a)(1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—<ref href="/us/pl/99/519">Pub. L. 99–519</ref> inserted sentence at end authorizing appropriations out of the Asbestos Trust Fund for years 1987, 1988, 1989, and 1990.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id0de400aa-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0de400ab-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, see note set out preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1681">section 1681 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
