<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0de671b8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4332"><num value="4332">§ 4332.</num><heading> Agreement for National Technical Institute for the Deaf</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0de671b9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4332/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> General authority</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0de671ba-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4332/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary is authorized to establish or continue an agreement with an institution of higher education for the establishment and operation, including construction and equipment, of a National Technical Institute for the Deaf.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0de671bb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4332/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Secretary and the institution of higher education with which the Secretary has an agreement under this section—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0de671bc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4332/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall periodically assess the need for modification of the agreement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0de671bd-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4332/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall periodically update the agreement as determined necessary by the Secretary or the institution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0de671be-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4332/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Provisions of agreement</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The agreement shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0de671bf-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4332/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> provide that Federal funds appropriated for the benefit of NTID will be used only for the purposes for which appropriated and in accordance with the applicable provisions of this chapter and the agreement made pursuant thereto;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0de671c0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4332/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> provide that the Board of Trustees or other governing body of the institution, subject to the approval of the Secretary, will appoint an advisory group to advise the Director of NTID in formulating and carrying out the basic policies governing its establishment and operation, which group shall include individuals who are professionally concerned with education and technical training at the postsecondary school level, persons who are professionally concerned with activities relating to education and training of individuals who are deaf, and members of the public familiar with the need for services provided by NTID;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0de671c1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4332/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> provide that the Board of Trustees or other governing body of the institution will prepare and submit to the Secretary, not later than June 1 following the fiscal year for which the report is submitted, an annual report containing an accounting of all indirect costs paid to the institution of higher education under the agreement with the Secretary, which accounting the Secretary shall transmit to the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives and to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, with such comments and recommendations as the Secretary may deem appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0de671c2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4332/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> include such other conditions as the Secretary deems necessary to carry out the purposes of this part;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0de671c3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4332/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> provide that any laborer or mechanic employed by any contractor or subcontractor in the performance of work on any construction aided by Federal funds appropriated for the benefit of NTID will be paid wages at rates not less than those prevailing on similar construction in the locality as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with subchapter IV of chapter 31 of title 40, commonly referred to as the Davis-Bacon Act; except that the Secretary of Labor shall have, with respect to the labor standards specified in this paragraph, the authority and functions set forth in Reorganization Plan Numbered 14 of 1950 (5 U.S.C. App.) and <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s3145">section 3145 of title 40</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0de671c4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4332/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> establish a policy of outreach and recruitment to employ and advance in employment qualified individuals with disabilities, particularly individuals who are deaf or hard of hearing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0de671c5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4332/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If, within twenty years after the completion of any construction (except minor remodeling or alteration) for which such funds have been paid—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0de671c6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4332/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the facility ceases to be used for the purposes for which it was constructed or the agreement is terminated, unless the Secretary determines that there is good cause for releasing the institution from its obligation, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0de671c7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4332/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the institution ceases to be the owner of the facility,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the United States shall be entitled to recover from the applicant or other owner of the facility an amount which has the same ratio with respect to the current market value of the facility as the amount of Federal funds expended for construction of such facility bears to the total cost of construction of the facility. The current market value of the facility shall be determined by agreement of the parties or by action brought in the United States district court for the district in which the facility is situated.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0de671c8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/371/tI/s112">Pub. L. 99–371, title I, § 112</ref>, formerly title II, § 202, <date date="1986-08-04">Aug. 4, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/785">100 Stat. 785</ref>; renumbered title I, § 112, and amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/421/tI">Pub. L. 102–421, title I</ref>, §§ 101(b)(3), (4), 121, 151(a)(4), <date date="1992-10-16">Oct. 16, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2151">106 Stat. 2151</ref>, 2155, 2164; <ref href="/us/pl/103/73/tII">Pub. L. 103–73, title II</ref>, §§ 202, 203(g), <date date="1993-08-11">Aug. 11, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/732">107 Stat. 732</ref>, 734; <ref href="/us/pl/105/244/tIX/s914">Pub. L. 105–244, title IX, § 914</ref>, <date date="1998-10-07">Oct. 7, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1830">112 Stat. 1830</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/tIX/s903">Pub. L. 110–315, title IX, § 903</ref>, <date date="2008-08-14">Aug. 14, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3451">122 Stat. 3451</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0de671c9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0de671ca-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id0de671cb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reorganization Plan Numbered 14 of 1950, referred to in subsec. (b)(5), is set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id0de671cc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to this section were contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s684">section 684 of this title</ref> prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/99/371">Pub. L. 99–371</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id0de671cd-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s903/1">Pub. L. 110–315, § 903(1)</ref>, struck out at end “The Secretary, in considering proposals from institutions of higher education to enter into an agreement under this part, shall give preference to institutions which are located in metropolitan industrial areas.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s903/2/A">Pub. L. 110–315, § 903(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate” for “Committee on Labor and Human Resources of the Senate”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/110/315/s903/2/B">Pub. L. 110–315, § 903(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “subchapter IV of chapter 31 of title 40, commonly referred to as the Davis-Bacon Act” for “the Act of <date date="1931-03-03">March 3, 1931</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s276a">40 U.S.C. 276a</ref>—276a–5) commonly referred to as the Davis-Bacon Act” and “<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s3145">section 3145 of title 40</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-13/s2">section 2 of the Act of June 13, 1934</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s276c">40 U.S.C. 276c</ref>)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/244">Pub. L. 105–244</ref> amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “The Secretary and the institution of higher education with which the Secretary has an agreement under this section shall, within 1 year after <date date="1992-10-16">October 16, 1992</date>, assess the need for modification of the agreement. The Secretary and the institution of higher education with which the Secretary has an agreement under this section shall also periodically update the agreement as determined to be necessary by the Secretary or the institution.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—<ref href="/us/pl/103/73/s203/g/1">Pub. L. 103–73, § 203(g)(1)</ref>, substituted “National Technical Institute for the Deaf” for “Institute” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/73/s203/g/2/A">Pub. L. 103–73, § 203(g)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “part” for “chapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/73/s203/g/2/B">Pub. L. 103–73, § 203(g)(2)(B)</ref>, in first sentence struck out comma after “The Secretary” and after “this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1), (2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/73/s202">Pub. L. 103–73, § 202</ref>, substituted “NTID” for “the Institute” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/103/73/s203/g/3/A">Pub. L. 103–73, § 203(g)(3)(A)</ref>, substituted “Secretary, not later than June 1 following the fiscal year for which the report is submitted, an annual report containing” for “Secretary an annual report, including”, “which accounting” for “which report”, and “Representatives” for “Representatives,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/103/73/s203/g/3/B">Pub. L. 103–73, § 203(g)(3)(B)</ref>, struck out “and” at end of par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/103/73/s203/g/3/C">Pub. L. 103–73, § 203(g)(3)(C)</ref>, substituted “except that the Secretary” for “and the Secretary” and “; and” for period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/73/s202">Pub. L. 103–73, § 202</ref>, substituted “NTID” for “the Institute”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/103/73/s203/g/3/D">Pub. L. 103–73, § 203(g)(3)(D)</ref>, substituted “or hard of hearing” for “or individuals who are hard of hearing”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/73/s203/g/4">Pub. L. 103–73, § 203(g)(4)</ref>, inserted a comma after “If”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/421/s121/1">Pub. L. 102–421, § 121(1)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/421/s151/a/4">Pub. L. 102–421, § 151(a)(4)</ref>, substituted “individuals who are deaf” for “the deaf”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/102/421/s121/2">Pub. L. 102–421, § 121(2)</ref>, substituted “will prepare and submit to the Secretary an annual report, including an accounting of all indirect costs paid to the institution of higher education under the agreement with the Secretary, which report the Secretary shall transmit to the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives, and to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources of the Senate,” for “will make an annual report together with an accounting of all indirect costs paid to the institution of higher education under the agreement to the Secretary, which the Secretary shall transmit to the Congress”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/102/421/s121/3">Pub. L. 102–421, § 121(3)</ref>, added par. (6).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0de671ce-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id0de671cf-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Education and Labor of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Education and the Workforce of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Eighteenth Congress, <date date="2023-01-09">Jan. 9, 2023</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0de671d0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/244">Pub. L. 105–244</ref> effective <date date="1998-10-01">Oct. 1, 1998</date>, except as otherwise provided in <ref href="/us/pl/105/244">Pub. L. 105–244</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/244/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 105–244</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">section 1001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0de671d1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/421">Pub. L. 102–421</ref> effective <date date="1992-10-01">Oct. 1, 1992</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/421/s161">section 161 of Pub. L. 102–421</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s4301">section 4301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0de671d2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Establishment of Institute</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Pursuant to an agreement entered into between the Secretary and the Rochester Institute of Technology on <date date="1966-12-20">Dec. 20, 1966</date>, the National Technical Institute for the Deaf (N.T.I.D.) was established and located at Rochester, New York.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
