<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0ded9cc8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4421"><num value="4421">§ 4421.</num><heading> Transfer of functions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0ded9cc9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4421/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Institute of American Indian Arts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are hereby transferred to the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Art Development, and such Institute shall perform, the functions of the Institute of American Indian Arts established by the Secretary in 1962.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0ded9cca-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4421/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain matters relating to transferred functions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0ded9ccb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4421/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Subject to subsection (d), all personnel, liabilities, contracts, real property (including the collections of the museum located on the site known as the “Santa Fe Indian School” but not the museum building), personal property, assets, and records as are determined by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to be employed, held, or used primarily in connection with any function transferred under the provisions of this chapter (regardless of the administrative entity providing the services on the date before the transfer) shall be transferred to the Institute.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0ded9ccc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4421/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Personnel engaged in functions transferred by this chapter shall be transferred in accordance with applicable laws and regulations relating to the transfer of functions, except that such transfer shall be without reduction in classification or compensation for one year after such transfer.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0ded9ccd-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4421/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> References in other laws</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All laws and regulations relating to the Institute of American Indian Arts established by the Secretary in 1962 shall, insofar as such laws and regulations are appropriate, and not inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter, remain in full force and effect and apply with respect to the Institute. All references in any other Federal law to the Institute of American Indian Arts, or any officer transferred to the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development under subsection (b), shall be deemed to refer to the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development or an officer of the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0ded9cce-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4421/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Forgiveness of amounts owed; hold harmless</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0ded9ccf-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4421/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Subject to paragraph (2)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0ded9cd0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4421/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Institute shall be responsible for all obligations of the Institute incurred after <date date="1988-06-02">June 2, 1988</date>, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0ded9cd1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4421/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Secretary shall be responsible for all obligations of the Institute incurred on or before <date date="1988-06-02">June 2, 1988</date>, including those which accrued by reason of any statutory, contractual, or other reason prior to <date date="1988-06-02">June 2, 1988</date>, which became payable within two years of <date date="1988-06-02">June 2, 1988</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0ded9cd2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s4421/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> With respect to all programs of the Federal Government, in whatever form or from whatever source derived, the Institute shall only be held responsible for actions and requirements, either administrative, regulatory, or statutory in nature, for events which occurred after <date date="1988-07-01">July 1, 1988</date>, including the submission of reports, audits, and other required information. The United States may not seek any monetary damages or repayment for the commission of events, or omission to comply with either administrative or regulatory requirements, for any action which occurred prior to <date date="1988-06-02">June 2, 1988</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0ded9cd3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/498/tXV/s1514">Pub. L. 99–498, title XV, § 1514</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1608">100 Stat. 1608</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/153/s8">Pub. L. 100–153, § 8</ref>, <date date="1987-11-05">Nov. 5, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/887">101 Stat. 887</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/297/tV/s5406/d">Pub. L. 100–297, title V, § 5406(d)</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/418">102 Stat. 418</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/644/tV/s503">Pub. L. 101–644, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="1990-11-29">Nov. 29, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4669">104 Stat. 4669</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/325/tXIII/s1331/f">Pub. L. 102–325, title XIII, § 1331(f)</ref>, <date date="1992-07-23">July 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/807">106 Stat. 807</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0ded9cd4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0ded9cd5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id0ded9cd6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/325/s1331/f/1">Pub. L. 102–325, § 1331(f)(1)</ref>, substituted “Subject to subsection (d), all personnel” for “All personnel”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/102/325/s1331/f/2">Pub. L. 102–325, § 1331(f)(2)</ref>, substituted “monetary damages” for “monetary damage”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/644/s503">Pub. L. 101–644, § 503</ref>, added subsec. (d) and struck out former subsec. (d) which read as follows: “Unless the Board provides otherwise, the Secretary of the Interior shall, until <date date="1989-10-01">October 1, 1989</date>, provide such technical and support assistance to the Institute as the Secretary determines reasonable or necessary to assist the Institute. Such assistance shall include audit, accounting, computer services, and building and maintenance services.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e), (f). <ref href="/us/pl/101/644/s503/1">Pub. L. 101–644, § 503(1)</ref>, struck out subsec. (e) which related to completion of transfers, final date of control of Institute by Secretary, payment of unexpended or unobligated funds, and responsibility for subsequently incurred obligations, and subsec. (f) which related to contract with University of New Mexico, terms of contract, and composition of advisory council.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (e)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/100/297">Pub. L. 100–297</ref> added pars. (3) and (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/100/153/s8/1">Pub. L. 100–153, § 8(1)</ref>, (2), substituted “Unless the Board provides otherwise” for “During the 2-year period beginning on the date referred to in subsection (f) of this section” and inserted “, until <date date="1989-10-01">October 1, 1989</date>,” after “Secretary of the Interior shall”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/100/153/s8/3">Pub. L. 100–153, § 8(3)</ref>, added subsec. (e) and struck out former subsec. (e) which read as follows: “During the period beginning on <date date="1986-10-17">October 17, 1986</date>, and ending on the date referred to in subsection (f) of this section, the Advisory Board for Institute of American Indian Arts shall continue to act in an advisory role for the Board and the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/100/153/s8/3">Pub. L. 100–153, § 8(3)</ref>, added subsec. (f) and struck out former subsec. (f) which read as follows: “The provisions of this section (other than subsection (e) of this section) shall take effect on <date date="1986-10-01">October 1, 1986</date>.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0ded9cd7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0ded9cd8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/325">Pub. L. 102–325</ref> effective <date date="1992-10-01">Oct. 1, 1992</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/325/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 102–325</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">section 1001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0ded9cd9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date and applicability of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/297">Pub. L. 100–297</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/297/s6303">section 6303 of Pub. L. 100–297</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1071">section 1071 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
