<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0c772939-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s59"><num value="59">§ 59.</num><heading> Collections of National Ocean Survey, United States Geological Survey, and others deposited in National Museum</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All collections of rocks, minerals, soils, fossils, and objects of natural history, archaeology, and ethnology, made by the National Ocean Survey, the United States Geological Survey, or by any other parties for the Government of the United States, when no longer needed for investigations in progress shall be deposited in the National Museum.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id0c77293a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/act/1879-03-03/ch182/s1">Mar. 3, 1879, ch. 182, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/20/394">20 Stat. 394</ref>; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1318">79 Stat. 1318</ref>; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref href="/us/stat/84/2090">84 Stat. 2090</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/154/tI">Pub. L. 102–154, title I</ref>, <date date="1991-11-13">Nov. 13, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1000">105 Stat. 1000</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0c77293b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0c77293c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id0c77293d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Words “Coast and Interior Survey” appearing in act <date date="1879-03-03">Mar. 3, 1879</date>, were in prior editions of the Code changed to “Coast and Geodetic Survey.” Congress never created a Coast and Interior Survey. In a communication dated <date date="1940-11-06">Nov. 6, 1940</date>, the Director of the Geological Survey explained that the words “Coast and Interior Survey” were inadvertently incorporated upon authority of report contained in Senate Misc. Doc. No. 9, 45th Congress, 3d Session, which recommended the “Coast and Geodetic Survey” be changed to “United States Coast and Interior Survey” and an organization be created in the Interior Department to be known as the “United States Geological Survey.” Congress adopted only the latter suggestion.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0c77293e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id0c77293f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“United States Geological Survey” substituted in text for “Geological Survey” pursuant to provision of title I of <ref href="/us/pl/102/154">Pub. L. 102–154</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s31">section 31 of Title 43</ref>, Public Lands.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0c772940-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">National Museum</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Establishment of the National Museum, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s50">section 50 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0c772941-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">National Museum of American History</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/441/s2">Pub. L. 96–441, § 2</ref>, <date date="1980-10-13">Oct. 13, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1884">94 Stat. 1884</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/441/s2">“The bureau of the Smithsonian Institution known as the Museum of History and Technology and so referred to in the Act entitled ‘An Act to authorize the construction of a building for a Museum of History and Technology for the Smithsonian Institution, including the preparation of plans and specifications, and all other work incidental thereto’, approved <date date="1955-06-28">June 28, 1955</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s59">20 U.S.C. 59</ref> note), shall be known as the ‘National Museum of American History’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provision deeming references to the Museum of History and Technology in laws and regulations to be references to the National Museum of American History, see section of 3 of <ref href="/us/pl/96/441">Pub. L. 96–441</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s71">section 71 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0c772942-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Museum of History and Technology for the Smithsonian Institution</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1955-06-28/ch201">Act June 28, 1955, ch. 201</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/189">69 Stat. 189</ref>, authorized construction of a building for a Museum of History and Technology, which was redesignated the National Museum of American History, for the use of the Smithsonian Institution, at a cost not to exceed $36,000,000.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id0c772943-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id0c772944-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Coast and Geodetic Survey consolidated with National Weather Bureau in 1965 to form Environmental Science Services Administration by Reorg. Plan No. 2 of 1965, eff. <date date="1965-07-13">July 13, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 8819, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1318">79 Stat. 1318</ref>. Environmental Science Services Administration abolished in 1970 and its personnel, property, records, etc., transferred to National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration by Reorg. Plan No. 4 of 1970, eff. <date date="1970-10-03">Oct. 3, 1970</date>, 35 F.R. 15627, <ref href="/us/stat/84/2090">84 Stat. 2090</ref>. By order of Acting Associate Administrator of National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, 35 F.R. 19249, <date date="1970-12-19">Dec. 19, 1970</date>, Coast and Geodetic Survey redesignated National Ocean Survey. See notes set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s311">section 311 of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
