<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0dfbcd28-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s5964"><num value="5964">§ 5964.</num><heading> Applications and plans</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0dfbcd29-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s5964/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Application</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to receive a grant under this subchapter, an eligible local educational agency shall submit to the Secretary an application that includes—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dfbcd2a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s5964/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an assessment of the current violence and crime problems in the schools to be served by the grant and in the community to be served by the applicant;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dfbcd2b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s5964/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> an assurance that the applicant has written policies regarding school safety, student discipline, and the appropriate handling of violent or disruptive acts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dfbcd2c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s5964/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a description of the schools and communities to be served by the grant, the activities and projects to be carried out with grant funds, and how these activities and projects will help to reduce the current violence and crime problems in the schools and communities served;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dfbcd2d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s5964/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> a description of educational materials to be developed in the first most predominate non-English language of the schools and communities to be served by the grant, if applicable;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dfbcd2e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s5964/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> if the local educational agency receives Federal education funds, an explanation of how activities assisted under this subchapter will be coordinated with and support any systemic education improvement plan prepared with such funds;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dfbcd2f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s5964/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> the applicant’s plan to establish school-level advisory committees, which include faculty, parents, staff, and students, for each school to be served by the grant and a description of how each committee will assist in assessing that school’s violence and discipline problems as well as in designing appropriate programs, policies, and practices to combat such problems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dfbcd30-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s5964/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> the applicant’s plan for collecting baseline and future data, by individual schools, to monitor violence and discipline problems and to measure the applicant’s progress in achieving the purpose of this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dfbcd31-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s5964/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> a description of how, in subsequent fiscal years, the grantee will integrate the violence prevention activities the grantee carries out with funds under this subchapter with activities carried out under the grantee’s comprehensive plan for drug and violence prevention adopted under the Drug-Free Schools and Communities Act of 1986;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dfbcd32-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s5964/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> a description of how the grantee will coordinate the grantee’s school crime and violence prevention efforts with education, law enforcement, judicial, health, and social service programs supported under the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t34/s11101">34 U.S.C. 11101</ref> et seq.], and other appropriate agencies and organizations serving the community;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dfbcd33-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s5964/a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> a description of how the grantee will inform parents about the extent of crime and violence in their children’s schools and maximize the participation of parents in the grantee’s violence prevention activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dfbcd34-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s5964/a/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> an assurance that grant funds under this subchapter will be used to supplement and not supplant State and local funds that would, in the absence of funds under this subchapter, be made available by the applicant for the purposes of the grant;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dfbcd35-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s5964/a/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> an assurance that the applicant will cooperate with, and provide assistance to, the Secretary in gathering statistics and other data the Secretary determines are necessary to determine the effectiveness of projects and activities assisted under this subchapter or the extent of school violence and discipline problems throughout the Nation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0dfbcd36-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s5964/a/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> such other information as the Secretary may require.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0dfbcd37-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s5964/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to receive funds under this subchapter for a second year, a grantee shall submit to the Secretary a comprehensive, long-term, school safety plan for reducing and preventing school violence and discipline problems. Such plan shall contain a description of how the grantee will coordinate the grantee’s school crime and violence prevention efforts with education, law-enforcement, judicial, health, social service, and other appropriate agencies and organizations serving the community.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0dfbcd38-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/227/tVII/s704">Pub. L. 103–227, title VII, § 704</ref>, <date date="1994-03-31">Mar. 31, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/205">108 Stat. 205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0dfbcd39-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0dfbcd3a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id0dfbcd3b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Drug-Free Schools and Communities Act of 1986, referred to in subsec. (a)(8), is title V of <ref href="/us/pl/89/10">Pub. L. 89–10</ref> as added by <ref href="/us/pl/100/297/tI/s1001">Pub. L. 100–297, title I, § 1001</ref>, <date date="1988-04-28">Apr. 28, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/252">102 Stat. 252</ref>, which was classified generally to subchapter V (§ 3171 et seq.) of chapter 47 of this title, prior to the general amendment of <ref href="/us/pl/89/10">Pub. L. 89–10</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/103/382/tI/s101">Pub. L. 103–382, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3519">108 Stat. 3519</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (a)(9), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/415">Pub. L. 93–415</ref>, <date date="1974-09-07">Sept. 7, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1109">88 Stat. 1109</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 111 (§ 11101 et seq.) of Title 34, Crime Control and Law Enforcement. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1974 Act note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10101">section 10101 of Title 34</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
