<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0e13c28c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434"><num value="6434">§ 6434.</num><heading> State plan and State agency applications</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e13c28d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> State plan</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e13c28e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each State educational agency that desires to receive a grant under this subpart shall submit, for approval by the Secretary, a plan—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e13c28f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> for meeting the educational needs of neglected, delinquent, and at-risk children and youth;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e13c290-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> for assisting in the transition of children and youth between correctional facilities and locally operated programs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e13c291-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> that is integrated with other programs under this chapter or other Acts, as appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e13c292-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each such State plan shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e13c293-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> describe the program objectives and outcomes established by the State that will be used to assess the effectiveness of the program in improving the academic, career, and technical skills of children in the program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e13c294-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provide that, to the extent feasible, such children will have the same opportunities to achieve as such children would have if such children were in the schools of local educational agencies in the State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e13c295-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> describe how the State will place a priority for such children to attain a regular high school diploma, to the extent feasible;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e13c296-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> contain an assurance that the State educational agency will—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e13c297-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/a/2/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> ensure that programs assisted under this subpart will be carried out in accordance with the State plan described in this subsection; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e13c298-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/a/2/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> ensure that the State agencies receiving subgrants under this subpart comply with all applicable statutory and regulatory requirements; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e13c299-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/a/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><chapeau> provide assurances that the State educational agency has established—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e13c29a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/a/2/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> procedures to ensure the timely re-enrollment of each student who has been placed in the juvenile justice system in secondary school or in a re-entry program that best meets the needs of the student, including the transfer of credits that such student earns during placement; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e13c29b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/a/2/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> opportunities for such students to participate in credit-bearing coursework while in secondary school, postsecondary education, or career and technical education programming.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e13c29c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Duration of the plan</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each such State plan shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e13c29d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> remain in effect for the duration of the State’s participation under this part; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e13c29e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> be periodically reviewed and revised by the State, as necessary, to reflect changes in the State’s strategies and programs under this part.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e13c29f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretarial approval and peer review</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e13c2a0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretarial approval</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall approve each State plan that meets the requirements of this subpart.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e13c2a1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Peer review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may review any State plan with the assistance and advice of individuals with relevant expertise.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e13c2a2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> State agency applications</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any State agency that desires to receive funds to carry out a program under this subpart shall submit an application to the State educational agency that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e13c2a3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> describes the procedures to be used, consistent with the State plan under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6311">section 6311 of this title</ref>, to assess the educational needs of the children to be served under this subpart and, to the extent practicable, provide for such assessment upon entry into a correctional facility;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e13c2a4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> provide an assurance that in making services available to children and youth in adult correctional institutions, priority will be given to such children and youth who are likely to complete incarceration within a 2-year period;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e13c2a5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> describes the program, including a budget for the first year of the program, with annual updates to be provided to the State educational agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e13c2a6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> describes how the program will meet the goals and objectives of the State plan;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e13c2a7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> describes how the State agency will consult with experts and provide the necessary training for appropriate staff, to ensure that the planning and operation of institution-wide projects under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6436">section 6436 of this title</ref> are of high quality;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e13c2a8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> describes how the State agency will use the results of the most recent evaluation under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7981">section 7981 of this title</ref> to plan and improve the program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e13c2a9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> includes data showing that the State agency has maintained the fiscal effort required of a local educational agency, in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7901">section 7901 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e13c2aa-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> describes how the programs will be coordinated with other appropriate State and Federal programs, such as programs under title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s3111">29 U.S.C. 3111</ref> et seq.], career and technical education programs, State and local dropout prevention programs, and special education programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e13c2ab-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> describes how the State agency will encourage correctional facilities receiving funds under this subpart to coordinate with local educational agencies or alternative education programs attended by incarcerated children and youth prior to and after their incarceration to ensure that student assessments and appropriate academic records are shared jointly between the correctional facility and the local educational agency or alternative education program in order to facilitate the transition of such children and youth between the correctional facility and the local educational agency or alternative education program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e13c2ac-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> describes how appropriate professional development will be provided to teachers and other staff;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e13c2ad-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> designates an individual in each affected correctional facility or institution for neglected or delinquent children and youth to be responsible for issues relating to the transition of such children and youth between such facility or institution and locally operated programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e13c2ae-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> describes how the State agency will endeavor to coordinate with businesses for training and mentoring for participating children and youth;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e13c2af-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> provides an assurance that the State agency will assist in locating alternative programs through which students can continue their education if the students are not returning to school after leaving the correctional facility or institution for neglected or delinquent children and youth;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e13c2b0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> provides assurances that the State agency will work with parents to secure parents’ assistance in improving the educational achievement of their children and youth, and preventing their children’s and youth’s further involvement in delinquent activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e13c2b1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><chapeau> provides an assurance that the State agency will work with children and youth with disabilities in order to meet an existing individualized education program and an assurance that the agency will notify the child’s or youth’s local school if the child or youth—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e13c2b2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/15/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is identified as in need of special education services while the child or youth is in the correctional facility or institution for neglected or delinquent children and youth; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e13c2b3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/15/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> intends to return to the local school;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e13c2b4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/16"><num value="16">(16)</num><content> provides an assurance that the State agency will work with children and youth who dropped out of school before entering the correctional facility or institution for neglected or delinquent children and youth to encourage the children and youth to reenter school and attain a regular high school diploma once the term of the incarceration is completed or provide the child or youth with the skills necessary to gain employment, continue the education of the child or youth, or attain a regular high school diploma or its recognized equivalent if the child or youth does not intend to return to school;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e13c2b5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/17"><num value="17">(17)</num><content> provides an assurance that certified or licensed teachers and other qualified staff are trained to work with children and youth with disabilities and other students with special needs taking into consideration the unique needs of such students;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e13c2b6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/18"><num value="18">(18)</num><content> describes any additional services to be provided to children and youth, such as career counseling, distance learning, and assistance in securing student loans and grants;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e13c2b7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/19"><num value="19">(19)</num><content> provides an assurance that the program under this subpart will be coordinated with any programs operated under the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t34/s11101">34 U.S.C. 11101</ref> et seq.] or other comparable programs, if applicable; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e13c2b8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/20"><num value="20">(20)</num><chapeau> describes how the State agency will, to the extent feasible—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e13c2b9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/20/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> note when a youth has come into contact with both the child welfare and juvenile justice systems; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e13c2ba-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s6434/c/20/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> deliver services and interventions designed to keep such youth in school that are evidence-based (to the extent a State determines that such evidence is reasonably available).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0e13c2bb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/10/tI/s1414">Pub. L. 89–10, title I, § 1414</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/107/110/tI/s101">Pub. L. 107–110, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1582">115 Stat. 1582</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/tI/s1401/3">Pub. L. 114–95, title I, § 1401(3)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1900">129 Stat. 1900</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0e13c2bc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0e13c2bd-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id0e13c2be-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act, referred to in subsec. (c)(8), is <ref href="/us/pl/113/128">Pub. L. 113–128</ref>, <date date="2014-07-22">July 22, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1425">128 Stat. 1425</ref>. Title I of the Act is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 3111 et seq.) of chapter 32 of Title 29, Labor. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s3101">section 3101 of Title 29</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (c)(19), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/415">Pub. L. 93–415</ref>, <date date="1974-09-07">Sept. 7, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1109">88 Stat. 1109</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 111 (§ 11101 et seq.) of Title 34, Crime Control and Law Enforcement. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1974 Act note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s10101">section 10101 of Title 34</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id0e13c2bf-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 6434, <ref href="/us/pl/89/10/tI/s1414">Pub. L. 89–10, title I, § 1414</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/103/382/tI/s101">Pub. L. 103–382, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3593">108 Stat. 3593</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dA/s101/f/tVIII/s405/d/18/B">Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 405(d)(18)(B), (f)(13)(B)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-337">112 Stat. 2681–337</ref>, 2681–422, 2681–431, related to State plan and State agency applications, prior to the general amendment of this subchapter by <ref href="/us/pl/107/110">Pub. L. 107–110</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id0e13c2c0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (a)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s1401/3/A/i">Pub. L. 114–95, § 1401(3)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “between correctional facilities and locally operated programs” for “from correctional facilities to locally operated programs”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s1401/3/A/ii/I">Pub. L. 114–95, § 1401(3)(A)(ii)(I)</ref>, substituted “the program objectives and outcomes established by the State” for “the program goals, objectives, and performance measures established by the State” and “career” for “vocational”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s1401/3/A/ii/II">Pub. L. 114–95, § 1401(3)(A)(ii)(II)</ref>, struck out “and” after semicolon at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(C), (D). <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s1401/3/A/ii/III">Pub. L. 114–95, § 1401(3)(A)(ii)(III)</ref>–(V), added subpar. (C), redesignated former subpar. (C) as (D), and in subpar. (D) in cl. (i) inserted “and” after semicolon at end, redesignated cl. (iii) as (ii), and struck out former cls. (ii) and (iv) which related to assurance that the agency would carry out the evaluation requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6471">section 6471 of this title</ref> and provide such other information as the Secretary might reasonably require.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s1401/3/A/ii/VI">Pub. L. 114–95, § 1401(3)(A)(ii)(VI)</ref>, added subpar. (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s1401/3/B/i">Pub. L. 114–95, § 1401(3)(B)(i)</ref>, inserted “and, to the extent practicable, provide for such assessment upon entry into a correctional facility” after “to be served under this subpart”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s1401/3/B/ii">Pub. L. 114–95, § 1401(3)(B)(ii)</ref>, substituted “will use” for “will carry out the evaluation requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7941">section 7941 of this title</ref> and how”, inserted “under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7981">section 7981 of this title</ref>” after “most recent evaluation”, and struck out “will be used” before “to plan and improve the program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s1401/3/B/iii">Pub. L. 114–95, § 1401(3)(B)(iii)</ref>, made technical amendment to reference in original act which appears in text as reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7901">section 7901 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s1401/3/B/iv">Pub. L. 114–95, § 1401(3)(B)(iv)</ref>, substituted “the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act” for “<ref href="/us/pl/105/220">Public Law 105–220</ref>” and “career” for “vocational”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s1401/3/B/v">Pub. L. 114–95, § 1401(3)(B)(v)</ref>, inserted “and after” after “prior to” and “in order to facilitate the transition of such children and youth between the correctional facility and the local educational agency or alternative education program” before semicolon at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s1401/3/B/vi">Pub. L. 114–95, § 1401(3)(B)(vi)</ref>, substituted “transition of such children and youth between such facility or institution and locally operated programs” for “transition of children and youth from such facility or institution to locally operated programs”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(16). <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s1401/3/B/vii">Pub. L. 114–95, § 1401(3)(B)(vii)</ref>, inserted “and attain a regular high school diploma” after “reenter school” and substituted “or attain a regular high school diploma” for “or achieve a secondary school diploma”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(17). <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s1401/3/B/viii">Pub. L. 114–95, § 1401(3)(B)(viii)</ref>, inserted “certified or licensed” before “teachers”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(20). <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s1401/3/B/ix">Pub. L. 114–95, § 1401(3)(B)(ix)</ref>–(xi), added par. (20).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0e13c2c1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0e13c2c2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2015 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/114/95">Pub. L. 114–95</ref> effective <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, except with respect to certain noncompetitive programs and competitive programs, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s5">section 5 of Pub. L. 114–95</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6301">section 6301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
