<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0e2464d3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114"><num value="7114">§ 7114.</num><heading> State use of funds</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2464d4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each State that receives an allotment under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7113">section 7113 of this title</ref> for a fiscal year shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e2464d5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> reserve not less than 95 percent of the allotment to make allocations to local educational agencies under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7115">section 7115 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e2464d6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> reserve not more than 1 percent of the allotment for the administrative costs of carrying out its responsibilities under this subpart, including public reporting on how funds made available under this subpart are being expended by local educational agencies, including the degree to which the local educational agencies have made progress toward meeting the objectives and outcomes described in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7116/e/1/E">section 7116(e)(1)(E) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e2464d7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> use the amount made available to the State and not reserved under paragraphs (1) and (2) for activities described in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2464d8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> State activities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each State that receives an allotment under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7113">section 7113 of this title</ref> shall use the funds available under subsection (a)(3) for activities and programs designed to meet the purposes of this subpart, which may include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e2464d9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> providing monitoring of, and training, technical assistance, and capacity building to, local educational agencies that receive an allotment under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7115">section 7115 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e2464da-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> identifying and eliminating State barriers to the coordination and integration of programs, initiatives, and funding streams that meet the purposes of this subpart, so that local educational agencies can better coordinate with other agencies, schools, and community-based services and programs; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e2464db-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> supporting local educational agencies in providing programs and activities that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e2464dc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> offer well-rounded educational experiences to all students, as described in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7117">section 7117 of this title</ref>, including female students, minority students, English learners, children with disabilities, and low-income students who are often underrepresented in critical and enriching subjects, which may include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e2464dd-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> increasing student access to and improving student engagement and achievement in—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0e2464de-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> high-quality courses in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics, including computer science;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0e2464df-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> activities and programs in music and the arts;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0e2464e0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/A/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> foreign languages;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0e2464e1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/A/i/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><chapeau> accelerated learning programs that provide—</chapeau><item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id0e2464e2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/A/i/IV/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> postsecondary level courses accepted for credit at institutions of higher education, including dual or concurrent enrollment programs, and early college high schools; or</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5" id="id0e2464e3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/A/i/IV/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> postsecondary level instruction and examinations that are accepted for credit at institutions of higher education, including Advanced Placement and International Baccalaureate programs;</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0e2464e4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/A/i/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> American history, civics, economics, geography, social studies, or government education;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0e2464e5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/A/i/VI"><num value="VI">(VI)</num><content> environmental education; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0e2464e6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/A/i/VII"><num value="VII">(VII)</num><content> other courses, activities, and programs or other experiences that contribute to a well-rounded education; or</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e2464e7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> reimbursing low-income students to cover part or all of the costs of accelerated learning examination fees, as described in clause (i)(IV);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e2464e8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> foster safe, healthy, supportive, and drug-free environments that support student academic achievement, as described in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7118">section 7118 of this title</ref>, which may include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e2464e9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> coordinating with any local educational agencies or consortia of such agencies implementing a youth PROMISE plan to reduce exclusionary discipline, as described in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7118/5/F">section 7118(5)(F) of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e2464ea-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> supporting local educational agencies to—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0e2464eb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> implement mental health awareness training programs that are evidence-based (to the extent the State determines that such evidence is reasonably available) to provide education to school personnel regarding resources available in the community for students with mental illnesses and other relevant resources relating to mental health or the safe de-escalation of crisis situations involving a student with a mental illness; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0e2464ec-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> expand access to or coordinate resources for school-based counseling and mental health programs, such as through school-based mental health services partnership programs;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e2464ed-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> providing local educational agencies with resources that are evidence-based (to the extent the State determines that such evidence is reasonably available) addressing ways to integrate health and safety practices into school or athletic programs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e2464ee-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> disseminating best practices and evaluating program outcomes relating to any local educational agency activities to promote student safety and violence prevention through effective communication as described in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7118/5/C/iv">section 7118(5)(C)(iv) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e2464ef-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> increase access to personalized, rigorous learning experiences supported by technology by—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e2464f0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> providing technical assistance to local educational agencies to improve the ability of local educational agencies to—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0e2464f1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> identify and address technology readiness needs, including the types of technology infrastructure and access available to the students served by the local educational agency, including computer devices, access to school libraries, Internet connectivity, operating systems, software, related network infrastructure, and data security;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0e2464f2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> use technology, consistent with the principles of universal design for learning, to support the learning needs of all students, including children with disabilities and English learners; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0e2464f3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/C/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> build capacity for principals, other school leaders, and local educational agency administrators to support teachers in using data and technology to improve instruction and personalize learning;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e2464f4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> supporting schools in rural and remote areas to expand access to high-quality digital learning opportunities;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e2464f5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> developing or using strategies that are innovative or evidence-based (to the extent the State determines that such evidence is reasonably available) for the delivery of specialized or rigorous academic courses and curricula through the use of technology, including digital learning technologies and assistive technology, which may include increased access to online dual or concurrent enrollment opportunities, career and technical courses, and programs leading to a recognized postsecondary credential (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s3102">section 3102 of title 29</ref>);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e2464f6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> disseminating promising practices related to technology instruction, data security, and the acquisition and implementation of technology tools and applications, including through making such promising practices publicly available on the website of the State educational agency;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e2464f7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/C/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> providing teachers, paraprofessionals, school librarians and media personnel, specialized instructional support personnel, and administrators with the knowledge and skills to use technology effectively, including effective integration of technology, to improve instruction and student achievement, which may include coordination with teacher, principal, and other school leader preparation programs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e2464f8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/b/3/C/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> making instructional content widely available through open educational resources, which may include providing tools and processes to support local educational agencies in making such resources widely available.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2464f9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7114/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rule</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A State that receives a grant under this subpart for fiscal year 2017 may use the amount made available to the State and not reserved under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) for such fiscal year to cover part or all of the fees for accelerated learning examinations taken by low-income students during the 2016-2017 school year, in accordance with subsection (b)(3)(A)(ii).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0e2464fa-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/10/tIV/s4104">Pub. L. 89–10, title IV, § 4104</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/tIV/s4101">Pub. L. 114–95, title IV, § 4101</ref>, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1971">129 Stat. 1971</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0e2464fb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0e2464fc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id0e2464fd-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 7114, <ref href="/us/pl/89/10/tIV/s4114">Pub. L. 89–10, title IV, § 4114</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/107/110/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 107–110, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1742">115 Stat. 1742</ref>, related to local educational agency programs, prior to the general amendment of this subpart by <ref href="/us/pl/114/95">Pub. L. 114–95</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another prior section 7114, <ref href="/us/pl/89/10/tIV/s4114">Pub. L. 89–10, title IV, § 4114</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/103/382/tI/s101">Pub. L. 103–382, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3679">108 Stat. 3679</ref>, related to governor’s programs, prior to the general amendment of this subchapter by <ref href="/us/pl/107/110">Pub. L. 107–110</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/89/10/s4104">section 4104 of Pub. L. 89–10</ref> was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s3064">section 3064 of this title</ref>, prior to the general amendment of <ref href="/us/pl/89/10">Pub. L. 89–10</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/103/382">Pub. L. 103–382</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0e2464fe-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id0e2464ff-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, except with respect to certain noncompetitive programs and competitive programs, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s5">section 5 of Pub. L. 114–95</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2015 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6301">section 6301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
