<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0e291fb1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c"><num value="7221c">§ 7221c.</num><heading> Facilities financing assistance</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e291fb2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Grants to eligible entities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e291fb3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">From the amount reserved under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7221a/b/1">section 7221a(b)(1) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall use not less than 50 percent to award, on a competitive basis, not less than 3 grants to eligible entities that have the highest-quality applications approved under subsection (d), after considering the diversity of such applications, to demonstrate innovative methods of helping charter schools to address the cost of acquiring, constructing, and renovating facilities by enhancing the availability of loans or bond financing.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e291fb4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible entity defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For the purposes of this section, the term “eligible entity” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e291fb5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a public entity, such as a State or local governmental entity;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e291fb6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a private nonprofit entity; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e291fb7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a consortium of entities described in subparagraphs (A) and (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e291fb8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Grantee selection</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall evaluate each application submitted under subsection (d), and shall determine whether the application is sufficient to merit approval.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e291fb9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Grant characteristics</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Grants under subsection (a) shall be of sufficient size, scope, and quality so as to ensure an effective demonstration of an innovative means of enhancing credit for the financing of charter school acquisition, construction, or renovation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e291fba-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Applications</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e291fbb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">An eligible entity desiring to receive a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary in such form as the Secretary may reasonably require.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e291fbc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">An application submitted under paragraph (1) shall contain—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e291fbd-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a statement identifying the activities that the eligible entity proposes to carry out with funds received under subsection (a), including how the eligible entity will determine which charter schools will receive assistance, and how much and what types of assistance charter schools will receive;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e291fbe-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a description of the involvement of charter schools in the application’s development and the design of the proposed activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e291fbf-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a description of the eligible entity’s expertise in capital market financing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e291fc0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/d/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> a description of how the proposed activities will leverage the maximum amount of private-sector financing capital relative to the amount of government funding used and otherwise enhance credit available to charter schools, including how the eligible entity will offer a combination of rates and terms more favorable than the rates and terms that a charter school could receive without assistance from the eligible entity under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e291fc1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/d/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> a description of how the eligible entity possesses sufficient expertise in education to evaluate the likelihood of success of a charter school program for which facilities financing is sought; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e291fc2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/d/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> in the case of an application submitted by a State governmental entity, a description of the actions that the eligible entity has taken, or will take, to ensure that charter schools within the State receive the funding that charter schools need to have adequate facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e291fc3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Charter school objectives</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An eligible entity receiving a grant under subsection (a) shall use the funds deposited in the reserve account established under subsection (f) to assist one or more charter schools to access private-sector capital to accomplish one or more of the following objectives:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e291fc4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The acquisition (by purchase, lease, donation, or otherwise) of an interest (including an interest held by a third party for the benefit of a charter school) in improved or unimproved real property that is necessary to commence or continue the operation of a charter school.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e291fc5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The construction of new facilities, or the renovation, repair, or alteration of existing facilities, necessary to commence or continue the operation of a charter school.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e291fc6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The predevelopment costs required to assess sites for purposes of paragraph (1) or (2) and that are necessary to commence or continue the operation of a charter school.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e291fc7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Reserve account</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e291fc8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">To assist charter schools in accomplishing the objectives described in subsection (e), an eligible entity receiving a grant under subsection (a) shall, in accordance with State and local law, directly or indirectly, alone or in collaboration with others, deposit the funds received under subsection (a) (other than funds used for administrative costs in accordance with subsection (g)) in a reserve account established and maintained by the eligible entity for this purpose. Amounts deposited in such account shall be used by the eligible entity for one or more of the following purposes:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e2b8fc9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Guaranteeing, insuring, and reinsuring bonds, notes, evidences of debt, loans, and interests therein, the proceeds of which are used for an objective described in subsection (e).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e2b8fca-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Guaranteeing and insuring leases of personal and real property for an objective described in subsection (e).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e2b8fcb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/f/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Facilitating financing by identifying potential lending sources, encouraging private lending, and other similar activities that directly promote lending to, or for the benefit of, charter schools.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e2b8fcc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/f/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Facilitating the issuance of bonds by charter schools, or by other public entities for the benefit of charter schools, by providing technical, administrative, and other appropriate assistance (including the recruitment of bond counsel, underwriters, and potential investors and the consolidation of multiple charter school projects within a single bond issue).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8fcd-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Investment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Funds received under subsection (a) and deposited in the reserve account established under paragraph (1) shall be invested in obligations issued or guaranteed by the United States or a State, or in other similarly low-risk securities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8fce-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Reinvestment of earnings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any earnings on funds received under subsection (a) shall be deposited in the reserve account established under paragraph (1) and used in accordance with this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8fcf-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on administrative costs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An eligible entity may use not more than 2.5 percent of the funds received under subsection (a) for the administrative costs of carrying out its responsibilities under this section (excluding subsection (k)).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8fd0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Audits and reports</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8fd1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Financial record maintenance and audit</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The financial records of each eligible entity receiving a grant under subsection (a) shall be maintained in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles and shall be subject to an annual audit by an independent public accountant.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8fd2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8fd3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/h/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Grantee annual reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Each eligible entity receiving a grant under subsection (a) shall submit to the Secretary an annual report of the entity’s operations and activities under this section (excluding subsection (k)).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8fd4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/h/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Each annual report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e2b8fd5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/h/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a copy of the most recent financial statements, and any accompanying opinion on such statements, prepared by the independent public accountant reviewing the financial records of the eligible entity;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e2b8fd6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/h/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a copy of any report made on an audit of the financial records of the eligible entity that was conducted under paragraph (1) during the reporting period;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e2b8fd7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/h/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> an evaluation by the eligible entity of the effectiveness of its use of the Federal funds provided under subsection (a) in leveraging private funds;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e2b8fd8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/h/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> a listing and description of the charter schools served during the reporting period, including the amount of funds used by each school, the type of project facilitated by the grant, and the type of assistance provided to the charter schools;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e2b8fd9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/h/2/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> a description of the activities carried out by the eligible entity to assist charter schools in meeting the objectives set forth in subsection (e); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e2b8fda-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/h/2/B/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> a description of the characteristics of lenders and other financial institutions participating in the activities carried out by the eligible entity under this section (excluding subsection (k)) during the reporting period.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8fdb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/h/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretarial report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall review the reports submitted under subparagraph (A) and shall provide a comprehensive annual report to Congress on the activities conducted under this section (excluding subsection (k)).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8fdc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> No full faith and credit for grantee obligation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No financial obligation of an eligible entity entered into pursuant to this section (such as an obligation under a guarantee, bond, note, evidence of debt, or loan) shall be an obligation of, or guaranteed in any respect by, the United States. The full faith and credit of the United States is not pledged to the payment of funds that may be required to be paid under any obligation made by an eligible entity pursuant to any provision of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8fdd-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Recovery of funds</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8fde-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/j/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary, in accordance with chapter 37 of title 31, shall collect—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e2b8fdf-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/j/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> all of the funds in a reserve account established by an eligible entity under subsection (f)(1) if the Secretary determines, not earlier than 2 years after the date on which the eligible entity first received funds under subsection (a), that the eligible entity has failed to make substantial progress in carrying out the purposes described in subsection (f)(1); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e2b8fe0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/j/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> all or a portion of the funds in a reserve account established by an eligible entity under subsection (f)(1) if the Secretary determines that the eligible entity has permanently ceased to use all or a portion of the funds in such account to accomplish any purpose described in subsection (f)(1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8fe1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/j/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Exercise of authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall not exercise the authority provided in paragraph (1) to collect from any eligible entity any funds that are being properly used to achieve one or more of the purposes described in subsection (f)(1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8fe2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/j/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The provisions of sections 451, 452, and 458 of the General Education Provisions Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1234">20 U.S.C. 1234</ref>, 1234a, 1234g] shall apply to the recovery of funds under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8fe3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/j/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">This subsection shall not be construed to impair or affect the authority of the Secretary to recover funds under part D of the General Education Provisions Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1234">20 U.S.C. 1234</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8fe4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Per-pupil facilities aid program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8fe5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition of per-pupil facilities aid program</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “per-pupil facilities aid program” means a program in which a State makes payments, on a per-pupil basis, to charter schools to provide the schools with financing—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e2b8fe6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> that is dedicated solely to funding charter school facilities; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e2b8fe7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a portion of which is dedicated for funding charter school facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8fe8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Grants</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8fe9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">From the amount reserved under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7221a/b/1">section 7221a(b)(1) of this title</ref> and remaining after the Secretary makes grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall make grants, on a competitive basis, to States to pay for the Federal share of the cost of establishing or enhancing, and administering, per-pupil facilities aid programs.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8fea-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Period</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall award grants under this subsection for periods of not more than 5 years.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8feb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal share</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Federal share of the cost described in subparagraph (A) for a per-pupil facilities aid program shall be not more than—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e2b8fec-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> 90 percent of the cost, for the first fiscal year for which the program receives assistance under this subsection;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e2b8fed-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> 80 percent for the second such year;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e2b8fee-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/2/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> 60 percent for the third such year;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e2b8fef-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/2/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> 40 percent for the fourth such year; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e2b8ff0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/2/C/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> 20 percent for the fifth such year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8ff1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/2/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> State share</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A State receiving a grant under this subsection may partner with 1 or more organizations, and such organizations may provide not more than 50 percent of the State share of the cost of establishing or enhancing, and administering, the per-pupil facilities aid program.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8ff2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/2/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Multiple grants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A State may receive more than 1 grant under this subsection, so long as the amount of total funds provided to charter schools increases with each successive grant.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8ff3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8ff4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A State that receives a grant under this subsection shall use the funds made available through the grant to establish or enhance, and administer, a per-pupil facilities aid program for charter schools in the State of the applicant.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8ff5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Evaluations; technical assistance; dissemination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">From the amount made available to a State through a grant under this subsection for a fiscal year, the State may reserve not more than 5 percent to carry out evaluations, to provide technical assistance, and to disseminate information.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8ff6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Supplement, not supplant</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Funds made available under this subsection shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, State and local public funds expended to provide per-pupil facilities aid programs, operations financing programs, or other programs, for charter schools.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8ff7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8ff8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Voluntary participation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">No State may be required to participate in a program carried out under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8ff9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> State law</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8ffa-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/4/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">To be eligible to receive a grant under this subsection, a State shall establish or enhance, and administer, a per-pupil facilities aid program for charter schools in the State, that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0e2b8ffb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/4/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> is specified in State law; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id0e2b8ffc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/4/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> provides annual financing, on a per-pupil basis, for charter school facilities.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8ffd-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/4/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rule</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">A State that is required under State law to provide its charter schools with access to adequate facility space, but that does not have a per-pupil facilities aid program for charter schools specified in State law, is eligible to receive a grant under this subsection if the State agrees to use the funds to develop a per-pupil facilities aid program consistent with the requirements of this subsection.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e2b8ffe-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7221c/k/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Applications</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">To be eligible to receive a grant under this subsection, a State shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0e2b8fff-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/10/tIV/s4304">Pub. L. 89–10, title IV, § 4304</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/tIV/s4301/1">Pub. L. 114–95, title IV, § 4301(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/2004">129 Stat. 2004</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0e2b9000-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0e2b9001-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id0e2b9002-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The General Education Provisions Act, referred to in subsec. (j)(4), is title IV of <ref href="/us/pl/90/247">Pub. L. 90–247</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/814">81 Stat. 814</ref>. Part D of the Act is classified generally to subchapter IV (§ 1234 et seq.) of chapter 31 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1221">section 1221 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id0e2b9003-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 7221c, <ref href="/us/pl/89/10/tIV/s4304">Pub. L. 89–10, title IV, § 4304</ref>, formerly title V, § 5204, as added <ref href="/us/pl/107/110/tV/s501">Pub. L. 107–110, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1792">115 Stat. 1792</ref>; renumbered title IV, § 4304, <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/tIV/s4001/b/2/A">Pub. L. 114–95, title IV, § 4001(b)(2)(A)</ref>, (B), (D)(iii), <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1967">129 Stat. 1967</ref>, related to administration, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s5">Pub. L. 114–95, § 5</ref>, title IV, § 4301(1), <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1806">129 Stat. 1806</ref>, 1993, effective <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, except with respect to certain noncompetitive programs and competitive programs.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/89/10/s4304">section 4304 of Pub. L. 89–10</ref> was renumbered section 8574, and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7974">section 7974 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0e2b9004-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id0e2b9005-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, except with respect to certain noncompetitive programs and competitive programs, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s5">section 5 of Pub. L. 114–95</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2015 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6301">section 6301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
