<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0e304b09-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274"><num value="7274">§ 7274.</num><heading> Promise neighborhoods</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e304b0a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Application requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An eligible entity desiring a grant under this subpart for activities described in this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require, including, at a minimum, all of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e304b0b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> A plan to significantly improve the academic outcomes of children living in a neighborhood that is served by the eligible entity—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e304b0c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> by providing pipeline services that address the needs of children in the neighborhood, as identified by the needs analysis described in paragraph (4); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e304b0d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> that is supported by effective practices.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e304b0e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A description of the neighborhood that the eligible entity will serve.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e304b0f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Measurable annual objectives and outcomes for the grant, in accordance with the metrics described in subsection (h), for each year of the grant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e304b10-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> An analysis of the needs and assets of the neighborhood identified in paragraph (1), including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e304b11-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the size and scope of the population affected;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e304b12-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a description of the process through which the needs analysis was produced, including a description of how parents, families, and community members were engaged in such analysis;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e304b13-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> an analysis of community assets and collaborative efforts (including programs already provided from Federal and non-Federal sources) within, or accessible to, the neighborhood, including, at a minimum, early learning opportunities, family and student supports, local businesses, local educational agencies, and institutions of higher education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e304b14-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the steps that the eligible entity is taking, at the time of the application, to address the needs identified in the needs analysis; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e304b15-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/4/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> any barriers the eligible entity, public agencies, and other community-based organizations have faced in meeting such needs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e304b16-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> A description of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e304b17-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> all information that the entity used to identify the pipeline services to be provided, which shall not include information that is more than 3 years old; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e304b18-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> how the eligible entity will—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e304b19-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/5/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> collect data on children served by each pipeline service; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e304b1a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/5/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> increase the percentage of children served over time.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e304b1b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> A description of the process used to develop the application, including the involvement of family and community members.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e304b1c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><chapeau> A description of how the pipeline services will facilitate the coordination of the following activities:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e304b1d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Providing early learning opportunities for children, including by—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e304b1e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/7/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> providing opportunities for families to acquire the skills to promote early learning and child development; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0e304b1f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/7/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> ensuring appropriate diagnostic assessments and referrals for children with disabilities and children aged 3 through 9 experiencing developmental delays, consistent with the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1400">20 U.S.C. 1400</ref> et seq.), where applicable.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e304b20-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Supporting, enhancing, operating, or expanding rigorous, comprehensive, effective educational improvements, which may include high-quality academic programs, expanded learning time, and programs and activities to prepare students for postsecondary education admissions and success.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e304b21-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Supporting partnerships between schools and other community resources with an integrated focus on academics and other social, health, and familial supports.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e304b22-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/7/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Providing social, health, nutrition, and mental health services and supports, for children, family members, and community members, which may include services provided within the school building.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e304b23-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/7/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Supporting evidence-based programs that assist students through school transitions, which may include expanding access to postsecondary education courses and postsecondary education enrollment aid or guidance, and other supports for at-risk youth.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e304b24-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> A description of the strategies that will be used to provide pipeline services (including a description of which programs and services will be provided to children, family members, community members, and children within the neighborhood) to support the purpose described in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7271/1">section 7271(1) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e304b25-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><chapeau> An explanation of the process the eligible entity will use to establish and maintain family and community engagement, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e304b26-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/9/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> involving representative participation by the members of such neighborhood in the planning and implementation of the activities of each grant awarded under this subpart for activities described in this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e304b27-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/9/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the provision of strategies and practices to assist family and community members in actively supporting student achievement and child development;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e304b28-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/9/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> providing services for students, families, and communities within the school building; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e304b29-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/9/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> collaboration with institutions of higher education, workforce development centers, and employers to align expectations and programming with postsecondary education and workforce readiness,</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e304b2a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> An explanation of how the eligible entity will continuously evaluate and improve the continuum of high-quality pipeline services to provide for continuous program improvement and potential expansion.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e304b2b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Priority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In awarding grants for activities described in this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that will use funds under subsection (d) for evidence-based activities, which, for purposes of this subsection, is defined as activities meeting the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7801/21/A/i">section 7801(21)(A)(i) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e304b2c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Memorandum of understanding</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As eligible entity shall, as part of the application described in subsection (a), submit a preliminary memorandum of understanding, signed by each partner entity or agency described in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7272/1/A/3">section 7272(1)(A)(3) of this title</ref> (if applicable) and detailing each partner’s financial, programmatic, and long-term commitment with respect to the strategies described in the application.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e304b2d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Uses of funds</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each eligible entity that receives a grant under this subpart to carry out a program of activities described in this section shall use the grant funds to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e304b2e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> support planning activities to develop and implement pipeline services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e304b2f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> implement the pipeline services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e304b30-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> continuously evaluate the success of the program and improve the program based on data and outcomes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e304b31-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rules</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e304b32-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Funds for pipeline services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each eligible entity that receives a grant under this subpart for activities described in this section shall, for the first year of the grant, use not less than 50 percent of the grant funds, and, for the second year of the grant, use not less than 25 percent of the grant funds, to carry out the activities described in subsection (d)(1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e304b33-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Operational flexibility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each eligible entity that operates a school in a neighborhood served by a grant program under this subpart for activities described in this section shall provide such school with the operational flexibility, including autonomy over staff, time, and budget, needed to effectively carry out the activities described in the application under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e304b34-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on use of funds for early childhood education programs</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Funds provided under this subpart for activities described in this section that are used to improve early childhood education programs shall not be used to carry out any of the following activities:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e304b35-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Assessments that provide rewards or sanctions for individual children or teachers.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e304b36-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A single assessment that is used as the primary or sole method for assessing program effectiveness.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e304b37-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/e/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Evaluating children, other than for the purposes of improving instruction, classroom environment, professional development, or parent and family engagement, or program improvement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e304b38-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each eligible entity that receives a grant under this subpart for activities described in this section shall prepare and submit an annual report to the Secretary, which shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e304b39-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> information about the number and percentage of children in the neighborhood who are served by the grant program, including a description of the number and percentage of children accessing each support or service offered as part of the pipeline services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e304b3a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> information relating to the performance metrics described in subsection (h).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e304b3b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Publicly available data</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each eligible entity that receives a grant under this subpart for activities described in this section shall make publicly available, including through electronic means, the information described in subsection (f). To the extent practicable, such information shall be provided in a form and language accessible to parents and families in the neighborhood served under the grant, and such information shall be a part of statewide longitudinal data systems.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e304b3c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Performance indicators</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e304b3d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish performance indicators under paragraph (2) and corresponding metrics to be used for the purpose of reporting under paragraph (3) and program evaluation under subsection (i).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e304b3e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Indicators</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The performance indicators established by the Secretary under paragraph (1) shall be indicators of improved academic and developmental outcomes for children, including indicators of school readiness, high school graduation, postsecondary education and career readiness, and other academic and developmental outcomes, to promote—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e304b3f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> data-driven decision-making by eligible entities receiving funds under this subpart; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e304b40-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> access to a community-based continuum of high-quality services for children living in the most distressed communities of the United States, beginning at birth.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e304b41-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/h/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Reporting</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each eligible entity that receives a grant under this subpart for activities described in this section shall annually collect and report to the Secretary data on the performance indicators described in paragraph (2) for use by the Secretary in making a determination concerning continuation funding and grant extension under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7273/b">section 7273(b) of this title</ref> for each eligible entity.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e304b42-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7274/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Evaluation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall reserve not more than 5 percent of the funds made available under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7251/b/2/A">section 7251(b)(2)(A) of this title</ref> to provide technical assistance and evaluate the implementation and impact of the activities funded under this section, in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7981">section 7981 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0e304b43-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/10/tIV/s4624">Pub. L. 89–10, title IV, § 4624</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/tIV/s4601">Pub. L. 114–95, title IV, § 4601</ref>, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/2026">129 Stat. 2026</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0e304b44-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0e304b45-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id0e304b46-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(7)(A)(ii), is title VI of <ref href="/us/pl/91/230">Pub. L. 91–230</ref>, <date date="1970-04-13">Apr. 13, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/175">84 Stat. 175</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 33 (§ 1400 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1400">section 1400 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0e304b47-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id0e304b48-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, except with respect to certain noncompetitive programs and competitive programs, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s5">section 5 of Pub. L. 114–95</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2015 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6301">section 6301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
