<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0c80c6f7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s76bb"><num value="76bb">§ 76bb.</num><heading> Joseph H. Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c80c6f8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s76bb/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Designation; administration by Board of Regents; cooperation of Board with Secretary of the Interior</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The museum and sculpture garden provided for by this subchapter shall be designated and known in perpetuity as the Joseph H. Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden, and shall be a free public museum and sculpture garden under the administration of the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution. In administering the sculpture garden the Board shall cooperate with the Secretary of <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002001">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002001"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by “the”.</note> Interior so that the development and use of the Garden is consistent with the open-space concept of the Mall, for which the Secretary of <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002001">1</ref> Interior is responsible, and with related development regarding underground garages and street development.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c80c6f9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s76bb/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The faith of the United States is pledged that the United States shall provide such funds as may be necessary for the upkeep, operation, and administration of the Joseph H. Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c80c6fa-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s76bb/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Uses</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Joseph H. Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden shall be the permanent home of the collections of art of Joseph H. Hirshhorn and the Joseph H. Hirshhorn Foundation, and shall be used for the storage, exhibition, and study of works of art, and for the administration of the affairs of the Joseph H. Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0c80c6fb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/788/s2">Pub. L. 89–788, § 2</ref>, <date date="1966-11-07">Nov. 7, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1403">80 Stat. 1403</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
