<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0c830ff8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s77"><num value="77">§ 77.</num><heading> National Air and Space Museum</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c830ff9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s77/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment; board; administration; reimbursement of expenses</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is hereby established under the Smithsonian Institution a bureau to be known as a National Air and Space Museum, which shall be administered by the Smithsonian Institution with the advice of a board to be composed of the Chief of Staff of the Air Force, or his designee, the Chief of Space Operations, or the Chief’s designee, the Chief of Naval Operations, or his designee, the Chief of Staff of the Army, or his designee, the Commandant of the Marine Corps, or his designee, the Commandant of the Coast Guard, or his designee, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, or his designee, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, or his designee, the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution, and three citizens of the United States appointed by the President from civilian life who shall serve at the pleasure of the President. The members of the board shall serve as such members without compensation but shall be reimbursed for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred by them in the performance of their duties as members of the board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c830ffa-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s77/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment and compensation of head of museum</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution, with the advice of the board, may appoint and fix the compensation and duties of the head of a national air and space museum whose appointment shall not be subject to the civil service laws.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0c830ffb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-08-12/ch955/s1">Aug. 12, 1946, ch. 955, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/997">60 Stat. 997</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343">July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 208(b), <ref href="/us/stat/61/503">61 Stat. 503</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/509">Pub. L. 89–509</ref>, pt. I, §§ 2, 3, <date date="1966-07-19">July 19, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/310">80 Stat. 310</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/670">Pub. L. 89–670</ref>, §§ 3(e), 6(c)(1), <date date="1966-10-15">Oct. 15, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/932">80 Stat. 932</ref>, 938; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tIX/s927/g">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 927(g)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3832">134 Stat. 3832</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0c830ffc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0c830ffd-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id0c830ffe-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, which directed amendment of subsec. (a) of <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-12/s1">section 1 of the Act of August 12, 1946</ref> (<ref href="/us/stat/60/997">60 Stat. 997</ref>, chapter 995; <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s77/a">20 U.S.C. 77(a)</ref>) by inserting “the Chief of Space Operations, or the Chief’s designee,” after “the Chief of Staff of the Air Force, or his designee,”, was executed to this section, which is section 1 of <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-12/ch955">act of Aug. 12, 1946, ch. 955</ref>, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/89/509/s2">Pub. L. 89–509, § 2</ref>, changed the name of the museum from the National Air Museum to the National Air and Space Museum, expanded the advisory board to include additional members including the Chief of Staff of the Army, the Commandant of the Marine Corps, the Commandant of the Coast Guard, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Agency, and an additional member appointed from civilian life to serve at the pleasure of the President, and provided for reimbursement for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred by them in the performance of their duties as members of the Board.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/89/509/s3">Pub. L. 89–509, § 3</ref>, substituted “national air and space museum” for “national air museum” and struck out provision that the salary of the head of the museum shall not be subject to the Classification Act of 1923, as amended.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0c830fff-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="id0c831000-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 1966 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/89/509/s1">Pub. L. 89–509, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-07-19">July 19, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/310">80 Stat. 310</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/89/509/s1">“That this Act [amending this section, sections 77a, 77c, and 77d of this title, and provisions set out as notes under this section and sections 77b and 77d of this title, and repealing <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s77b">section 77b of this title</ref>] may be cited as ‘the National Air Museum Amendments Act of 1965’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id0c831001-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Chief of Staff of the Air Force” substituted in subsec. (a) for “Commanding General of the Army Air Forces” pursuant to <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343/tII/s208/b">act July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II, § 208(b)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/503">61 Stat. 503</ref>, which transferred functions of Commanding General of the Army Air Forces to Chief of Staff, United States Air Force. Section 208(b) of act <date date="1947-07-26">July 26, 1947</date> was repealed by section 53 of <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041">act Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/641">70A Stat. 641</ref>. See sections 8031 and 8034 of Title 10, Armed Forces.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Federal Aviation Administration” substituted in subsec. (a) for “Federal Aviation Agency” pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/89/670">Pub. L. 89–670</ref>, §§ 3(e), 6(c)(1), <date date="1966-10-15">Oct. 15, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/932">80 Stat. 932</ref>, 938, which transferred all functions, powers, and duties of Federal Aviation Agency and of Administrator and other offices and officers thereof to Secretary of Transportation and established a Federal Aviation Administration in Department of Transportation. See <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s106">section 106 of Title 49</ref>, Transportation.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0c831002-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Appropriations</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1946-08-12/ch955/s6">Act Aug. 12, 1946, ch. 955, § 6</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/998">60 Stat. 998</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/89/509">Pub. L. 89–509</ref>, pt. I, § 10, <date date="1966-07-19">July 19, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/311">80 Stat. 311</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/89/509">“There is hereby authorized to be appropriated the sum of $50,000 for the purposes of this Act [this subchapter] and there are hereby authorized to be appropriated annually hereafter such sums as may be necessary to maintain and administer said national air and space museum including salaries and all other necessary expenses.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0c831003-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Construction of Museum Center</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/222">Pub. L. 104–222</ref>, <date date="1996-10-01">Oct. 1, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3025">110 Stat. 3025</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/222">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1">“SECTION 1.</num><heading> CONSTRUCTION OF MUSEUM CENTER.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“The Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution is authorized to construct the Smithsonian Institution National Air and Space Museum Dulles Center at Washington Dulles International Airport.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="2">“SEC. 2.</num><heading> LIMITATION ON USE OF FUNDS.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“No appropriated funds may be used to pay any expense of the construction authorized by section 1.”</p>
</content>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0c831004-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Extension at Washington Dulles International Airport</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/57">Pub. L. 103–57</ref>, <date date="1993-08-02">Aug. 2, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/279">107 Stat. 279</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/57">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1">“SECTION 1.</num><heading> PLAN FOR NATIONAL AIR AND SPACE MUSEUM EXTENSION.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“The Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution shall have authority to plan and design an extension of the National Air and Space Museum at Washington Dulles International Airport.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="2">“SEC. 2.</num><heading> AUTHORIZATION OF APPROPRIATIONS.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“There is authorized to be appropriated for fiscal years beginning after <date date="1993-09-30">September 30, 1993</date>, a total of $8,000,000 to carry out this Act.”</p>
</content>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0c831005-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Ratification of Compensation Paid Head of Museum</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/89/509">Pub. L. 89–509</ref>, pt. I, § 11, <date date="1966-07-19">July 19, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/311">80 Stat. 311</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/89/509">“Payments of compensation heretofore made to the head of the National Air Museum at rates fixed by the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution without regard to the Classification Act of 1949, as amended [chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees] are hereby ratified and affirmed.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
