<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0e45ced6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704"><num value="7704">§ 7704.</num><heading> Policies and procedures relating to children residing on Indian lands</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e45ced7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A local educational agency that claims children residing on Indian lands for the purpose of receiving funds under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7703">section 7703 of this title</ref> shall establish policies and procedures to ensure that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e45ced8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> such children participate in programs and activities supported by such funds on an equal basis with all other children;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e45ced9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> parents of such children and Indian tribes are afforded an opportunity to present their views on such programs and activities, including an opportunity to make recommendations on the needs of those children and how the local educational agency may help such children realize the benefits of such programs and activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e45ceda-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> parents and Indian tribes are consulted and involved in planning and developing such programs and activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e45cedb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> relevant applications, evaluations, and program plans are disseminated to the parents and Indian tribes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e45cedc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> parents and Indian tribes are afforded an opportunity to present their views to such agency regarding such agency’s general educational program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e45cedd-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Records</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A local educational agency that claims children residing on Indian lands for the purpose of receiving funds under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7703">section 7703 of this title</ref> shall maintain records demonstrating such agency’s compliance with the requirements contained in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e45cede-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A local educational agency that claims children residing on Indian lands for the purpose of receiving funds under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7703">section 7703 of this title</ref> shall not be required to comply with the requirements of subsections (a) and (b) for any fiscal year with respect to any Indian tribe from which such agency has received a written statement that the agency need not comply with those subsections because the tribe is satisfied with the provision of educational services by such agency to such children.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e45cedf-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Technical assistance and enforcement</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e45cee0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> provide technical assistance to local educational agencies, parents, and Indian tribes to enable such agencies, parents, and tribes to carry out this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e45cee1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> enforce this section through such actions, which may include the withholding of funds, as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, after affording the affected local educational agency, parents, and Indian tribe an opportunity to present their views.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e45cee2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Complaints</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e45cee3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e45cee4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Any tribe, or its designee, which has students in attendance at a local educational agency may, in its discretion and without regard to the requirements of any other provision of law, file a written complaint with the Secretary regarding any action of a local educational agency taken pursuant to, or relevant to, the requirements of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e45cee5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Within ten working days from receipt of a complaint, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e45cee6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/e/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> designate a time and place for a hearing into the matters relating to the complaint at a location in close proximity to the local educational agency involved, or if the Secretary determines there is good cause, at some other location convenient to both the tribe, or its designee, and the local educational agency;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e45cee7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/e/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> designate a hearing examiner to conduct the hearing; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e45cee8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/e/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> notify the affected tribe or tribes and the local educational agency involved of the time, place, and nature of the hearing and send copies of the complaint to the local educational agency and the affected tribe or tribes.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e45cee9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Hearing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The hearing shall be held within 30 days of the designation of a hearing examiner and shall be open to the public. A record of the proceedings shall be established and maintained.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e45ceea-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Evidence; recommendations; cost</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The complaining tribe, or its designee, and the local educational agency shall be entitled to present evidence on matters relevant to the complaint and to make recommendations concerning the appropriate remedial actions. Each party to the hearing shall bear only its own costs in the proceedings.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e45ceeb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/e/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Findings and recommendations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Within 30 days of the completion of the hearing, the hearing examiner shall, on the basis of the record, make written findings of fact and recommendations concerning appropriate remedial action, if any, which should be taken. The hearing examiner’s findings and recommendations, along with the hearing record, shall be forwarded to the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e45ceec-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/e/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Written determination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Within 30 days of the Secretary’s receipt of the findings, recommendations, and record, the Secretary shall, on the basis of the record, make a written determination of the appropriate remedial action, if any, to be taken by the local educational agency, the schedule for completion of the remedial action, and the reasons for the Secretary’s decision.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e45ceed-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/e/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Copies provided</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon completion of the Secretary’s final determination, the Secretary shall provide the complaining tribe, or its designee, and the local educational agency with copies of the hearing record, the hearing examiner’s findings and recommendations, and the Secretary’s final determination. The final determination of the Secretary shall be subject to judicial review.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e45ceee-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/e/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Consolidation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In all actions under this subsection, the Secretary shall have discretion to consolidate complaints involving the same tribe or local educational agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e45ceef-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/e/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Withholding</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the local educational agency rejects the determination of the Secretary, or if the remedy required is not undertaken within the time established and the Secretary determines that an extension of the time established will not effectively encourage the remedy required, the Secretary shall withhold payment of all moneys to which such local agency is eligible under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7703">section 7703 of this title</ref> until such time as the remedy required is undertaken, except where the complaining tribe or its designee formally requests that such funds be released to the local educational agency, except that the Secretary may not withhold such moneys during the course of the school year if the Secretary determines that such withholding would substantially disrupt the educational programs of the local educational agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0e45cef0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/e/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Rejection of determination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the local educational agency rejects the determination of the Secretary and a tribe exercises the option under section 1101(d) of the Education Amendments of 1978, to have education services provided either directly by the Bureau of Indian Education or by contract with the Bureau of Indian Education, any Indian students affiliated with that tribe who wish to remain in attendance at the local educational agency against whom the complaint which led to the tribal action under such subsection (d) was lodged may be counted with respect to that local educational agency for the purpose of receiving funds under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7703">section 7703 of this title</ref>. In such event, funds under such section shall not be withheld pursuant to paragraph (8) and no further complaints with respect to such students may be filed under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e45cef1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s7704/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section is based upon the special relationship between the Indian nations and the United States and nothing in this section shall be construed to relieve any State of any duty with respect to any citizens of that State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0e45cef2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/10/tVII/s7004">Pub. L. 89–10, title VII, § 7004</ref>, formerly title VIII, § 8004, as added <ref href="/us/pl/103/382/tI/s101">Pub. L. 103–382, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3759">108 Stat. 3759</ref>; renumbered title VII, § 7004, and amended <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/tVII">Pub. L. 114–95, title VII</ref>, §§ 7001(c)(1), (d)(2), 7005, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/2074">129 Stat. 2074</ref>, 2086.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0e45cef3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0e45cef4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id0e45cef5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 1101(d) of the Education Amendments of 1978, referred to in subsec. (e)(9), is <ref href="/us/pl/95/561/s1101/d">section 1101(d) of Pub. L. 95–561</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2315">92 Stat. 2315</ref>, set out below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id0e45cef6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—<ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s7001/d/2">Pub. L. 114–95, § 7001(d)(2)</ref>, made technical amendments to references in original act which appear in text as references to <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7703">section 7703 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s7005">Pub. L. 114–95, § 7005</ref>, substituted “Indian Education” for “Indian Affairs” in two places.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0e45cef7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0e45cef8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2015 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/114/95">Pub. L. 114–95</ref> effective <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, and effective with respect to appropriations for use under this subchapter beginning fiscal year 2017, except as otherwise provided in such amendment, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s5">section 5 of Pub. L. 114–95</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6301">section 6301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0e45cef9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Contract Authority of Indian Tribes if Remedial Action Is Not Taken; Election To Have Services Provided by Bureau Schools; Special Regulations</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/561/tXI/s1101/d">Pub. L. 95–561, title XI, § 1101(d)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2315">92 Stat. 2315</ref>, directed Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, in cooperation with Commissioner of Education, within one year of <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, to promulgate special regulations which would provide that where a local educational agency had not undertaken the remedial action required by the Commissioner under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s240/b/3/C/vi">20 U.S.C. 240(b)(3)(C)(vi)</ref>, the affected tribes could elect for the Bureau of Indian Affairs to provide educational services provided by the local educational agency.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
