<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0c85819f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80g–1"><num value="80g–1">§ 80g–1.</num><heading> Hubert H. Humphrey Fellowship in Social and Political Thought</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c8581a0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80g–1/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment in Center</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is hereby established in the Center a Hubert H. Humphrey Fellowship in Social and Political Thought.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c8581a1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80g–1/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Selection of Humphrey Fellow; term; compensation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each year the Board shall select a distinguished scholar, statesman, or cultural figure, from the United States or abroad, to serve at the Center for a period of up to one year as the Hubert H. Humphrey Fellow in Social and Political Thought (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Humphrey Fellow”). Each Humphrey Fellow shall receive compensation in an amount, determined by the Board, not to exceed the annual income of the trust fund established under subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c8581a2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80g–1/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Functions of Humphrey Fellow; publication and dissemination by Board of Memorial Lectures</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each Humphrey Fellow shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0c8581a3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80g–1/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> deliver a Hubert H. Humphrey Memorial Lecture; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0c8581a4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80g–1/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> carry out such projects and work as are consistent with the Humphrey Fellowship.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Board shall provide for the publication and dissemination of the Hubert H. Humphrey Memorial Lectures.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c8581a5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80g–1/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Hubert H. Humphrey Fellowship Trust Fund; establishment, composition, investments, etc.</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0c8581a6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80g–1/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the Hubert H. Humphrey Fellowship Trust Fund (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “fund”). The Secretary of the Treasury shall deposit in the fund such sums as may be appropriated to the fund under subsection (f) and shall receive into the Treasury and deposit into the fund such sums as may be received as contributions to the fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0c8581a7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80g–1/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary of the Treasury shall invest amounts in the fund in public debt securities with maturities suitable for the needs of the fund and bearing interest at prevailing market rates; and the interest on such investments shall be credited to and form a part of the fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0c8581a8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80g–1/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s80g/a/2">section 80g(a)(2) of this title</ref> any gift, bequest, or devise of money, securities or other property for the benefit of the Hubert H. Humphrey Fellowship in Social and Political Thought received by the Board shall, upon receipt, be deposited into the fund as provided by paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c8581a9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80g–1/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Payments to Board from investments for implementation of Fellowship purposes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury shall pay to the Board from amounts received as interest on investments under subsection (d)(2) such sums as the Board determines are necessary and appropriate for the purposes of the Humphrey Fellowship.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c8581aa-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80g–1/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the fund for the fiscal year beginning <date date="1978-10-01">October 1, 1978</date>, $1,000,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0c8581ab-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/637/s5">Pub. L. 90–637, § 5</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/95/286/s1/2">Pub. L. 95–286, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1978-05-26">May 26, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/278">92 Stat. 278</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
