<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0c858190-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80g"><num value="80g">§ 80g.</num><heading> Powers and duties of Board</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c858191-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80g/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment of scholars; gifts, bequests, etc.; grants; location of Center; physical facilities; compensation of officers; plans and specifications for Center</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In administering the Center, the Board shall have all necessary and proper powers, which shall include but not be limited to the power to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0c858192-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80g/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> appoint scholars, from the United States and abroad, and, where appropriate, provide stipends, grants, and fellowships to such scholars, and to hire or accept the voluntary services of consultants, advisory boards, and panels to aid the Board in carrying out its responsibilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0c858193-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80g/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> solicit, accept, and dispose of gifts, bequests, and devises of money, securities, and other property of whatsoever character for the benefit of the Center; any such money, securities, or other property shall, upon receipt, be deposited with the Smithsonian Institution, and unless otherwise restricted by the terms of the gift, expenditures shall be in the discretion of the Board for the purposes of the Center;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0c858194-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80g/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> obtain grants from, and make contracts with, State, Federal, local, and private agencies, organizations, institutions, and individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0c858195-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80g/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> acquire such site as a location for the Center as may subsequently be authorized by the Congress;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0c858196-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80g/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> acquire, hold, maintain, use, operate, and dispose of any physical facilities, including equipment, necessary for the operation of the Center;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0c858197-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80g/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> appoint and fix the compensation and duties of the director and such other officers of the Center as may be necessary for the efficient administration of the Center; the director and two other officers of the Center may be appointed and compensated without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service and chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0c858198-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80g/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> prepare plans and specifications for the Center, including the design and development of all buildings, facilities, open spaces, and other structures on the site in consultation with the President’s Temporary Commission on Pennsylvania Avenue, or its successor, and with other appropriate Federal and local agencies, such plans to include an exterior classic frieze memorial to Woodrow Wilson.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c858199-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80g/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Relocation assistance and programs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board shall, in connection with acquisition of any site authorized by Congress, as provided for in paragraph (4) of subsection (a) of this section, provide, to businesses and residents displaced from any such site, relocation assistance, including payments and other benefits, equivalent to that authorized to displace businesses and residents under the Housing Act of 1949, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1441">42 U.S.C. 1441</ref> et seq.]. The Board shall develop a relocation program for existing businesses and residents within the site and submit such program to the government of the District of Columbia for a determination as to its adequacy and feasibility. In providing such relocation assistance and developing such relocation program the Board shall utilize to the maximum extent the services and facilities of the appropriate Federal and local agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0c85819a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/637/s4">Pub. L. 90–637, § 4</ref>, <date date="1968-10-24">Oct. 24, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1358">82 Stat. 1358</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/286/s2">Pub. L. 95–286, § 2</ref>, <date date="1978-05-26">May 26, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/279">92 Stat. 279</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0c85819b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0c85819c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id0c85819d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Housing Act of 1949, as amended, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/act/1949-07-15/ch338">act July 15, 1949, ch. 338</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/413">63 Stat. 413</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 8A (§ 1441 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1441">section 1441 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id0c85819e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/95/286">Pub. L. 95–286</ref> substituted “devises” for “devices”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
