<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0c85822e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80q–5"><num value="80q–5">§ 80q–5.</num><heading> Museum facilities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c85822f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80q–5/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> National Museum mall facility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board of Regents shall plan, design, and construct a facility on the area bounded by Third Street, Maryland Avenue, Independence Avenue, Fourth Street, and Jefferson Drive, Southwest, in the District of Columbia to house the portion of the National Museum to be located in the District of Columbia. The Board of Regents shall pay not more than ⅔ of the total cost of planning, designing, and constructing the facility from funds appropriated to the Board of Regents. The remainder of the costs shall be paid from non-Federal sources.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c858230-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80q–5/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> National Museum Heye Center facility</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0c858231-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80q–5/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Lease of space from GSA</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0c858232-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80q–5/b/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Terms</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding section 586(a) and (b) of title 40, the Administrator of General Services may lease, at a nominal charge, to the Smithsonian Institution space in the Old United States Custom House at One Bowling Green, New York, New York, to house the portion of the National Museum to be located in the city of New York. The lease shall be subject to such terms as may be mutually agreed upon by the Administrator and the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution. The term of the lease shall not be less than 99 years.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0c858233-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80q–5/b/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Reimbursement of Federal buildings fund</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Administrator of General Services may reimburse the fund established by <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s592">section 592 of title 40</ref> for the difference between the amount charged to the Smithsonian Institution for leasing space under this paragraph and the commercial charge under section 586(a) and (b) of title 40 which, but for this paragraph, would apply to the leasing of such space. There are authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subparagraph for fiscal years beginning after <date date="1990-09-30">September 30, 1990</date>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0c87f234-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80q–5/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Construction</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0c87f235-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80q–5/b/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Museum facility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Board of Regents shall plan, design, and construct a significant facility for the National Museum in the space leased under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0c87f236-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80q–5/b/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Auditorium and loading dock facility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Administrator of General Services shall plan, design, and construct an auditorium and loading dock in the Old United States Custom House at One Bowling Green, New York, New York, for the shared use of all the occupants of the building, including the National Museum.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0c87f237-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80q–5/b/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Square footage</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The facilities to be constructed under this paragraph shall have, in the aggregate, a total square footage of approximately 82,500 square feet.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0c87f238-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80q–5/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Repairs and alterations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">After construction of the facility under paragraph (2)(A), repairs and alterations of the facility shall be the responsibility of the Board of Regents.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0c87f239-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80q–5/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Reimbursement of GSA</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Board of Regents shall reimburse the Administrator for the Smithsonian Institution’s pro rata share of the cost of utilities, maintenance, cleaning, and other services incurred with respect to the space leased under paragraph (1) and the full cost of any repairs or alterations made by the General Services Administration at the request of the Smithsonian Institution with respect to the space.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0c87f23a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80q–5/b/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Cost sharing</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0c87f23b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80q–5/b/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> General rules</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Board of Regents shall pay ⅓ of the costs of planning, designing, and constructing the facility under paragraph (2)(A) from funds appropriated to the Board of Regents. The remainder of the costs shall be paid from non-Federal sources.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0c87f23c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80q–5/b/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Responsibilities of New York City and State</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Of the costs which are required to be paid from non-Federal sources under this paragraph, the city of New York, New York, and the State of New York have each agreed to pay $8,000,000 or an amount equal to ⅓ of the costs of planning, designing, and constructing the facility under paragraph (2)(A), whichever is less. Such payments shall be made to the Board of Regents in accordance with a payment schedule to be agreed upon by the city and State and the Board of Regents.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id0c87f23d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80q–5/b/5/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on obligations of Federal funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Federal funds may not be obligated for actual construction of a facility under paragraph (2)(A) in a fiscal year until non-Federal sources have paid to the Board of Regents the non-Federal share of such costs which the Board of Regents estimates will be incurred in such year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0c87f23e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80q–5/b/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Designation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The facility to be constructed under paragraph (2)(A) shall be known and designated as the “George Gustav Heye Center of the National Museum of the American Indian”.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c87f23f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80q–5/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Museum Support Center facility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board of Regents shall plan, design, and construct a facility for the conservation and storage of the collections of the National Museum at the Museum Support Center of the Smithsonian Institution.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c87f240-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80q–5/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Minimum square footage</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The facilities to be constructed under this section shall have, in the aggregate, a total square footage of at least 400,000 square feet.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c87f241-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80q–5/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to contract with GSA</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board of Regents and the Administrator of General Services may enter into such agreements as may be necessary for planning, designing, and constructing facilities under this section (other than subsection (b)(2)(B)). Under such agreements, the Board of Regents shall transfer to the Administrator, from funds available for planning, designing, and constructing such facilities, such amounts as may be necessary for expenses of the General Services Administration with respect to planning, designing, and constructing such facilities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c87f242-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80q–5/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on obligation of Federal funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, funds appropriated for carrying out this section may not be obligated for actual construction of any facility under this section until the 60th day after the date on which the Board of Regents transmits to Congress a written analysis of the total estimated cost of the construction and a cost-sharing plan projecting the amount for Federal appropriations and for non-Federal contributions for the construction on a fiscal year basis.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0c87f243-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/185/s7">Pub. L. 101–185, § 7</ref>, <date date="1989-11-28">Nov. 28, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1339">103 Stat. 1339</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0c87f244-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0c87f245-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id0c87f246-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Section 586(a) and (b) of title 40” substituted in subsec. (b)(1)(A) for “section 210(j) of the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s490/j">40 U.S.C. 490(j)</ref>)”, “<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s592">section 592 of title 40</ref>” substituted in subsec. (b)(1)(B) for “section 210(f) of the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s490/f">40 U.S.C. 490(f)</ref>)”, and “section 586(a) and (b) of title 40” substituted in subsec. (b)(1)(B) for “section 210(j) of such Act” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s5/c">Pub. L. 107–217, § 5(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1303">116 Stat. 1303</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0c87f247-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0c87f248-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">National Native American Veterans’ Memorial</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/384">Pub. L. 103–384</ref>, <date date="1994-10-22">Oct. 22, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4067">108 Stat. 4067</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/113/70/s2">Pub. L. 113–70, § 2</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/1208">127 Stat. 1208</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/70/s2">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1">“SECTION 1.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This Act may be cited as the ‘Native American Veterans’ Memorial Establishment Act of 1994’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="2">“SEC. 2.</num><heading> FINDINGS.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“The Congress finds the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Native Americans across the Nation—Indians, Native Alaskans, and Native Hawaiians—have a long, proud and distinguished tradition of service in the Armed Forces of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Native Americans have historically served in the Armed Forces of the United States in numbers which far exceed their representation in the population of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Native American veterans count among themselves a number of Medal of Honor recipients. Their numbers are also conspicuous in the ranks of those who have received other decorations for valor and distinguished service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Native Americans have lost their lives in the service of their Nation and in the cause of peace.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> The National Museum of the American Indian was established as a living memorial to Native Americans. Its mission is to advance knowledge and understanding of Native American cultures, including art, history, language, and the contributions Native Americans have made to our society.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> The National Museum of the American Indian is an extraordinary site and an ideal location to establish a National Native American Veterans’ Memorial.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> A National Native American Veterans’ Memorial would further the purposes of the National Museum of the American Indian by giving all Americans the opportunity to learn of the proud and courageous tradition of service of Native Americans in the Armed Forces of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="3">“SEC. 3.</num><heading> AUTHORITY TO ESTABLISH MEMORIAL.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The National Museum of the American Indian (established by the National Museum of the American Indian Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s80q">20 U.S.C. 80q</ref> et seq.)), in close consultation with the National Congress of American Indians and other Native American groups, is authorized to construct and maintain a National Native American Veterans’ Memorial (hereafter in this Act referred to as the ‘memorial’).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Location</inline>.—</heading><content>The memorial shall be located at a site determined to be suitable by the Museum on property under the jurisdiction of the Museum on the site described in section 7(a) of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s80q–5/a">20 U.S.C. 80q–5(a)</ref>) (relating to housing the portion of the Museum to be located in the District of Columbia).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Design and Plans</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The National Congress of American Indians and the National Museum of the American Indian are authorized to hold a competition to select the design of the Memorial. Any design so selected shall be compatible with both the purpose of the Museum, as set forth in section 3(b) of the National Museum of the American Indian Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s80q–1">20 U.S.C. 80q–1</ref> [(b)]), and with any existing design plans for the Museum’s structure and its surroundings.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Any design so selected shall be subject to the approval of the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="4">“SEC. 4.</num><heading> PAYMENT OF EXPENSES AND USE OF NAME.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Responsibility of National Congress of American Indians and National Museum of the American Indian</inline>.—</heading><content>The National Congress of American Indians and the National Museum of the American Indian shall be responsible for acceptance of contributions for, and payment of the expenses of, the establishment of the memorial. No Federal funds may be used to pay any expense of the establishment of the memorial.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Name</inline>.—</heading><content>Use of the name of the Smithsonian Institution or the National Museum of the American Indian in any material regarding the memorial produced by the National Congress of American Indians, other than in a manner simply describing the location of the memorial, shall be subject to consultation with, and the approval of, the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution.”</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
