<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0c8a3c74-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80s–1"><num value="80s–1">§ 80s–1.</num><heading> Establishment of joint project at Library of Congress and National Museum of African American History and Culture to collect video and audio recordings of histories of participants in American Civil Rights movement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c8a3c75-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80s–1/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of project</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0c8a3c76-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80s–1/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Within the limits of available funds, the Librarian of Congress (hereafter referred to as the “Librarian”) and the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution (hereafter referred to as the “Secretary)”,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002008">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002008"><num>1</num> So in original. The closing quotation marks probably should precede the closing parenthesis.</note> acting jointly, shall establish an oral history project—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0c8a3c77-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80s–1/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to survey, during the initial phase of the project, collections of audio and video recordings of the reminiscences of participants in the Civil Rights movement that are housed in archives, libraries, museums, and other educational institutions, as well as ongoing documentary work, in order to augment and complement these endeavors and avoid duplication of effort;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0c8a3c78-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80s–1/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> to solicit, reproduce, and collect—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0c8a3c79-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80s–1/a/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> video and audio recordings of personal histories and testimonials of individuals who participated in the Civil Rights movement, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0c8a3c7a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80s–1/a/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> visual and written materials (such as letters, diaries, photographs, and ephemera) relevant to the personal histories of individuals;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0c8a3c7b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80s–1/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> to create a collection of the recordings and other materials obtained, and to catalog and index the collection in a manner the Librarian and the Secretary consider appropriate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0c8a3c7c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80s–1/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> to make the collection available for public use through the Library of Congress and the National Museum of African American History and Culture, as well as through such other methods as the Librarian and the Secretary consider appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id0c8a3c7d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80s–1/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Role of Director of museum</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall carry out the Secretary’s duties under this subchapter through the Director of the National Museum of African American History and Culture.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c8a3c7e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80s–1/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of and consultation with other entities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Librarian and the Secretary may carry out the activities described in subsection (a)(1) through agreements and partnerships entered into with other government and private entities, and may otherwise consult with interested persons (within the limits of available resources) and develop appropriate guidelines and arrangements for soliciting, acquiring, and making available recordings under the project under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c8a3c7f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80s–1/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Services of experts and consultants; acceptance of volunteer services; advance payments</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out activities described in subsection (a)(1), the Librarian and the Secretary may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0c8a3c80-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80s–1/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> procure temporary and intermittent services under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3109">section 3109 of title 5</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0c8a3c81-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80s–1/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> accept and utilize the services of volunteers and other uncompensated personnel and reimburse them for travel expenses, including per diem, as authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5703">section 5703 of title 5</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0c8a3c82-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80s–1/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> make advances of money and payments in advance in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3324">section 3324 of title 31</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c8a3c83-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80s–1/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Timing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As soon as practicable after <date date="2009-05-12">May 12, 2009</date>, the Librarian and the Secretary shall begin collecting video and audio recordings and other materials under subsection (a)(1), and shall attempt to collect the first such recordings from the oldest individuals involved.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0c8a3c84-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s80s–1/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this subchapter, the term “Civil Rights movement” means the movement to secure racial equality in the United States for African Americans that, focusing on the period 1954 through 1968, challenged the practice of racial segregation in the Nation and achieved equal rights legislation for all American citizens.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0c8a3c85-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/111/19/s3">Pub. L. 111–19, § 3</ref>, <date date="2009-05-12">May 12, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1613">123 Stat. 1613</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
