<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0c8cadda-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s84"><num value="84">§ 84.</num><heading> Plans for buildings and bridges</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All plans and specifications for the construction of buildings and bridges in the National Zoological Park shall be prepared under the supervision of the Smithsonian Institution.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id0c8caddb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/act/1912-08-24/ch355/s1">Aug. 24, 1912, ch. 355, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/37/437">37 Stat. 437</ref>; 1966 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. <date date="1966-08-23">Aug. 23, 1966</date>, 31 FR 11137, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1611">80 Stat. 1611</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0c8caddc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id0c8caddd-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I71" topic="reorganizationPlan" id="id0c8cadde-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>REORGANIZATION PLAN NO. 4 OF 1966</b><br />Eff. <date date="1966-08-23">Aug. 23, 1966</date>, 31 F.R. 11137, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1611">80 Stat. 1611</ref></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I25" class="indent1 firstIndent-1">Prepared by the President and transmitted to the Senate and the House of Representatives in Congress assembled, <date date="1966-06-13">June 13, 1966</date>, pursuant to the provisions of the Reorganization Act of 1949, <ref href="/us/stat/63/203">63 Stat. 203</ref>, as amended [see <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s901">5 U.S.C. 901</ref> et seq.].</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I71" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0c8caddf-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered">NATIONAL ZOOLOGICAL PARK BUILDINGS AND BRIDGES</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">All those functions of the Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia which were vested in the municipal architect of the District of Columbia by the provisions of the Act of <date date="1912-08-24">August 24, 1912</date>, c. 355, <ref href="/us/stat/37/437">37 Stat. 437</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s84">20 U.S.C. 84</ref>; D.C. Code [former] § 8–134), in respect of buildings of the National Zoological Park, and all functions of that Board which were vested in the engineer of bridges of the District of Columbia by those provisions in respect of bridges of the National Zoological Park, are hereby transferred to the Smithsonian Institution.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0c8cade0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Message of the President</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">To the Congress of the United States:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">I transmit herewith Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1966, prepared in accordance with the Reorganization Act of 1949, as amended, and providing for a reorganization relating to the National Zoological Park located in the District of Columbia.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Today, all responsibilities for the administration of the park are vested in the Smithsonian Institution with one exception—the function of preparing plans and specifications for the construction of buildings and bridges at the zoo. That statutory responsibility is now conducted by the Board of Commissioners of the District of Columbia [now the Mayor].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Under the accompanying reorganization plan, the responsibility for the preparation of these plans and specifications would be transferred from the District of Columbia Board of Commissioners to the Smithsonian. The complete administration of the park would then be vested in one agency—the Smithsonian Institution. This will allow the more efficient and effective development and management of the park.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In 1912, the functions to be transferred were vested in the Municipal Architect of the District of Columbia and in the Engineers of the Bridges of the District of Columbia. In 1952, they were transferred to the Board of Commissioners.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">When the 1912 act was passed, the District of Columbia shared the costs of capital improvements in the National Zoological Park. In 1961, it ceased sharing these costs, and the Federal Government assumed complete responsibility for financing the improvements. Accordingly, the District government retains no capital improvement responsibilities for the National Zoological Park except those functions relating to construction plans and specifications for buildings and bridges, as specified in the 1912 statute. Upon the transfer of these remaining functions to the Smithsonian Institution, the administration of the National Zoological Park will, at last, be fully centered in one agency. It is not practicable at this time, however, to itemize the resulting reduction in expenditures.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">I have found, after investigation, that each reorganization included in the accompanying reorganization plan is necessary to accomplish one or more of the purposes set forth in section 2(a) of the Reorganization Act of 1949, as amended.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">I recommend that the Congress allow the reorganization plan to become effective.</p>
<signature>
<name>Lyndon B. Johnson.</name>
</signature>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">The White House</inline>, <date date="1966-06-13">June 13, 1966</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
