<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0e673928-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9578"><num value="9578">§ 9578.</num><heading> Scientific or technical employees</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e673929-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9578/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director may appoint, for terms not to exceed 6 years (without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointment in the competitive service) and may compensate (without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates) such scientific or technical employees to carry out the functions of the Institute or the office, board, committee, or center, respectively, if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e67392a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9578/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> at least 30 days prior to the appointment of any such employee, public notice is given of the availability of such position and an opportunity is provided for qualified individuals to apply and compete for such position;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e67392b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9578/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the rate of basic pay for such employees does not exceed the maximum rate of basic pay payable for positions at GS–15, as determined in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5376">section 5376 of title 5</ref>, except that not more than 7 individuals appointed under this section may be paid at a rate that does not exceed the rate of basic pay for level III of the Executive Schedule;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e67392c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9578/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the appointment of such employee is necessary (as determined by the Director on the basis of clear and convincing evidence) to provide the Institute or the office, board, committee, or center with scientific or technical expertise which could not otherwise be obtained by the Institute or the office, board, committee, or center through the competitive service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e67392d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9578/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the total number of such employees does not exceed 40 individuals or ⅕ of the number of full-time, regular scientific or professional employees of the Institute, whichever is greater.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e67392e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9578/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties of employees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All employees described in subsection (a) shall work on activities of the Institute or the office, board, committee, or center, and shall not be reassigned to other duties outside the Institute or the office, board, committee, or center during their term.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0e67392f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/107/279/tI/s188">Pub. L. 107–279, title I, § 188</ref>, <date date="2002-11-05">Nov. 5, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1973">116 Stat. 1973</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0e673930-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0e673931-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id0e673932-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">GS–15, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), is contained in the General Schedule, which is set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5332">section 5332 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Level III of the Executive Schedule, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), is set out in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5314">section 5314 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0e673933-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0e673934-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References to Maximum Rate Under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5376">5 U.S.C. 5376</ref></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For reference to maximum rate under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5376">section 5376 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/372/s2/d/3">section 2(d)(3) of Pub. L. 110–372</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 2008 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5376">section 5376 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
