<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0cb0619e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959"><num value="959">§ 959.</num><heading> Administrative provisions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0cb0619f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> General authority of Chairpersons</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In addition to any authorities vested in them by other provisions of this subchapter, the Chairperson of the National Endowment for the Arts and the Chairperson of the National Endowment for the Humanities, in carrying out their respective functions, shall each have authority—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0cb061a0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to prescribe such regulations as the Chairperson deems necessary governing the manner in which the Chairperson’s functions shall be carried out;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0cb061a1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> in the discretion of the Chairperson of an Endowment, after receiving the recommendation of the National Council of that Endowment, to receive money and other property donated, bequeathed, or devised to that Endowment with or without a condition or restriction, including a condition that the Chairperson use other funds of that Endowment for the purposes of the gift, except that a Chairperson may receive a gift without a recommendation from the Council to provide support for any application or project which can be approved without Council recommendation under the provisions of sections 955(f) and 957(f) of this title, and may receive a gift of $15,000, or less, without Council recommendation in the event the Council fails to provide such recommendation within a reasonable period of time, and to use, sell, or otherwise dispose of such property for the purpose of carrying out sections 954(c) and 956(c) of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0cb061a2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to appoint employees, subject to the civil service laws, as necessary to carry out the Chairperson’s functions, define their duties, and supervise and direct their activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0cb061a3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to utilize experts and consultants, including panels of experts, who may be employed as authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3109">section 3109 of title 5</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0cb061a4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> to accept and utilize the services of voluntary and uncompensated personnel and reimburse them for travel expenses, including per diem, as authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5703">section 5703 of title 5</ref> for persons in the Government service employed without compensation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0cb061a5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> to make advance, progress, and other payments without regard to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3324">section 3324 of title 31</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0cb061a6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> to rent office space in the District of Columbia; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0cb061a7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> to make other necessary expenditures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0cb061a8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Rules for distribution of donations, bequests, and devises; gifts with or without conditions; transfers for tax purposes</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0cb061a9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In any case in which any money or other property is donated, bequeathed, or devised to the Foundation without designation of the Endowment for the benefit of which such property is intended, and without condition or restriction other than that it be used for the purposes of the Foundation, such property shall be deemed to have been donated, bequeathed, or devised in equal shares to each Endowment and each Chairperson of an Endowment shall have authority to receive such property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0cb061aa-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In any case in which any money or other property is donated, bequeathed, or devised to the Foundation with a condition or restriction, such property shall be deemed to have been donated, bequeathed, or devised to that Endowment whose function it is to carry out the purpose or purposes described or referred to by the terms of such condition or restriction, and each Chairperson of an Endowment shall have authority to receive such property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0cb061ab-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> For the purposes of the preceding sentence, if one or more of the purposes of such a condition or restriction is covered by the functions of both Endowments, or if some of the purposes of such a condition or restriction are covered by the functions of one Endowment and other of the purposes of such a condition or restriction are covered by the functions of the other Endowment, the Federal Council on the Arts and the Humanities shall determine an equitable manner for distribution between each of the Endowments of the property so donated, bequeathed, or devised.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0cb061ac-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> For the purposes of the income tax, gift tax, and estate tax laws of the United States, any money or other property donated, bequeathed, or devised to the Foundation or one of its Endowments and received by the Chairperson of an Endowment pursuant to authority derived under this subsection shall be deemed to have been donated, bequeathed, or devised to or for the use of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0cb061ad-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Advisory panels; membership; procedures</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Chairperson of the National Endowment for the Arts shall utilize advisory panels to review applications, and to make recommendations to the National Council on the Arts in all cases except cases in which the Chairperson exercises authority delegated under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s955/f">section 955(f) of this title</ref>. When reviewing applications, such panels shall recommend applications for projects, productions, and workshops solely on the basis of artistic excellence and artistic merit. The Chairperson shall issue regulations and establish procedures—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0cb061ae-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to ensure that all panels are composed, to the extent practicable, of individuals reflecting a wide geographic, ethnic, and minority representation as well as individuals reflecting diverse artistic and cultural points of view;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0cb061af-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to ensure that all panels include representation of lay individuals who are knowledgeable about the arts but who are not engaged in the arts as a profession and are not members of either artists’ organizations or arts organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0cb061b0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to ensure that, when feasible, the procedures used by panels to carry out their responsibilities are standardized;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0cb061b1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> to require panels—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0cb061b2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> to create written records summarizing—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0cb061b3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/c/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> all meetings and discussions of such panel; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id0cb061b4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/c/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the recommendations made by such panel to the Council; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0cb061b5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to make such records available to the public in a manner that protects the privacy of individual applicants and panel members;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0cb061b6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> to require, when necessary and feasible, the use of site visitations to view the work of the applicant and deliver a written report on the work being reviewed, in order to assist panelists in making their recommendations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0cb061b7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> to require that the membership of each panel change substantially from year to year and to provide that each individual is ineligible to serve on a panel for more than 3 consecutive years.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">In making appointments to panels, the Chairperson shall ensure that an individual who has a pending application for financial assistance under this subchapter, or who is an employee or agent of an organization with a pending application, does not serve as a member of any panel before which such application is pending. The prohibition described in the preceding sentence shall commence with respect to such individual beginning on the date such application is submitted and shall continue for so long as such application is pending.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0cb061b8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Endowment activities reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Chairperson of the National Endowment for the Arts and the Chairperson of the National Endowment for the Humanities shall each submit an annual report to the President for transmittal to the Congress on or before the 15th day of April of each year. The report shall summarize the activities of the Endowment for the preceding year, and may include such recommendations as the Chairperson deems appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0cb061b9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Council activities reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The National Council on the Arts and the National Council on the Humanities, respectively, may each submit an annual report to the President for transmittal to the Congress on or before the 15th day of April of each year setting forth a summary of its activities during the preceding year or its recommendations for any measures which it considers necessary or desirable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0cb061ba-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Post-award evaluation of assisted projects, productions, and programs; reports; extension of time for compliance; failure to satisfy purposes of assistance</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0cb061bb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Chairperson of the National Endowment for the Arts and the Chairperson of the National Endowment for the Humanities shall conduct a post-award evaluation of projects, productions, and programs for which financial assistance is provided by their respective Endowments under sections 954(c) and 956(c) of this title. Such evaluation may include an audit to determine the accuracy of the reports required to be submitted by recipients under clauses (i) and (ii) of paragraph (2)(A). As a condition of receiving such financial assistance, a recipient shall comply with the requirements specified in paragraph (2) that are applicable to the project, production, or program for which such financial assistance is received.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0cb061bc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0cb061bd-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> The recipient of financial assistance provided by either of the Endowments shall submit to the Chairperson of the Endowment involved—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0cb061be-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/f/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a financial report containing such information as the Chairperson deems necessary to ensure that such financial assistance is expended in accordance with the terms and conditions under which it is provided;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0cb061bf-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/f/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a report describing the project, production, or program carried out with such financial assistance; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0cb061c0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/f/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> if practicable, as determined by the Chairperson, a copy of such project, production, or program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0cb061c1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Such recipient shall comply with the requirements of this paragraph not later than 90 days after the end of the period for which such financial assistance is provided. The Chairperson may extend the 90-day period only if the recipient shows good cause why such an extension should be granted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id0cb061c2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> If such recipient substantially fails to satisfy the purposes for which such financial assistance is provided and the criteria specified in subsection (c)(3)(A),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002022">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002022"><num>1</num> So in original. Subsec. (c)(3) does not contain a subpar. (A).</note> as determined by the Chairperson of the Endowment that provided such financial assistance, then such Chairperson may—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0cb061c3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/f/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> for purposes of determining whether to provide any subsequent financial assistance, take into consideration the results of the post-award evaluation conducted under this subsection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0cb061c4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/f/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> prohibit the recipient of such financial assistance to use the name of, or in any way associate such project, production, or program with the Endowment that provided such financial assistance; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0cb061c5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s959/f/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> if such project, production, or program is published, require that the publication contain the following statement: “The opinions, findings, conclusions, and recommendations expressed herein do not reflect the views of the National Endowment for the Arts or the National Endowment for the Humanities.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0cb061c6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/209/s10">Pub. L. 89–209, § 10</ref>, <date date="1965-09-29">Sept. 29, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/852">79 Stat. 852</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/348/s5">Pub. L. 90–348, § 5</ref>, <date date="1968-06-18">June 18, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/186">82 Stat. 186</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/346">Pub. L. 91–346</ref>, §§ 5(a)(3), 10, 11, <date date="1970-07-20">July 20, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/443">84 Stat. 443</ref>, 446; <ref href="/us/pl/93/133/s2/a/9">Pub. L. 93–133, § 2(a)(9)</ref>, (10), <date date="1973-10-19">Oct. 19, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/465">87 Stat. 465</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/496/tI/s107">Pub. L. 96–496, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1980-12-04">Dec. 4, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2588">94 Stat. 2588</ref>; renumbered title I, § 10, <ref href="/us/pl/98/306/s2">Pub. L. 98–306, § 2</ref>, <date date="1984-05-31">May 31, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/223">98 Stat. 223</ref>; renumbered § 10 and amended <ref href="/us/pl/99/194/tI">Pub. L. 99–194, title I</ref>, §§ 101(1), 110, <date date="1985-12-20">Dec. 20, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1332">99 Stat. 1332</ref>, 1339; <ref href="/us/pl/101/512/tIII/s318/tI/s109">Pub. L. 101–512, title III, § 318 [title I, § 109]</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1960">104 Stat. 1960</ref>, 1970.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0cb061c7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0cb061c8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id0cb061c9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (a)(5), reference to “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5703">section 5703 of title 5</ref>” substituted for “law (<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s73b–2">5 U.S.C. 73b–2</ref>)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s7/b">Pub. L. 89–554, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/631">80 Stat. 631</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id0cb061ca-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/512/s318/tI/s109/5/A">Pub. L. 101–512, § 318 [title I, § 109(5)(A)]</ref>, redesignated concluding provisions of subsec. (a) as subsec. (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/101/512/s318/tI/s109/1/A">Pub. L. 101–512, § 318 [title I, § 109(1)(A)]</ref>, struck out “from time to time, as appropriate,” after “to utilize”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/101/512/s318/tI/s109/1/B">Pub. L. 101–512, § 318 [title I, § 109(1)(B)]</ref>, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3324">section 3324 of title 31</ref>” for “the provisions of section 3648 of the Revised Statutes (<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s529">31 U.S.C. 529</ref>)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/101/512/s318/tI/s109/9">Pub. L. 101–512, § 318 [title I, § 109(9)]</ref>, which directed amendment of this section by striking the sixth sentence and all that follows through “pending.” was executed by striking all that follows through “pending.” the second place it appeared to reflect the probable intent of Congress. The provisions struck out read as follows: “In selecting panels of experts under clause (4) to review and make recommendations with respect to the approval of applications for financial assistance under this subchapter, each Chairperson shall appoint individuals who have exhibited expertise and leadership in the field under review, who broadly represent diverse characteristics in terms of aesthetic or humanistic perspective, and geographical factors, and who broadly represent cultural diversity. Each Chairperson shall assure that the membership of panels changes substantially from year to year, and that no more than 20 per centum of the annual appointments shall be for service beyond the limit of three consecutive years on a subpanel. In making appointments, each Chairperson shall give due regard to the need for experienced as well as new members on each panel. Panels of experts appointed to review or make recommendations with respect to the approval of applications or projects for funding by the National Endowment for the Arts shall, when reviewing such applications and projects, recommend for funding only applications and projects that in the context in which they are presented, in the experts’ view, foster excellence, are reflective of exceptional talent, and have significant literary, scholarly, cultural, or artistic merit. Whenever there is pending an application submitted by an individual for financial assistance under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s954/c">section 954(c) of this title</ref>, such individual may not serve as a member of any subpanel (or panel where a subpanel does not exist) before which such application is pending. The prohibition described in the previous sentence shall commence on the date the application is submitted and continue for so long as the application is pending.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/512/s318/tI/s109/8">Pub. L. 101–512, § 318 [title I, § 109(8)]</ref>, which directed amendment of the fifth sentence of this section by making the substitution for “For the purpose”, was executed by substituting “(4) For the purposes” for “For the purposes” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/512/s318/tI/s109/4">Pub. L. 101–512, § 318 [title I, § 109(4)–(7)]</ref>, redesignated concluding provisions of subsec. (a) as subsec. (b), inserted pars. (1), (2), and (3) designations, and struck out “(A)” before “without designation” and “(B)” before “without condition”. Former subsec. (b) redesignated (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c) to (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/512/s318/tI/s109/3">Pub. L. 101–512, § 318 [title I, § 109(3), (4), (9)]</ref>, added subsec. (c), redesignated former subsecs. (b) and (c) as (d) and (e), respectively, and struck out former subsec. (e) which related to studies and reports on the state and quality of arts and humanities education in public elementary and secondary schools. Former subsec. (d) redesignated (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/101/512/s318/tI/s109/2">Pub. L. 101–512, § 318 [title I, § 109(2)–(4)]</ref>, redesignated subsec. (d) as (f) and, in par. (3), substituted “subsection (c)(3)(A)” for “the last sentence of subsection (a)”, and struck out former subsec. (f) which related to report to Congress on selection of experts for appointment to panels, and procedures for recommendations on financial assistance applications.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/194/s110/1">Pub. L. 99–194, § 110(1)</ref>, substituted “Chairperson” for “Chairman” in two places in provisions preceding cl. (1); in cl. (1) substituted “the chairperson” and “the chairperson’s” for “he” and “his”, respectively; in cl. (2) substituted “Chairperson” for “Chairman” wherever appearing; in cl. (3) substituted “the Chairperson’s” for “his”; in cl. (4) substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3109">section 3109 of title 5</ref>” for “section 15 of the Administrative Expenses Act of 1946, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s55a">5 U.S.C. 55a</ref>)” and struck out proviso that any advisory panel appointed to review or make recommendations with respect to the approval of applications or projects for funding was to have broad geographic and culturally diverse representation; and in provisions following par. (8) substituted “Chairperson” for “Chairman” wherever appearing and inserted provisions relating to the selection of a panel of experts to review financial assistance applications and the considerations to be made in the review of such applications.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/194/s110/2">Pub. L. 99–194, § 110(2)</ref>, substituted “Chairperson” for “Chairman” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d) to (f). <ref href="/us/pl/99/194/s110/3">Pub. L. 99–194, § 110(3)</ref>, added subsecs. (d) to (f). Former subsec. (d), relating to studies and reports to the President and the Congress on endowment uses of donations, bequests, and devises, was struck out.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/96/496/s107/a">Pub. L. 96–496, § 107(a)</ref>, inserted “and culturally diverse”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/496/s107/b">Pub. L. 96–496, § 107(b)</ref>, (c), substituted “April” for “January”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/96/496/s107/d">Pub. L. 96–496, § 107(d)</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/93/133/s2/a/9">Pub. L. 93–133, § 2(a)(9)</ref>, added exception that a Chairman may receive a gift without a recommendation from the Council to provide support for any application or project which can be approved without Council recommendation under the provisions of sections 955(f) and 957(f) of this title, and may receive a gift of $15,000 or less without Council recommendation when the Council fails to recommend within a reasonable period of time.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/93/133/s2/a/10">Pub. L. 93–133, § 2(a)(10)</ref>, inserted proviso that any advisory panel appointed to review or make recommendations with respect to the approval of applications or projects for funding shall have broad geographic representation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/91/346/s5/a/3">Pub. L. 91–346, § 5(a)(3)</ref>, struck out reference to the functions transferred by <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s955/a">section 955(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3) to (5). <ref href="/us/pl/91/346/s11/1">Pub. L. 91–346, § 11(1)</ref>–(3), inserted “to” at beginning of cls. (3) to (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6) to (8). <ref href="/us/pl/91/346">Pub. L. 91–346</ref>, §§ 10, 11(4), (5), redesignated cls. (6) and (7), and all references thereto, as cls. (7) and (8), added new cl. (6), and inserted “to” at beginning of cls. (7) and (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/90/348">Pub. L. 90–348</ref> combined provisions of cls. (2) and (3) into cl. (2), and, in cl. (2) as thus combined, extended the area for the exercise of discretion of the Chairman of an Endowment, after receiving the recommendation of the National Council of that Endowment, in the disposition of gifts to include both gifts made with condition and gifts made without condition, redesignated cls. (4) to (8) as (3) to (7), and in provisions following cl. (7), struck out references to cls. (2) and (3) wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id0cb061cb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0cb061cc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/512">Pub. L. 101–512</ref> effective <date date="1990-10-01">Oct. 1, 1990</date>, see section 318 [title IV, § 403(a)] of <ref href="/us/pl/101/512">Pub. L. 101–512</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s951">section 951 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0cb061cd-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1973 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/93/133">Pub. L. 93–133</ref> effective on and after <date date="1973-07-01">July 1, 1973</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/133/s2/b">section 2(b) of Pub. L. 93–133</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s951">section 951 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id0cb061ce-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1970 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/346/s5/a/3">section 5(a)(3) of Pub. L. 91–346</ref> effective after <date date="1970-06-30">June 30, 1970</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/346/s5/d/3/A">section 5(d)(3)(A) of Pub. L. 91–346</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s955">section 955 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0cb061cf-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, of provisions of law requiring submittal to Congress of any annual, semiannual, or other regular periodic report listed in House Document No. 103–7 (in which certain reporting requirements under subsec. (d) of this section are listed in item 7 on page 183), see <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, and section 1(a)(4) [div. A, § 1402(1)] of <ref href="/us/pl/106/554">Pub. L. 106–554</ref>, set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id0cb061d0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id0cb061d1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Certain Reporting Authority</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, 69 F.R. 74937, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum for the Chairperson of the National Endowment for the Arts</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, including <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref>, United States Code, I hereby delegate to you the functions conferred upon the President in the National Foundation on the Arts and Humanities Act of 1965, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s959/d">20 U.S.C. 959(d)</ref>) to provide the specified report relating to the National Endowment for the Arts to the Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the Federal Register.</p>
<signature>
<name>George W. Bush.</name>
</signature>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, 69 F.R. 74939, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum for the Chairperson of the National Endowment for the Humanities</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, including <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref>, United States Code, I hereby delegate to you the functions conferred upon the President in the National Foundation on the Arts and Humanities Act of 1965, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s959/d">20 U.S.C. 959(d)</ref>) to provide the specified report relating to the National Endowment for the Humanities to the Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the Federal Register.</p>
<signature>
<name>George W. Bush.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
