<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0e6bf591-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9831"><num value="9831">§ 9831.</num><heading> Purpose</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the purpose of this part—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6bf592-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9831/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to raise academic achievement through Advanced Placement and International Baccalaureate programs by increasing, by 70,000, over a 4-year period beginning in 2008, the number of teachers serving high-need schools who are qualified to teach Advanced Placement or International Baccalaureate courses in mathematics, science, and critical foreign languages;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6bf593-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9831/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> to increase, to 700,000 per year, the number of students attending high-need schools who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e6bf594-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9831/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> take and score a 3, 4, or 5 on an Advanced Placement examination in mathematics, science, or a critical foreign language administered by the College Board; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e6bf595-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9831/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> achieve a passing score on an examination administered by the International Baccalaureate Organization in such a subject;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6bf596-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9831/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to increase the availability of, and enrollment in, Advanced Placement or International Baccalaureate courses in mathematics, science, and critical foreign languages, and pre-Advanced Placement or pre-International Baccalaureate courses in such subjects, in high-need schools; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6bf597-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9831/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to support statewide efforts to increase the availability of, and enrollment in, Advanced Placement or International Baccalaureate courses in mathematics, science, and critical foreign languages, and pre-Advanced Placement or pre-International Baccalaureate courses in such subjects, in high-need schools.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id0e6bf598-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/110/69/tVI/s6121">Pub. L. 110–69, title VI, § 6121</ref>, <date date="2007-08-09">Aug. 9, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/634">121 Stat. 634</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
