<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id0e6e6696-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903"><num value="9903">§ 9903.</num><heading> Grant program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e6e6697-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director shall establish a grant program to support programs at institutions of higher education to carry out the purpose of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e6e6698-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Geographical considerations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the administration of this chapter, the Director shall take such steps as may be necessary to ensure that grants are equitably distributed across all regions of the United States, taking into account population density and other geographic and demographic considerations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e6e6699-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount of grant</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to the requirements of subsection (d), the Director may award grants annually on a competitive basis to institutions of higher education in the amount of $2,000,000, per institution of which—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6e669a-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> $1,500,000 shall be used—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e6e669b-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to design, implement, and evaluate a program that meets the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s9902">section 9902 of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e6e669c-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to employ master teachers at the institution to oversee field experiences;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e6e669d-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> to provide a stipend to mentor teachers participating in the program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e6e669e-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/c/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> to support curriculum development and implementation strategies for science, technology, engineering, and mathematics content courses taught through the program; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6e669f-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> up to $500,000 shall be set aside by the grantee for technical support and evaluation services from the institution whose programs will be replicated.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e6e66a0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To be eligible to apply for a grant under this section, an institution of higher education shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6e66a1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> include former secondary school science, technology, engineering, or mathematics master teachers as faculty in its science department for this program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6e66a2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> grant terminal degrees in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6e66a3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> have a process to be used in establishing partnerships with local educational agencies for placement of participating students in their field experiences, including a process for identifying mentor teachers working in local schools to supervise classroom field experiences in cooperation with university-based master teachers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6e66a4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> maintain policies allowing flexible entry to the program throughout the undergraduate coursework;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6e66a5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> require that master teachers employed by the institution will supervise field experiences of students in the program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6e66a6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> require that the program complies with State certification or licensing requirements and the requirements under section 9101(23) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002257">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002257"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7801/23">20 U.S.C. 7801(23)</ref>) for highly qualified teachers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6e66a7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/d/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><chapeau> develop during the course of the grant a plan for long-term support and assessment of its graduates, which shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e6e66a8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/d/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> induction support for graduates in their first one to two years of teaching;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e6e66a9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/d/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> systems to determine the teaching status of graduates and thereby determine retention rates; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id0e6e66aa-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/d/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> methods to analyze the achievement of students taught by graduates, and methods to analyze classroom practices of graduates; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6e66ab-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/d/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> be able upon completion of the grant at the end of 5 years to fund essential program costs, including salaries of master teachers and other necessary personnel, from recurring university budgets.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e6e66ac-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Application requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An institution of higher education seeking a grant under the program shall submit an application to the Director in such form, at such time, and containing such information and assurances as the Director may require, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6e66ad-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a description of the current rate at which individuals majoring in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics become certified as elementary and secondary teachers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6e66ae-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a description for the institution’s plan for increasing the numbers of students enrolled in and graduating from the program supported under this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6e66af-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a description of the institution’s capacity to develop a program in which individuals majoring in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics can become certified as elementary and secondary teachers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6e66b0-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> identification of the organizational unit within the department or division of arts and sciences or the science department at the institution that will adopt teacher certification for elementary and secondary teachers as its primary mission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6e66b1-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> identification of core faculty within the department or division of arts and sciences or the science department at the institution to champion teacher preparation in their departments by teaching courses dedicated to preparing future elementary and secondary school teachers, helping create new degree plans, advising prospective students within their major, and assisting as needed with program administration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6e66b2-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/e/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> identification of core faculty in the education department or its equivalent at the institution to champion teacher preparation by creating and teaching courses specific to the preparation of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics and working closely with colleagues in the department or division of arts and sciences or the science department; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6e66b3-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/e/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> a description of involving practical, field-based experience in teaching and degree plans enabling students to graduate in 4 years with a major in science, technology, engineering, or mathematics and elementary or secondary school teacher certification.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e6e66b4-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Matching requirement</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An institution of higher education may not receive a grant under this section unless it provides, from non-federal sources, to carry out the activities supported by the grant, an amount that is not less than—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6e66b5-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> 35 percent of the amount of the grant for the first fiscal year of the grant;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6e66b6-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> 55 percent of the amount of the grant for the second and third fiscal years of the grant; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id0e6e66b7-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> 75 percent of the amount of the grant for the fourth and fifth fiscal years of the grant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id0e6e66b8-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795" identifier="/us/usc/t20/s9903/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Guidance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within 90 days after <date date="2011-01-04">January 4, 2011</date>, the Director shall initiate a proceeding to promulgate guidance for the administration of the grant program established under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id0e6e66b9-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">(<ref href="/us/pl/111/358/tV/s553">Pub. L. 111–358, title V, § 553</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4022">124 Stat. 4022</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id0e6e66ba-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id0e6e66bb-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id0e6e66bc-3a70-11f1-a648-bee82ed8a795">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965, referred to in subsec. (d)(6), was amended by <ref href="/us/pl/114/95">Pub. L. 114–95</ref> and, as so amended, is now section 8101 of the Act and no longer relates to highly qualified teachers. A reference in this section to “highly qualified”, as defined in section 9101 of the Act, with respect to a teacher, means that the teacher meets applicable State certification and licensure requirements, including any requirements for certification obtained through alternative routes to certification. See <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s9214/a/2">section 9214(a)(2) of Pub. L. 114–95</ref>, set out as a Use of the Term “Highly Qualified” in Other Laws note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070g–2">section 1070g–2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
