<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd0a7e74-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c" identifier="/us/usc/t13/s191"><num value="191">§ 191.</num><heading> Geographic scope of censuses</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd0a7e75-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c" identifier="/us/usc/t13/s191/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Each of the censuses authorized by this chapter shall include each State, the District of Columbia, the Virgin Islands, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and as may be determined by the Secretary, such other possessions and areas over which the United States exercises jurisdiction, control, or sovereignty. Inclusion of other areas over which the United States exercises jurisdiction or control shall be subject to the concurrence of the Secretary of State.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd0a7e76-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c" identifier="/us/usc/t13/s191/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> For censuses taken in the Virgin Islands, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or any possession or area not specifically designated in subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary may use census information collected by the Governor or highest ranking Federal official, if such information was obtained in accordance with plans prescribed or approved by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd0a7e77-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c" identifier="/us/usc/t13/s191/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> If, pursuant to a determination by the Secretary under subsection (a) of this section, any census is not taken in a possession or area over which the United States exercises jurisdiction, control, or sovereignty, the Secretary may include data obtained from other Federal agencies or government sources in the census report. Any data obtained from foreign governments shall be obtained through the Secretary of State.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd0a7e78-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c">(Added <ref href="/us/pl/85/207/s14">Pub. L. 85–207, § 14</ref>, <date date="1957-08-28">Aug. 28, 1957</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/71/483">71 Stat. 483</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/94/521/s9">Pub. L. 94–521, § 9</ref>, <date date="1976-10-17">Oct. 17, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2463">90 Stat. 2463</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd0a7e79-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd0a7e7a-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd0a7e7b-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/521">Pub. L. 94–521</ref> struck out “(other than censuses of population)” after “this chapter” and “Alaska, Hawaii” after “the District of Columbia”, inserted “the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands” after “Guam”, and struck out provision that censuses of population shall include all geographic areas referred to in first sentence of subsec. (a).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/94/521">Pub. L. 94–521</ref> inserted “the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands” after “Guam”, and substituted “use census information” for “utilize or adopt census data” and “if such information was obtained” for “when such data are obtained”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/94/521">Pub. L. 94–521</ref> substituted “If, pursuant to a determination by the Secretary under subsection (a) of this section” for “When, under determination by the Secretary as provided in paragraph (a) above”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd0a7e7c-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbd0a7e7d-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/521">Pub. L. 94–521</ref> effective <date date="1976-10-17">Oct. 17, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/521/s17">section 17 of Pub. L. 94–521</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbd0a7e7e-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd0a7e7f-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Admission of Alaska and Hawaii to Statehood</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Alaska was admitted into the Union on <date date="1959-01-03">Jan. 3, 1959</date>, on issuance of Proc. No. 3269, <date date="1959-01-03">Jan. 3, 1959</date>, 24 F.R. 81, 73 Stat. c16, and Hawaii was admitted into the Union on <date date="1959-08-21">Aug. 21, 1959</date>, on issuance of Proc. No. 3309, <date date="1959-08-21">Aug. 21, 1959</date>, 24 F.R. 6868, 73 Stat. c74. For Alaska Statehood Law, see <ref href="/us/pl/85/508">Pub. L. 85–508</ref>, <date date="1958-07-07">July 7, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/339">72 Stat. 339</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s21">section 21 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions. For Hawaii Statehood Law, see <ref href="/us/pl/86/3">Pub. L. 86–3</ref>, <date date="1959-03-18">Mar. 18, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/4">73 Stat. 4</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s491">section 491 of Title 48</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
