<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd0a7e9a-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c" identifier="/us/usc/t13/s212"><num value="212">§ 212.</num><heading> Refusal or neglect of employees to perform duties</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whoever, being an employee referred to in subchapter II of chapter 1 of this title, and having taken and subscribed the oath of office, neglects or refuses, without justifiable cause, to perform the duties enjoined on such employee by this title, shall be fined not more than $500.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbd0a7e9b-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-31/ch1158">Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/1022">68 Stat. 1022</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd0a7e9c-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idbd0a7e9d-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on title 13, U.S.C., 1952 ed., §§ 122, 208, 252, and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1442">section 1442 of title 42</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., The Public Health and Welfare (<ref href="/us/act/1929-06-18/ch28/s8">June 18, 1929, ch. 28, § 8</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/23">46 Stat. 23</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-19/ch502/s2">June 19, 1948, ch. 502, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/479">62 Stat. 479</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-06-19/ch338">June 19, 1949, ch. 338</ref>, title VI, § 607, <ref href="/us/stat/63/441">63 Stat. 441</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1950-09-07/ch910/s2">Sept. 7, 1950, ch. 910, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/784">64 Stat. 784</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section consolidates part of <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s208">section 208 of title 13</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., which was a part of chapter 4 of such title relating to the censuses of population, agriculture, etc., with those parts of sections 122 and 252 of such title which made such section 208 applicable to the censuses of manufacturers, the mineral industries and other businesses, and governments, and with that part of subsection (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1442">section 1442 of title 42</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., which made such section 208 applicable to the housing censuses. For remainder of sections 122, 208 and 252 of title 13, U.S.C., 1952 ed., and of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1442">section 1442 of title 42</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., (which section has been transferred in its entirety to this revised title), see Distribution Table.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section has been made applicable to all employees referred to in subchapter II of chapter 1 of this title, and to duties enjoined on them by any provision of this title, which was probably the original legislative intent.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The words “being an employee referred to in subchapter II of chapter 1 of this title” were substituted for the enumeration in <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s208">section 208 of title 13</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., of “supervisor, supervisor’s clerk, enumerator, interpreter, special agent, or other employee”, since such reference will cover those employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reference in <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s208">section 208 of title 13</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., to the offense, herein described as a misdemeanor, and words therein “, and upon conviction thereof”, were omitted, the former, as superseded and covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1">section 1 of title 18</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., Crimes and Criminal Procedure, classifying offenses, and the latter, as surplusage.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Changes were made in phraseology.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
