<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd0a7ea6-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c" identifier="/us/usc/t13/s214"><num value="214">§ 214.</num><heading> Wrongful disclosure of information</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whoever, being or having been an employee or staff member referred to in subchapter II of chapter 1 of this title, having taken and subscribed the oath of office, or having sworn to observe the limitations imposed by <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s9">section 9 of this title</ref>, or whoever, being or having been a census liaison within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s16">section 16 of this title</ref>, publishes or communicates any information, the disclosure of which is prohibited under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s9">section 9 of this title</ref>, and which comes into his possession by reason of his being employed (or otherwise providing services) under the provisions of this title, shall be fined not more than $5,000 or imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbd0a7ea7-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-31/ch1158">Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/1023">68 Stat. 1023</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/521/s12/a">Pub. L. 94–521, § 12(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-17">Oct. 17, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2464">90 Stat. 2464</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/430/s2/c">Pub. L. 103–430, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4394">108 Stat. 4394</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd0a7ea8-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idbd0a7ea9-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on title 13, U.S.C., 1952 ed., §§ 73, 83, 122, 208, 252, and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1442">section 1442 of title 42</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., The Public Health and Welfare (<ref href="/us/act/1916-08-07/ch274/s3">Aug. 7, 1916, ch. 274, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/437">39 Stat. 437</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1924-04-02/ch80/s3">Apr. 2, 1924, ch. 80, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/43/31">43 Stat. 31</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1929-06-18/ch28">June 18, 1929, ch. 28</ref>, §§ 8, 21, <ref href="/us/stat/46/23">46 Stat. 23</ref>, 26; <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-25/ch331">July 25, 1947, ch. 331</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/437">61 Stat. 437</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-19/ch502/s2">June 19, 1948, ch. 502, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/479">62 Stat. 479</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-07-15/ch338">July 15, 1949, ch. 338</ref>, title VI, § 607, <ref href="/us/stat/63/441">63 Stat. 441</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1950-09-07/ch910/s2">Sept. 7, 1950, ch. 910, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/784">64 Stat. 784</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section consolidates parts of sections 73, 83 and 208 of title 13, U.S.C., 1952 ed., that part of section 122 of such title which made such section 208 applicable to the quinquennial censuses of manufactures, the mineral industries, and other businesses (see subchapter I of chapter 5 of this revised title), that part of section 252 of such title which made such section 208 applicable to the quinquennial censuses of governments (see subchapter III of chapter 5 of this revised title), and that part of subsection (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1442">section 1442 of title 42</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., which made such section 208 applicable to the decennial censuses of housing (see subchapter II of chapter 5 of this title).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Words “Secretary or other authorized officer or employee of the Department of Commerce or bureau or agency thereof” were substituted for reference to the Director of the Census. See Revision Note to <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s9">section 9 of this title</ref>, into which other parts of sections 73, 83 and 208 of title 13, U.S.C., 1952 ed., have been carried.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The provision in <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s208">section 208 of title 13</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., designating the offense as a felony, was omitted as covered by <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1">section 1 of title 18</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., Crimes and Criminal Procedure, and words in such section “upon conviction thereof” and “in the discretion of the court”, were omitted as surplusage.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Changes were made in phraseology.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd0a7eaa-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd0a7eab-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/430">Pub. L. 103–430</ref> inserted “or whoever, being or having been a census liaison within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s16">section 16 of this title</ref>,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—<ref href="/us/pl/94/521">Pub. L. 94–521</ref> provided that staff members would be liable for wrongful communication of information under this section, inserted “or having sworn to observe the limitations imposed by <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s9">section 9 of this title</ref>” after “oath of office”, substituted a provision predicating liability under this section upon disclosure of information prohibited by <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s9">section 9 of this title</ref> for a former provision predicating such liability upon disclosure of information without the written authority of the Secretary or other authorized officer or employee of the Department of Commerce or bureau or agency thereof, substituted “being employed (or otherwise providing services)” for “employment”, increased maximum amount of fine under this section to $5,000 from $1,000, and increased maximum prison term to 5 years from 2 years.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd0a7eac-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbd0a7ead-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/521">Pub. L. 94–521</ref> effective <date date="1976-10-17">Oct. 17, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/521/s17">section 17 of Pub. L. 94–521</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
