<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbd00e167-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c" identifier="/us/usc/t13/s23"><num value="23">§ 23.</num><heading> Additional officers and employees</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd00e168-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c" identifier="/us/usc/t13/s23/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Secretary may establish, at rates of compensation to be fixed by him without regard to the Classification Act of 1949, as many temporary positions as may be necessary to meet the requirements of the work provided for by law. Bureau employees who are transferred to any such temporary positions shall not lose their permanent civil service status by reason of the transfer. The Secretary may make appointments to such temporary positions in conformity with the civil service laws and rules.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd00e169-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c" identifier="/us/usc/t13/s23/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> In addition to employees of the Department of Commerce, employees of other departments and independent offices of the Government may, with the consent of the head of the respective department or office, be employed and compensated for field work in connection with the work provided for by law without regard to section 301 of the Dual Compensation Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbd00e16a-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c" identifier="/us/usc/t13/s23/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The Secretary may utilize temporary staff, including employees of Federal, State, or local agencies or instrumentalities, and employees of private organizations to assist the Bureau in performing the work authorized by this title, but only if such temporary staff is sworn to observe the limitations imposed by <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s9">section 9 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbd00e16b-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-31/ch1158">Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/1014">68 Stat. 1014</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/769/s2">Pub. L. 86–769, § 2</ref>, <date date="1960-09-13">Sept. 13, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/911">74 Stat. 911</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/448/tIV/s401/p">Pub. L. 88–448, title IV, § 401(p)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-19">Aug. 19, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/492">78 Stat. 492</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/521/s12/b">Pub. L. 94–521, § 12(b)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-17">Oct. 17, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2465">90 Stat. 2465</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbd00e16c-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idbd00e16d-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on title 13, U.S.C., 1952 ed., §§ 203, 216, and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1442">section 1442 of title 42</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., The Public Health and Welfare (<ref href="/us/act/1929-06-18/ch28">June 18, 1929, ch. 28</ref>, §§ 3, 16, <ref href="/us/stat/46/21">46 Stat. 21</ref>, 25; <ref href="/us/act/1949-07-06/ch298">July 6, 1949, ch. 298</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <ref href="/us/stat/63/406">63 Stat. 406</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-07-15/ch338">July 15, 1949, ch. 338</ref>, title VI, § 607, <ref href="/us/stat/63/441">63 Stat. 441</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-10-28/ch782">Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782</ref>, title XI, § 1106(a), <ref href="/us/stat/63/972">63 Stat. 972</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1952-07-16/ch912">July 16, 1952, ch. 912</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/736">66 Stat. 736</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section consolidates parts of sections 203 and 216 of title 13, U.S.C., 1952 ed., with that part of subsection (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1442">section 1442 of title 42</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., which made such sections 203 and 216 applicable to the censuses of housing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t13/s122">Section 122 of title 13</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., which related to quinquennial censuses of manufacturers, the mineral industries, transportation, and other businesses (see subchapter I of chapter 5 of this revised title), and <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s252">section 252 of title 13</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., which related to quinquennial censuses of governments (see subchapter III of chapter 5 of this title), made section 203 of such title applicable to those censuses. However, since the particular provisions of such section 203 that have been carried into this revised section apparently related, as supplemented by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1442/b">section 1442(b) of title 42</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., to the decennial censuses provided for in sections 201 et seq. of such title, and in such <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1442">section 1442 of title 42</ref> (see subchapter II of chapter 5 of this revised title), and apparently could have no relevancy to the quinquennial censuses referred to above, this revised section relates only to such decennial censuses.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsection (a), “Departmental Service” was substituted for “District of Columbia”, since the Bureau of the Census now has its headquarters in Maryland, and not in the District of Columbia.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In this section, a reference to the Bureau of the Census was changed to a reference to the Department of Commerce, and references to the Director of the Census were changed in all but one case to references to the Secretary (of Commerce) to conform with 1950 Reorganization Plan No. 5, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3174, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1263">64 Stat. 1263</ref>. See Revision Note to <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s4">section 4 of this title</ref>. The provision of <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s203">section 203 of title 13</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., that appointments under the particular provisions thereof that have been carried into subsection (a) of this revised section should be made upon the recommendation of the Director of the Census, have been omitted from such subsection (a) for the same reason. Further, words “or to whatever other officer is designated by the Secretary to take the census provided for in sections 141 and 142 of this title” were inserted after “Director of the Census” in par. (1) of subsection (a), to conform with such 1950 Reorganization Plan.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The first paragraph of <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s203">section 203 of title 13</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., which provided for the employment of two assistant directors for each decennial census period, was omitted as obsolete and superseded, in view of section 122 of such title, which made such section 203 applicable to the quinquennial censuses of manufactures and other businesses, and to surveys (see subchapter IV of chapter 5 of this title), thus rendering such first paragraph ineffective and meaningless. See also <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s121/b">section 121(b) of title 13</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The third proviso in the second paragraph of <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s203">section 203 of title 13</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., giving preference in appointments to disabled war veterans, their widows, and, under certain circumstances, to their wives, was omitted as superseded and covered by the Veterans’ Preference Act of 1944 (chapter 17 of title 5, U.S.C., 1952 ed., Executive Departments and Government Officers and Employees).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Changes were made in phraseology and arrangement.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Remainder of <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s203">section 203 of title 13</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., is incorporated in this subchapter, and for remainder of section 216 thereof, and of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1442">section 1442 of title 42</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed. (which has been transferred in its entirety to this revised title), see Distribution Table.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbd00e16e-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbd00e16f-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Classification Act of 1949, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1949-10-28/ch782">act Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/954">63 Stat. 954</ref>, which was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s8/a">Pub. L. 89–554, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/632">80 Stat. 632</ref>, and reenacted by the first section thereof as chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 301 of the Dual Compensation Act, referred to in subsec. (b), which was classified to section 3105 of former Title 5, Executive Departments and Government Officers and Employees, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s8/a">Pub. L. 89–554, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/632">80 Stat. 632</ref>, and reenacted by the first section thereof as <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5533">section 5533 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbd00e170-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/94/521">Pub. L. 94–521</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1964—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/88/448">Pub. L. 88–448</ref> inserted “without regard to section 301 of the Dual Compensation Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1960—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/86/769">Pub. L. 86–769</ref> substituted “The Secretary may establish, at rates of compensation to be fixed by him without regard to the Classification Act of 1949, as many temporary positions as may be necessary to meet the requirements of the work provided for by law. Bureau employees who are transferred to any such temporary positions shall not lose their permanent civil service status by reason of the transfer. The Secretary may make appointments to such temporary positions in conformity with the civil service laws and rules” for “The Secretary may appoint, without regard to the Classification Act of 1949, at rates of compensation to be fixed by him, as many temporary employees in the Departmental Service as may be necessary to meet the requirements of the work provided for in this title. Census employees who are transferred to any such temporary positions shall not lose their permanent Civil Service status by reason of the transfer. The Secretary shall make all such temporary appointments in conformity with the Civil Service laws and rules”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/86/769">Pub. L. 86–769</ref> substituted “by law” for “in this title”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbd00e171-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbd00e172-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/521">Pub. L. 94–521</ref> effective <date date="1976-10-17">Oct. 17, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/521/s17">section 17 of Pub. L. 94–521</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbd00e173-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1964 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/88/448">Pub. L. 88–448</ref> effective on first day of first month which begins later than ninetieth day following <date date="1964-08-19">Aug. 19, 1964</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/88/448/s403">section 403 of Pub. L. 88–448</ref>, title IV, <date date="1964-08-19">Aug. 19, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/496">78 Stat. 496</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd00e174-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Temporary Positions Relating to Decennial Censuses</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/447/dB/tII/s205">Pub. L. 108–447, div. B, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/2883">118 Stat. 2883</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/447/dB/tII/s205">“Hereafter, none of the funds made available by this or any other Act for the Department of Commerce shall be available to reimburse the Unemployment Trust Fund or any other fund or account of the Treasury to pay for any expenses authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8501">section 8501 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, for services performed by individuals appointed to temporary positions within the Bureau of the Census for purposes relating to the decennial censuses of population.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>Similar provisions were contained in the following prior appropriation acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/553/s1/a/2/tII/s204">Pub. L. 106–553, § 1(a)(2) [title II, § 204]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2762">114 Stat. 2762</ref>, 2762A–78.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/1/tII/s204">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(1) [title II, § 204]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1535">113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–31.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dA/s101/b/tII/s204">Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(b) [title II, § 204]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-50">112 Stat. 2681–50</ref>, 2681–86.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/119/tII/s204">Pub. L. 105–119, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1997-11-26">Nov. 26, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2479">111 Stat. 2479</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tI/s101/a/tII/s204">Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(a) [title II, § 204]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009">110 Stat. 3009</ref>, 3009–39.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/134/tI/s101">Pub. L. 104–134, title I, § 101[(a)]</ref> [title II, § 204], <date date="1996-04-26">Apr. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1321">110 Stat. 1321</ref>, 1321–30; renumbered title I, <ref href="/us/pl/104/140/s1/a">Pub. L. 104–140, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-05-02">May 2, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1327">110 Stat. 1327</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/317/tII/s204">Pub. L. 103–317, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1994-08-26">Aug. 26, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1749">108 Stat. 1749</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/121/tII/s204">Pub. L. 103–121, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1993-10-27">Oct. 27, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1177">107 Stat. 1177</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/395/tII/s204">Pub. L. 102–395, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1855">106 Stat. 1855</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/140/tII/s204">Pub. L. 102–140, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1991-10-28">Oct. 28, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/806">105 Stat. 806</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/515/tI/s104">Pub. L. 101–515, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2108">104 Stat. 2108</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/101/382/tI/s141">Pub. L. 101–382, title I, § 141</ref>, <date date="1990-08-20">Aug. 20, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/654">104 Stat. 654</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/382/tI/s141">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">General Rule</inline>.—</heading><content>The determination of whether temporary 1990 census services constitute ‘Federal service’ for purposes of subchapter I of chapter 85 of title 5, United States Code, shall be made under the provisions of such subchapter without regard to any provision of law not contained in such subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Temporary</inline> 1990 <inline class="small-caps">Census Services</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of subsection (a), the term ‘temporary 1990 census services’ means services performed by individuals appointed to temporary positions within the Bureau of the Census for purposes relating to the 1990 decennial census of population (as determined under regulations determined by the Secretary of Commerce).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/101/302/tII">Pub. L. 101–302, title II</ref>, <date date="1990-05-25">May 25, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/215">104 Stat. 215</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/302/tII">“Services performed after <date date="1990-04-20">April 20, 1990</date>, by individuals appointed to temporary positions within the Bureau of the Census for purposes relating to the 1990 decennial census of population shall not constitute ‘Federal service’ for purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8501">section 8501 of title 5</ref>, United States Code.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/86">Pub. L. 101–86</ref>, <date date="1989-08-16">Aug. 16, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/593">103 Stat. 593</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/101/293/s1">Pub. L. 101–293, § 1</ref>, <date date="1990-05-17">May 17, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/192">104 Stat. 192</ref>, provided that Federal annuitants or former members of the uniformed services who return to Government service under temporary appointments to assist in carrying out the 1990 decennial census of population would be exempt from certain provisions of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, relating to offsets from pay and other benefits.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[<ref href="/us/pl/101/293/s2">Pub. L. 101–293, § 2</ref>, <date date="1990-05-17">May 17, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/192">104 Stat. 192</ref>, provided that amendment of <ref href="/us/pl/101/86">Pub. L. 101–86</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/101/293">Pub. L. 101–293</ref> may not be considered to make an exemption under <ref href="/us/pl/101/86">Pub. L. 101–86</ref> applicable to any service performed before <date date="1990-05-17">May 17, 1990</date>, which was in excess of that allowable under <ref href="/us/pl/101/86">Pub. L. 101–86</ref> (as then in effect).]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbd00e175-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Policy and Practices of Bureau of Census Regarding Use of Temporary Staff; Publication</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/454/s3">Pub. L. 97–454, § 3</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2494">96 Stat. 2494</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/454/s3">
<inline>“Not later than 180 days after the effective date of this Act [<date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>], the Secretary of Commerce shall publish in the Federal Register a statement of the policy and practices of the Bureau of the Census relating to the administration of <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s23/c">section 23(c) of title 13</ref>, United States Code. Such statement shall include a description of—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the policy of the Secretary for the use of all individuals as temporary staff pursuant to such section 23(c) to assist the Bureau of the Census in performing work authorized under such title 13;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the functions for which the Secretary, in his discretion, may appoint temporary staff to assist the Bureau in performing work authorized under such title 13;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the practice applicable to the appointment of such temporary staff in performing such work;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the requirements and penalties under such title applicable to temporary staff performing such work, together with safeguards to ensure that such temporary staff will observe the limitations imposed in section 9 of such title.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
