<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbcfe970b-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c" identifier="/us/usc/t13/s7"><num value="7">§ 7.</num><heading> Printing; requisitions upon Director of the Government Publishing Office; publication of bulletins and reports</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may make requisition upon the Director of the Government Publishing Office for miscellaneous printing necessary to carry out the provisions of this title. He may further have printed by the Director of the Government Publishing Office, in such editions as he deems necessary, preliminary and other census bulletins, and final reports of the results of the several investigations authorized by this title, and may publish and distribute such bulletins and reports.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbcfe970c-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-31/ch1158">Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/1013">68 Stat. 1013</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/235/dH/tI/s1301/d">Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(d)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2537">128 Stat. 2537</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbcfe970d-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idbcfe970e-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on title 13, U.S.C., 1952 ed., § 213, and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1442">section 1442 of title 42</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., The Public Health and Welfare (<ref href="/us/act/1929-06-18/ch28/s13">June 18, 1929, ch. 28, § 13</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/25">46 Stat. 25</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-07-15/ch338">July 15, 1949, ch. 338</ref>, title VI, § 607, <ref href="/us/stat/63/441">63 Stat. 441</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section consolidates <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s213">section 213 of title 13</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., with that part of subsection (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1442">section 1442 of title 42</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., which made such section 213 applicable to the censuses of housing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The enumeration in <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s213">section 213 of title 13</ref>, U.S.C. 1952 ed., of the types of printing (“Blanks, schedules, circulars, pamphlets, envelopes, work sheets”) was omitted as unnecessary and covered by the words “miscellaneous printing”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The provisions have been reworded to make it clear that they relate to all statistical and census operations under this title, and changes were made in phraseology.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For remainder of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1442">section 1442 of title 42</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed. (which section has been transferred in its entirety to this revised title), see Distribution Table.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbcfe970f-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idbcfe9710-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Director of the Government Publishing Office” substituted for “Public Printer” in section catchline and in two places in text on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/113/235/s1301/d">section 1301(d) of Pub. L. 113–235</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s301">section 301 of Title 44</ref>, Public Printing and Documents.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
