<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbcfe9711-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c" identifier="/us/usc/t13/s8"><num value="8">§ 8.</num><heading> Authenticated transcripts or copies of certain returns; other data; restriction on use; disposition of fees received</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcfe9712-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c" identifier="/us/usc/t13/s8/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Secretary may, upon written request, furnish to any respondent, or to the heir, successor, or authorized agent of such respondent, authenticated transcripts or copies of reports (or portions thereof) containing information furnished by, or on behalf of, such respondent in connection with the surveys and census provided for in this title, upon payment of the actual or estimated cost of searching the rec­ords and furnishing such transcripts or copies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcfe9713-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c" identifier="/us/usc/t13/s8/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Subject to the limitations contained in sections 6(c) and 9 of this title, the Secretary may furnish copies of tabulations and other statistical materials which do not disclose the information reported by, or on behalf of, any particular respondent, and may make special statistical compilations and surveys, for departments, agencies, and establishments of the Federal Government, the government of the District of Columbia, the government of any possession or area (including political subdivisions thereof) referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s191/a">section 191(a) of this title</ref>, State or local agencies, or other public and private persons and agencies, upon payment of the actual or estimated cost of such work. In the case of nonprofit agencies or organizations, the Secretary may engage in joint statistical projects, the purpose of which are otherwise authorized by law, but only if the cost of such projects are shared equitably, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcfe9714-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c" identifier="/us/usc/t13/s8/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> In no case shall information furnished under this section be used to the detriment of any respondent or other person to whom such information relates, except in the prosecution of alleged violations of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbcfe9715-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c" identifier="/us/usc/t13/s8/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> All moneys received in payment for work or services enumerated under this section shall be deposited in a separate account which may be used to pay directly the costs of such work or services, to repay appropriations which initially bore all or part of such costs, or to refund excess sums when necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbcfe9716-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-31/ch1158">Aug. 31, 1954, ch. 1158</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/1013">68 Stat. 1013</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/207/s4">Pub. L. 85–207, § 4</ref>, <date date="1957-08-28">Aug. 28, 1957</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/71/481">71 Stat. 481</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/521/s6/a">Pub. L. 94–521, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-17">Oct. 17, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2460">90 Stat. 2460</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbcfe9717-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idbcfe9718-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Historical and Revision Notes</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Based on title 13, U.S.C., 1952 ed., § 218, and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1442">section 1442 of title 42</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., The Public Health and Welfare (<ref href="/us/act/1929-06-18/ch28/s18">June 18, 1929, ch. 28, § 18</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/46/25">46 Stat. 25</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-07-15/ch338">July 15, 1949, ch. 338</ref>, title VI, § 607, <ref href="/us/stat/63/441">63 Stat. 441</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section consolidates <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s218">section 218 of title 13</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., with that part of subsection (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1442">section 1442 of title 42</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., which made such section 218 applicable to the censuses of housing. For remainder of such <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1442">section 1442 of title 42</ref> (which has been transferred in its entirety to this revised title), see Distribution Table.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References to the Secretary, meaning the Secretary of Commerce, were substituted for references to the Director of the Census, to conform with 1950 Reorganization Plan No. 5, §§ 1, 2, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3174, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1263">64 Stat. 1263</ref>. See Revision Note to <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s4">section 4 of this title</ref>. For the same reason, a reference in <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s218">section 218 of title 13</ref>, U.S.C., 1952 ed., to the Bureau of the Census was changed, in subsection (e) of this revised section to “Department of Commerce or any bureau or agency thereof”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Changes were made in phraseology and arrangement.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbcfe9719-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbcfe971a-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—<ref href="/us/pl/94/521">Pub. L. 94–521</ref> substituted “Authenticated transcripts or copies” for “Certified copies” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/521">Pub. L. 94–521</ref> substituted provision that the Secretary may furnish to any respondent, or the successor or authorized agent of such respondent, transcripts or copies of reports containing information furnished in connection with the surveys and census, upon payment of the necessary costs, for provision that authorized the Secretary, in his discretion, to furnish the Governors of States and Territories, courts of record, and individuals, data for genealogical and other proper purposes, from the population, agriculture, and housing schedules prepared under the authority of subchapter II of chapter 5 of this title, upon payment of the necessary costs, plus one dollar for supplying a certificate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/94/521">Pub. L. 94–521</ref> inserted provision subjecting the Secretary to the limitations contained in sections 6(c) and 9 of this title, when furnishing statistical materials under this section, substituted “copies of tabulations and other statistical materials” for “transcripts or copies of tables and other census records”, inserted provision that materials furnished under this section may not disclose information reported by, or on behalf of, a particular respondent, and substituted a provision enumerating the public and private establishments and individuals, on behalf of whom, special statistical compilations may be conducted for provision that such compilations may be conducted on behalf of State or local officials, private concerns, or individuals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/94/521">Pub. L. 94–521</ref> struck out “the authority of” after “furnished under”, substituted “any respondent or other person” for “the persons”, and inserted “except in the prosecution of alleged violations of this title” after “relates,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1957—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/85/207/s4/a">Pub. L. 85–207, § 4(a)</ref>, inserted sentence at end respecting engagement in joint statistical projects.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/85/207/s4/b">Pub. L. 85–207, § 4(b)</ref>, required the deposit in a separate account of moneys received in payment for work or services, previously credited to an appropriation for collecting statistics, and permitted certain uses of such account.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbcfe971b-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbcfe971c-76cd-11f0-842a-a3c49cc8bf0c"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/521">Pub. L. 94–521</ref> effective <date date="1976-10-17">Oct. 17, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/521/s17">section 17 of Pub. L. 94–521</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t13/s1">section 1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
