<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id27f5ef7b-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202"><num value="1202">§ 1202.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the term—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27f5ef7c-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> “Alaska Railroad” means the agency of the United States Government that is operated by the Department of Transportation as a rail carrier in Alaska under authority of the Act of <date date="1914-03-12">March 12, 1914</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s975">43 U.S.C. 975</ref> et seq.) (popularly referred to as the “Alaska Railroad Act”) and section 6(i) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002080">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002080"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of the Department of Transportation Act, or, as the context requires, the railroad operated by that agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27f5ef7d-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> “Alaska Railroad Revolving Fund” means the public enterprise fund maintained by the Department of the Treasury into which revenues of the Alaska Railroad and appropriations for the Alaska Railroad are deposited, and from which funds are expended for Alaska Railroad operation, maintenance and construction work authorized by law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27f5ef7e-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> “claim of valid existing rights” means any claim to the rail properties of the Alaska Railroad on record in the Department of the Interior as of <date date="1983-01-13">January 13, 1983</date>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27f5ef7f-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> “date of transfer” means the date on which the Secretary delivers to the State the four documents referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s1203/b/1">section 1203(b)(1) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27f5ef80-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> “employees” means all permanent personnel employed by the Alaska Railroad on the date of transfer, including the officers of the Alaska Railroad, unless otherwise indicated in this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27f5ef81-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> “exclusive-use easement” means an easement which affords to the easement holder the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id27f5ef82-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the exclusive right to use, possess, and enjoy the surface estate of the land subject to this easement for transportation, communication, and transmission purposes and for support functions associated with such purposes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id27f5ef83-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the right to use so much of the subsurface estate of the lands subject to this easement as is necessary for the transportation, communication, and transmission purposes and associated support functions for which the surface of such lands is used;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id27f5ef84-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> subjacent and lateral support of the lands subject to the easement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id27f5ef85-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/6/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the right (in the easement holder’s discretion) to fence all or part of the lands subject to this easement and to affix track, fixtures, and structures to such lands and to exclude other persons from all or part of such lands;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27f5ef86-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> “Native Corporation” has the same meaning as such term has under section 102(6) of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t16/s3102/6">16 U.S.C. 3102(6)</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27f5ef87-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> “officers of the Alaska Railroad” means the employees occupying the following positions at the Alaska Railroad as of the day before the date of transfer: General Manager; Assistant General Manager; Assistant to the General Manager; Chief of Administration; and Chief Counsel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27f5ef88-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> “public lands” has the same meaning as such term has under section 3(e) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1602/e">43 U.S.C. 1602(e)</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27f5ef89-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><chapeau> “rail properties of the Alaska Railroad” means all right, title, and interest of the United States to lands, buildings, facilities, machinery, equipment, supplies, records, rolling stock, trade names, accounts receivable, goodwill, and other real and personal property, both tangible and intangible, in which there is an interest reserved, withdrawn, appropriated, owned, administered or otherwise held or validly claimed for the Alaska Railroad by the United States or any agency or instrumentality thereof as of <date date="1983-01-14">January 14, 1983</date>, but excluding any such properties disposed of, and including any such properties acquired, in the ordinary course of business after that date but before the date of transfer, and also including the exclusive-use easement within the Denali National Park and Preserve conveyed to the State pursuant to this chapter and also excluding the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id27f5ef8a-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/10/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the unexercised reservation to the United States for future rights-of-way required in all patents for land taken up, entered, or located in Alaska, as provided by the Act of <date date="1914-03-12">March 12, 1914</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s975">43 U.S.C. 975</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id27f5ef8b-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/10/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the right of the United States to exercise the power of eminent domain;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id27f5ef8c-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/10/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> any moneys in the Alaska Railroad Revolving Fund which the Secretary demonstrates, in consultation with the State, are unobligated funds appropriated from general tax revenues or are needed to satisfy obligations incurred by the United States in connection with the operation of the Alaska Railroad which would have been paid from such Fund but for this chapter and which are not assumed by the State pursuant to this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id27f5ef8d-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/10/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> any personal property which the Secretary demonstrates, in consultation with the State, prior to the date of transfer under <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s1203">section 1203 of this title</ref>, to be necessary to carry out functions of the United States after the date of transfer; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id27f5ef8e-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/10/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> any lands or interest therein (except as specified in this chapter) within the boundaries of the Denali National Park and Preserve;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27f5ef8f-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><chapeau> “right-of-way” means, except as used in <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s1208">section 1208 of this title</ref>—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id27f5ef90-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/11/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an area extending not less than one hundred feet on both sides of the center line of any main line or branch line of the Alaska Railroad; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id27f5ef91-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/11/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> an area extending on both sides of the center line of any main line or branch line of the Alaska Railroad appropriated or retained by or for the Alaska Railroad that, as a result of military jurisdiction over, or non-Federal ownership of, lands abutting the main line or branch line, is of a width less than that described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27f5ef92-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> “Secretary” means the Secretary of Transportation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27f5ef93-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> “State” means the State of Alaska or the State-owned railroad, as the context requires;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27f5ef94-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> “State-owned railroad” means the authority, agency, corporation or other entity which the State of Alaska designates or contracts with to own, operate or manage the rail properties of the Alaska Railroad or, as the context requires, the railroad owned, operated, or managed by such authority, agency, corporation, or other entity; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27f5ef95-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1202/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content> “Village Corporation” has the same meaning as such term has under section 3(j) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1602/j">43 U.S.C. 1602(j)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id27f5ef96-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/468/tVI/s603">Pub. L. 97–468, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="1983-01-14">Jan. 14, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2556">96 Stat. 2556</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id27f5ef97-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id27f5ef98-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id27f5ef99-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1914-03-12">March 12, 1914</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s975">43 U.S.C. 975</ref> et seq.) (popularly referred to as the “Alaska Railroad Act”), referred to in pars. (1) and (10)(A), is <ref href="/us/act/1914-03-12/ch37">act Mar. 12, 1914, ch. 37</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/38/305">38 Stat. 305</ref>, which enacted <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s353a">section 353a of Title 16</ref>, Conservation, and sections 975 to 975g of Title 43, Public Lands, and which was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/97/468/s615/a/1">section 615(a)(1) of Pub. L. 97–468</ref> effective on the date of transfer of Alaska Railroad to the State [<date date="1985-01-05">Jan. 5, 1985</date>], pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s1203">section 1203 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 6(i) of the Department of Transportation Act, referred to in par. (1), is <ref href="/us/pl/89/670/s6/i">section 6(i) of Pub. L. 89–670</ref>, which was classified to section 1655(i) of former Title 49, Transportation, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/97/468/tVI/s615/a/4">Pub. L. 97–468, title VI, § 615(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-14">Jan. 14, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2578">96 Stat. 2578</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
