<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id27fad16b-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1303"><num value="1303">§ 1303.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this chapter—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27fad16c-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1303/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the term “capital expenditures” means amounts expended by the Corporation and its subsidiaries for replacement or rehabilitation of, or enhancements to, the railroad plant, property, trackage, and equipment of the Corporation and its subsidiaries, as determined in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, and in interpreting generally accepted accounting principles, no amount spent on normal repair, maintenance, and upkeep of such railroad plant, property, trackage, and equipment in the ordinary course of business shall constitute capital expenditures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27fad16d-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1303/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the term “Commission” means the Interstate Commerce Commission;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27fad16e-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1303/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the term “consolidated funded debt” means the aggregate, after eliminating intercompany items, of all funded debt of the Corporation and its consolidated subsidiaries, consolidated in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27fad16f-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1303/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> the term “consolidated tangible net worth” means the market value of the common equity of the Corporation as of the sale date, plus or minus the change from the sale date to the date of measurement in the excess, after making appropriate deductions for any minority interest in the net worth of subsidiaries, of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id27fad170-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1303/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the assets of the Corporation and its subsidiaries (excluding intercompany items) which, in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, are tangible assets, after deducting adequate reserves in each case where, in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, a reserve is proper, over</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id27fad171-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1303/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> all liabilities of the Corporation and its subsidiaries (excluding intercompany items),</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">taking into account inventory and securities on the basis of the cost or current market value, whichever is lower, and not taking into account patents, trademarks, trade names, copyrights, licenses, goodwill, treasury stock, or any write-up in the book value of any assets;</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27fad172-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1303/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the term “Corporation” means the Consolidated Rail Corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27fad173-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1303/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> the term “cumulative net income” means, for any period, the net income of the Corporation and its consolidated subsidiaries as determined in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, before provision for expenses (net of income tax effect) related to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id27fad174-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1303/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> amounts paid by the Corporation under section 4024(e), and comparable payments made to present and former employees of the Corporation not covered by such section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id27fad175-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1303/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the aggregate value of any shares and cash distributed by the Corporation under section 4024(f);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27fad176-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1303/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> the term “debt” means (A) indebtedness, whether or not represented by bonds, debentures, notes, or other securities, for the repayment of money borrowed, (B) deferred indebtedness for the payment of the purchase price of property or assets purchased, (C) guarantees, endorsements, assumptions, and other contingent obligations in respect of, or to purchase or to otherwise acquire, indebtedness of others, and (D) indebtedness secured by any mortgage, pledge, or lien existing on property owned, subject to such mortgage, pledge, or lien, whether or not indebtedness secured thereby shall have been assumed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27fad177-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1303/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> the term “funded debt” means all debt created, assumed, or guaranteed, directly or indirectly, by the Corporation and its subsidiaries which matures by its terms, or is renewable at the option of the Corporation or any such subsidiary to a date, more than 1 year after the date of the original creation, assumption, or guarantee of such debt by the Corporation or such subsidiary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27fad178-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1303/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> the term “liabilities” means all items of indebtedness or liability which, in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles, would be included in determining total liabilities as shown on the liabilities side of a balance sheet as at the date as of which liabilities are to be determined;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27fad179-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1303/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> the term “person” means an individual, corporation, partnership, association, trust, or other entity or organization, including a government or political subdivision thereof or a governmental body;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27fad17a-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1303/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> the term “preferred stock” means any class or series of preferred stock, and any class or series of common stock having liquidation and dividend rights and preferences superior to the common stock of the Corporation offered for sale under <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s1312">section 1312 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27fad17b-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1303/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> the term “public offering” means an underwritten offering to the public of such common stock of the Corporation as the Secretary of Transportation determines to sell under <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s1312">section 1312 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27fad17c-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1303/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> the term “sale date” means the date on which the initial public offering is closed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27fad17d-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1303/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> the term “subsidiary” means any corporation more than 50 percent of whose outstanding voting securities are directly or indirectly owned by the Corporation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27fad17e-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1303/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content> the term “United States share” means a share of common stock of the Corporation held by the United States Government on <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, or as a result of any split required pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s1312/d">section 1312(d) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id27fad17f-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/509/tIV/s4004">Pub. L. 99–509, title IV, § 4004</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1894">100 Stat. 1894</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id27fad180-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id27fad181-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id27fad182-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 4024(e) and section 4024(f), referred to in par. (6), are section 4024(e) and (f) of <ref href="/us/pl/99/509">Pub. L. 99–509</ref>, and are set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s797">section 797 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id27fad183-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id27fad184-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Interstate Commerce Commission and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Interstate Commerce Commission abolished and functions of Commission transferred, except as otherwise provided in <ref href="/us/pl/104/88">Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, to Surface Transportation Board effective <date date="1996-01-01">Jan. 1, 1996</date>, by <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1302">section 1302 of Title 49</ref>, Transportation, and <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s101">section 101 of Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1301">section 1301 of Title 49</ref>. References to Interstate Commerce Commission deemed to refer to Surface Transportation Board, a member or employee of the Board, or Secretary of Transportation, as appropriate, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s205">section 205 of Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1301">section 1301 of Title 49</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
