<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id27fad1b4-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1321"><num value="1321">§ 1321.</num><heading> Rail service obligations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27fad1b5-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1321/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Obligations of Corporation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">During a period of 5 years beginning on <date date="1986-10-21">October 21, 1986</date>, the following obligations shall apply to the Corporation:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27fad1b6-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1321/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Corporation shall spend in each fiscal year the greater of (A) an amount equal to the Corporation’s depreciation for financial reporting purposes for such year or (B) $500,000,000, in capital expenditures. With respect to any fiscal year, the Corporation’s Board of Directors may reduce the required capital expenditures for such year to an amount which the Board determines is justified by prudent business and engineering practices, except that the Corporation’s capital expenditures shall not be less than $350,000,000 for its first fiscal year beginning after the sale date, a total of $700,000,000 for its first two fiscal years beginning after the sale date, a total of $1,050,000,000 for its first three fiscal years beginning after the sale date, a total of $1,400,000,000 for its first four fiscal years beginning after the sale date, and a total of $1,750,000,000 for its first five fiscal years beginning after the sale date.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27fad1b7-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1321/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/101/213/s2/b/3">Pub. L. 101–213, § 2(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-11">Dec. 11, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1843">103 Stat. 1843</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27fad1b8-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1321/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Corporation shall continue its affirmative action program and its minority vendor program, substantially as such programs were being conducted by the Corporation as of <date date="1985-02-08">February 8, 1985</date>, subject to any provisions of applicable law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27fad1b9-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1321/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Corporation shall not permit to occur any transaction or series of transactions (other than in the ordinary course of business of the Corporation and its subsidiaries) whereby all or any substantial part of the railroad assets and business of the Corporation and its subsidiaries taken as a whole are sold, leased, transferred, or otherwise disposed of to any corporation or entity other than to a wholly owned subsidiary of the Corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27fad1ba-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1321/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The Corporation shall offer any line for which an abandonment certificate is issued by the Commission to a purchaser who agrees to provide interconnecting rail service. Such offer shall last for the 120-day period following the date of issuance of the abandonment certificate and the price for such abandoned line shall be equal to 75 percent of net liquidation value as determined by the Commission, pursuant to regulations that had been issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s748">section 748 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27fad1bb-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1321/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The Corporation and its subsidiaries shall maintain, preserve, protect, and keep their respective properties in good repair, working order, and condition, and shall not permit deferral of normal and prudent maintenance necessary to provide and maintain rail service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27fad1bc-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1321/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Compliance certificates</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27fad1bd-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1321/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Within 90 days after the close of each of its fiscal years, or at the time its financial statements have been audited, whichever occurs later, the Corporation shall deliver to the Secretary of Transportation a certificate executed by an executive officer of the Corporation. Such certificate shall certify that, as of such date, the Corporation is in compliance with all requirements (other than the requirement regarding a common stock dividend or a preferred stock dividend) set forth in this section. Such certificate shall include audited consolidated financial statements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27fad1be-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1321/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Within 5 days after the declaration of any common stock dividend or preferred stock dividend, the Corporation shall deliver to the Secretary of Transportation a certificate executed by an executive officer of the Corporation. Such certificate shall certify that, after giving effect to any such dividend, the Corporation shall be in compliance with any requirement regarding a common stock dividend or a preferred stock dividend set forth in this section. Such certificate shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27fad1bf-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1321/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> quarterly financial statements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27fad1c0-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s1321/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a report of the Corporation’s total capital expenditures,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">for the period with respect to which the dividend has been declared, and the fiscal year to date, and shall compare such capital expenditures to the budgeted capital expenditures and to the capital expenditures during the comparable periods of the previous fiscal year.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id27fad1c1-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/509/tIV/s4021">Pub. L. 99–509, title IV, § 4021</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1898">100 Stat. 1898</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/213/s2/b/3">Pub. L. 101–213, § 2(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-11">Dec. 11, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1843">103 Stat. 1843</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id27fad1c2-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id27fad1c3-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id27fad1c4-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/213">Pub. L. 101–213</ref> struck out par. (2) which set forth circumstances under which Corporation could declare or pay a common or preferred stock dividend and defined terms “common stock dividend” and “preferred stock dividend”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id27fad1c5-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id27fad1c6-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Interstate Commerce Commission and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Interstate Commerce Commission abolished and functions of Commission transferred, except as otherwise provided in <ref href="/us/pl/104/88">Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, to Surface Transportation Board effective <date date="1996-01-01">Jan. 1, 1996</date>, by <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1302">section 1302 of Title 49</ref>, Transportation, and <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s101">section 101 of Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1301">section 1301 of Title 49</ref>. References to Interstate Commerce Commission deemed to refer to Surface Transportation Board, a member or employee of the Board, or Secretary of Transportation, as appropriate, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s205">section 205 of Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1301">section 1301 of Title 49</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
