<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id279b4b94-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s157"><num value="157">§ 157.</num><heading> Arbitration</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">First. Submission of controversy to arbitration</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever a controversy shall arise between a carrier or carriers and its or their employees which is not settled either in conference between representatives of the parties or by the appropriate adjustment board or through mediation, in the manner provided in sections 151—156 of this title such controversy may, by agreement of the parties to such controversy, be submitted to the arbitration of a board of three (or, if the parties to the controversy so stipulate, of six) persons: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the failure or refusal of either party to submit a controversy to arbitration shall not be construed as a violation of any legal obligation imposed upon such party by the terms of this chapter or otherwise.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">Second. Manner of selecting board of arbitration</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Such board of arbitration shall be chosen in the following manner:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">(a) In the case of a board of three the carrier or carriers and the representatives of the employees, parties respectively to the agreement to arbitrate, shall each name one arbitrator; the two arbitrators thus chosen shall select a third arbitrator. If the arbitrators chosen by the parties shall fail to name the third arbitrator within five days after their first meeting, such third arbitrator shall be named by the Mediation Board.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">(b) In the case of a board of six the carrier or carriers and the representatives of the employees, parties respectively to the agreement to arbitrate, shall each name two arbitrators; the four arbitrators thus chosen shall, by a majority vote, select the remaining two arbitrators. If the arbitrators chosen by the parties shall fail to name the two arbitrators within fifteen days after their first meeting, the said two arbitrators, or as many of them as have not been named, shall be named by the Mediation Board.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">Third. Board of arbitration; organization; compensation; procedure</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">(a) Notice of selection or failure to select arbitrators</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">When the arbitrators selected by the respective parties have agreed upon the remaining arbitrator or arbitrators, they shall notify the Mediation Board; and, in the event of their failure to agree upon any or upon all of the necessary arbitrators within the period fixed by this chapter, they shall, at the expiration of such period, notify the Mediation Board of the arbitrators selected, if any, or of their failure to make or to complete such selection.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">(b) Organization of board; procedure</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The board of arbitration shall organize and select its own chairman and make all necessary rules for conducting its hearings: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the board of arbitration shall be bound to give the parties to the controversy a full and fair hearing, which shall include an opportunity to present evidence in support of their claims, and an opportunity to present their case in person, by counsel, or by other representative as they may respectively elect.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">(c) Duty to reconvene; questions considered</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon notice from the Mediation Board that the parties, or either party, to an arbitration desire the reconvening of the board of arbitration (or a subcommittee of such board of arbitration appointed for such purpose pursuant to the agreement to arbitrate) to pass upon any controversy over the meaning or application of their award, the board, or its subcommittee, shall at once reconvene. No question other than, or in addition to, the questions relating to the meaning or application of the award, submitted by the party or parties in writing, shall be considered by the reconvened board of arbitration or its subcommittee.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Such rulings shall be acknowledged by such board or subcommittee thereof in the same manner, and filed in the same district court clerk’s office, as the original award and become a part thereof.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">(d) Competency of arbitrators</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No arbitrator, except those chosen by the Mediation Board, shall be incompetent to act as an arbitrator because of his interest in the controversy to be arbitrated, or because of his connection with or partiality to either of the parties to the arbitration.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">(e) Compensation and expenses</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each member of any board of arbitration created under the provisions of this chapter named by either party to the arbitration shall be compensated by the party naming him. Each arbitrator selected by the arbitrators or named by the Mediation Board shall receive from the Mediation Board such compensation as the Mediation Board may fix, together with his necessary traveling expenses and expenses actually incurred for subsistence, while serving as an arbitrator.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">(f) Award; disposition of original and copies</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The board of arbitration shall furnish a certified copy of its award to the respective parties to the controversy, and shall transmit the original, together with the papers and proceedings and a transcript of the evidence taken at the hearings, certified under the hands of at least a majority of the arbitrators, to the clerk of the district court of the United States for the district wherein the controversy arose or the arbitration is entered into, to be filed in said clerk’s office as hereinafter provided. The said board shall also furnish a certified copy of its award, and the papers and proceedings, including testimony relating thereto, to the Mediation Board to be filed in its office; and in addition a certified copy of its award shall be filed in the office of the Interstate Commerce Commission: <i>Provided, however</i>, That such award shall not be construed to diminish or extinguish any of the powers or duties of the Interstate Commerce Commission, under subtitle IV of title 49.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">(g) Compensation of assistants to board of arbitration; expenses; quarters</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A board of arbitration may, subject to the approval of the Mediation Board, employ and fix the compensation of such assistants as it deems necessary in carrying on the arbitration proceedings. The compensation of such employees, together with their necessary traveling expenses and expenses actually incurred for subsistence, while so employed, and the necessary expenses of boards of arbitration, shall be paid by the Mediation Board.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever practicable, the board shall be supplied with suitable quarters in any Federal building located at its place of meeting or at any place where the board may conduct its proceedings or deliberations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">(h) Testimony before board; oaths; attendance of witnesses; production of documents; subpoenas; fees</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All testimony before said board shall be given under oath or affirmation, and any member of the board shall have the power to administer oaths or affirmations. The board of arbitration, or any member thereof, shall have the power to require the attendance of witnesses and the production of such books, papers, contracts, agreements, and documents as may be deemed by the board of arbitration material to a just determination of the matters submitted to its arbitration, and may for that purpose request the clerk of the district court of the United States for the district wherein said arbitration is being conducted to issue the necessary subpoenas, and upon such request the said clerk or his duly authorized deputy shall be, and he is, authorized, and it shall be his duty, to issue such subpoenas.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any witness appearing before a board of arbitration shall receive the same fees and mileage as witnesses in courts of the United States, to be paid by the party securing the subpoena.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id279b4b95-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">(<ref href="/us/act/1926-05-20/ch347/s7">May 20, 1926, ch. 347, § 7</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/582">44 Stat. 582</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-21/ch691/s7">June 21, 1934, ch. 691, § 7</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1197">48 Stat. 1197</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/452/tII/s238">Pub. L. 91–452, title II, § 238</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/930">84 Stat. 930</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id279b4b96-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id279b4b97-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id279b4b98-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In par. Third (f), “subtitle IV of title 49” substituted for “the Interstate Commerce Act, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1">49 U.S.C. 1</ref> et seq.]” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/95/473/s3/b">Pub. L. 95–473, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-17">Oct. 17, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1466">92 Stat. 1466</ref>, the first section of which enacted subtitle IV of Title 49, Transportation.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id279b4b99-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Par. Third, (h). <ref href="/us/pl/91/452">Pub. L. 91–452</ref> struck out provisions authorizing board to invoke aid of the United States courts to compel witnesses to attend and testify and to produce such books, papers, contracts, agreements, and documents to same extent and under same conditions and penalties as provided for in the Interstate Commerce Act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1934—Act <date date="1934-06-21">June 21, 1934</date>, substituted “Mediation Board” for “Board of Mediation” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id279b4b9a-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id279b4b9b-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1970 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/452">Pub. L. 91–452</ref> effective on sixtieth day following <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, and not to affect any immunity to which any individual is entitled under this section by reason of any testimony given before sixtieth day following <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/452/s260">section 260 of Pub. L. 91–452</ref>, set out as an Effective Date; Savings Provision note under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s6001">section 6001 of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id279b4b9c-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Interstate Commerce Commission and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Interstate Commerce Commission abolished and functions of Commission transferred, except as otherwise provided in <ref href="/us/pl/104/88">Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, to Surface Transportation Board effective <date date="1996-01-01">Jan. 1, 1996</date>, by <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1302">section 1302 of Title 49</ref>, Transportation, and <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s101">section 101 of Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1301">section 1301 of Title 49</ref>. References to Interstate Commerce Commission deemed to refer to Surface Transportation Board, a member or employee of the Board, or Secretary of Transportation, as appropriate, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s205">section 205 of Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1301">section 1301 of Title 49</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id279b4b9d-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Work Rules Dispute</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/88/108">Pub. L. 88–108</ref>, <date date="1963-08-28">Aug. 28, 1963</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/77/132">77 Stat. 132</ref>, provided:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/88/108">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="1">“[Sec. 1.</num><content> Settlement of disputes]. That no carrier which served the notices of <date date="1959-11-02">November 2, 1959</date>, and no labor organizations which received such notices or served the labor organization notices of <date date="1960-09-07">September 7, 1960</date>, shall make any change except by agreement, or pursuant to an arbitration award as hereinafter provided, in rates of pay, rules, or working conditions encompassed by any of such notices, or engage in any strike or lockout over any dispute arising from any of such notices. Any action heretofore taken which would be prohibited by the foregoing sentence shall be forthwith rescinded and the status existing immediately prior to such action restored.</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="2">“Sec. 2.</num><content> [Arbitration board]. There is hereby established an arbitration board to consist of seven members. The representatives of the carrier and organization parties to the aforesaid dispute are hereby directed, respectively, within five days after the enactment hereof [<date date="1963-08-28">Aug. 28, 1963</date>] each to name two persons to serve as members of such arbitration board. The four members thus chosen shall select three additional members. The seven members shall then elect a chairman. If the members chosen by the parties shall fail to name one or more of the additional three members within ten days, such additional members shall be named by the President. If either party fails to name a member or members to the arbitration board within the five days provided, the President shall name such member or members in lieu of such party and shall also name the additional three members necessary to constitute a board of seven members, all within ten days after the date of enactment of this joint resolution [<date date="1963-08-28">Aug. 28, 1963</date>]. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the National Mediation Board is authorized and directed: (1) to compensate the arbitrators not named by the parties at a rate not in excess of $100 for each day together with necessary travel and subsistence expenses, and (2) to provide such services and facilities as may be necessary and appropriate in carrying out the purposes of this joint resolution.</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="3">“Sec. 3.</num><content> [Decision of board]. Promptly upon the completion of the naming of the arbitration board the Secretary of Labor shall furnish to the board and to the parties to the dispute copies of his statement to the parties of <date date="1963-08-02">August 2, 1963</date>, and the papers therewith submitted to the parties, together with memorandums and such other data as the board may request setting forth the matters with respect to which the parties were in tentative agreement and the extent of disagreement with respect to matters on which the parties were not in tentative agreement. The arbitration board shall make a decision, pursuant to the procedures hereinafter set forth, as to what disposition shall be made of those portions of the carriers’ notices of <date date="1959-11-02">November 2, 1959</date>, identified as ‘Use of Firemen (Helpers) on Other Than Steam Power’ and ‘Consist of Road and Yard Crews’ and that portion of the organizations’ notices of <date date="1960-09-07">September 7, 1960</date>, identified as ‘Minimum Safe Crew Consist’ and implementing proposals pertaining thereto. The arbitration board shall incorporate in such decision any matters on which it finds the parties were in agreement, shall resolve the matters on which the parties were not in agreement, and shall, in making its award, give due consideration to those matters on which the parties were in tentative agreement. Such award shall be binding on both the carrier and organization parties to the dispute and shall constitute a complete and final disposition of the aforesaid issues covered by the decision of the board of arbitration.</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="4">“Sec. 4.</num><content> [Award]. To the extent not inconsistent with this joint resolution the arbitration shall be conducted pursuant to sections 7 and 8 of the Railway Labor Act [this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s158">section 158 of this title</ref>], the board’s award shall be made and filed as provided in said sections and shall be subject to section 9 of said Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t45/s159">section 159 of this title</ref>]. The United States District Court for the District of Columbia is hereby designated as the court in which the award is to be filed, and the arbitration board shall report to the National Mediation Board in the same manner as arbitration boards functioning pursuant to the Railway Labor Act [this chapter]. The award shall continue in force for such period as the arbitration board shall determine in its award, but not to exceed two years from the date the award takes effect, unless the parties agree otherwise.</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="5">“Sec. 5.</num><content> [Hearings]. The arbitration board shall begin its hearings thirty days after the enactment of this joint resolution [<date date="1963-08-28">Aug. 28, 1963</date>] or on such earlier date as the parties to the dispute and the board may agree upon and shall make and file its award not later than ninety days after the enactment of this joint resolution [<date date="1963-08-28">Aug. 28, 1963</date>]: <i>Provided, however</i>, That said award shall not become effective until sixty days after the filing of the award.</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="6">“Sec. 6.</num><content> [Collective bargaining for issues not arbitrated]. The parties to the disputes arising from the aforesaid notices shall immediately resume collective bargaining with respect to all issues raised in the notices of <date date="1959-11-02">November 2, 1959</date>, and <date date="1960-09-07">September 7, 1960</date>, not to be disposed of by arbitration under section 3 of this joint resolution and shall exert every reasonable effort to resolve such issues by agreement. The Secretary of Labor and the National Mediation Board are hereby directed to give all reasonable assistance to the parties and to engage in mediatory action directed toward promoting such agreement.</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="7">“Sec. 7.</num><heading> [Considerations affecting award; enforcement.]</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> In making any award under this joint resolution the arbitration board established under section 2 shall give due consideration to the effect of the proposed award upon adequate and safe transportation service to the public and upon the interests of the carrier and employees affected, giving due consideration to the narrowing of the areas of disagreement which has been accomplished in bargaining and mediation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The obligations imposed by this joint resolution, upon suit by the Attorney General, shall be enforcible through such orders as may be necessary by any court of the United States having jurisdiction of any of the parties.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="8">“Sec. 8.</num><content> [Expiration date]. This joint resolution shall expire one hundred and eighty days after the date of its enactment [<date date="1963-08-28">Aug. 28, 1963</date>], except that it shall remain in effect with respect to the last sentence of section 4 for the period prescribed in that sentence.</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="9">“Sec. 9.</num><content> [Separability]. If any provision of this joint resolution or the application thereof is held invalid, the remainder of this joint resolution and the application of such provision to other parties or in other circumstances not held invalid shall not be affected thereby.”</content>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
