<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id279b4bb2-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s159"><num value="159">§ 159.</num><heading> Award and judgment thereon; effect of chapter on individual employee</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">First. Filing of award</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The award of a board of arbitration, having been acknowledged as herein provided, shall be filed in the clerk’s office of the district court designated in the agreement to arbitrate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">Second. Conclusiveness of award; judgment</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An award acknowledged and filed as herein provided shall be conclusive on the parties as to the merits and facts of the controversy submitted to arbitration, and unless, within ten days after the filing of the award, a petition to impeach the award, on the grounds hereinafter set forth, shall be filed in the clerk’s office of the court in which the award has been filed, the court shall enter judgment on the award, which judgment shall be final and conclusive on the parties.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">Third. Impeachment of award; grounds</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Such petition for the impeachment or contesting of any award so filed shall be entertained by the court only on one or more of the following grounds:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">(a) That the award plainly does not conform to the substantive requirements laid down by this chapter for such awards, or that the proceedings were not substantially in conformity with this chapter;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">(b) That the award does not conform, nor confine itself, to the stipulations of the agreement to arbitrate; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">(c) That a member of the board of arbitration rendering the award was guilty of fraud or corruption; or that a party to the arbitration practiced fraud or corruption which fraud or corruption affected the result of the arbitration: <i>Provided, however</i>, That no court shall entertain any such petition on the ground that an award is invalid for uncertainty; in such case the proper remedy shall be a submission of such award to a reconvened board, or subcommittee thereof, for interpretation, as provided by this chapter: <i>Provided further</i>, That an award contested as herein provided shall be construed liberally by the court, with a view to favoring its validity, and that no award shall be set aside for trivial irregularity or clerical error, going only to form and not to substance.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">Fourth. Effect of partial invalidity of award</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the court shall determine that a part of the award is invalid on some ground or grounds designated in this section as a ground of invalidity, but shall determine that a part of the award is valid, the court shall set aside the entire award: <i>Provided, however</i>, That, if the parties shall agree thereto, and if such valid and invalid parts are separable, the court shall set aside the invalid part, and order judgment to stand as to the valid part.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">Fifth. Appeal; record</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">At the expiration of 10 days from the decision of the district court upon the petition filed as aforesaid, final judgment shall be entered in accordance with said decision, unless during said 10 days either party shall appeal therefrom to the court of appeals. In such case only such portion of the record shall be transmitted to the appellate court as is necessary to the proper understanding and consideration of the questions of law presented by said petition and to be decided.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">Sixth. Finality of decision of court of appeals</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The determination of said court of appeals upon said questions shall be final, and, being certified by the clerk thereof to said district court, judgment pursuant thereto shall thereupon be entered by said district court.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">Seventh. Judgment where petitioner’s contentions are sustained</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the petitioner’s contentions are finally sustained, judgment shall be entered setting aside the award in whole or, if the parties so agree, in part; but in such case the parties may agree upon a judgment to be entered disposing of the subject matter of the controversy, which judgment when entered shall have the same force and effect as judgment entered upon an award.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2">Eighth. Duty of employee to render service without consent; right to quit</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to require an individual employee to render labor or service without his consent, nor shall anything in this chapter be construed to make the quitting of his labor or service by an individual employee an illegal act; nor shall any court issue any process to compel the performance by an individual employee of such labor or service, without his consent.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id279dbcb3-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">(<ref href="/us/act/1926-05-20/ch347/s9">May 20, 1926, ch. 347, § 9</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/585">44 Stat. 585</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646/s32/a">June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 32(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/991">62 Stat. 991</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-05-24/ch139/s127">May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 127</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/107">63 Stat. 107</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id279dbcb4-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id279dbcb5-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id279dbcb6-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">As originally enacted, pars. Fifth and Sixth contained references to the “circuit court of appeals”. Act <date date="1948-06-25">June 25, 1948</date>, as amended by act <date date="1949-05-24">May 24, 1949</date>, substituted “court of appeals” for “circuit court of appeals”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
