<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id27cd7f57-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362"><num value="362">§ 362.</num><heading> Duties and powers of Board</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27cd7f58-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Witnesses; subpenas, service, fees, etc.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of any investigation or other proceeding relative to the determination of any right to benefits, or relative to any other matter within its jurisdiction under this chapter, the Board shall have the power to issue subpenas requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of any evidence, documentary or otherwise, that relates to any matter under investigation or in question, before the Board or any member, employee, or representative thereof. Any member of the Board or any of its employees or representatives designated by it may administer oaths and affirmations, examine witnesses, and receive evidence. Such attendance of witnesses and production of evidence may be required from any place in the United States or any Territory or possession thereof at any designated place of hearing. All subpenas may be served and returned by anyone authorized by the Board in the same manner as is now provided by law for the service and return by United States marshals of subpenas in suits in equity. Such service may also be made by registered mail or by certified mail and in such case the return post-office receipt shall be proof of service. Witnesses summoned in accordance with this subsection shall be paid the same fees and mileage as are paid witnesses in the district courts of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27cd7f59-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement of subpenas by courts; contempts; service of orders, writs, or processes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In case of contumacy by, or refusal to obey a subpena lawfully issued to, any person, the Board may invoke the aid of the district court of the United States or the United States courts of any Territory or possession, where such person is found or resides or is otherwise subject to service of process, or the United States District Court for the District of Columbia if the investigation or proceeding is being carried on in the District of Columbia, or the United States District Court for the Northern District of Illinois, if the investigation or proceeding is being carried on in the Northern District of Illinois, in requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of evidence. Any such court shall issue an order requiring such person to appear before the Board or its specified employee or representative at the place specified in the subpena of the Board, whether within or without the judicial district of the court, there to produce evidence, if so ordered, or there to give testimony concerning the matter under investigation or in question; and any failure to obey such order of the court may be punished by said court as a contempt thereof. All orders, writs, and processes in any such proceeding may be served in the judicial district of the district court issuing such order, writ, or process, except that the orders, writs, and processes of the United States District Court for the District of Columbia or of the United States District Court for the Northern District of Illinois in such proceedings may run and be served anywhere in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27cd7f5a-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/91/452/tII/s239">Pub. L. 91–452, title II, § 239</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/930">84 Stat. 930</ref></heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27cd7f5b-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Information as confidential</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Information obtained by the Board in connection with the administration of this chapter shall not be revealed or open to inspection nor be published in any manner revealing an employee’s identity: <i>Provided, however</i>, That (i) the Board may arrange for the exchange of any information with governmental agencies engaged in functions related to the administration of this chapter; (ii) the Board may disclose such information in cases in which the Board finds that such disclosure is clearly in furtherance of the interest of the employee or his estate; (iii) any claimant of benefits under this chapter shall, upon his request, be supplied with information from the Board’s records pertaining to his claim; and (iv) the Board shall disclose to any base-year employer of a claimant for benefits any information, including information as to the claimant’s identity, that is necessary or appropriate to notify such employer of the claim for benefits or to full and fair participation by such employer in an appeal, hearing, or other proceeding relative to the claim pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s355">section 355 of this title</ref>. Subject to the provisions of this section, the Board may furnish such information to any person or organization upon payment by such person or organization to the Board of the cost incurred by the Board by reason thereof; and the amounts so paid to the Board shall be credited to the railroad unemployment insurance administration fund established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s361/a">section 361(a) of this title</ref>;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27cd7f5c-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Certification of claims; authorization of employee to make payments; bond</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board shall provide for the certification of claims for benefits and refunds and may arrange total or partial settlements at such times and in such manner as may appear to the Board to be expedient. The Board shall designate and authorize one or more of its employees to sign vouchers for the payment of benefits and refunds under this chapter. Each such employee shall give bond, in form and amount fixed by the Board, conditioned upon the faithful performance of his duties. The premiums due on such bonds shall be paid from the fund and deemed to be a part of the expenses of administering this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27cd7f5d-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Cooperation with other agencies administering unemployment or sickness compensation laws; agreements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board may cooperate with or enter into agreement with the appropriate agencies charged with the administration of State, Territorial, Federal, or foreign unemployment-compensation or sickness laws or employment offices, with respect to investigations, the exchange of information and services, the establishment, maintenance, and use of free employment service facilities, and such other matters as the Board deems expedient in connection with the administration of this chapter, and may compensate any such agency for services or facilities supplied to the Board in connection with the administration of this chapter. The Board may enter also into agreements with any such agency, pursuant to which any unemployment or sickness benefits provided for by this chapter or any other unemployment-compensation or sickness law, may be paid through a single agency to persons who have, during the period on the basis of which eligibility for and duration of benefits is determined under the law administered by such agency or under this chapter, or both, performed services covered by one or more of such laws, or performed services which constitute employment as defined in this chapter: <i>Provided</i>, That the Board finds that any such agreement is fair and reasonable as to all affected interests.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27cd7f5e-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Benefits also subject to a State law; mutual reimbursement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In determining whether an employee has qualified for benefits in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s353">section 353 of this title</ref>, and in determining the amount of benefits to be paid to such employee in accordance with section 352(a) and (c) of this title, the Board is authorized to consider as employment (and compensation therefor) services for hire other than employment (and remuneration therefor) if such services for hire are subject to an unemployment or sickness compensation law of any State, provided that such State has agreed to reimburse the United States such portion of the benefits to be paid upon such basis to such employee as the Board deems equitable. Any amounts collected pursuant to this paragraph shall be credited to the account.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If a State, in determining whether an employee is eligible for unemployment or sickness benefits under an unemployment or sickness compensation law of such State, and in determining the amount of unemployment or sickness benefits to be paid to such employee pursuant to such unemployment or sickness compensation law, considers as services for hire (and remuneration therefor) included within the provisions of such unemployment or sickness compensation law, employment (and compensation therefor), the Board is authorized to reimburse such State such portion of such unemployment or sickness benefits as the Board deems equitable; such reimbursements shall be paid from the account, and are included within the meaning of the word “benefits” as used in this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27cd7f5f-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Assistance from employers and labor organizations; compensation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board may enter into agreements or arrangements with employers, organizations of employers, and railway-labor organizations which are duly organized in accordance with the provisions of the Railway Labor Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t45/s151">45 U.S.C. 151</ref> et seq.], for securing the performance of services or the use of facilities in connection with the administration of this chapter, and may compensate any such employer or organization therefor upon such reasonable basis as the Board shall prescribe, but not to exceed the additional expense incurred by such employer or organization by reason of the performance of such services or making available the use of such facilities pursuant to such agreements or arrangements. Such employers and organizations, and persons employed by either of them, shall not be subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s209">section 209 of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27cd7f60-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Free employment offices; registration of unemployed; statements of sickness; reemployment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board may establish, maintain, and operate free employment offices, and may designate as free employment offices facilities maintained by (i) a railway labor organization which is duly authorized and designated to represent employees in accordance with the Railway Labor Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t45/s151">45 U.S.C. 151</ref> et seq.], or (ii) any other labor organization which has been or may be organized in accordance with the provisions of the Railway Labor Act, or (iii) one or more employers, or (iv) an organization of employers, or (v) a group of such employers and labor organizations, or (vi) a State, Territorial, foreign, or the Federal Government. The Board may also enter into agreements or arrangements with one or more employers or railway labor organizations organized in accordance with the provisions of the Railway Labor Act, pursuant to which notice of the availability of work and the rights of employees with respect to such work under agreements between such employers and railway labor organizations may be filed with employment offices and pursuant to which employees registered with employment offices may be referred to such work.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board shall prescribe a procedure for registration of unemployed employees at employment offices. Such procedure for registration shall be prescribed with a view to such registration affording substantial evidence of the days of unemployment of the employees who register. The Board may, when such registration is made personally by an employee, accept such registration as initial proof of unemployment sufficient to certify for payment a claim for benefits.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board shall provide a form or forms for statements of sickness and a procedure for the execution and filing thereof. Such forms and procedure shall be designated with a view to having such statements provide substantial evidence of the days of sickness of the employee. Such statements may be executed by any doctor (authorized to practice in the State or foreign jurisdiction in which he practices his profession) or any officer or supervisory employee of a hospital, clinic, group health association, or other similar organization, who is qualified under such regulations as the Board may prescribe to execute such statements. The Board shall issue regulations for the qualification of such persons to execute such statements. When so executed by any such person, or, in the discretion of the Board, by others designated by the Board individually or by groups, they may be accepted as initial proof of days of sickness sufficient to certify for payment a claim for benefits.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The regulations of the Board concerning registration at employment offices by unemployed persons may provide for group registration and reporting, through employers, and need not be uniform with respect to different classes of employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The operation of any employment facility operated by the Board shall be directed primarily toward the reemployment of employees who have theretofore been substantially employed by employers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27cfc951-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Advisory councils; members’ remuneration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board may appoint national or local advisory councils composed of equal numbers of representatives of employers, representatives of employees, and persons representing the general public, for the purpose of discussing problems in connection with the administration of this chapter and aiding the Board in formulating policies. The members of such councils shall serve without remuneration, but shall be reimbursed for any necessary traveling and subsistence expenses or on a per diem basis in lieu of subsistence expenses.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27cfc952-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Reduction of unemployment; training and reemployment of unemployed employees, etc.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board, with the advice and aid of any advisory council appointed by it, shall take appropriate steps to reduce and prevent unemployment and loss of earnings; to encourage and assist in the adoption of practical methods of vocational training, retraining, and vocational guidance; to promote the reemployment of unemployed employees; and to these ends to carry on and publish the results of investigations and research studies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27cfc953-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Necessary and incidental powers; employees of Board, employment, remuneration, civil-service laws, registration of unemployed, and detail</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In addition to the powers and duties expressly provided, the Board shall have and exercise all the powers and duties necessary to administer or incidental to administering this chapter, and in connection therewith shall have such of the powers, duties, and remedies provided in subdivisions (5), (6), and (9) of section 7(b) of the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t45/s231f/b">45 U.S.C. 231f(b)</ref>] with respect to the administration of the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t45/s231">45 U.S.C. 231</ref> et seq.], as are not inconsistent with the express provisions of this chapter. A person in the employ of the Board under section 205 of the Act of Congress approved <date date="1937-06-24">June 24, 1937</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/50/307">50 Stat. 307</ref>), shall acquire a competitive classified civil-service status if, after recommendation by the Board to the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, he shall pass such noncompetitive tests of fitness as the Director of the Office of Personnel Management may prescribe. A person in the employ of the Board on <date date="1939-06-30">June 30, 1939</date>, and on <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>, and who has had experience in railroad service, shall acquire a competitive classified civil-service status if, after recommendation by the Board to the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, he shall pass such noncompetitive tests of fitness for the position for which the Board recommends him as the Director of the Office of Personnel Management may prescribe.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board may employ such persons and provide for their remuneration and expenses, as may be necessary for the proper administration of this chapter. Such persons shall be employed and their remuneration prescribed in accordance with the civil-service laws and chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5: <i>Provided</i>, That all positions to which such persons are appointed, except one administrative assistant to each member of the Board, shall be in and under the competitive civil service and shall not be removed or excepted therefrom: <i>Provided</i>, That in the employment of such persons the Board shall give preference, as between applicants attaining the same grades, to persons who have had experience in railroad service, and notwithstanding any other provisions of law, rules, or regulations, no other preference shall be given or recognized: <i>And provided further</i>, That certification by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management of persons for appointment to any positions at minimum salaries of $4,600 per annum, or less, shall, if the Board so requests, be upon the basis of competitive examinations, written, oral, or both, as the Board may request: <i>And provided further</i>, That, for the purpose of registering unemployed employees who reside in areas in which no employer facilities are located, or in which no employer will make facilities available for the registration of such employees, the Board may, without regard to civil-service laws and chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, appoint persons to accept, in such areas, registration of such employees and perform services incidental thereto and may compensate such persons on a piece-rate basis to be determined by the Board. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Board may detail employees from stations outside the District of Columbia to other stations outside the District of Columbia or to service in the District of Columbia, and may detail employees in the District of Columbia to service outside the District of Columbia: <i>Provided</i>, That all details hereunder shall be made by specific order and in no case for a period of time exceeding one hundred and twenty days. Details so made may, on expiration, be renewed from time to time by order of the Board, in each particular case, for periods not exceeding one hundred and twenty days.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27cfc954-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362/m"><num value="m" class="bold">(m)</num><heading class="bold"> Delegation of powers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board is authorized to delegate to any member, officer, or employee of the Board any of the powers conferred upon the Board by this chapter, excluding only the power to prescribe rules and regulations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27cfc955-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362/n"><num value="n" class="bold">(n)</num><heading class="bold"> Sickness benefits; examinations; information and reports; contracts and expenses for examinations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any employee claiming, entitled to, or receiving sickness benefits under this chapter may be required to take such examination, physical, medical, mental, or otherwise, in such manner and at such times and by such qualified individuals, including medical officers or employees of the United States or a State, as the Board may prescribe. The place or places of examination shall be reasonably convenient for the employee. No sickness benefits shall be payable under this chapter with respect to any period during which the employee unreasonably refuses to take or willfully obstructs an examination as prescribed by the Board.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any doctor who renders any attendance, treatment, attention, or care, or performs any examination with respect to a sickness of an employee, upon which a claim or right to benefits under this chapter is based, shall furnish the Board, in such manner and form and at such times as the Board by regulations may prescribe, information and reports relative thereto and to the condition of the employee. An application for sickness benefits under this chapter shall contain a waiver of any doctor-patient privilege that the employee may have with respect to any sickness period upon which such application is based: <i>Provided</i>, That such information shall not be disclosed by the Board except in a proceeding relating to any claim for benefits by the employee under this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board may enter into agreements or arrangements with doctors, hospitals, clinics, or other persons for securing the examination, physical, medical, mental, or otherwise, of employees claiming, entitled to, or receiving sickness benefits under this chapter and the performance of services or the use of facilities in connection with the execution of statements of sickness. The Board may compensate any such doctors, hospitals, clinics, or other persons upon such reasonable basis as the Board shall prescribe. Such doctors, hospitals, clinics, or other persons and persons employed by any of them shall not be subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s209">section 209 of title 18</ref>. In the event that the Board pays for the physical or mental examination of an employee or for the execution of a statement of sickness and such employee’s claim for benefits is based upon such examination or statement, the Board shall deduct from any sickness benefits payable to the employee pursuant to such claim such amount as, in the judgment of the Board, is a fair and reasonable charge for such examination or execution of such statement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27cfc956-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362/o"><num value="o" class="bold">(o)</num><heading class="bold"> Liability of third party for sickness; reimbursement of Board</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Benefits payable to an employee with respect to days of sickness shall be payable regardless of the liability of any person to pay damages for such infirmity. The Board shall be entitled to reimbursement from any sum or damages paid or payable to such employee or other person through suit, compromise, settlement, judgment, or otherwise on account of any liability (other than a liability under a health, sickness, accident, or similar insurance policy) based upon such infirmity, to the extent that it will have paid or will pay benefits for days of sickness resulting from such infirmity. Upon notice to the person against whom such right or claim exists or is asserted, the Board shall have a lien upon such right or claim, any judgment obtained thereunder, and any sum or damages paid under such right or claim, to the extent of the amount to which the Board is entitled by way of reimbursement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27cfc957-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362/p"><num value="p" class="bold">(p)</num><heading class="bold"> Disqualification to execute statements of sickness or receive fees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board may, after hearing, disqualify any person from executing statements of sickness who, the Board finds, (i) will have solicited, or will have employed another to solicit, for himself or for another the execution of any such statement, or (ii) will have made false or misleading statements to the Board, to any employer, or to any employee, in connection with the awarding of any benefits under this chapter, or (iii) will have failed to submit medical reports and records required by the Board under this chapter, or will have failed to submit any other reports, records, or information required by the Board in connection with the administration of this chapter or any other Act heretofore or hereafter administered by the Board, or (iv) will have engaged in any malpractice or other professional misconduct. No fees or charges of any kind shall accrue to any such person from the Board after his disqualification.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27cfc958-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362/q"><num value="q" class="bold">(q)</num><heading class="bold"> Investigations and research with respect to accidents and disabilities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board shall engage in and conduct research projects, investigations, and studies with respect to the cause, care, and prevention of, and benefits for, accidents and disabilities and other subjects deemed by the Board to be related thereto, and shall recommend legislation deemed advisable in the light of such research projects, investigations, and studies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27cfc959-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362/r"><num value="r" class="bold">(r)</num><heading class="bold"> Duty of Board to make certain computations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id27cfc95a-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362/r/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation base</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">On or before <date date="1988-12-01">December 1, 1988</date>, and on or before December 1 of each year thereafter, the Board shall compute—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id27cfc95b-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362/r/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s351/i">section 351(i) of this title</ref>, the monthly compensation base which shall be applicable with respect to months in the next succeeding calendar year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id27cfc95c-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362/r/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the amounts described in <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s351/k">section 351(k) of this title</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s352/c">section 352(c) of this title</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s353">section 353 of this title</ref>, and section 354(a–2)(i)(A) of this title that are related to changes in the monthly compensation base.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id27cfc95d-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362/r/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Maximum daily benefit rate</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">On or before <date date="1989-06-01">June 1, 1989</date>, and on or before June 1 of each year thereafter, the Board shall compute in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s352/a/3">section 352(a)(3) of this title</ref> the maximum daily benefit rate which shall be applicable with respect to days of unemployment and days of sickness in registration periods beginning after June 30 of that year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id27cfc95e-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s362/r/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice in Federal Register and to employers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 10 days after each computation made under this subsection, the Board shall publish notice in the Federal Register and shall notify each employer and employee representative of the amount so computed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id27cfc95f-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">(<ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch680/s12">June 25, 1938, ch. 680, § 12</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/1107">52 Stat. 1107</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1939-06-20/ch227/s16">June 20, 1939, ch. 227, § 16</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/53/848">53 Stat. 848</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1940-10-10/ch842">Oct. 10, 1940, ch. 842</ref>, §§ 23, 24, <ref href="/us/stat/54/1099">54 Stat. 1099</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1946-07-31/ch709">July 31, 1946, ch. 709</ref>, §§ 319–323, <ref href="/us/stat/60/739">60 Stat. 739</ref>, 740; <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646">June 25, 1948, ch. 646</ref>, §§ 1, 32(b), <ref href="/us/stat/62/878">62 Stat. 878</ref>, 895, 991; <ref href="/us/act/1949-05-24/ch139/s127">May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 127</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/107">63 Stat. 107</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-10-28/ch782">Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782</ref>, title II, § 202(29), title XI, § 1106(a), <ref href="/us/stat/63/956">63 Stat. 956</ref>, 972; <ref href="/us/act/1955-08-12/ch869/s6">Aug. 12, 1955, ch. 869, § 6</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/716">69 Stat. 716</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/927">Pub. L. 85–927</ref>, pt. II, § 206, <date date="1958-09-06">Sept. 6, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1783">72 Stat. 1783</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/507/s1/37">Pub. L. 86–507, § 1(37)</ref>, <date date="1960-06-11">June 11, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/202">74 Stat. 202</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/700/tII/s206">Pub. L. 89–700, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1966-10-30">Oct. 30, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1087">80 Stat. 1087</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/257/tII/s206">Pub. L. 90–257, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="1968-02-15">Feb. 15, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/25">82 Stat. 25</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/452/tII/s239">Pub. L. 91–452, title II, § 239</ref>, <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/930">84 Stat. 930</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/445/tIV/s405">Pub. L. 93–445, title IV, § 405</ref>, <date date="1974-10-16">Oct. 16, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1359">88 Stat. 1359</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3783">92 Stat. 3783</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tVII">Pub. L. 100–647, title VII</ref>, §§ 7101(e), 7104(d), (e), <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3758">102 Stat. 3758</ref>, 3772.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id27cfc960-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id27cfc961-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id27cfc962-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch680">act June 25, 1938, ch. 680</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/1094">52 Stat. 1094</ref>, which enacted this chapter and amended sections 503 and 1104 and former <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1107">section 1107 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s367">section 367 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Railway Labor Act, referred to in subsecs. (h) and (i), is <ref href="/us/act/1926-05-20/ch347">act May 20, 1926, ch. 347</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/577">44 Stat. 577</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 8 (§ 151 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s151">section 151 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Railroad Retirement Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (<i>l</i>), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-29/ch812">act Aug. 29, 1935, ch. 812</ref>, as amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/93/445/tI/s101">Pub. L. 93–445, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1974-10-16">Oct. 16, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1305">88 Stat. 1305</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter IV (§ 231 et seq.) of chapter 9 of this title. For further details and complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Codification note set out preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s231">section 231 of this title</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s231t">section 231t of this title</ref>, and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 205 of the Act of Congress approved <date date="1937-06-24">June 24, 1937</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/50/307">50 Stat. 307</ref>), referred to in subsec. (<i>l</i>), is section 205 of <ref href="/us/act/1937-06-24/ch382">act June 24, 1937, ch. 382</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/50/307">50 Stat. 307</ref>, which is not classified to the Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id27cfc963-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsecs. (h) and (n), “<ref href="/us/usc/t18/s209">section 209 of title 18</ref>” substituted for reference to the Act of <date date="1917-03-03">March 3, 1917</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/39/1106">39 Stat. 1106</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s66">5 U.S.C. 66</ref>) on authority of (1) <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch645">act June 25, 1948, ch. 645</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/683">62 Stat. 683</ref>, section 1 of which enacted Title 18, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, and which enacted in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1914">section 1914 of Title 18</ref> the provisions formerly classified to section 66 of former Title 5; and (2) <ref href="/us/pl/87/849/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 87–849</ref>, <date date="1962-10-23">Oct. 23, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/1126">76 Stat. 1126</ref>, which repealed <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1914">section 1914 of Title 18</ref> and supplanted it with section 209, and which provided that exemptions from section 1914 shall be deemed exemptions from section 209. For further details, see Exemptions note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s203">section 203 of Title 18</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (<i>l</i>), “chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5” substituted for “the Classification Act of 1949, as amended” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s7/b">Pub. L. 89–554, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/631">80 Stat. 631</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In penultimate sentence of subsec. (<i>l</i>), following the first word “Notwithstanding”, the words “the provisions of the Act of <date date="1906-06-22">June 22, 1906</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/34/449">34 Stat. 449</ref>), or” have been omitted as obsolete. The provisions were enacted as <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3342">section 3342 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees, by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554">Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/425">80 Stat. 425</ref>. <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3342">Section 3342 of Title 5</ref> was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/89/762/s1/a">Pub. L. 89–762, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-11-05">Nov. 5, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1312">80 Stat. 1312</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id27cfc964-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s7104/d">Pub. L. 100–647, § 7104(d)</ref>, added cl. (iv).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s7104/e">Pub. L. 100–647, § 7104(e)</ref>, struck out “court” before “proceeding” in proviso of second par.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (r). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s7101/e">Pub. L. 100–647, § 7101(e)</ref>, added subsec. (r).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/93/445">Pub. L. 93–445</ref> substituted “subdivisions (5), (6), and (9) of section 7(b) of the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974” for “section 10(b)(4) of the Railroad Retirement Act of 1937”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/91/452">Pub. L. 91–452</ref> struck out subsec. (c) which related to immunity from prosecution of any person compelled to testify or produce evidence, documentary or otherwise, after claiming his privilege against self-incrimination.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/90/257/s206/a">Pub. L. 90–257, § 206(a)</ref>, struck out references to maternity benefits and laws and made changes in punctuation and grammar necessitated thereby.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/90/257/s206/b">Pub. L. 90–257, § 206(b)</ref>, struck out references to maternity benefits and maternity compensation laws and made changes in punctuation and grammar necessitated thereby.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/90/257/s206/c">Pub. L. 90–257, § 206(c)</ref>, struck out provisions making reference to maternity sickness and to expected and actual date of birth of the child required to be included in report of maternity sickness.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n). <ref href="/us/pl/90/257/s206/d">Pub. L. 90–257, § 206(d)</ref>, struck out references to maternity benefits and to services of a doctor as to expected date of birth of a female employee’s child, or the birth of such a child.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/89/700">Pub. L. 89–700</ref> authorized Board to furnish such information to any person or organization upon payment of the cost incurred by reason thereof, and requiring amounts so paid to Board to be credited to railroad unemployment insurance administration fund.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/89/700">Pub. L. 89–700</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t45/s353">section 353 of this title</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t45/s353/a">section 353(a) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1960—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/86/507">Pub. L. 86–507</ref> inserted “or by certified mail” after “registered mail”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/85/927">Pub. L. 85–927</ref> struck out “except that the Board may fix the salary of a director of unemployment insurance at $10,000 per annum” before first proviso in second paragraph, and substituted “Classification Act of 1949” for “Classification Act of 1923”, immediately preceding such first proviso, which substitution had already been executed in accordance with act <date date="1949-10-28">Oct. 28, 1949</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1955—Subsec. (<i>l</i>). Act <date date="1955-08-12">Aug. 12, 1955</date>, specifically provided for employees of Railroad Retirement Board to be in and under competitive civil service.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1949—Subsec. (<i>l</i>). Act <date date="1949-10-28">Oct. 28, 1949</date>, substituted “Classification Act of 1949” for “Classification Act of 1923” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1946—Subsec. (b). Act <date date="1946-07-31">July 31, 1946</date>, § 319, inserted provisions relating to the District Court of the United States for the Northern District of Illinois.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). Act <date date="1946-07-31">July 31, 1946</date>, § 320, inserted references to sickness or maternity laws and benefits.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). Act <date date="1946-07-31">July 31, 1946</date>, § 321, inserted references to sickness or maternity laws and benefits and struck out phrase limiting second paragraph to eligibility with respect to unemployment after <date date="1939-06-30">June 30, 1939</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). Act <date date="1946-07-31">July 31, 1946</date>, § 322, added third par., providing for form, execution and filing of statements of sickness.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (n) to (q). Act <date date="1946-07-31">July 31, 1946</date>, § 323, added subsecs. (n) to (q).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1940—Subsec. (<i>l</i>). Act <date date="1940-10-10">Oct. 10, 1940</date>, § 22, inserted provisions relating to acquisition of competitive classified civil-service status by a person in the employ of Board on <date date="1939-06-30">June 30, 1939</date>, and <date date="1940-06-30">June 30, 1940</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act <date date="1940-10-10">Oct. 10, 1940</date>, § 23, inserted provisos relating to personnel for registering unemployed employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1939—Subsec. (g). Act <date date="1939-06-20">June 20, 1939</date>, inserted “, with respect to unemployment after <date date="1939-06-30">June 30, 1939</date>” after “employee is eligible” and struck out “<date date="1939-06-30">June 30, 1939</date>” after “therefor) after”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id27cfc965-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id27cfc966-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b) of this section was amended by act <date date="1948-06-25">June 25, 1948</date>, § 32(b), eff. <date date="1948-09-01">Sept. 1, 1948</date>, as amended by act <date date="1949-05-24">May 24, 1949</date>, which substituted “United States District Court for the District of Columbia” for “District Court of the United States for the District of Columbia”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“United States District Court for the Northern District of Illinois” substituted for “District Court of the United States for the Northern District of Illinois” in view of act <date date="1948-06-25">June 25, 1948</date>, which states that “There shall be in each judicial district a district court which shall be a court of record known as the United States District Court for the district”, and that “Illinois is divided into three judicial districts to be known as the Northern, Southern, and Eastern Districts of Illinois.” See sections 88 and 132 of Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id27cfc967-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 7104(d), (e) of <ref href="/us/pl/100/647">Pub. L. 100–647</ref>, effective <date date="1990-01-01">Jan. 1, 1990</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s7104/f">section 7104(f) of Pub. L. 100–647</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s355">section 355 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id27cfc968-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1974 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/93/445">Pub. L. 93–445</ref> effective <date date="1975-01-01">Jan. 1, 1975</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/93/445/s603">section 603 of Pub. L. 93–445</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s402">section 402 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id27cfc969-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1970 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/452">Pub. L. 91–452</ref> effective on sixtieth day following <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, and not to affect any immunity to which any individual is entitled under this section by reason of any testimony given before sixtieth day following <date date="1970-10-15">Oct. 15, 1970</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/452/s260">section 260 of Pub. L. 91–452</ref>, set out as an Effective Date; Savings Provisions note under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s6001">section 6001 of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id27cfc96a-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1968 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/90/257">Pub. L. 90–257</ref> effective <date date="1968-07-01">July 1, 1968</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/257/s208">section 208 of Pub. L. 90–257</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s352">section 352 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id27cfc96b-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1958 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/85/927">Pub. L. 85–927</ref> effective <date date="1958-09-06">Sept. 6, 1958</date>, except as otherwise indicated, see <ref href="/us/pl/85/927/s207/c">section 207(c) of Pub. L. 85–927</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s351">section 351 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id27cfc96c-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1946 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by act <date date="1946-07-31">July 31, 1946</date>, effective <date date="1946-07-31">July 31, 1946</date>, see section 401 of act <date date="1946-07-31">July 31, 1946</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id27cfc96d-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1940 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of amendment by act <date date="1940-10-10">Oct. 10, 1940</date>, see section 1 of act <date date="1940-10-10">Oct. 10, 1940</date>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s351">section 351 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="repeals" id="id27cfc96e-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Repeals</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1949-10-28/ch782">Act Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782</ref>, cited as a credit to this section, was repealed (subject to a savings clause) by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554">Pub. L. 89–554</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, § 8, <ref href="/us/stat/80/632">80 Stat. 632</ref>, 655.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id27cfc96f-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Advisory Councils</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Advisory councils in existence on <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period following <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, unless, in the case of a council established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such council is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a council established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided by law. Advisory councils established after <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on the date of their establishment, unless, in the case of a council established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such council is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a council established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided by law. See sections 1001(2) and 1013 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id27cfc970-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Railroad Unemployment Compensation Committee</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/76/tV/s504">Pub. L. 98–76, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="1983-08-12">Aug. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/441">97 Stat. 441</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/76/tV/s504">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> Representatives of railroad labor and railroad management shall jointly establish (and jointly appoint the members of) a committee to be known as the ‘Railroad Unemployment Compensation Committee’ (hereinafter in this section referred to as the ‘Committee’).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><chapeau> The Committee shall consist of five members—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> two of whom shall be representatives of railroad labor,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> two of whom shall be representatives of railroad management, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> one of whom shall be an individual who shall not be in the employment of or pecuniarily or otherwise interested in any employer (as defined in section 1 of the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t45/s231">45 U.S.C. 231</ref>]) or any organization of employees (as defined in section 1 of such Act).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><chapeau> The Committee shall review all aspects of the unemployment and sickness insurance systems provided by the Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act [this chapter] including (but not limited to) a review of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> benefit levels,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> experience rating,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> debt repayment and interest on debt,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> waiting period for unemployment benefits and qualifying requirements, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> alternatives to the railroad unemployment insurance system such as covering railroad employees under the Federal-State unemployment compensation system.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><chapeau> Not later than <date date="1984-04-01">April 1, 1984</date>, the Committee shall submit a report to the Congress containing recommendations—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> with respect to the review conducted under subsection (c), and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> with respect to the repayment of funds which the railroad unemployment insurance system has borrowed from the Railroad Retirement Account.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Any recommendation submitted under paragraph (2) shall contain adjustments in contributions and benefits which will enable the railroad unemployment compensation system to repay all loans from the Railroad Retirement Account before <date date="2000-12-31">December 31, 2000</date>.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><content> The Railroad Retirement Board (and any other department, agency, or instrumentality of the Federal Government) is authorized to cooperate with, and assist, the Committee (at its request) in carrying out its duties by furnishing services, information, data, or other material which the Committee determines will be helpful in carrying out its duties.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id27cfc971-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id27cfc972-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Director of the Office of Personnel Management” substituted for “Civil Service Commission” in subsec. (<i>l</i>), pursuant to Reorg. Plan No. 2 of 1978, § 102, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3783">92 Stat. 3783</ref>, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1101">section 1101 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees, which transferred functions vested by statute in United States Civil Service Commission to Director of Office of Personnel Management (except as otherwise specified), effective <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, as provided by section 1–102 of Ex. Ord. No. 12107, <date date="1978-12-28">Dec. 28, 1978</date>, 44 F.R. 1055, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1101">section 1101 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id27cfc973-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of President under subsec. (<i>l</i>) of this section delegated to Chairman of the Railroad Retirement Board by Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2005-02-09">Feb. 9, 2005</date>, 70 F.R. 7631, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s231f">section 231f of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
