<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id27d6f5fa-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s712"><num value="712">§ 712.</num><heading> Functions of Association</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27d6f5fb-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s712/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> General</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Association is authorized to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27d6f5fc-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s712/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> monitor the financial performance of the Corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27d6f5fd-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s712/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> review whether the goals and requirements of this chapter are met;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27d6f5fe-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s712/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> purchase or otherwise acquire or receive, and hold and dispose of securities (whether debt or equity) of the Corporation under sections 726 and 727 of this title and exercise all of the rights, privileges, and powers of a holder of any such securities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27d6f5ff-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s712/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> purchase accounts receivable of the Corporation in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s727">section 727 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27d6f600-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s712/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> appoint and fix the compensation of such personnel as the Association considers necessary and appropriate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27d6f601-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s712/a/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002036">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002036"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “(6)”.</note> determine the value of the Alaska Railroad, as required by <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s1204">section 1204 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27d6f602-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s712/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Investment of funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Uncommitted funds of the Association shall be kept in cash on hand or on deposit, or invested in obligations of the United States or guaranteed thereby, or in obligations, participations, or other investments which are lawful investments for fiduciary, trust, or public funds.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27d6f603-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s712/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Exemption from taxation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Association, including its franchise, capital reserves, surplus, security holdings, and income shall be exempt from all taxation now or hereafter imposed by the United States, any commonwealth, territory, dependency, or possession thereof, or by any State or political subdivision thereof, except that any real property of the Association shall be subject to taxation to the same extent according to its value as other real property is taxed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27d6f604-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s712/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27d6f605-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s712/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002037">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002037"><num>2</num> Par. “(1)” designation supplied editorially.</note> The Association shall transmit to the Congress and the President, not later than 90 days after the end of each fiscal year, a comprehensive and detailed report on all activities of the Association during the preceding fiscal year. Each such report shall include (A) the Association’s statement of specific and detailed objectives for the activities and programs conducted and assisted under this chapter; (B) statements of the Association’s conclusions as to the effectiveness of such activities and programs in meeting the stated objectives and the purposes of this chapter, measured through the end of the preceding fiscal year; (C) recommendations with respect to any legislation or administrative action which the Association deems necessary or desirable; (D) a statistical compilation of the obligations issued, certificates of value issued, securities purchased, and loans made under this chapter; (E) a summary of outstanding problems confronting the Association, in order of priority; (F) all other information required to be submitted to the Congress pursuant to any other provision of this chapter; and (G) the Association’s projections and plans for its activities and programs during the next fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27d6f606-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s712/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> For the fiscal year beginning <date date="1977-10-01">October 1, 1977</date>, and ending <date date="1978-09-30">September 30, 1978</date>, the Association shall transmit to the Congress and the President, not later than 30 days after the end of each quarter of such fiscal year, a comprehensive and detailed report on all expenditures and use of funds during the preceding fiscal quarter, including an assessment of the status of projects for such preceding fiscal quarter and a projection of activities proposed for the next fiscal quarter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27d6f607-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s712/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The Association shall transmit to the Congress, no later than 30 days after the end of each fiscal quarter, a report with respect to the proceedings before the special court to determine the valuation of rail properties conveyed to the Corporation under <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s743">section 743 of this title</ref>. Each such report shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27d6f608-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s712/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a detailed accounting of the Federal funds expended during such quarter in connection with such proceedings, and the purposes for which such funds were expended;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27d6f609-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s712/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> an explanation of the status of such proceedings, including the prospects for settlement or conclusion; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27d6f60a-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s712/d/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> an identification of which responsibilities in connection with such proceedings are being carried out directly by the Association, and which are being carried out by contract with private organizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27d6f60b-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s712/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Budget</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The receipts and disbursements of the Association (other than administrative expenses referred to in subsection (g) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002038">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002038"><num>3</num> So in original. Subsec. (g) redesignated (f) by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref>.</note> of this section and receipts and disbursements under <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s726">section 726 of this title</ref> and <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s746">section 746 of this title</ref>) in the discharge of its functions shall not be included in the totals of the budget of the United States Government, and shall be exempt from any annual expenditure and net lending (budget outlays) limitations imposed on a budget of the United States Government. The Chairman of the Association shall transmit annually to the Congress a budget for program activities and for administrative expenses of the Association. The Chairman shall report annually to the Congress the amount of net lending of the Association, which would be included in the totals of the budgets of the United States Government, if the Association’s activities were not excluded from those totals as a result of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27d6f60c-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s712/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Accountability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Chairman of the Association shall transmit annually to the Office of Management and Budget a budget for administrative expenses of the Association. Whenever the Association submits any budget estimate or request to the Office of Management and Budget, it shall concurrently transmit a copy of the estimate or request to the Congress. Within budgetary constraints of the Congress, the maximum feasible and prudent budgetary flexibility shall be provided to the Association to permit effective operations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27d6f60d-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s712/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of litigation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No later than <date date="1980-03-01">March 1, 1980</date>, the Association and the Attorney General of the United States shall develop and submit to the Congress a feasibility study for the transfer, to the appropriate department or agency of the Federal Government, of all responsibility for representing the United States in the proceedings before the special court to determine the valuation of rail properties conveyed to the Corporation under <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s743">section 743 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27d6f60e-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s712/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of other functions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No later than <date date="1980-03-01">March 1, 1980</date>, the Association and the Secretary of Transportation shall develop and submit to the Congress a feasibility study for the transfer of all functions of the Association, other than those referred to in subsection (h) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002039">4</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002039"><num>4</num> So in original. Subsec. (h) redesignated (g) by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref>.</note> of this section, to the appropriate department or agency of the Federal Government, including the abolition of those functions which will no longer be necessary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27d6f60f-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s712/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Monitoring of contractors</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board of Directors of the Association shall adopt procedures to insure (1) that contractors, including law firms, provide reports containing written verification of tasks assigned, work performed, time worked, and costs incurred, including periodic status reports on work performed, (2) that such reports are audited by the Association, (3) that no funds are paid to contractors without written reports complying with the requirements of this subsection, and (4) that the Association applies such procedures uniformly to all contractors.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id27d6f610-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/236/tII/s202">Pub. L. 93–236, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1974-01-02">Jan. 2, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/990">87 Stat. 990</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/5/s2/a">Pub. L. 94–5, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1975-02-28">Feb. 28, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/7">89 Stat. 7</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/210/tVI">Pub. L. 94–210, title VI</ref>, §§ 601(c), 607(b), (c), <date date="1976-02-05">Feb. 5, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/84">90 Stat. 84</ref>, 96; <ref href="/us/pl/95/199/s2">Pub. L. 95–199, § 2</ref>, <date date="1977-11-23">Nov. 23, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1423">91 Stat. 1423</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/73/tII">Pub. L. 96–73, title II</ref>, §§ 202, 203, <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/555">93 Stat. 555</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXI/s1148/a">Pub. L. 97–35, title XI, § 1148(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/674">95 Stat. 674</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/468/tVI/s605/e">Pub. L. 97–468, title VI, § 605(e)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-14">Jan. 14, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2564">96 Stat. 2564</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id27d6f611-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id27d6f612-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id27d6f613-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f), formerly (g), of this section as originally enacted consisted of pars. (1) and (2). Par. (1), which amended section 856 of former Title 31, Money and Finance, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s5/b">Pub. L. 97–258, § 5(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1068">96 Stat. 1068</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 31.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id27d6f614-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (a)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/97/468">Pub. L. 97–468</ref> added par. (11).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s1148/a/1">Pub. L. 97–35, § 1148(a)(1)</ref>, substituted provisions respecting financial performance monitoring, goal review, etc., for provisions respecting plan preparation and implementation, issuance of obligations, etc.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b) to (j). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s1148/a">Pub. L. 97–35, § 1148(a)</ref>, struck out subsec. (b) which related to additional duties of the Association, and redesignated subsecs. (c) to (j) as (b) to (i), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/96/73/s202">Pub. L. 96–73, § 202</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (h) to (j). <ref href="/us/pl/96/73/s203">Pub. L. 96–73, § 203</ref>, added subsecs. (h) to (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/95/199">Pub. L. 95–199</ref> substituted “Reports” for “Annual report” in heading, redesignated cls. (1) through (7) as cls. (A) through (G) in first par., and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/94/210/s601/c">Pub. L. 94–210, § 601(c)</ref>, inserted provisions relating to securities under <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s726">section 726 of this title</ref> and certificates of value under <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s746">section 746 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/94/210/s607/b">Pub. L. 94–210, § 607(b)</ref>, in cl. (4) inserted “, certificates of value issued, securities purchased,” after “obligations issued”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/94/210/s607/c">Pub. L. 94–210, § 607(c)</ref>, inserted provisions relating to receipts and disbursements under sections 726 and 746 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/94/5/s2/a/1">Pub. L. 94–5, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “and express” after “rail” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/94/5/s2/a/2">Pub. L. 94–5, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “; and” for a period at end of par. (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/94/5/s2/a/3">Pub. L. 94–5, § 2(a)(3)</ref>, added par. (8).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id27d6f615-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id27d6f616-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> effective <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s1169">section 1169 of Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s1101">section 1101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id27d6f617-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1979 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/73">Pub. L. 96–73</ref> effective <date date="1979-10-01">Oct. 1, 1979</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/73/s501/a">section 501(a) of Pub. L. 96–73</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id27d6f618-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, of provisions of law requiring submittal to Congress of any annual, semiannual, or other regular periodic report listed in House Document No. 103–7 (in which reports required under subsecs. (d)(1), (3), (e), and (f) of this section are listed as the 3rd through 6th items on page 195), see <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, and section 1(a)(4) [div. A, § 1402(1)] of <ref href="/us/pl/106/554">Pub. L. 106–554</ref>, set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id27d6f619-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Special Court, Regional Rail Reorganization Act of 1973, and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Special court abolished and all jurisdiction and functions transferred to United States District Court for District of Columbia, see <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s719/b/2">section 719(b)(2) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id27d6f61a-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of United States Railway Association and Transfer of Functions and Securities</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">See <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s1341">section 1341 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id27d6f61b-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Applicability of National Environmental Policy Act</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Application of National Environmental Policy Act to actions of Commission not affected by title VI of <ref href="/us/pl/94/210">Pub. L. 94–210</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/210/s619">section 619 of Pub. L. 94–210</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s791">section 791 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
