<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id27de210b-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s722"><num value="722">§ 722.</num><heading> Records, audit, and examination</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27de210c-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s722/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Records</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each recipient of financial assistance under this subchapter, whether in the form of loans, obligations, or other arrangements, shall keep such records as the Association or the Secretary shall prescribe, including records which fully disclose the amount and disposition by such recipient of the proceeds of such assistance and such other records as will facilitate an effective audit.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27de210d-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s722/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Audit and examination</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Association, the Secretary, and the Comptroller General of the United States, or any of their duly authorized representatives shall, until the expiration of 3 years after the implementation of the final system plan, have access for the purpose of audit and examination to any books, documents, papers, and records of such recipients which in the opinion of the Association, the Secretary, or the Comptroller General may be related or pertinent to the loans, obligations or other arrangements referred to in subsection (a) of this section. The Association or any of its duly authorized representatives shall, until any financial assistance received under this subchapter has been repaid to the Association, have access to any such materials which concern any matter that may bear upon—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27de210e-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s722/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the ability of the recipient of such financial assistance to make repayment within the time fixed therefor;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27de210f-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s722/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the effectiveness with which the proceeds of such assistance is used; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27de2110-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s722/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the implementation of the final system plan and the realization of the declaration of policy of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id27de2111-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/236/tII/s212">Pub. L. 93–236, title II, § 212</ref>, <date date="1974-01-02">Jan. 2, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/1002">87 Stat. 1002</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id27de2112-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id27de2113-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id27de2114-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of United States Railway Association and Transfer of Functions and Securities</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">See <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s1341">section 1341 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
