<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id27e54d34-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744"><num value="744">§ 744.</num><heading> Termination and continuation of rail services</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27e54d35-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Discontinuance</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d36-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in subsections (c) and (f) of this section, rail service on rail properties of a railroad in reorganization in the region, or of a person leased, operated, or controlled by such a railroad, which transfers to the Corporation or to profitable railroads operating in the region all or substantially all of its rail properties designated for such conveyance in the final system plan, and rail service on rail properties of a profitable railroad operating in the region which transfers substantially all of its rail properties to the Corporation or to other railroads pursuant to the final system plan, may be discontinued, to the extent such discontinuance is not precluded by the terms of the leases and agreements referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s743/b/2">section 743(b)(2) of this title</ref>, if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27e54d37-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the final system plan does not designate rail service to be operated over such rail properties;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27e54d38-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> not sooner than 30 days following the effective date of the final system plan, the trustee or trustees of the applicable railroad in reorganization or a profitable railroad give notice in writing of intent to discontinue such service on a date certain which is not less than 60 days after the date of such notice or on the date of any conveyance ordered by the special court pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s743/b/1">section 743(b)(1) of this title</ref>, whichever is later; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27e54d39-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the notice required by subparagraph (B) of this paragraph is sent by certified mail to the Commission; to the chief executive officer, the transportation agencies, and the government of each political subdivision of each State in which such rail properties are located; and to each shipper who has used such rail service during the previous 12 months.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d3a-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d3b-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> If rail properties are not, in accordance with the designations in the final system plan, required to be operated, as a consequence of a recommended arrangement for joint use or operation of rail properties (under <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s716/g">section 716(g) of this title</ref>) or as part of a coordination project (under sections 716(c) and (g) of this title), rail service on such properties may be discontinued, subsequent to the date of conveyance of rail properties pursuant to such <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s743/b/1">section 743(b)(1) of this title</ref>, if the Commission determines that such rail service on such rail properties is not compensatory and if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27e54d3c-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/a/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the petitioner and any other railroad involved in such arrangement or coordination project have, prior to filing an application for such discontinuance, entered into a binding agreement (effective on or before the effective date of such discontinuance) to carry out such arrangement or project;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27e54d3d-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/a/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> such application is filed with the Commission not later than 1 year after the effective date of the final system plan; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27e54d3e-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/a/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> such discontinuance is not precluded by the terms of the leases and agreements referred to in such section 743(b)(2).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d3f-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> For purposes of this paragraph, rail service on rail properties is compensatory if the revenue attributable to such properties from such service equals or exceeds the sum of the avoidable costs of providing such service on such properties plus a reasonable return on the value of such rail properties, as determined in accordance with the standards developed pursuant to section 10362(b)(6) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002057">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002057"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of title 49.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d40-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The Commission shall make its final determination, with respect to any discontinuance requested under this paragraph, not later than 120 days after the date of filing of an application therefor. The applicant shall have the burden of proving that the service involved is not compensatory. If the Commission fails to make a final determination within such time, the application shall be deemed to be granted.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d41-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> The Commission may issue such rules, regulations, and procedures as it deems necessary for the conduct of its functions under this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27e54d42-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Abandonment</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d43-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in subsections (c) and (f) of this section, rail properties over which rail service has been discontinued under subsection (a) of this section may not be abandoned sooner than 120 days after the effective date of the discontinuance. Thereafter, except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, such rail properties may be abandoned upon 30 days’ notice in writing to any person (including a government entity) required to receive notice under subsection (a)(1)(C) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d44-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In any case in which rail properties proposed to be abandoned under this section are designated by the final system plan as rail properties which are suitable for use for other public purposes (including roads or highways, other forms of mass transportation, conservation, and recreation), such rail properties shall not be sold, leased, exchanged, or otherwise disposed of during the 240-day period beginning on the date of notice of proposed abandonment under this section unless such rail properties have first been offered, upon reasonable terms, for acquisition for public purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d45-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Rail service may be discontinued, under subsection (a) of this section, and rail properties may be abandoned, under this section, notwithstanding any provision of part A of subtitle IV of title 49, the constitution or law of any State, or the decision of any court or administrative agency of the United States or of any State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27e54d46-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Continuation of rail services</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No rail service may be discontinued and no rail properties may be abandoned, pursuant to this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27e54d47-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> in the case of service and properties referred to in subsections (a)(1) and (b)(1) of this section, after 2 years from the effective date of the final system plan or more than 2 years after the date on which the final rail service continuation payment is received, whichever is later; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27e54d48-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> if a financially responsible person (including a government entity) offers—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id27e54d49-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to provide a rail service continuation payment which is designed to cover the difference between the revenue attributable to such rail properties and the avoidable costs of providing rail service on such properties, together with a reasonable return on the value of such properties;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id27e54d4a-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to provide a rail service continuation payment which is payable pursuant to a lease or agreement with a State or with a local or regional transportation authority under which financial support was being provided on <date date="1974-01-02">January 2, 1974</date> for the continuation of rail passenger service; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id27e54d4b-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> to purchase, pursuant to subsection (f) of this section, such rail properties in order to operate rail services thereon.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">If a rail service continuation payment is offered, pursuant to paragraph (2)(A) of this subsection, for both freight and passenger service on the same rail properties, the owner of such properties may not be entitled to more than one payment of a reasonable return on the value of such properties.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27e54d4c-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Rail freight service</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d4d-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> If a rail service continuation payment is offered, pursuant to subsection (c)(2)(A) of this section, for rail freight service, the person offering such payment shall designate the operator of such service and enter into an operating agreement with such operator. The person offering such payment shall designate as the operator of such service—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27e54d4e-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Corporation, if rail properties of the Corporation connect with the line of railroad involved, unless the Commission determines that such rail service continuation could be performed more efficiently and economically by another railroad;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27e54d4f-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any other railroad whose rail properties connect with such line, if the Corporation’s rail properties do not so connect or if the Commission makes a determination in accordance with subparagraph (A) of this paragraph; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27e54d50-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> any responsible person (including a government entity) which is willing to operate rail service over such rail properties.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">A designated railroad may refuse to enter into such an operating agreement only if the Commission determines, on petition by any affected party, that the agreement would substantially impair such railroad’s ability to serve adequately its own patrons or to meet its outstanding common carrier obligations. The designated operator shall, pursuant to each such operating agreement (i) be obligated to operate rail freight service on such rail properties, and (ii) be entitled to receive, from the person offering such payment, the difference between the revenue attributable to such properties and the avoidable costs of providing service on such rail properties, together with a reasonable management fee, as determined by the Office.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d51-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The trustees of a railroad in reorganization shall permit rail service to be continued on any rail properties with respect to which a rail service continuation payment operating agreement has been entered into under this subsection. Such trustees shall receive a reasonable return on the value of such properties, as determined in accordance with the standards developed pursuant to section 10362(b)(6) <sup>1</sup> of title 49.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d52-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If necessary to prevent any disruption or loss of rail service, at any time after the date of conveyance, pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s743/b/1">section 743(b)(1) of this title</ref>, the Commission shall take such action as may be appropriate under its existing authority (including the enforcement of common carrier requirements applicable to railroads in reorganization in the region) to ensure compliance with obligations imposed under this subsection. The district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction, upon petition by the Commission or any interested person (including a government entity), to enforce any order of the Commission issued pursuant to the exercise of its authority under this subsection, or to enjoin any designated entity or the trustees of a railroad in reorganization in the region from refusing to comply with the provisions of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d53-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> No determination of reasonable payment for the use of rail properties of a railroad in reorganization in the region, and no determination of value of rail properties of such a railroad (including supporting or related documents or reports of any kind) which is made in connection with any lease agreement, contract of sale, or other agreement or understanding which is entered into after <date date="1976-10-19">October 19, 1976</date>—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27e54d54-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/d/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> pursuant to this section; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27e54d55-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/d/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> pursuant to section 762 <sup>1</sup> of this title or section 17 <sup>1</sup> of the Federal Transit Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1613">49 U.S.C. 1613</ref>),</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be admitted as evidence, or used for any other purpose, in any civil action, or any other proceeding for damages or compensation, arising under this chapter.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27e54d56-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Rail passenger service</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d57-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Corporation (or a profitable railroad) shall provide rail passenger service for a period of 180 days immediately following the date of conveyance (pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s743/b/1">section 743(b)(1) of this title</ref>), with respect to any rail properties over which a railroad in reorganization in the region, or a person leased, operated, or controlled by such a railroad, was providing rail passenger service immediately prior to such date of conveyance. Such service shall be provided on such properties regardless of whether or not such properties are designated in the final system plan as rail properties over which rail service is required to be operated, except with respect to properties over which such service is provided by the National Railroad Passenger Corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d58-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> If a State (or a local or regional transportation authority) was providing financial assistance to support the operation of rail passenger service, pursuant to a lease or agreement which was in effect immediately prior to the date of conveyance (pursuant to such <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s743/b/1">section 743(b)(1) of this title</ref>), the Corporation (or a profitable railroad) shall be bound by the service provisions of such lease or agreement for the duration of the 180-day mandatory operation period specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection. If a State or such an authority was providing financial assistance for the continuation of rail passenger service on rail properties immediately prior to such date of conveyance, it shall provide the same level of financial assistance during such 180-day mandatory operation period. If no such financial assistance was being provided or if no such lease or agreement was in effect immediately prior to such date of conveyance, with respect to any such rail properties, the Corporation (or a profitable railroad) shall provide the same level of rail passenger service, for the duration of such 180-day mandatory operation period, that was provided prior to such date by the applicable railroad. If—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27e54d59-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> such financial assistance is not provided;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27e54d5a-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a State (or a local or regional transportation authority) has not, by the end of such 180-day mandatory operation period, offered a rail service continuation payment pursuant to subsection (c)(2)(A) of this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27e54d5b-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> an applicable rail service continuation payment pursuant to such subsection (c)(2)(A) is not paid when it is due; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27e54d5c-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/e/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> a payment required under a lease or agreement, pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s743/b/2">section 743(b)(2) of this title</ref> or subsection (c)(2)(B) of this section, is not paid when it is due,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Corporation (or, where applicable, the National Railroad Passenger Corporation, a profitable railroad, or the trustee or trustees of a railroad in reorganization in the region) may (i) discontinue such rail passenger service, and (ii) with respect to rail properties not designated for inclusion in the final system plan, abandon such properties pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) of this section.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d5d-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to affect the obligation of the Corporation (or a profitable railroad), or of the trustees of the railroads in reorganization in the region, to provide rail passenger service pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s743/b/2">section 743(b)(2) of this title</ref> or subsection (c)(2)(B) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d5e-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> If a State (or a local or regional transportation authority)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27e54d5f-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/e/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> offers a rail service continuation payment, pursuant to subsection (c)(2)(A) of the <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002058">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002058"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “this”.</note> section, for the operation of rail passenger service after the 180-day mandatory operation period, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27e54d60-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/e/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provides compensation, pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection, for operations conducted during the 180-day mandatory operation period; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27e54d61-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/e/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> offers a rail service continuation payment, pursuant to subsection (c)(2)(A) of this section, for the operation of rail passenger service provided under an agreement or lease pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s743/b/2">section 743(b)(2) of this title</ref> or subsection (c)(2)(B) of this section where such offer is made for the continuation of the service beyond the period required by such agreement or lease, except that such services shall not be eligible for assistance under section 17(a)(2) <sup>1</sup> of the Federal Transit Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1613/a/2">49 U.S.C. 1613(a)(2)</ref>),</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Corporation (or a profitable railroad) shall continue to provide such service after the end of such period, except as otherwise provided in this subsection.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d62-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d63-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/e/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary shall reimburse the Corporation (or a profitable railroad) for any loss which is incurred by it during the 180-day mandatory operation period specified in paragraph (1) of this subsection which is not compensated for by a State (or a local or regional transportation authority). The amount of such reimbursement shall be determined pursuant to section 17(a)(1) <sup>1</sup> of the Federal Transit Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d64-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/e/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary shall reimburse States, local public bodies, and agencies thereof for additional costs incurred by such States, bodies, and agencies for rail service continuation payments for rail passenger service pursuant to section 17(a)(2) <sup>1</sup> of the Federal Transit Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d65-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/e/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> For purposes of the obligation of the Secretary to reimburse the Corporation (or a profitable railroad) or States, local public bodies, and agencies thereof under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of this paragraph, the level of rail passenger service shall be determined on the basis of train miles, car miles, or some other appropriate indicia of scheduled train movements. Programs to correct deferred maintenance on rolling stock, right-of-way, and other facilities which are designed to maintain service, meet on-time performance, and maintain a reasonable degree of passenger comfort (and costs incurred incident thereto) shall be included within the meaning of the term “loss” as used in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph and within the meaning of the term “additional costs” as used in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph and section 17(a)(2) <sup>1</sup> of the Federal Transit Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1613/a/2">49 U.S.C. 1613(a)(2)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d66-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/e/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> If a dispute arises with respect to the application of any such regulations, the parties to such dispute may submit such dispute to arbitration by a third party. If the parties are unable to agree upon the selection of an arbitrator, the Chairman of the Commission shall serve in that capacity (except as to matters required to be decided by the Commission, pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s562/a">section 562(a) of this title</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d67-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/e/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, the Corporation is not obligated to provide rail passenger service on rail properties if a State (or a local or regional transportation authority) contracts for such service to be provided on such properties by an operator other than the Corporation, except that the Corporation shall, where appropriate, provide such operator with access to such properties for such purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d68-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/e/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d69-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/e/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> If a State (or a local or regional transportation authority) in the region offers to provide payment for the provision of additional rail passenger service, the Corporation shall undertake to provide such service pursuant to this subsection (including the discontinuance provisions of paragraph (2) of this subsection). An offer to provide payment for the provision of additional rail passenger service shall be made in accordance with subsection (c)(2)(A) of this section, and shall be designed to avoid any additional costs to the Corporation arising from the construction or modification of capital facilities or from any additional operating delays or costs arising from the absence of such construction or modification. The State (or local or regional transportation authority) shall demonstrate that it has acquired, leased, or otherwise obtained access to all rail properties, other than those designated for conveyance to the National Railroad Passenger Corporation pursuant to sections 716(c)(1)(C) and 716(c)(1)(D) of this title and to the Corporation pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s743/b/1">section 743(b)(1) of this title</ref>, necessary to provide the additional rail passenger service and that it has completed, or will complete prior to the inception of the additional rail service, all capital improvements necessary to avoid significant costs which cannot be avoided by improved scheduling or other means on other existing rail services (including rail freight service) and to assure that the additional service will not detract from the level and quality of existing rail passenger and freight service.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d6a-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/e/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> As used in this paragraph, the term “additional rail passenger service” means rail passenger service (other than rail passenger service provided pursuant to the provisions of paragraphs (2) and (4) of this subsection), including extended or expanded service and modified routings, which is to be provided over rail properties conveyed to the Corporation pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s743/b/1">section 743(b)(1) of this title</ref>, or over (i) rail properties contiguous thereto conveyed to the National Railroad Passenger Corporation pursuant to this chapter, or (ii) any other rail properties contiguous thereto to which a State (or local or regional transportation authority) has obtained access.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d6b-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/e/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of this paragraph, the Corporation shall not be required to operate additional rail passenger service over rail properties leased or acquired from or owned or leased by a profitable railroad in the region.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27e54d6c-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/e/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> The Secretary shall, in consultation with the Association, conduct a study to determine the best means of compensating the Corporation for liabilities which it may incur for damages to persons or property, resulting from the operation of rail passenger service required to be operated pursuant to this subsection or <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s743/b/2">section 743(b)(2) of this title</ref>, which are not underwritten by private insurance carriers or are not indemnified by a State (or local or regional transportation authority). Such study shall identify the nature of the risks to the Corporation, the probable degree of uninsurability of such risks, and the desirability and feasibility of various indemnification programs, including subsidy offers made pursuant to this section, self-insurance through a passenger tax or other mechanism, or government indemnification for such liabilities. Within one year after <date date="1978-11-08">November 8, 1978</date>, the Secretary shall prepare a report with appropriate recommendations and shall submit such report to the Congress. Such report shall specify the most appropriate means of indemnifying the Corporation for such liabilities in a manner which shall prevent the cross-subsidization of passenger services with revenues from freight services operated by the Corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27e54d6d-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Purchase</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If an offer to purchase is made under subsection (c)(2)(C) of this section, such offer shall be accompanied by an offer of a rail service continuation payment. Such payment shall continue until the purchase transaction is completed, unless a railroad assumes operations over such rail properties of its own account pursuant to an order or authorization of the Commission. Whenever a railroad in reorganization in the region or a profitable railroad gives notice of intent to discontinue service pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, such railroad shall, upon the request of anyone apparently qualified to make an offer to purchase or to provide a rail service continuation payment, promptly make available its most recent reports on the physical condition of such property, together with such traffic and revenue data as would be required under subpart B of part 1121 of chapter X of title 49 of the Code of Federal Regulations and such other data as are necessary to ascertain the avoidable costs of providing service over such rail properties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27e54d6e-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Abandonment by Corporation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After the rail system to be operated by the Corporation or a subsidiary thereof under the final system plan has been in operation for 2 years, the Commission may authorize the Corporation or a subsidiary thereof to abandon any rail properties as to which it determines that rail service over such properties is not required by the public convenience and necessity, if the Corporation or a subsidiary thereof can demonstrate that no State (or local or regional transportation authority) is willing to offer a rail service continuation payment pursuant to subsection (c) of this section. The Commission may, at any time after the effective date of the final system plan, authorize additional rail service in the region or authorize the abandonment of rail properties which are not being operated by the Corporation or any subsidiary or affiliate thereof or by any other person. Determinations by the Commission under this subsection shall be made pursuant to applicable provisions of part A of subtitle IV of title 49.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27e54d6f-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Interim abandonment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After <date date="1976-02-05">February 5, 1976</date>, and prior to the date of conveyance (pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s743/b/1">section 743(b)(1) of this title</ref>), no railroad in reorganization in the region may discontinue service or abandon any line of railroad other than in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, unless (1) it is authorized to do so by the Association, and (2) no affected State (or local or regional transportation authority) reasonably opposes such action, notwithstanding any provision of any other Federal law, the constitution or law of any State, or the decision or order of, or the pendency of any proceeding before any Federal or State court, agency, or authority.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27e54d70-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Disposition of designated rail properties</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No railroad in reorganization in the region and no person leased, operated or controlled by such a railroad shall sell, transfer, encumber, or otherwise dispose of rail property, or any right or interest therein, designated for transfer to the Corporation or conveyance to a profitable railroad in the final system plan, except pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s743/b">section 743(b) of this title</ref>. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to any such sale, transfer, encumbrance, or other disposition—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27e54d71-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> as to which the Association generally or specifically consents in writing;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27e54d72-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> which, prior to <date date="1976-02-05">February 5, 1976</date>, had been specifically approved by a United States district court having jurisdiction over the reorganization of a railroad in reorganization under section 77 of the Bankruptcy Act; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id27e54d73-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s744/i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> following certification to the special court, pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s719/c">section 719(c) of this title</ref>, of any such rail properties not previously so certified.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id27e54d74-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/236/tIII/s304">Pub. L. 93–236, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1974-01-02">Jan. 2, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/1008">87 Stat. 1008</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/210/tVI/s607/i">Pub. L. 94–210, title VI, § 607(i)</ref>, title VIII, § 804, <date date="1976-02-05">Feb. 5, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/97">90 Stat. 97</ref>, 133; <ref href="/us/pl/94/555/tII">Pub. L. 94–555, title II</ref>, §§ 205, 206, <date date="1976-10-19">Oct. 19, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2620">90 Stat. 2620</ref>, 2621; <ref href="/us/pl/95/473/s4/b">Pub. L. 95–473, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-17">Oct. 17, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1466">92 Stat. 1466</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/607/tII/s201">Pub. L. 95–607, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1978-11-08">Nov. 8, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3064">92 Stat. 3064</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/449/s4/b/2">Pub. L. 97–449, § 4(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-12">Jan. 12, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2441">96 Stat. 2441</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/240/tIII/s3003/b">Pub. L. 102–240, title III, § 3003(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-18">Dec. 18, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/2088">105 Stat. 2088</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/tIII/s327/3">Pub. L. 104–88, title III, § 327(3)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/951">109 Stat. 951</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/287/s6/f/4/A">Pub. L. 104–287, § 6(f)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3399">110 Stat. 3399</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id27e54d75-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id27e54d76-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id27e54d77-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t49/s10362/b/6">Section 10362(b)(6) of title 49</ref>, referred to in subsecs. (a)(2)(B) and (d)(2), was omitted in the general amendment of subtitle IV of Title 49, Transportation, by <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/tI/s102/a">Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/804">109 Stat. 804</ref>. Previously, in subsec. (d)(2), “<ref href="/us/usc/t49/s10362/b/6">section 10362(b)(6) of title 49</ref>” was substituted for “section 205(d)(6) of this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/93/236/s205/d/6">section 205(d)(6) of Pub. L. 93–236</ref>, on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/95/473/s3/b">Pub. L. 95–473, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-17">Oct. 17, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1466">92 Stat. 1466</ref>, the first section of which enacted subtitle IV of Title 49.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t45/s762">Section 762 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (d)(4)(B), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/94/210/tVIII/s806">Pub. L. 94–210, title VIII, § 806</ref>, <date date="1976-02-05">Feb. 5, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/143">90 Stat. 143</ref>, eff. <date date="1978-04-01">Apr. 1, 1978</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 17 of the Federal Transit Act, referred to in subsecs. (d)(4)(B) and (e)(4)(C), (5)(A) to (C), which was classified to section 1613 of former Title 49, Transportation, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/103/272/s7/b">Pub. L. 103–272, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-07-05">July 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1379">108 Stat. 1379</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 77 of the Bankruptcy Act, referred to in subsec. (i)(2), was classified to section 205 of former Title 11, Bankruptcy. The Bankruptcy Act (<ref href="/us/act/1898-07-01/ch541">act July 1, 1898, ch. 541</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/30/544">30 Stat. 544</ref>) was repealed effective <date date="1979-10-01">Oct. 1, 1979</date>, by <ref href="/us/pl/95/598">Pub. L. 95–598</ref>, §§ 401(a), 402(a), <date date="1978-11-06">Nov. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2682">92 Stat. 2682</ref>, section 101 of which enacted revised Title 11. For current provisions relating to railroad reorganization, see subchapter IV (§ 1161 et seq.) of chapter 11 of Title 11.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id27e54d78-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/287">Pub. L. 104–287</ref> made technical amendment to directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s327/3/B">Pub. L. 104–88, § 327(3)(B)</ref>. See 1995 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s327/3/A">Pub. L. 104–88, § 327(3)(A)</ref>, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t49/s10362/b/6">section 10362(b)(6) of title 49</ref>” for “section 205(d)(6) of this Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s327/3/B">Pub. L. 104–88, § 327(3)(B)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/287">Pub. L. 104–287</ref>, substituted “part A of subtitle IV of title 49” for “the Interstate Commerce Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s327/3/C">Pub. L. 104–88, § 327(3)(C)</ref>, substituted “this title, the Commission” for “this title, the Commission—”, struck out “(A)” before “shall take such action”, and substituted “under this subsection.” for “under this subsection; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) shall have authority, in accordance with the provisions of section 1(16)(b) of the Interstate Commerce Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1/16/b">49 U.S.C. 1(16)(b)</ref>), to direct rail service to be provided by any designated railroad or by the trustees of a railroad in reorganization in the region, if a rail service continuation payment has been offered but an applicable operating or lease agreement is not in effect.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of the preceding sentence, any compensation required as a result of such directed service shall be determined in accordance with the standards developed pursuant to section 205(d)(6) of this Act.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s327/3/D/i">Pub. L. 104–88, § 327(3)(D)(i)</ref>, struck out “and under regulations issued by the Office pursuant to section 205(d)(5) of this Act” before “, for the operation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(4)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s327/3/D/ii">Pub. L. 104–88, § 327(3)(D)(ii)</ref>, struck out “and regulations issued by the Office pursuant to section 205(d)(5) of this Act” after “subsection (c)(2)(A) of this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(5)(A), (B). <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s327/3/E">Pub. L. 104–88, § 327(3)(E)</ref>, struck out before period at end “and under regulations issued by the Office pursuant to section 205(d)(5) of this Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(7)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s327/3/F">Pub. L. 104–88, § 327(3)(F)</ref>, struck out “and under regulations issued by the Office pursuant to section 205(d)(5) of this Act” after “subsection (c)(2)(A) of this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s327/3/G">Pub. L. 104–88, § 327(3)(G)</ref>, substituted “part A of subtitle IV of title 49” for “the Interstate Commerce Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsecs. (d)(4)(B), (e)(4)(C), (5)(A) to (C). <ref href="/us/pl/102/240">Pub. L. 102–240</ref> substituted “Federal Transit Act” for “Urban Mass Transportation Act of 1964”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/97/449">Pub. L. 97–449</ref> repealed <ref href="/us/pl/93/236/s304/j">section 304(j) of Pub. L. 93–236</ref>, effective <date date="1978-10-17">Oct. 17, 1978</date>, the date <ref href="/us/pl/95/473">Pub. L. 95–473</ref> repealed subsec. (j) by repealing section 804 “Sec. 304(j)” of <ref href="/us/pl/94/210">Pub. L. 94–210</ref>. See 1978 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/95/607">Pub. L. 95–607</ref> added subpar. (C) of par. (4) and pars. (7) and (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/95/473">Pub. L. 95–473</ref> struck out subsec. (j) which provided for exempt rail mass transportation not under the jurisdiction of the Interstate Commerce Commission.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/210/s804">Pub. L. 94–210, § 804</ref>, redesignated existing provisions as par. (1) and inserted provision relating to applicability to a railroad in reorganization in the region, or of a person leased, operated, or controlled by such a railroad, in subpar. (B) inserted provision relating to notice on the date of any conveyance ordered by the special court, and in subpar. (C) inserted requirement that notice be sent to the Commission and substituted reference to the chief executive officer for reference to the Governor, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/94/210/s804">Pub. L. 94–210, § 804</ref>, in par. (1) inserted exception of subsecs. (c) and (f) of this section and substituted provisions requiring notice to be sent to any person (including a government entity), for provisions requiring notice to be sent to all those required to receive notice, in par. (2) substituted “240” for “180”, and added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/94/210/s804">Pub. L. 94–210, § 804</ref>, substituted provisions relating to continuation of rail services and applicability of rail service continuation payments to such continuation, for provisions relating to limitations of Interstate Commerce Act, State constitution or law, or decision of Federal or State court or agency on power to discontinue rail service and abandon rail properties and applicability of rail service continuation subsidies on such power.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/94/210/s804">Pub. L. 94–210, § 804</ref>, added subsec. (d). Former subsec. (d) redesignated (f) and amended.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/94/555/s205/a">Pub. L. 94–555, § 205(a)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/94/210">Pub. L. 94–210</ref>, §§ 607(i), 804, added subsec. (e). Former subsec. (e) redesignated (g) and amended.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(5)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/94/555/s205/b">Pub. L. 94–555, § 205(b)</ref>, redesignated former subpar. (C) as (D) and added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/94/210/s804">Pub. L. 94–210, § 804</ref>, redesignated former subsec. (d) as (f) and substituted provisions relating to rail service continuation payments, for provisions relating to rail service continuation subsidies. Former subsec. (f) redesignated (h) and amended.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/94/210/s804">Pub. L. 94–210, § 804</ref>, redesignated former subsec. (e) as (g) and inserted reference to any subsidiary of a Corporation and provision relating to demonstration by the Corporation, etc., that no State (or local or regional transportation authority) will offer a continuation payment under subsec. (c) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/94/210/s804">Pub. L. 94–210, § 804</ref>, redesignated former subsec. (f) as (h), substituted “<date date="1976-02-05">February 5, 1976</date>, and prior to the date of conveyance (pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s743/b/1">section 743(b)(1) of this title</ref>)” for “<date date="1974-01-02">January 2, 1974</date>” and “reorganization in the region may” for “reorganization may”, and made minor changes in structure.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (i), (j). <ref href="/us/pl/94/210/s804">Pub. L. 94–210, § 804</ref>, added subsecs. (i) and (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/94/555/s206/1">Pub. L. 94–555, § 206(1)</ref>, inserted limitation “by rail” to mass transportation services, and provided that any local body providing mass transportation services by rail is exempted from the rules, regulations, and orders promulgated under the Interstate Commerce Act, if interstate fares or application to the Interstate Commerce Commission for a change in such fares is subject to the approval or disapproval of the Governor of any state in which it provides services.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/94/555/s206/2">Pub. L. 94–555, § 206(2)</ref>, substituted definition of “mass transportation services” for “mass transportation”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id27e54d79-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id27e54d7a-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/287/s6/f/4/A">Pub. L. 104–287, § 6(f)(4)(A)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3399">110 Stat. 3399</ref>, provided that the amendment made by section 6(f)(4)(A) is effective <date date="1995-12-29">Dec. 29, 1995</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id27e54d7b-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1995 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/88">Pub. L. 104–88</ref> effective <date date="1996-01-01">Jan. 1, 1996</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1301">section 1301 of Title 49</ref>, Transportation.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id27e54d7c-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/94/555">Pub. L. 94–555</ref> effective <date date="1976-10-01">Oct. 1, 1976</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/555/s303">section 303 of Pub. L. 94–555</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s702">section 702 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id27e54d7d-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Special Court, Regional Rail Reorganization Act of 1973, and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Special court abolished and all jurisdiction and functions transferred to United States District Court for District of Columbia, see <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s719/b/2">section 719(b)(2) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id27e54d7e-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of Interstate Commerce Commission and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Interstate Commerce Commission abolished and functions of Commission transferred, except as otherwise provided in <ref href="/us/pl/104/88">Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, to Surface Transportation Board effective <date date="1996-01-01">Jan. 1, 1996</date>, by <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1302">section 1302 of Title 49</ref>, Transportation, and <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s101">section 101 of Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1301">section 1301 of Title 49</ref>. References to Interstate Commerce Commission deemed to refer to Surface Transportation Board, a member or employee of the Board, or Secretary of Transportation, as appropriate, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/88/s205">section 205 of Pub. L. 104–88</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s1301">section 1301 of Title 49</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id27e54d7f-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of United States Railway Association and Transfer of Functions and Securities</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">See <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s1341">section 1341 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id27e54d80-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Applicability of National Environmental Policy Act</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Application of National Environmental Policy Act to actions of Commission not affected by title VI of <ref href="/us/pl/94/210">Pub. L. 94–210</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/210/s619">section 619 of Pub. L. 94–210</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s791">section 791 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
