<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id27eec398-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s908"><num value="908">§ 908.</num><heading> Employee protection agreements</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27eec399-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s908/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Agreement between Milwaukee Railroad and labor organizations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Milwaukee Railroad and labor organizations representing the employees of such railroad may, not later than 20 days after <date date="1979-11-04">November 4, 1979</date>, enter into an agreement providing protection for employees of such railroad who are adversely affected as a result of a reduction in service by such railroad or a restructuring transaction carried out by such railroad. Such employee protection may include, but need not be limited to, interim employee assistance, moving expenses, employee relocation incentive compensation, and separation allowances.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27eec39a-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s908/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission of matter to National Mediation Board</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Milwaukee Railroad and the labor organizations representing the employees of such railroad are unable to enter into an employee protection agreement under subsection (a) of this section within 20 days after <date date="1979-11-04">November 4, 1979</date>, the parties shall immediately submit the matter to the National Mediation Board. The National Mediation Board shall attempt, by mediation, to bring the parties to an agreement with respect to employee protection no later than 40 days after <date date="1979-11-04">November 4, 1979</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27eec39b-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s908/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Fair and equitable agreements</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27eec39c-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s908/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If the National Mediation Board is unable to bring the parties to an agreement under subsection (b) of this section within 40 days after <date date="1979-11-04">November 4, 1979</date>, the Milwaukee Railroad and the labor organizations representing the employees of such railroad shall immediately enter into an employee protection agreement that is fair and equitable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id27eec39d-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s908/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If an employee protection agreement is entered into under this subsection, any claim of an employee for benefits and allowances under such agreement shall be filed with the Board in such time and manner as the Board by regulation shall prescribe. The Board shall determine the amount for which such employee is eligible under such agreement and shall certify such amount to the Milwaukee Railroad for payment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id27eec39e-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419" identifier="/us/usc/t45/s908/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment of benefits and allowances</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Benefits and allowances under an employee protection agreement entered into under this section shall be paid by the Milwaukee Railroad in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t45/s914">section 914 of this title</ref>, and claims of employees for such benefits and allowances shall be treated as administrative expenses of the estate of the Milwaukee Railroad.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id27eec39f-2a4a-11ef-83f3-c9aca8a7e419">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/101/s9">Pub. L. 96–101, § 9</ref>, <date date="1979-11-04">Nov. 4, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/741">93 Stat. 741</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
