<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idec0bcb94-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53" identifier="/us/usc/t51/s60604"><num value="60604">§ 60604.</num><heading> Research activities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idec0bcb95-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53" identifier="/us/usc/t51/s60604/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Basic Research</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Director of the National Science Foundation, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, and the Secretary of Defense, shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idec0bcb96-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53" identifier="/us/usc/t51/s60604/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> continue to carry out basic research on heliophysics, geospace science, and space weather; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idec0bcb97-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53" identifier="/us/usc/t51/s60604/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> support competitive, peer-reviewed proposals for conducting research, advancing modeling, and monitoring of space weather and its impacts, including the science goals outlined in decadal surveys in solar and space physics conducted by the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idec0bcb98-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53" identifier="/us/usc/t51/s60604/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Multidisciplinary Research.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idec0bcb99-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53" identifier="/us/usc/t51/s60604/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading><content>Congress finds that the multidisciplinary nature of solar and space physics creates funding challenges that require coordination across scientific disciplines and Federal agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idec0bcb9a-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53" identifier="/us/usc/t51/s60604/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sense of congress</inline>.—</heading><content>It is the sense of Congress that science centers could coordinate multidisciplinary solar and space physics research. The Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and Director of the National Science Foundation should support competitively awarded grants for multidisciplinary science centers that advance solar and space physics research, including research-to-operations and operations-to-research processes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idec0bcb9b-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53" identifier="/us/usc/t51/s60604/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Multidisciplinary research</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of the National Science Foundation, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, shall each pursue multidisciplinary research in subjects that further the understanding of solar physics, space physics, and space weather.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idec0bcb9c-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53" identifier="/us/usc/t51/s60604/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Science Missions</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration should implement missions that meet the science objectives identified in solar and space physics decadal surveys conducted by the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idec0bcb9d-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53" identifier="/us/usc/t51/s60604/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Research to Operations; Operations to Research</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The interagency working group shall, upon consideration of the advice of the advisory group, develop formal mechanisms to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idec0bcb9e-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53" identifier="/us/usc/t51/s60604/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> transition the space weather research findings, models, and capabilities of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the National Science Foundation, the United States Geological Survey, and other relevant Federal agencies, as appropriate, to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and the Department of Defense;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idec0bcb9f-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53" identifier="/us/usc/t51/s60604/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> enhance coordination between research modeling centers and forecasting centers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idec0bcba0-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53" identifier="/us/usc/t51/s60604/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> communicate the operational needs of space weather forecasters of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and Department of Defense, as appropriate, to the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the National Science Foundation, and the United States Geological Survey.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idec0bcba1-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53">(<ref href="/us/pl/116/181/s2/b">Pub. L. 116–181, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2020-10-21">Oct. 21, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/889">134 Stat. 889</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
