<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idec0e15aa-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53" identifier="/us/usc/t51/s70901"><num value="70901">§ 70901.</num><heading> Peaceful uses of space station</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No civil space station authorized under section 103(a)(1) of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 1991 (<ref href="/us/pl/101/611">Public Law 101–611</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3190">104 Stat. 3190</ref>) may be used to carry or place in orbit any nuclear weapon or any other weapon of mass destruction, to install any such weapon on any celestial body, or to station any such weapon in space in any other manner. This civil space station may be used only for peaceful purposes.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idec0e15ab-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53">(<ref href="/us/pl/111/314/s3">Pub. L. 111–314, § 3</ref>, <date date="2010-12-18">Dec. 18, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3436">124 Stat. 3436</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idec0e15ac-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53">
<note topic="historicalAndRevision" id="idec0e15ad-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53">
<html:table class="HNR" width="50%" style="border-collapse:collapse;  border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc: c3,L2,tp7,s10,xls64,xs90,tp7,s10,xls64,xs90; " id="idec0e15ae-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53">
<html:colgroup>
<html:col style="min-width: 44pt;" />
<html:col style="width:68pt ; max-width:68pt;" />
<html:col style="width:94pt ; max-width:94pt;" />
</html:colgroup>
<html:thead>
<html:tr class="title" style="font-size:7pt; border-bottom:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I95;">
<html:th colspan="3">
<html:p style=""><html:span style="font-variant:small-caps">Historical and Revision Notes</html:span></html:p></html:th>
</html:tr>
<html:tr class="header" style="font-size:6pt; border-bottom:1px solid black;  border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:h1;">
<html:th style="min-width: 44.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-bottom:0em;"><html:i>Revised</html:i></html:p><html:p style=" text-align:center; margin-top:0em;"><html:i>Section</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:68.0pt ; max-width:68.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (U.S. Code)</html:i></html:p></html:th><html:th style="width:94.0pt ; max-width:94.0pt; text-align:center; vertical-align:middle; border-left:1px solid black;"><html:p style=" text-align:center;"><html:i>Source (Statutes at Large)</html:i></html:p></html:th></html:tr>
</html:thead>
<html:tbody style="line-height:7pt; font-size:6pt;">
<html:tr style="border-top:1px solid black; -uslm-lc:I01;"><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;" class="leaders"><html:span>70901</html:span></html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-right:1px solid black; border-left:1px solid black; padding-right:2pt; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;">(not previously classified)</html:p></html:td><html:td style=" text-align:left; vertical-align:top; border-left:1px solid black; padding-left: 2pt;"><html:p style=" text-align:left; text-indent: -1em; padding-left:1em;"><html:a href="/us/pl/101/611/tI/s123">Pub. L. 101–611, title I, § 123</html:a>, <html:span class="date">Nov. 16, 1990</html:span>, <html:a href="/us/stat/104/3204">104 Stat. 3204</html:a>.</html:p></html:td></html:tr>
</html:tbody>
</html:table>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The words “the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 1991 (<ref href="/us/pl/101/611">Public Law 101–611</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3190">104 Stat. 3190</ref>)” are substituted for “this Act” to clarify the reference.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idec0e15af-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idec0e15b0-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 103(a)(1) of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 1991 (<ref href="/us/pl/101/611">Public Law 101–611</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3190">104 Stat. 3190</ref>), referred to in text, is not classified to the Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idec0e15b1-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idec0e15b2-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Priorities for International Space Station</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/167/dB/tVII/s10816">Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title VII, § 10816</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/1739">136 Stat. 1739</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/167/dB/tVII/s10816">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator [of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration] shall assess International Space Station research activities and shall ensure that crew time and resources allocated to the [National Aeronautics and Space] Administration for use on the International Space Station prioritize—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the research of the Human Research Program, including research on and development of countermeasures relevant to reducing human health and performance risks, behavioral and psychological risks, and other astronaut safety risks related to long-duration human spaceflight;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> risk reduction activities relevant to exploration technologies, including for the Environmental Control and Life Support System, extravehicular activity and space suits, environmental monitoring, safety, emergency response, and deep space communications;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the advancement of United States leadership in basic and applied space life and physical science research, consistent with the priorities of the most recent space life and physical sciences decadal survey of the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> other research and development activities identified by the Administrator as essential to Moon to Mars activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assessment and prioritization</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>], the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress [Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives] a report on—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the assessment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the steps taken to achieve the prioritization required by subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Space flight participants</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on measures taken, with respect to space flight participants aboard the ISS [International Space Station], to ensure government astronaut safety, to avoid interference in ISS operations and research priorities, and to prevent undue demands on crew time and resources.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual progress reports</inline>.—</heading><content>Concurrent with the annual budget submission of the President to Congress under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105/a">section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, United States Code, the Administrator shall provide to the appropriate committees of Congress an annual accounting of the use of Administration crew time and ISS resources, including the allocation of such resources toward the priorities described in subsection (a).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “deep space”, “space flight participant”, and “government astronaut” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/167/s10816">section 10816 of Pub. L. 117–167</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/167/s10802">section 10802 of Pub. L. 117–167</ref>, set out as a Definitions note under <ref href="/us/usc/t51/s10101">section 10101 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idec0e15b3-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53"><heading class="centered smallCaps">International Space Station</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/69/tII/s2006">Pub. L. 110–69, title II, § 2006</ref>, <date date="2007-08-09">Aug. 9, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/584">121 Stat. 584</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/69/tII/s2006">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sense of Congress</inline>.—</heading><content>It is the sense of Congress that the International Space Station National Laboratory offers unique opportunities for educational activities and provides a unique resource for research and development in science, technology, and engineering, which can enhance the global competitiveness of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Development of Educational Projects</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration shall develop a detailed plan for implementation of 1 or more education projects that utilize the resources offered by the International Space Station. In developing any detailed plan according to this paragraph, the Administrator shall make use of the findings and recommendations of the International Space Station National Laboratory Education Concept Development Task Force.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Development of Research Plans for Competitiveness Enhancement</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall develop a detailed plan for identification and support of research to be conducted aboard the International Space Station, which offers the potential for enhancement of United States competitiveness in science, technology, and engineering. In developing any detailed plan pursuant to this subsection, the Administrator shall consult with agencies and entities with which cooperative agreements have been reached regarding utilization of International Space Station National Laboratory facilities.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/106/391/tII">Pub. L. 106–391, title II</ref>, §§ 201–203, 205, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1586-1590">114 Stat. 1586–1590</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/108/271/s8/b">Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/814">118 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/155/tII/s207/b">Pub. L. 109–155, title II, § 207(b)</ref>, title VII, § 706(a), <date date="2005-12-30">Dec. 30, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2916">119 Stat. 2916</ref>, 2937, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/155/tII/s207/b">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="201">“SEC. 201.</num><heading> INTERNATIONAL SPACE STATION CONTINGENCY PLAN.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Bimonthly Reporting on Russian Status</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than the first day of the first month beginning more than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>], and semiannually thereafter until <date date="2011-12-31">December 31, 2011</date>, the Administrator [of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration] shall report to Congress whether or not the Russians have performed work expected of them and necessary to complete the International Space Station. Each such report shall also include a statement of the Administrator’s judgment concerning Russia’s ability to perform work anticipated and required to complete the International Space Station before the next report under this subsection. Each such report shall also identify each Russian entity or person to whom NASA has, since the date of the enactment of the Iran Nonproliferation Amendments Act of 2005 [<date date="2005-11-22">Nov. 22, 2005</date>], made a payment in cash or in-kind for work to be performed or services to be rendered under the Agreement Concerning Cooperation on the Civil International Space Station, with annex, signed at Washington <date date="1998-01-29">January 29, 1998</date>, and entered into force <date date="2001-03-27">March 27, 2001</date>, or any protocol, agreement, memorandum of understanding, or contract related thereto. Each report shall include the specific purpose of each payment made to each entity or person identified in the report.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Decision on Russian Critical Path Items</inline>.—</heading><content>The President shall notify Congress within 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>] of the decision on whether or not to proceed with permanent replacement of any Russian elements in the critical path [as defined in <ref href="/us/pl/106/391/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 106–391</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t51/s10101">51 U.S.C. 10101</ref> note] of the International Space Station or any Russian launch services. Such notification shall include the reasons and justifications for the decision and the costs associated with the decision. Such decision shall include a judgment of when all elements identified in Revision E assembly sequence as of June 1999 will be in orbit and operational. If the President decides to proceed with a permanent replacement for any Russian element in the critical path or any Russian launch services, the President shall notify Congress of the reasons and the justification for the decision to proceed with the permanent replacement and the costs associated with the decision.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assurances</inline>.—</heading><content>The United States shall seek assurances from the Russian Government that it places a higher priority on fulfilling its commitments to the International Space Station than it places on extending the life of the Mir Space Station, including assurances that Russia will not utilize assets allocated by Russia to the International Space Station for other purposes, including extending the life of Mir.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Equitable Utilization</inline>.—</heading><content>In the event that any International Partner in the International Space Station Program willfully violates any of its commitments or agreements for the provision of agreed-upon Space Station-related hardware or related goods or services, the Administrator should, in a manner consistent with relevant international agreements, seek a commensurate reduction in the utilization rights of that Partner until such time as the violated commitments or agreements have been fulfilled.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Operation Costs</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator shall, in a manner consistent with relevant international agreements, seek to reduce the National Aeronautics and Space Administration’s share of International Space Station common operating costs, based upon any additional capabilities provided to the International Space Station through the National Aeronautics and Space Administration’s Russian Program Assurance activities.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467" status="repealed"><num value="202">“[SEC. 202.</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/109/155/tII/s207/b">Pub. L. 109–155, title II, § 207(b)</ref>, <date date="2005-12-30">Dec. 30, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2916">119 Stat. 2916</ref>, effective 30 days after <date date="2006-12-01">Dec. 1, 2006</date>.]</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="203">“SEC. 203.</num><heading> RESEARCH ON INTERNATIONAL SPACE STATION.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Administrator [of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration] shall enter into a contract with the National Research Council and the National Academy of Public Administration to jointly conduct a study of the status of life and microgravity research as it relates to the International Space Station. The study shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> an assessment of the United States scientific community’s readiness to use the International Space Station for life and microgravity research;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> an assessment of the current and projected factors limiting the United States scientific community’s ability to maximize the research potential of the International Space Station, including, but not limited to, the past and present availability of resources in the life and microgravity research accounts within the Office of Human Spaceflight and the Office of Life and Microgravity Sciences and Applications and the past, present, and projected access to space of the scientific community; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> recommendations for improving the United States scientific community’s ability to maximize the research potential of the International Space Station, including an assessment of the relative costs and benefits of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> dedicating an annual mission of the Space Shuttle to life and microgravity research during assembly of the International Space Station; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> maintaining the schedule for assembly in place at the time of the enactment [<date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>].</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>], the Administrator shall transmit to the Committee on Science [now Committee on Science, Space, and Technology] of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on the results of the study conducted under this section.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="205">“SEC. 205.</num><heading> SPACE STATION RESEARCH UTILIZATION AND COMMERCIALIZATION MANAGEMENT.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Research Utilization and Commercialization Management Activities</inline>.—</heading><content>The Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration shall enter into an agreement with a non-government organization to conduct research utilization and commercialization management activities of the International Space Station subsequent to substantial completion as defined in section 202(b)(3). The agreement may not take effect less than 120 days after the implementation plan for the agreement is submitted to the Congress under subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation Plan</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than <date date="2001-09-30">September 30, 2001</date>, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science [now Committee on Science, Space, and Technology] of the House of Representatives an implementation plan to incorporate the use of a non-government organization for the International Space Station. The implementation plan shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> a description of the respective roles and responsibilities of the Administration and the non-government organization;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> a proposed structure for the non-government organization;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> a statement of the resources required;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> a schedule for the transition of responsibilities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> a statement of the duration of the agreement.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[<ref href="/us/pl/109/155/tVII/s706/a/2">Pub. L. 109–155, title VII, § 706(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2005-12-30">Dec. 30, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2937">119 Stat. 2937</ref>, which directed insertion of two sentences at end of <ref href="/us/pl/106/391/s201">section 201 of Pub. L. 106–391</ref>, set out above, was executed by making the insertion at the end of <ref href="/us/pl/106/391/s201/a">section 201(a) of Pub. L. 106–391</ref>, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idec0e15b4-3a70-11f1-9081-fe88c1712d53"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Permanently Manned Space Station</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/147/tI">Pub. L. 100–147, title I</ref>, §§ 106–112, <date date="1987-10-30">Oct. 30, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/863-865">101 Stat. 863–865</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/102/195/s16">Pub. L. 102–195, § 16</ref>, <date date="1991-12-09">Dec. 9, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1614">105 Stat. 1614</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/362/tXI/s1101/c">Pub. L. 105–362, title XI, § 1101(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3292">112 Stat. 3292</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/362/tXI/s1101/c">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="106">“Sec. 106.</num><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a"> (a)</num><chapeau> The Administrator [of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration] is directed to undertake the construction of a permanently manned space station (hereinafter referred to as the ‘space station’) to become operational in 1995. The space station will be used for the following purposes—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the conduct of scientific experiments, applications experiments, and engineering experiments;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the servicing, rehabilitation, and construction of satellites and space vehicles;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the development and demonstration of commercial products and processes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the establishment of a space base for other civilian and commercial space activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The space station shall be developed and operated in a manner that supports other science and space activities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> In order to reduce the cost of operations of the space station and its ground support system, the Administrator shall undertake the development of such advanced technologies as may be appropriate within the level of funding authorized in this Act [see Tables for classification].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><content> The Administrator shall seek to have portions of the space station constructed and operated by the private sector, where appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><content> The Administrator shall promote international cooperation in the space station program by undertaking the development, construction, and operation of the space station in conjunction with (but not limited to) the Governments of Europe, Japan, and Canada.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><content> The space station shall be designed, developed, and operated in a manner that enables evolutionary enhancement.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21" status="repealed"><num value="107">“[Sec. 107.</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/105/362/tXI/s1101/c">Pub. L. 105–362, title XI, § 1101(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3292">112 Stat. 3292</ref>.]</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="108">“Sec. 108.</num><content> In order to ensure that the development of the space station is part of a balanced civilian space program, the Administrator is instructed to establish as a goal a funding profile that limits (1) space station total annual costs under the capital development plan in section 107 to 25 percent of the total budget request for the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and (2) all space station direct operations costs, except for those costs associated with the utilization of the space station, to 10 percent of the total budget request for the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="109">“Sec. 109.</num><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a"> (a)</num><content> It is the sense of the Congress that the launching and servicing of the space station should be accomplished by the most cost-effective use of space transportation systems, including the space shuttle and expendable launch vehicles.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><chapeau> Not later than <date date="1988-01-15">January 15, 1988</date>, the Administrator shall submit a preliminary report on the cost-effective use of space transportation systems for the launch of space station elements during the development and operation of the space station. The Administrator shall consider—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the potential use of future advanced or heavy lift expendable launch vehicles for purposes of the assembly and operation of the space station;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the use of existing expendable launch vehicles of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Department of Defense, and the Private Sector;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the requirement for space shuttle launches; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the risk of capital losses from the use of expendable launch vehicles and the space shuttle.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="110">“Sec. 110.</num><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a"> (a)</num><content> The Administrator shall set and collect reasonable user fees for the use and maintenance of the space station.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><chapeau> The Administrator shall set user fees so as to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> promote the use of the space station consistent with the policy set forth in section 106;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> recover the costs of the use of the space station, including reasonable charges for any enhancement needed for such use; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> conserve and efficiently allocate the resources of the space station.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><chapeau> The Administrator may, on a case-by-case basis, waive or modify such user fees when in the Administrator’s judgment such waiver or modification will further the goals and purposes of the National Aeronautics and Space Act of 1958 [see <ref href="/us/usc/t51/s20101">51 U.S.C. 20101</ref> et seq.], including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the advancement of scientific or engineering knowledge;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> international cooperation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the commercial use of space.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="111">“Sec. 111.</num><content> No later than <date date="1988-09-30">September 30, 1988</date>, the Administrator shall submit a detailed plan for collecting reimbursements for the utilization of the space station under section 110, including the services to be offered, the methodology and bases by which prices will be charged, and the estimated revenues.</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="112">“Sec. 112.</num><content> The Intergovernmental Agreement currently being negotiated between the United States Government and Canada, Japan, and member governments of the European Space Agency, and the Memorandum of Understanding currently being negotiated between the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and its counterpart agencies in Canada, Japan, and Europe concerning the detailed design, development, construction, operation, or utilization of the space station shall be submitted to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives. No such agreement shall take effect until 30 days have passed after the receipt by such committees of the agreement.”</content>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
