<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id91587bc5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503"><num value="10503">§ 10503.</num><heading> Minimum standards for the elimination of corruption and assessment of efforts to combat corruption</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id91587bc6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The government of a country is complying with the minimum standards for the elimination of corruption if the government—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91587bc7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> has enacted and implemented laws and established government structures, policies, and practices that prohibit corruption, including significant corruption;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91587bc8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> enforces the laws described in paragraph (1) by punishing any person who is found, through a fair judicial process, to have violated such laws;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91587bc9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> prescribes punishment for significant corruption that is commensurate with the punishment prescribed for serious crimes; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91587bca-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> is making serious and sustained efforts to address corruption, including through prevention.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id91587bcb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Factors for assessing government efforts to combat corruption</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In determining whether a government is making serious and sustained efforts to address corruption, the Secretary of State shall consider, to the extent relevant or appropriate, factors such as—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91587bcc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> whether the government of the country has criminalized corruption, investigates and prosecutes acts of corruption, and convicts and sentences persons responsible for such acts over which it has jurisdiction, including, as appropriate, incarcerating individuals convicted of such acts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91587bcd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> whether the government of the country vigorously investigates, prosecutes, convicts, and sentences public officials who participate in or facilitate corruption, including nationals of the country who are deployed in foreign military assignments, trade delegations abroad, or other similar missions, who engage in or facilitate significant corruption;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91587bce-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> whether the government of the country has adopted measures to prevent corruption, such as measures to inform and educate the public, including potential victims, about the causes and consequences of corruption;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91587bcf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> what steps the government of the country has taken to prohibit government officials from participating in, facilitating, or condoning corruption, including the investigation, prosecution, and conviction of such officials;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91587bd0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the extent to which the country provides access, or, as appropriate, makes adequate resources available, to civil society organizations and other institutions to combat corruption, including reporting, investigating, and monitoring;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91587bd1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> whether an independent judiciary or judicial body in the country is responsible for, and effectively capable of, deciding corruption cases impartially, on the basis of facts and in accordance with the law, without any improper restrictions, influences, inducements, pressures, threats, or interferences (direct or indirect);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91587bd2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> whether the government of the country is assisting in international investigations of transnational corruption networks and in other cooperative efforts to combat significant corruption, including, as appropriate, cooperating with the governments of other countries to extradite corrupt actors;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91587bd3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> whether the government of the country recognizes the rights of victims of corruption, ensures their access to justice, and takes steps to prevent victims from being further victimized or persecuted by corrupt actors, government officials, or others;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91587bd4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> whether the government of the country protects victims of corruption or whistleblowers from reprisal due to such persons having assisted in exposing corruption, and refrains from other discriminatory treatment of such persons;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91587bd5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> whether the government of the country is willing and able to recover and, as appropriate, return the proceeds of corruption;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91587bd6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/b/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> whether the government of the country is taking steps to implement financial transparency measures in line with the Financial Action Task Force recommendations, including due diligence and beneficial ownership transparency requirements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91587bd7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/b/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> whether the government of the country is facilitating corruption in other countries in connection with state-directed investment, loans or grants for major infrastructure, or other initiatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91587bd8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/b/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> such other information relating to corruption as the Secretary of State considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id91587bd9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Assessing government efforts to combat corruption in relation to relevant international commitments</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In determining whether a government is making serious and sustained efforts to address corruption, the Secretary of State shall consider the government of a country’s compliance with the following, as relevant:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91587bda-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Inter-American Convention against Corruption of the Organization of American States, done at Caracas <date date="1996-03-29">March 29, 1996</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91587bdb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Convention on Combating Bribery of Foreign Public Officials in International Business Transactions of the Organisation of <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002469">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002469"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “for”.</note> Economic Co-operation and Development, done at Paris December 21,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002470">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002470"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “17,”.</note> 1997 (commonly referred to as the “Anti-Bribery Convention”).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91587bdc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The United Nations Convention against Transnational Organized Crime, done at New York <date date="2000-11-15">November 15, 2000</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91587bdd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The United Nations Convention against Corruption, done at New York <date date="2003-10-31">October 31, 2003</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91587bde-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s10503/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Such other treaties or conventions ratified by the United States as the Secretary of State considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id91587bdf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dE/tLIV/s5404">Pub. L. 118–31, div. E, title LIV, § 5404</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/945">137 Stat. 945</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
