<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8ef86c64-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1358"><num value="1358">§ 1358.</num><heading> Rights of third countries</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The benefits granted by subchapters I to IV of this chapter, and by the executive agreement provided for in subchapter III, to the Philippines, Philippine articles or products, and Philippine citizens, shall not, by reason of any provision of any existing treaty or agreement with any third country, be extended to such country or its products, citizens, or subjects.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8ef86c65-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-04-30/ch244">Apr. 30, 1946, ch. 244</ref>, title V, § 509, <ref href="/us/stat/60/158">60 Stat. 158</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8ef86c66-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8ef86c67-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Suspension of Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section not applicable during such time as the revised agreement between the United States and the Philippines is in effect, see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1373">section 1373 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8ef86c68-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8ef86c69-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subchapters I to IV of this chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1946-04-30/ch244">act Apr. 30, 1946, ch. 244</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/141">60 Stat. 141</ref>, known as the Philippine Trade Act of 1946, which is classified principally to subchapters I to IV of this chapter. Subchapters I, II, and III of this chapter were omitted from the Code. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1354">section 1354 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The executive agreement provided for in subchapter III of this chapter, referred to in text, expired <date date="1974-07-04">July 4, 1974</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
