<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8eff9795-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1453"><num value="1453">§ 1453.</num><heading> Acceptance of office under foreign governments of assigned personnel; oath of allegiance</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person in the employ or service of the Government of the United States while assigned for service to or in cooperation with another government under authority of this chapter may, at the discretion of his Government agency, with the concurrence of the Director of the United States Information Agency, and without additional compensation therefor, accept an office under the government to which he is assigned, if the acceptance of such an office in the opinion of such agency is necessary to permit the effective performance of duties for which he is assigned, including the making or approving on behalf of such foreign government the disbursement of funds provided by such government or of receiving from such foreign government funds for deposit and disbursement on behalf of such government, in carrying out programs undertaken pursuant to this chapter: <i>Provided, however</i>, That such acceptance of office shall in no case involve the taking of an oath of allegiance to another government.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8eff9796-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-01-27/ch36">Jan. 27, 1948, ch. 36</ref>, title III, § 303, <ref href="/us/stat/62/8">62 Stat. 8</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/241/tIII/s304/a/1/B">Pub. L. 97–241, title III, § 304(a)(1)(B)</ref>, (2)(B), <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/292">96 Stat. 292</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8eff9797-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8eff9798-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8eff9799-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—<ref href="/us/pl/97/241">Pub. L. 97–241</ref> substituted “person in the employ or service of the Government of the United States” for “citizen of the United States” and “Director of the United States Information Agency” for “Secretary”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8eff979a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id8eff979b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">United States Information Agency (other than Broadcasting Board of Governors and International Broadcasting Bureau) abolished and functions transferred to Secretary of State, see sections 6531 and 6532 of this title.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
