<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8f01e106-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1464a"><num value="1464a">§ 1464a.</num><heading> Broadcasting Board of Governors satellite and television</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f01e107-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1464a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Broadcasting Board of Governors is authorized to lease or otherwise acquire time on commercial or United States Government satellites for the purpose of transmitting materials and programs to posts and other users abroad.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f01e108-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1464a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Broadcast principles</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress finds that the long-term interests of the United States are served by communicating directly with the peoples of the world by television. To be effective, the Broadcasting Board of Governors must win the attention and respect of viewers. These principles will therefore govern the television broadcasts of the United States International Television Service:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f01e109-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1464a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The United States International Television Service will serve as a consistently reliable and authoritative source of news. The United States International Television Service news will be accurate and objective.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f01e10a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1464a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The United States International Television Service will represent the United States, not any single segment of American society and will, therefore, present a balanced and comprehensive projection of significant American thought and institutions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f01e10b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1464a/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The United States International Television Service will present the policies of the United States clearly and effectively and will also present responsible discussions and opinion on these policies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f01e10c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1464a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Programs</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Broadcasting Board of Governors is authorized to produce, acquire, or broadcast television programs, via satellite, only if such programs—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f01e10d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1464a/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> are interactive, consisting of interviews among participants in different locales;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f01e10e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1464a/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> cover news, public affairs, or other current events;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f01e10f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1464a/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> cover official activities of government, Federal or State, including congressional proceedings and news briefings of any agency of the Executive branch; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f01e110-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1464a/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> are of an artistic or scientific character or are otherwise representative of American culture.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f01e111-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1464a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Costs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">When a comparable program produced by United States public or commercial broadcasters and producers is available at a cost which is equal to or less than the cost of production by the United States International Television Service, the Broadcasting Board of Governors shall use such materials in preference to the United States International Television Service produced materials.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f01e112-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1464a/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Allocation of funds</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f01e113-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1464a/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Of the funds authorized to be appropriated to the Broadcasting Board of Governors not more than $12,000,000 for the fiscal year 1990 and not more than $12,480,000 for the fiscal year 1991 may be obligated or expended for the United States International Television Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f01e114-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1464a/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Broadcasting Board of Governors shall prepare and submit to the Congress quarterly reports which contain a detailed explanation of expenditures for the United States International Television Service during the fiscal years 1990 and 1991. Such reports shall contain specific justification and supporting information pertaining to all programs, particularly those described in subsection (c)(4), that were produced in-house by the United States International Television Service. Each such report shall include a statement by the Broadcasting Board of Governors that, according to the best information available to the Broadcasting Board of Governors, no comparable United States commercially-produced or public television program is available at a cost which is equal to or less than the cost of production by the United States International Television Service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f01e115-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1464a/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Of the funds authorized to be appropriated to the Broadcasting Board of Governors, $1,500,000 for the fiscal year 1990 and $1,500,000 for the fiscal year 1991 shall be available only for the purchase or use of programs produced with grants from the Corporation for Public Broadcasting or produced by United States public broadcasters.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8f01e116-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-01-27/ch36">Jan. 27, 1948, ch. 36</ref>, title V, § 505, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/246/tII/s205/a">Pub. L. 101–246, title II, § 205(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-02-16">Feb. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/50">104 Stat. 50</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dG">Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIII, § 1335(a)(1), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-786">112 Stat. 2681–786</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8f01e117-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8f01e118-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8f01e119-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1335/a/1/A">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1335(a)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “Broadcasting Board of Governors” for “Director of the United States Information Agency”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1335/a/1/B">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1335(a)(1)(B)</ref>, (C)(i), in introductory provisions, substituted “Broadcasting Board of Governors” for “United States Information Agency” and “television broadcasts of the United States International Television Service” for “Agency’s television broadcasts (hereinafter in this section referred to as ‘USIA–TV’)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1) to (3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1335/a/1/C/ii">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1335(a)(1)(C)(ii)</ref>, substituted “The United States International Television Service” for “USIA–TV”, wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1335/a/1/A">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1335(a)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “Broadcasting Board of Governors” for “Director of the United States Information Agency” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1335/a/1/A">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1335(a)(1)(A)</ref>, (D), substituted “Broadcasting Board of Governors” for “Director of the United States Information Agency” and substituted “the United States International Television Service” for “USIA–TV” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1335/a/1/B">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1335(a)(1)(B)</ref>, (D), substituted “Broadcasting Board of Governors” for “United States Information Agency” and “the United States International Television Service” for “USIA–TV”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1335/a/1/D">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1335(a)(1)(D)</ref>, substituted “the United States International Television Service” for “USIA–TV”, wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1335/a/1/A">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1335(a)(1)(A)</ref>, (B), in first sentence, substituted “Broadcasting Board of Governors” for “United States Information Agency”, and in last sentence, substituted “Broadcasting Board of Governors” for “Director of the United States Information Agency” after “statement by the” and for “United States Information Agency” after “available to the”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1335/a/1/B">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1335(a)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “Broadcasting Board of Governors” for “United States Information Agency”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8f01e11a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id8f01e11b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Broadcasting Board of Governors renamed United States Agency for Global Media pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/21">section 6204(a)(21) of this title</ref>. The renaming was effectuated by notice to congressional appropriations committees dated <date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>, and became effective <date date="2018-08-22">Aug. 22, 2018</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id8f01e11c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref> effective <date date="1999-10-01">Oct. 1, 1999</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1301">section 1301 of Pub. L. 105–277</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6531">section 6531 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8f01e11d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Television Service of USIA</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/204/tII/s207">Pub. L. 100–204, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1374">101 Stat. 1374</ref>, which provided that the television and film service of the United States Information Agency was to operate under same criteria and conditions as specified for Voice of America by <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1463">section 1463 of this title</ref>, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dG">Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIII, § 1336(7), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-790">112 Stat. 2681–790</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
