<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8f01e13c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1465a"><num value="1465a">§ 1465a.</num><heading> Additional functions of Broadcasting Board of Governors</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f01e13d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1465a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Radio broadcasting to Cuba</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to carry out the objectives set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1465">section 1465 of this title</ref>, the Broadcasting Board of Governors (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Board”) shall provide for the open communication of information and ideas through the use of radio broadcasting to Cuba. Radio broadcasting to Cuba shall serve as a consistently reliable and authoritative source of accurate, objective, and comprehensive news.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f01e13e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1465a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Broadcasting as part of Voice of America</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Radio broadcasting in accordance with subsection (a) shall be part of the Voice of America radio broadcasting to Cuba and shall be in accordance with all Voice of America standards to ensure the broadcast of programs which are objective, accurate, balanced, and which present a variety of views.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f01e13f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1465a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Location of broadcast facilities; frequency; leased time from nongovernmental shortwave stations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Radio broadcasting to Cuba authorized by this subchapter shall utilize the broadcasting facilities located at Marathon, Florida, and the 1180 AM frequency that were used by the Voice of America prior to <date date="1983-10-04">October 4, 1983</date>. Other frequencies, not on the commercial Amplitude Modulation (AM) Band (535 kHz to 1605 kHz), may also be simultaneously utilized: <i>Provided</i>, That no frequency shall be used for radio broadcasts to Cuba in accordance with this subchapter which is not also used for all other Voice of America broadcasts to Cuba. Time leased from nongovernmental shortwave radio stations may be used to carry all or part of the Service programs and to rebroadcast Service programs: <i>Provided</i>, That not less than 30 per centum of the programs broadcast or rebroadcast shall be regular Voice of America broadcasts with particular emphasis on news and programs meeting the requirements of section 1463(2) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002060">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002060"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f01e140-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1465a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Changes in frequencies to other AM bands; jamming and interference</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding subsection (c), in the event that broadcasts to Cuba on the 1180 AM frequency are subject to jamming or interference greater by 25 per centum or more than the average daily jamming or interference in the twelve months preceding <date date="1983-09-01">September 1, 1983</date>, the Broadcasting Board of Governors may lease time on commercial or noncommercial educational AM band radio broadcasting stations. The Federal Communications Commission shall determine levels of jamming and interference by conducting regular monitoring of the 1180 AM frequency. In the event that more than two hours a day of time is leased, not less than 30 per centum of the programing broadcast shall be regular Voice of America broadcasts with particular emphasis on news and programs meeting the requirements of section 1463(2) <sup>1</sup> of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f01e141-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1465a/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Voice of America: Cuba Service; Voice of America: Radio Marti program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any program of United States Government radio broadcasts to Cuba authorized by this section shall be designated “Voice of America: Cuba Service” or “Voice of America: Radio Marti program”.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f01e142-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1465a/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of other facilities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the event broadcasting facilities located at Marathon, Florida, are rendered inoperable by natural disaster or by unlawful destruction, the Broadcasting Board of Governors may, for the period in which the facilities are inoperable but not to exceed one hundred and fifty days, use other United States Government-owned transmission facilities for Voice of America broadcasts to Cuba authorized by this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8f01e143-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/111/s3">Pub. L. 98–111, § 3</ref>, <date date="1983-10-04">Oct. 4, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/749">97 Stat. 749</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dG">Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIII, § 1324(1)–(3), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-780">112 Stat. 2681–780</ref>, 2681–781.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8f01e144-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I84" topic="prospectiveAmendment" id="id8f01e145-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered fontsize8 smallCaps">Repeal of Section</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">Section repealed upon transmittal of determination by President under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6063/c/3">section 6063(c)(3) of this title</ref> that democratically elected government in Cuba is in power, see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6037/c">section 6037(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8f01e146-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8f01e147-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1463">Section 1463 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsecs. (c) and (d), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/tIII/s315/a">Pub. L. 103–236, title III, § 315(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/445">108 Stat. 445</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8f01e148-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Radio Broadcasting to Cuba Act which comprises this subchapter, and not as part of the United States Information and Educational Exchange Act of 1948 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8f01e149-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1324/1">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1324(1)</ref>, (2), substituted “Broadcasting Board of Governors” for “United States Information Agency” and “Board” for “Agency”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d), (f). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1324/3">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1324(3)</ref>, substituted “the Broadcasting Board of Governors” for “the Director of the United States Information Agency”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8f01e14a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id8f01e14b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Broadcasting Board of Governors renamed United States Agency for Global Media pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/21">section 6204(a)(21) of this title</ref>. The renaming was effectuated by notice to congressional appropriations committees dated <date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>, and became effective <date date="2018-08-22">Aug. 22, 2018</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id8f01e14c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref> effective <date date="1999-10-01">Oct. 1, 1999</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1301">section 1301 of Pub. L. 105–277</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6531">section 6531 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
