<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8f0dc7e2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1622g"><num value="1622g">§ 1622g.</num><heading> Independence of Foreign Claims Settlement Commission of the United States; finality of Commission decisions</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to diminish the independence of the Commission in making its determinations on claims in programs that it is authorized to administer pursuant to the powers and responsibilities conferred upon the Commission by the War Claims Act of 1948, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4101">50 U.S.C. 4101</ref> et seq.], the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1621">22 U.S.C. 1621</ref> et seq.], and Reorganization Plan Numbered 1 of 1954. The decisions of the Commission with respect to claims shall be final and conclusive on all questions of law and fact, and shall not be subject to review by the Attorney General or any other official of the United States or by any court by mandamus or otherwise.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8f0dc7e3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/209/tI/s107">Pub. L. 96–209, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1980-03-14">Mar. 14, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/97">94 Stat. 97</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8f0dc7e4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8f0dc7e5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8f0dc7e6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/96/209">Pub. L. 96–209</ref>, <date date="1980-03-14">Mar. 14, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/96">94 Stat. 96</ref>, which enacted sections 1622a to 1622g of this title, amended <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5316">section 5316 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees, and <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4101">section 4101 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, and enacted provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1622a">section 1622a of this title</ref>, section 363 of former Title 31, Money and Finance, and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s7546">section 7546 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The War Claims Act of 1948, as amended, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1948-07-03/ch826">act July 3, 1948, ch. 826</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/1240">62 Stat. 1240</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 51 (§ 4101 et seq.) of Title 50, War and National Defense. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The International Claims Settlement Act of 1949, as amended, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1950-03-10/ch54">act Mar. 10, 1950, ch. 54</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/12">64 Stat. 12</ref>, which is classified generally to this chapter (§ 1621 et seq.). For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1621">section 1621 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reorganization Plan Numbered 1 of 1954, referred to in text, is Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1954, <date date="1954-07-01">July 1, 1954</date>, 19 F.R. 3985, <ref href="/us/stat/68/1279">68 Stat. 1279</ref>, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1622">section 1622 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8f0dc7e7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was not enacted as part of the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8f0dc7e8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id8f0dc7e9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1980-03-14">Mar. 14, 1980</date>, see title VI of <ref href="/us/pl/96/209">Pub. L. 96–209</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1622a">section 1622a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
