<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8f0dc82f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627"><num value="1627">§ 1627.</num><heading> Creation of special funds in Treasury</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f0dc830-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Credits to, and payment from funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are created in the Treasury of the United States (1) a special fund to be known as the Yugoslav Claims Fund; and (2) such other special funds as may, in the discretion of the Secretary of the Treasury, be required, each to be a claims fund to be known by the name of the foreign government which has entered into a settlement agreement with the Government of the United States as described in subsection (a) of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1623">section 1623 of this title</ref>. There shall be covered into the Treasury to the credit of the proper special fund all funds hereinafter specified. All payments authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1626">section 1626 of this title</ref> shall be disbursed from the proper fund, as the case may be, and all amounts covered into the Treasury to the credit of the aforesaid funds are permanently appropriated for the making of the payments authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1626">section 1626 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f0dc831-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Credits to Yugoslav Claims Fund; credits to other funds</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized and directed to cover into—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f0dc832-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Yugoslav Claims Fund the sum of $17,000,000 being the amount paid by the Government of the Federal People’s Republic of Yugoslavia pursuant to the Yugoslav Claims Agreement of 1948;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f0dc833-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a special fund created for that purpose pursuant to subsection (a) of this section any amounts hereafter paid, in United States dollars, by a foreign government which has entered into a claims settlement agreement with the Government of the United States as described in subsection (a) of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1623">section 1623 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f0dc834-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment of awards</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized and directed out of the sums covered, prior to <date date="1968-07-24">July 24, 1968</date>, into any of the funds pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, and after making the deduction provided for in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1626/b/1">section 1626(b)(1) of this title</ref>—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f0dc835-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to make payments in full of the principal of awards of $1,000 or less, certified pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1624">section 1624 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f0dc836-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to make payments of $1,000 on the principal of each award of more than $1,000 in principal amount, certified pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1624">section 1624 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f0dc837-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to make additional payment of not to exceed 25 per centum of the unpaid principal of awards in the principal amount of more than $1,000;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f0dc838-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> after completing the payments prescribed by paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection, to make payments, from time to time in ratable proportions, on account of the unpaid principal of all awards in the principal amount of more than $1,000, according to the proportions which the unpaid principal of such awards bear to the total amount in the fund available for distribution at the time such payments are made; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f0dc839-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> after payment has been made of the principal amounts of all such awards, to make pro rata payments on account of accrued interest on such awards as bear interest.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f0dc83a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment of balance to Yugoslav Government; certification of adjudication costs; finality of certification</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury, upon the concurrence of the Secretary of State, is authorized and directed, out of the sum covered into the Yugoslav Claims Fund pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, after completing the payments of such funds pursuant to subsection (c) of this section, to make payment of the balance of any sum remaining in such fund to the Government of the Federal People’s Republic of Yugoslavia to the extent required under article 1(c) of the Yugoslav Claims Agreement of 1948. The Secretary of State shall certify to the Secretary of the Treasury the total cost of adjudication, not borne by the claimants, attributable to the Yugoslav Claims Agreement of 1948. Such certification shall be final and conclusive and shall not be subject to review by any other official, or department, agency, or establishment of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f0dc83b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Payments; priorities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (f), the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized and directed out of sums covered, subsequent to <date date="1968-07-24">July 24, 1968</date>, into any special fund created pursuant to this section to make payment on account of awards certified by the Commission pursuant to this subchapter with respect to claims included within the terms of a claims settlement agreement concluded between the Government of the United States and a foreign government as described in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1623/a">section 1623(a) of this title</ref>, as follows and in the following order of priority:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f0dc83c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Payment in the amount of $1,000 or the principal amount of the award, whichever is less;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f0dc83d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Thereafter, payments from time to time on account of the unpaid principal balance of each remaining award which shall bear to such unpaid principal balance the same proportion as the total amount available for distribution at the time such payments are made bears to the aggregate unpaid principal balance of all such awards; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f0dc83e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Thereafter, payments from time to time on account of the unpaid balance of each award of interest which shall bear to such unpaid balance of interest, the same proportion as the total amount available for distribution at the time such payments are made bears to the aggregate unpaid balance of interest of all such awards.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f0dc83f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> People’s Republic of China; claim payment priorities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f0dc840-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Out of sums covered after <date date="1979-05-11">May 11, 1979</date>, into the special fund created pursuant to this section to receive funds paid by the People’s Republic of China, the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized and directed to make payments on account of awards certified by the Commission pursuant to subchapter V with respect to claims included within the terms of the Agreement Between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the People’s Republic of China Concerning the Settlement of Claims, signed on <date date="1979-05-11">May 11, 1979</date>, in the following order of priority:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f0dc841-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Payment in the amount of $1,000 or the principal amount of the award, whichever is less.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f0dc842-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Thereafter, except as provided in paragraph (2), to the extent there remain unpaid principal balances on awards, payments from time to time on account of the unpaid principal balance of each remaining award which bear to such unpaid principal balance the same proportion as the total amount available for distribution at the time such payments are made bears to the aggregate unpaid principal balance of all such awards.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f0dc843-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/f/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Thereafter, payments from time to time on account of the unpaid balance of each award of interest which bear to such unpaid balance of interest the same proportion as the total amount available for distribution at the time such payments are made bears to the aggregate unpaid balance of interest of all such awards.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f0dc844-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f103945-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> For the purpose of computing the payments to be made under paragraph (1) to any claimant which was an incorporated business enterprise on the date of nationalization or other taking of property, the award certified by the Commission under subchapter V shall be reduced by the amount of Federal tax benefits derived by such claimant on account of the losses upon which such claim was based, but in no case shall such payments be reduced below the amount paid to such claimant on account of such claim before <date date="1980-10-13">October 13, 1980</date>. For purposes of this subparagraph, such Federal tax benefits shall be the amount by which the claimant’s taxes in any prior taxable year or years under chapters 1, 2A, 2B, 2D, and 2E of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939, or subtitle A of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, were decreased with respect to the loss or losses upon which the claim was based. The sum of the amounts which would otherwise be payable but for this paragraph which are not paid to any such claimant shall be aggregated, and the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized and directed to make payments out of such aggregated sums in accordance with subparagraph (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f103946-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> To the extent that there remain unpaid principal balances on awards to claimants which were, on the date of nationalization or other taking of property, nonprofit organizations operated exclusively for the promotion of social welfare, religious, charitable, or educational purposes (after payments made to such nonprofit organizations pursuant to subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) are taken into account), the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized and directed to make payments from time to time on account of the unpaid principal balance of each remaining award to such nonprofit organizations which bear to such unpaid principal balance the same proportion as the total sums aggregated pursuant to subparagraph (A) at the times such payments are made bear to the aggregate unpaid principal balance of all such awards to nonprofit organizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f103947-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1627/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to invest and recover expenses from funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized and directed to invest the amounts held respectively in the “special funds” established by this section in public debt securities with maturities suitable for the needs of the separate accounts and bearing interest at rates determined by the Secretary, taking into consideration the average market yield on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States of comparable maturities. The interest earned on the amounts in each special fund shall be used to make payments, in accordance with subsection (c), on awards payable from that special fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8f103948-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1950-03-10/ch54">Mar. 10, 1950, ch. 54</ref>, title I, § 8, <ref href="/us/stat/64/17">64 Stat. 17</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1955-08-09/ch645/s1">Aug. 9, 1955, ch. 645, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/562">69 Stat. 562</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/421/s1/4">Pub. L. 90–421, § 1(4)</ref>, (5), <date date="1968-07-24">July 24, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/420">82 Stat. 420</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/445">Pub. L. 96–445</ref>, <date date="1980-10-13">Oct. 13, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1891">94 Stat. 1891</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/204/tI/s142/a">Pub. L. 100–204, title I, § 142(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1350">101 Stat. 1350</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8f103949-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8f10394a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8f10394b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Internal Revenue Code of 1939, referred to in subsec. (f)(2)(A), was generally repealed by section 7851 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954, Title 26. The Internal Revenue Code of 1954 was redesignated the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>. For table of comparisons of the 1939 Code to the 1986 Code, see Table I preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code. See also <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7852/b">section 7852(b) of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code, for provision that references in any other law to a provision of the 1939 Code, unless expressly incompatible with the intent thereof, shall be deemed a reference to the corresponding provision of the 1986 Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Chapter 1 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939, referred to in subsec. (f)(2)(A), was comprised of sections 1 to 482 of former Title 26, Internal Revenue Code. Section 14 of former Title 26 was repealed by <ref href="/us/act/1951-10-20/ch521/tI">act Oct. 20, 1951, ch. 521, title I</ref>, pt. II, § 121(g), <ref href="/us/stat/65/469">65 Stat. 469</ref>. Sections 34 and 185 of former Title 26 were repealed by <ref href="/us/act/1944-02-25/ch63/tI">act Feb. 25, 1944, ch. 63, title I</ref>, §§ 106(c)(2), 107(a), <ref href="/us/stat/58/31">58 Stat. 31</ref>. Sections 264 and 363 of former Title 26 were repealed by <ref href="/us/act/1942-10-21/ch619/tI">act Oct. 21, 1942, ch. 619, title I</ref>, §§ 159(e), 170(a), <ref href="/us/stat/56/860">56 Stat. 860</ref>, 878. Sections 430 to 474 of former Title 26 were omitted, and subsequently, along with the remaining sections of former Title 26 comprising chapter 1, except sections 143 and 144, were repealed by sections 7851(a)(1)(A) of Title 26, Internal Revenue Code. Sections 143 and 144 of former Title 26 were repealed by <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7851/a/1/B">section 7851(a)(1)(B) of Title 26</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Chapter 2A of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939, referred to in subsec. (f)(2)(A), was comprised of sections 500 to 511 of former Title 26, Internal Revenue Code. Sections 500 to 511 were repealed by <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7851/a/1/A">section 7851(a)(1)(A) of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Chapter 2B of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939, referred to in subsec. (f)(2)(A), was comprised of sections 600 to 605 of former Title 26, Internal Revenue Code. Sections 600 to 605 were repealed by <ref href="/us/act/1945-11-08/ch453/tII/s202">act Nov. 8, 1945, ch. 453, title II, § 202</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/59/574">59 Stat. 574</ref>, eff. with respect to taxable years ending <date date="1946-06-30">June 30, 1946</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Chapter 2D of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939, referred to in subsec. (f)(2)(A), was comprised of sections 700 to 706 of former Title 26, Internal Revenue Code. Sections 700 to 716 were repealed by <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7851/a/1/A">section 7851(a)(1)(A) of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Chapter 2E of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939, referred to in subsec. (f)(2)(A), was comprised of sections 710 to 784 of former Title 26, Internal Revenue Code. Sections 710 to 736, 740, 742 to 744, 750, 751, 760, 761 and 780 to 784 were repealed by <ref href="/us/act/1945-11-08/ch453/tI/s122/a">act Nov. 8, 1945, ch. 453, title I, § 122(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/59/568">59 Stat. 568</ref>. Section 741 was repealed by <ref href="/us/act/1942-10-21/ch619/tII">act Oct. 21, 1942, ch. 619, title II</ref>, §§ 224(b), 228(b), <ref href="/us/stat/56/920">56 Stat. 920</ref>, 925. Section 752 was repealed by <ref href="/us/act/1942-10-21/ch619/tII/s229/a/1">act Oct. 21, 1942, ch. 619, title II, § 229(a)(1)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/56/931">56 Stat. 931</ref>, eff. as of <date date="1940-10-08">Oct. 8, 1940</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subtitle A of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, referred to in subsec. (f)(2)(A), is subtitle A of <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-16/ch736">act Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68A/4">68A Stat. 4</ref>, which comprises Subtitle A (§ 1 et seq.) of Title 26, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8f10394c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/100/204">Pub. L. 100–204</ref> added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (f)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> substituted “Internal Revenue Code of 1986” for “Internal Revenue Code of 1954”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/96/445/s1/1">Pub. L. 96–445, § 1(1)</ref>, substituted “Except as provided in subsection (f), the Secretary of the Treasury” for “The Secretary of the Treasury”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/96/445/s1/2">Pub. L. 96–445, § 1(2)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/90/421/s1/4">Pub. L. 90–421, § 1(4)</ref>, inserted “, prior to <date date="1968-07-24">July 24, 1968</date>,” after “the sums covered” and substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1626/b/1">section 1626(b)(1) of this title</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1626/b">section 1626(b) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/90/421/s1/5">Pub. L. 90–421, § 1(5)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1955—Act <date date="1955-08-09">Aug. 9, 1955</date>, amended credit to section by designating act <date date="1950-03-10">Mar. 10, 1950</date>, as “title I”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8f10394d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8f10394e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References to This Subchapter Deemed To Include Section 119 of H.R. 2076</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References to this subchapter deemed to include section 119 of H.R. 2076, see section 119(b) of H.R. 2076, as enacted into law by <ref href="/us/pl/104/91">Pub. L. 104–91</ref>, set out as an Authority of Foreign Claims Settlement Commission note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1644">section 1644 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id8f10394f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8f103950-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Abolition of International Claims Commission and Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">International Claims Commission of the United States, including offices of its members, abolished and functions of Commission and of members, officers, and employees thereof transferred to Foreign Claims Settlement Commission of the United States by Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1954, §§ 1, 2, 4, eff. <date date="1954-07-01">July 1, 1954</date>, 19 F.R. 3985, <ref href="/us/stat/68/1279">68 Stat. 1279</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1622">section 1622 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions transferring Foreign Claims Settlement Commission of the United States as a separate agency within the Department of Justice, see section 1622a et seq. of this title.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
