<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8f10399d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1631l"><num value="1631l">§ 1631l.</num><heading> Determination of expenses and time for filing suit, notice of claim and debt claim</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Prior to covering the net proceeds of liquidation of any property into the Treasury pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1631a/a">section 1631a(a) of this title</ref>, the designee of the President under this subchapter shall determine—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f10399e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1631l/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the amount of his administrative expenses attributable to the performance of his functions under this subchapter with respect to such property and the proceeds thereof. The amount so determined, together with an amount not exceeding that expended or incurred for the conservation, preservation, or maintenance of such property and the proceeds thereof, and for taxes in respect of same, shall be deducted and retained by the designee from the proceeds otherwise covered into the Treasury; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f10399f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1631l/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> that the time for the institution of a suit under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1631f/a">section 1631f(a) of this title</ref>, for the filing of a notice of claim under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1631f/b">section 1631f(b) of this title</ref>, and for the filing of debt claims under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1631g">section 1631g of this title</ref> has elapsed.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The determinations of the designee under this section shall be final and conclusive.</continuation>
<sourceCredit id="id8f1039a0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1950-03-10/ch54">Mar. 10, 1950, ch. 54</ref>, title II, § 213, as added <ref href="/us/act/1955-08-09/ch645/s3">Aug. 9, 1955, ch. 645, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/570">69 Stat. 570</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
