<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8f14f45d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1643"><num value="1643">§ 1643.</num><heading> Congressional declaration of purpose</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the purpose of this subchapter to provide for the determination of the amount and validity of claims against the Government of Cuba, or the Chinese Communist regime, which have arisen since <date date="1959-01-01">January 1, 1959</date>, in the case of claims against the Government of Cuba, or since <date date="1949-10-01">October 1, 1949</date>, in the case of claims against the Chinese Communist regime, out of nationalization, expropriation, intervention, or other takings of, or special measures directed against, property of nationals of the United States, and claims for disability or death of nationals of the United States arising out of violations of international law by the Government of Cuba, or the Chinese Communist regime, in order to obtain information concerning the total amount of such claims against the Government of Cuba, or the Chinese Communist regime, on behalf of nationals of the United States. This subchapter shall not be construed as authorizing an appropriation or as any intention to authorize an appropriation for the purpose of paying such claims.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8f14f45e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1950-03-10/ch54">Mar. 10, 1950, ch. 54</ref>, title V, § 501, as added <ref href="/us/pl/88/666">Pub. L. 88–666</ref>, <date date="1964-10-16">Oct. 16, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/1110">78 Stat. 1110</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/89/262/s1">Pub. L. 89–262, § 1</ref>, <date date="1965-10-19">Oct. 19, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/988">79 Stat. 988</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/780/s1">Pub. L. 89–780, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-11-06">Nov. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1365">80 Stat. 1365</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8f14f45f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8f14f460-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8f14f461-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—<ref href="/us/pl/89/780">Pub. L. 89–780</ref> provided for applicability of section to the Chinese Communist regime in the case of claims which have arisen since <date date="1949-10-01">October 1, 1949</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—<ref href="/us/pl/89/262">Pub. L. 89–262</ref> struck out “which have arisen out of debts for merchandise furnished or services rendered by nationals of the United States without regard to the date on which such merchandise was furnished or services were rendered or” after “Government of Cuba” in first sentence.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8f14f462-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="separability" id="id8f14f463-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Separability</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1950-03-10/ch54/tV/s513">Act Mar. 10, 1950, ch. 54, title V, § 513</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/88/666">Pub. L. 88–666</ref>, <date date="1964-10-16">Oct. 16, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/1113">78 Stat. 1113</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/88/666">“If any provision of this Act [enacting this subchapter], or the application thereof to any person or circumstances, shall be held invalid, the remainder of the Act, or the application of such provision to other persons or circumstances, shall not be affected.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
