<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8f1c2031-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1741c–2"><num value="1741c–2">§ 1741c–2.</num><heading> Coordination with transportation authorities and industry on Department of State travel advisories</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f1c2032-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1741c–2/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination with the Department of Homeland Security</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id8f1c2033-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1741c–2/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary of State shall, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security and representatives of any other Federal agency determined necessary, and in consultation with the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs and the Assistant Secretary of State for Consular Affairs, develop messaging and informational guidance to be delivered at all United States international airports and on relevant United States Government websites warning United States nationals of the risks of wrongful or unlawful detention or hostage-taking in covered countries.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id8f1c2034-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1741c–2/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Messaging and guidance</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The messaging and guidance described under paragraph (1) may include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f1c2035-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1741c–2/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> posters, brochures, and other informational materials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f1c2036-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1741c–2/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> web banners or other warnings to be displayed on relevant United States Government websites and webpages;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f1c2037-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1741c–2/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> verbal warnings at United States international airports to United States nationals whose destinations, to the extent they are discernable, are covered countries; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f1c2038-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1741c–2/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> other methods deemed appropriate by the Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security and representatives of any other Federal agency determined necessary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f1c2039-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1741c–2/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Department of State coordination with United States airlines</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security and representatives of any other Federal agency determined necessary, and in consultation with the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs and Assistant Secretary of the Bureau of Consular Affairs, work with United States airlines to provide warnings about the risk of wrongful or unlawful detention and hostage-taking to United States nationals booking travel through their airlines to a covered country.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f1c203a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1741c–2/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than one year after <date date="2024-12-23">December 23, 2024</date>, the Secretary of State shall, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security and representatives of any other Federal agency determined necessary, submit to Congress a report detailing—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f1c203b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1741c–2/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the additional steps taken to warn United States nationals of the risks of wrongful or unlawful detention and hostage-taking abroad, including those described in this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f1c203c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1741c–2/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> efforts to improve the visibility and expand the reach of Department of State travel advisories concerning the risks to United States nationals of wrongful or unlawful detention and hostage-taking abroad; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f1c203d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1741c–2/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> additional recommendations on steps the United States Government might take to improve the awareness of United States nationals of the risk of wrongful or unlawful detention and hostage-taking abroad.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f1c203e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s1741c–2/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Covered country defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “covered country” means a country for which a Department of State travel advisory contains either the “K—Kidnapping or Hostage Taking” or “D—Wrongful Detention” Risk Indicators.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8f1c203f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dFF/tIII/s305B">Pub. L. 116–260, div. FF, title III, § 305B</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dG/tLXXVII/s7705">Pub. L. 118–159, div. G, title LXXVII, § 7705</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2554">138 Stat. 2554</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
