<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8f2ce972-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2024"><num value="2024">§ 2024.</num><heading> Authorization of appropriations for payment of expenses</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated annually to the Department of State, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, such sums as may be necessary for the payment by the United States of its share of the expenses of the International Atomic Energy Agency as apportioned by the Agency in accordance with paragraph (D) of article XIV of the Statute of the Agency, and for all necessary salaries and expenses of the representatives provided for in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2021">section 2021 of this title</ref> and of their appropriate staffs, including personal services without regard to the civil service laws and chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5; travel expenses without regard to the Standardized Government Travel Regulations, as amended, subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5, and <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5731">section 5731 of title 5</ref>, as amended; salaries as authorized by the Foreign Service Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3901">22 U.S.C. 3901</ref> et seq.], or as authorized by the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2011">42 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et seq.], and expenses and allowances of personnel and dependents as authorized by the Foreign Service Act of 1980; services as authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3109">section 3109 of title 5</ref>; translating and other services, by contract; hire of passenger motor vehicles and other local transportation; printing and binding without regard to <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s501">section 501 of title 44</ref>; official functions and courtesies; such sums as may be necessary to defray the expenses of United States participation in the Preparatory Commission for the Agency, established pursuant to annex I of the Statute of the Agency; and such other expenses as may be authorized by the Secretary of State.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8f2ce973-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/85/177/s5">Pub. L. 85–177, § 5</ref>, <date date="1957-08-28">Aug. 28, 1957</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/71/454">71 Stat. 454</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/465/tII/s2206/a/7/B">Pub. L. 96–465, title II, § 2206(a)(7)(B)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2161">94 Stat. 2161</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8f2ce974-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8f2ce975-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8f2ce976-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Paragraph (D) of article XIV of the Statute of the Agency, referred to in text, provides “The Board of Governors shall apportion the expenses referred to in subparagraph B–1 above, among members in accordance with a scale to be fixed by the General Conference. In fixing the scale the General Conference shall be guided by the principles adopted by the United Nations in assessing contributions of Member States to the regular budget of the United Nations”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Foreign Service Act of 1980, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/96/465">Pub. L. 96–465</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2071">94 Stat. 2071</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 52 (§ 3901 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3901">section 3901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Atomic Energy Act of 1954, as amended, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-30/ch1073/s1">act Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/919">68 Stat. 919</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 23 (§ 2011 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2011">section 2011 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8f2ce977-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5”, “subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5”, “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5731">section 5731 of title 5</ref>”, and “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3109">section 3109 of title 5</ref>” substituted in text for “the Classification Act of 1949, as amended”, “the Travel Expense Act of 1949, as amended”, “<ref href="/us/act/1933-03-03/s10">section 10 of the Act of March 3, 1933</ref>, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s73b">5 U.S.C. 73b</ref>]”, and “<ref href="/us/act/1946-08-02/s15">section 15 of the Act of August 2, 1946</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s55a">5 U.S.C. 55a</ref>)”, respectively, on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s7/b">Pub. L. 89–554, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/631">80 Stat. 631</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“<ref href="/us/usc/t44/s501">Section 501 of title 44</ref>” substituted in text for “section II of the Act of <date date="1919-03-01">March 1, 1919</date> (<ref href="/us/usc/t44/s111">44 U.S.C. 111</ref>)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/90/620/s2/b">Pub. L. 90–620, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1305">82 Stat. 1305</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 44, Public Printing and Documents.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8f2ce978-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—<ref href="/us/pl/96/465">Pub. L. 96–465</ref> substituted references to the Foreign Service Act of 1980 for references to the Foreign Service Act of 1946.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8f2ce979-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id8f2ce97a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/465">Pub. L. 96–465</ref> effective <date date="1981-02-15">Feb. 15, 1981</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/465/s2403">section 2403 of Pub. L. 96–465</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3901">section 3901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8f2ce97b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Authority Under This Section</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Authority under this section to terminate if Senate refuses its advice and consent by a formal vote to an amendment to the Statute of the Agency, see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2026">section 2026 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
