<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8f2f32d4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2078"><num value="2078">§ 2078.</num><heading> International Center for Middle Eastern-Western Dialogue Trust Fund</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f2f32d5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2078/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the International Center for Middle Eastern-Western Dialogue Trust Fund. The income from the fund shall be used for operations of the International Center for Middle Eastern-Western Dialogue to promote dialogue and scholarship in the Middle East. The fund may accept contributions and gifts from public and private sources.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f2f32d6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2078/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties of Secretary of State; investments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be the duty of the Secretary of the Treasury to invest in full amounts made available to the fund. Such investments may be made only in interest-bearing obligations of the United States or in obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by the United States. The interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in the fund shall be credited to and form a part of the fund and shall remain available without fiscal year limitation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f2f32d7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2078/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For each fiscal year, there is authorized to be appropriated from the fund for the operations of the International Center for Middle Eastern-Western Dialogue the total amount of the interest and earnings credited to the fund under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f2f32d8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2078/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of additional appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the International Center for Middle Eastern-Western Dialogue Trust Fund, without fiscal year limitation, such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section and to provide for the permanent endowment for the International Center for Middle Eastern-Western Dialogue established under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f2f32d9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2078/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Ownership of Center location</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The United States, through the Department of State, shall retain ownership of the Palazzo Corpi building in Istanbul, Turkey, and the Secretary of State shall be responsible for maintaining the International Center for Middle Eastern-Western Dialogue at such location.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8f2f32da-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/108/199/dB/tVI/s633">Pub. L. 108–199, div. B, title VI, § 633</ref>, <date date="2004-01-23">Jan. 23, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/100">118 Stat. 100</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8f2f32db-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8f2f32dc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8f2f32dd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of <ref href="/us/pl/108/199/dB/s633">section 633 of div. B of Pub. L. 108–199</ref>. Subsec. (f) of <ref href="/us/pl/108/199/dB/s633">section 633 of div. B of Pub. L. 108–199</ref> amended <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1321/a">section 1321(a) of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
