<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8f2f3312-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2102"><num value="2102">§ 2102.</num><heading> Authority of Secretary</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f2f3313-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2102/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of health research and research training resources</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To carry out the purposes of clause (1) of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2101">section 2101 of this title</ref>, the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare (hereafter referred to as the “Secretary”) may in the exercise of his responsibilities under the Vocational Rehabilitation Act, sections 191 to 194 of title 42, and any other provision of law, to conduct and support health research and research training, including research and research training relating to the rehabilitation of the handicapped, make such use of health research and research training resources in participating foreign countries as he may deem necessary and desirable.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f2f3314-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2102/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Fellowships; equipment, meetings and conferences; interchange of scientists and experts; consultants; compensation and travel expenses</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To carry out his responsibilities under this section the Secretary may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f2f3315-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2102/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> establish and maintain fellowships in the United States and in participating foreign countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f2f3316-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2102/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> make grants to public institutions or agencies and to nonprofit private institutions or agencies in the United States and in participating foreign countries for the purpose of establishing and maintaining fellowships;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f2f3317-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2102/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> make grants or loans of equipment, medical, biological, physical, or chemical substances or other materials, for use by public institutions or agencies, or nonprofit private institutions or agencies, or by individuals, in participating foreign countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f2f3318-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2102/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> participate and otherwise cooperate in any international health or medical research or research training meetings, conferences, or other activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f2f3319-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2102/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> facilitate the interchange between the United States and participating foreign countries, and among participating foreign countries, of research scientists and experts who are engaged in experiments and programs of research or research training, and in carrying out such purpose may pay per diem compensation, subsistence, and travel for such scientists and experts when away from their places of residence at rates not to exceed those provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5703">section 5703 of title 5</ref> for persons in the Government service intermittently employed; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f2f331a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2102/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> procure, in accordance with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3109">section 3109 of title 5</ref>, the temporary or intermittent services of experts or consultants; individuals so employed shall receive compensation at a rate to be fixed by the Secretary, but not in excess of $50 per diem, including travel time, and while away from their homes or regular places of business may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5703">section 5703 of title 5</ref> for persons in the Government service employed intermittently.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f2f331b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2102/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f2f331c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2102/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “health research” shall include, but not be limited to, research, investigations, and studies relating to causes and methods of prevention of accidents, including but not limited to highway and aviation accidents.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f2f331d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2102/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “participating foreign countries” means those foreign countries which cooperate with the United States in carrying out the purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8f2f331e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/86/610/s4">Pub. L. 86–610, § 4</ref>, <date date="1960-07-12">July 12, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/365">74 Stat. 365</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8f2f331f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8f2f3320-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8f2f3321-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Vocational Rehabilitation Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1920-06-02/ch219">act June 2, 1920, ch. 219</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/41/735">41 Stat. 735</ref>, which was classified generally to chapter 4 (§ 31 et seq.) of Title 29, Labor, and was repealed by § 500(a) of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, <ref href="/us/pl/93/112/tV">Pub. L. 93–112, title V</ref>, <date date="1973-09-26">Sept. 26, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/355">87 Stat. 355</ref>. The Rehabilitation Act of 1973 is classified generally to chapter 16 (§ 701 et seq.) of Title 29. Section 500(a), classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s790">section 790 of Title 29</ref>, in part provided that references to the Vocational Rehabilitation Act in any other provision of law be deemed reference to the Rehabilitation Act of 1973.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8f2f3322-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (b)(5), (6), “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5703">section 5703 of title 5</ref>” and “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3109">section 3109 of title 5</ref>” substituted for “section 5 of the Administrative Expenses Act of 1946 (<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s73b–2">5 U.S.C. 73b–2</ref>)” and “section 15 of the Administrative Expenses Act of 1946 (<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s55a">5 U.S.C. 55a</ref>)” respectively, on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s7/b">Pub. L. 89–554, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/631">80 Stat. 631</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8f2f3323-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id8f2f3324-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions and offices relating to the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 [see References in Text note above] of Secretary and Department of Health, Education, and Welfare to Secretary and Department of Education and redes­ignation of Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare as Secretary of Health and Human Services, see sections 3441 and 3508 of Title 20, Education.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
