<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8f470104-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2151–2"><num value="2151–2">§ 2151–2.</num><heading> Actions to improve the international gender policy of the United States Agency for International Development</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f470105-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2151–2/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Gender analysis defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “gender analysis”—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f470106-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2151–2/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> means a socioeconomic analysis of available or gathered quantitative and qualitative information to identify, understand, and explain gaps between men and women which typically involves examining—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f470107-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2151–2/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> differences in the status of women and men and their differential access to and control over assets, resources, education, opportunities, and services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f470108-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2151–2/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the influence of gender roles, structural barriers, and norms on the division of time between paid employment, unpaid work (including the subsistence production and care for family members), and volunteer activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f470109-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2151–2/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the influence of gender roles, structural barriers, and norms on leadership roles and decision making; constraints, opportunities, and entry points for narrowing gender gaps and empowering women; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f47010a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2151–2/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> potential differential impacts of development policies and programs on men and women, including unintended or negative consequences; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f47010b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2151–2/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> includes conclusions and recommendations to enable development policies and programs to narrow gender gaps and improve the lives of women and girls.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f47010c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2151–2/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> International development cooperation policy</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be the international development cooperation policy of the United States—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f47010d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2151–2/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to reduce gender disparities with respect to economic, social, political, educational, and cultural resources, wealth, opportunities, and services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f47010e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2151–2/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to strive to eliminate gender-based violence and mitigate its harmful effects on individuals and communities including through efforts to develop standards and capacity to reduce gender-based violence in the workplace and other places where women work;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f47010f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2151–2/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> to support activities that secure private property rights and land tenure for women in developing countries, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f470110-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2151–2/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> legal frameworks that give women equal rights to own, register, use, profit from, and inherit land and property;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f470111-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2151–2/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> improving legal literacy to enable women to exercise the rights described in subparagraph (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f470112-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2151–2/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> improving the capacity of law enforcement and community leaders to enforce such rights;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f470113-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2151–2/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to increase the capability of women and girls to fully exercise their rights, determine their life outcomes, assume leadership roles, and influence decision-making in households, communities, and societies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f470114-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2151–2/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> to improve the access of women and girls to education, particularly higher education opportunities in business, finance, and management, in order to enhance financial literacy and business development, management, and strategy skills.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f470115-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2151–2/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Actions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to advance the policy described in subsection (b), the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall ensure that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f470116-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2151–2/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> strategies, projects, and activities of the Agency are shaped by a gender analysis;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f470117-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2151–2/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> standard indicators are used to assess such strategies, projects, and activities, if applicable; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f470118-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2151–2/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> gender equality and female empowerment are integrated throughout the Agency’s program cycle and related processes for purposes of strategic planning, project design and implementation, monitoring, and evaluation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8f470119-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/115/428/s3">Pub. L. 115–428, § 3</ref>, <date date="2019-01-09">Jan. 9, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5511">132 Stat. 5511</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8f47011a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8f47011b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8f47011c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Women’s Entrepreneurship and Economic Empowerment Act of 2018, and not as part of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8f47011d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8f47011e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Madeleine K. Albright Women’s Leadership Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dK/tVII/s7059/b">Pub. L. 117–328, div. K, title VII, § 7059(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5079">136 Stat. 5079</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/328/dK/tVII/s7059/b">“Of the funds appropriated under title III of this Act [title III of div. K of <ref href="/us/pl/117/328">Pub. L. 117–328</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4985">136 Stat. 4985</ref>, see Tables for classification], not less than $50,000,000 shall be made available for programs specifically designed to increase leadership opportunities for women in countries where women and girls suffer discrimination due to law, policy, or practice, by strengthening protections for women’s political status, expanding women’s participation in political parties and elections, and increasing women’s opportunities for leadership positions in the public and private sectors at the local, provincial, and national levels: <i>Provided</i>, That such programs shall hereafter be collectively named the ‘Madeleine K. Albright Women’s Leadership Program’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8f47011f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Findings</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/428/s2">Pub. L. 115–428, § 2</ref>, <date date="2019-01-09">Jan. 9, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5509">132 Stat. 5509</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/428/s2">
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Congress finds the following:</p>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Because women make up the majority of the world’s poor and gender inequalities prevail in incomes, wages, access to finance, ownership of assets, and control over the allocation of resources, women’s entrepreneurship and economic empowerment is important to achieve inclusive economic growth at all levels of society.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Research shows that when women exert greater influence over household finances, economic outcomes for families improve, and childhood survival rates, food security, and educational attainment increase. Women also tend to place a greater emphasis on household savings which improves family financial resiliency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> A 2016 report by the McKinsey Global Institute estimated that achieving global gender parity in economic activity could add as much as $28,000,000,000,000 to annual global gross domestic product by 2025.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Lack of access to financial services that address gender-specific constraints impedes women’s economic inclusion. Roughly 1,000,000,000 women around the world are currently left out of the formal financial system, which causes many women to rely on informal means of saving and borrowing that are riskier and less reliable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Among other consequences, this lack of access hampers the success of women entrepreneurs, including women who are seeking to run or grow small and medium-sized enterprises. The International Finance Corporation has estimated that 70 percent of women-owned small and medium-sized enterprises in the formal sector are unserved or underserved in terms of access to financial services, resulting in a financing gap of $300,000,000,000 for women-owned small businesses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><chapeau> Women’s economic empowerment is inextricably linked to a myriad of other women’s human rights that are essential to their ability to thrive as economic actors across the lifecycle, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> living lives free of violence and exploitation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> achieving the highest possible standard of health and well-being;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> enjoying full legal and human rights, such as access to registration, identification, and citizenship documents;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> benefitting from formal and informal education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> equal protection of and access to land and property rights;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> access to fundamental labor rights;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> policies to address disproportionate care burdens; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> business and management skills and leadership opportunities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> Discriminatory legal and regulatory systems and banking practices are obstacles to women’s access to capital and assets, including land, machinery, production facilities, technology, and human resources. These barriers are often connected to a woman’s marital status, which can determine whether she is able to inherit land or own property in her name. These constraints contribute to women frequently running smaller businesses, with fewer employees and lower asset values.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> Savings groups primarily comprised of women are recognized as a vital entry point, especially for poor and very poor women, to formal financial services. There is a high demand for such groups to protect and grow the savings of women with formal financial institutions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> Evidence shows that, once a saving group is linked to a bank, the average savings per member increases between 40 to 100 percent and the average profit per member doubles. Investing in financial literacy, business leadership training, and mentorship are key elements to these outcomes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="10">“(10)</num><content> United States support for microenterprise and microfinance development programs, which seek to reduce poverty in low-income countries by giving small loans to small-scale entrepreneurs without collateral, have been a useful mechanism to help families weather economic shocks, but many microcredit borrowers largely remain in poverty.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="11">“(11)</num><content> The vast majority of microcredit borrowers are women who would like to move up the economic ladder, but are held back by binding constraints that create a missing middle – large numbers of microenterprises, a handful of large firms or conglomerates, and very few small and medium-sized enterprises in between, which are critical to driving economic growth in developing countries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="12">“(12)</num><content> According to the World Bank, small and medium-sized enterprises create 4 out of 5 new positions in emerging markets, but approximately 50 percent of formal small and medium-sized enterprises lack access to formal credit. The financing gap is even larger when micro and informal enterprises are taken into account. Overall, approximately 70 percent of all micro, small, and medium-sized enterprises in emerging markets lack access to credit.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
