<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8f613ee1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2166"><num value="2166">§ 2166.</num><heading> Regional development in Africa</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President is requested to seek and to take appropriate action, in cooperation and consultation with African and other interested nations and with international development organizations, to further and assist in the advancement of African regional development institutions, including the African Development Bank, with the view toward promoting African economic development.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8f613ee2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, pt. I, § 206, as added <ref href="/us/pl/89/171">Pub. L. 89–171</ref>, pt. I, § 102(b), <date date="1965-09-06">Sept. 6, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/653">79 Stat. 653</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8f613ee3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8f613ee4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8f613ee5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">African Assistance Policy; Presidential Report to Congress</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/93/559/s49">Pub. L. 93–559, § 49</ref>, <date date="1974-12-30">Dec. 30, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1816">88 Stat. 1816</ref>, which related to Presidential review and report on African assistance policy, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/97/113/tVII/s734/a/8">Pub. L. 97–113, title VII, § 734(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1560">95 Stat. 1560</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8f613ee6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Portuguese African Territories of Angola, Mozambique, and Guinea-Bissau: Independence Policy</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/559/s50">Pub. L. 93–559, § 50</ref>, <date date="1974-12-30">Dec. 30, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1816">88 Stat. 1816</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/97/113/tVII/s734/a/8">Pub. L. 97–113, title VII, § 734(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1560">95 Stat. 1560</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/113/tVII/s734/a/8">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Congress finds that the Government of Portugal’s recognition of the right to independence of the African territories of Angola, Mozambique, and Guinea-Bissau marks a significant advance toward the goal of self-determination for all the peoples of Africa, without which peace on the continent is not secure.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Congress finds that progress toward independence for the Portuguese African territories will have a significant impact on the international organizations and the community of nations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Congress commends the Portuguese Government’s initiatives on these fronts as evidence of a reaffirmation of that Government’s support for her obligations under both the United Nations Charter and the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><chapeau> Therefore, Congress calls upon the President and the Secretary of State to take the following actions designed to make clear United States support for a peaceful and orderly transition to independence in the Portuguese African territories:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> An official statement should be issued of United States support for the independence of Angola, Mozambique and Guinea-Bissau, and of our desire to have good relations with the future governments of the countries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> It should be made clear to the Government of of Portugal that we view the efforts toward a peaceful and just settlement of the conflict in the African territories as consistent with Portugal’s obligations under the North Atlantic Treaty Organization partnership.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The United States should encourage United Nations support for a peaceful transition to independence, negotiated settlement of all differences, and the protection of human rights of all citizens of the three territories.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The United States should open a dialog with potential leaders of Angola, Mozambique, and Guinea-Bissau and assure them of our commitment to their genuine political and economic independence.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> The economic development needs of the three territories will be immense when independence is achieved. Therefore, it is urged that the United States Agency for International Development devote attention to assessing the economic situation in Angola, Mozambique, and Guinea-Bissau and be ready to cooperate with the future governments in providing the kind of assistance that will help make their independence viable. In addition, the United States Government should take the initiative among other donors, both bilateral and multilateral, in seeking significant contribution of development assistance for the three territories.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> In light of the need of Angola, Mozambique, and Guinea-Bissau for skilled and educated manpower, a priority consideration should be given to expanding current United States programs of educational assistance to the territories as a timely and substantive contribution to their independence.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> [Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/97/113/tVII/s734/a/8">Pub. L. 97–113, title VII, § 734(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1560">95 Stat. 1560</ref>.]</heading><content>”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id8f613ee7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id8f613ee8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of functions of President under this section, see Ex. Ord. No. 12163, <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 56673, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2381">section 2381 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id8f613ee9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 12599</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 12599, <date date="1987-06-23">June 23, 1987</date>, 52 F.R. 23779, which established the Coordinating Committee for Sub-Saharan Africa and assigned its functions in order to establish procedures for development of a common long-term goal for all United States economic programs and policies in Sub-Saharan Africa, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 13118, § 10(3), <date date="1999-03-31">Mar. 31, 1999</date>, 64 F.R. 16598.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
