<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8f6d2695-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2221"><num value="2221">§ 2221.</num><heading> General authority</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f6d2696-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2221/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Voluntary contributions; grants and loans in case of the Indus Basin Development Fund</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">When he determines it to be in the national interest, the President is authorized to make voluntary contributions on a grant basis to international organizations and to programs administered by such organizations, and in the case of the Indus Basin Development Fund administered by the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development to make grants and loans payable as to principal and interest in United States dollars and subject to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151t/b">section 2151t(b) of this title</ref>, on such terms and conditions as he may determine, in order to further the purposes of subchapter I of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f6d2697-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2221/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/97/113/tVII/s734/a/1">Pub. L. 97–113, title VII, § 734(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1560">95 Stat. 1560</ref></heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f6d2698-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2221/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Palestine refugees; considerations and conditions for furnishing assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No contributions by the United States shall be made to the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East except on the condition that the United Nations Relief and Works Agency take all possible measures to assure that no part of the United States contribution shall be used to furnish assistance to any refugee who is receiving military training as a member of the so-called Palestine Liberation Army or any other guerrilla type organization or who has engaged in any act of terrorism.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f6d2699-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2221/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Audit of funds; report to Congress and the President</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In any case in which a fund established solely by United States contributions under this chapter or any other Act is administered by an international organization under the terms of an agreement between the United States and such international organization, such agreement shall provide that the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct such audits as are necessary to assure that such fund is administered in accordance with such agreement. The President shall undertake to modify any existing agreement entered into before <date date="1967-11-14">November 14, 1967</date>, to conform to the requirements of the preceding sentence. The Comptroller General shall report simultaneously to the Congress and the President the results of the audits conducted under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f6d269a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2221/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Evaluation of United Nations and its affiliated organizations; International Bank for Reconstruction and Development; Asian Development Bank</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f6d269b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2221/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In the case of the United Nations and its affiliated organizations, including the International Atomic Energy Agency, the President shall, acting through the United States representative to such organizations, propose and actively seek the establishment by the governing authorities of such organizations of external, professionally qualified groups of appropriate size for the purpose of providing an independent and continuous program of selective examination, review, evaluation, and audits of the programs and activities of such organizations. Such proposal shall provide that such groups shall be established in accordance with such terms of reference as such governing authority may prescribe and that the reports of such groups on each examination, review, evaluation, or audit shall be submitted directly to such governing authority for transmittal to the representative of each individual member nation. Such proposal shall further include a statement of auditing and reporting standards, as prepared by the Comptroller General of the United States, for the consideration of the governing authority of the international organization concerned to assist in formulating terms of reference for such review and evaluation groups.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f6d269c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2221/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In the case of the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development and the Asian Development Bank, the President shall, acting through the United States representative to such organizations, propose and actively seek the establishment by the governing authorities of such organizations professionally qualified groups of appropriate size for the purpose of providing an independent and continuous program of selective examination, review, evaluation, and audit of the programs and activities of such organizations. Such proposal shall provide that such groups shall be established in accordance with such terms of reference as such governing authorities may prescribe, and that the reports of such groups on each examination, review, evaluation, or audit shall be submitted directly to such governing authority for transmittal to the representative of each individual member nation. Such proposal shall further include a statement of auditing and reporting standards, as prepared by the Comptroller General of the United States, for the consideration of the governing authority of the international organization concerned to assist in formulating terms of reference for such review and evaluation groups.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f6d269d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2221/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> International Fertilizer Development Center; United States participation and assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President is hereby authorized to permit United States participation in the International Fertilizer Development Center and is authorized to use any of the funds made available under this part for the purpose of furnishing assistance to the Center on such terms and conditions as he may determine.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f6d269e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2221/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of funding of technological assistance programs to United Nations Development Program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that the President should instruct the appropriate representatives of the United States to the United Nations to encourage the specialized agencies of the United Nations to transfer the funding of technical assistance programs carried out by such agencies to the United Nations Development Program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f6d269f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2221/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> International Food Policy Research Institute; availability of funds, etc.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President is authorized to permit the United States to participate in and to use any of the funds made available under subchapter I of this chapter after <date date="1981-12-29">December 29, 1981</date>, for the purpose of furnishing assistance (on such terms and conditions as the President may determine) to the International Food Policy Research Institute.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8f6d26a0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, pt. I, § 301, <date date="1961-09-04">Sept. 4, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/433">75 Stat. 433</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/171">Pub. L. 89–171</ref>, pt. I, § 106 (a), <date date="1965-09-06">Sept. 6, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/656">79 Stat. 656</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/583">Pub. L. 89–583</ref>, pt. I, § 107(a)–(c), <date date="1966-09-19">Sept. 19, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/800">80 Stat. 800</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/137">Pub. L. 90–137</ref>, pt. I, § 110(a), <date date="1967-11-14">Nov. 14, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/453">81 Stat. 453</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/175">Pub. L. 91–175</ref>, pt. I, § 108(a), <date date="1969-12-30">Dec. 30, 1969</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/83/819">83 Stat. 819</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/189/s9/1">Pub. L. 93–189, § 9(1)</ref>, <date date="1973-12-17">Dec. 17, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/718">87 Stat. 718</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/161/tIII/s313/c">Pub. L. 94–161, title III, § 313(c)</ref>, <date date="1975-12-20">Dec. 20, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/866">89 Stat. 866</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/424/tI">Pub. L. 95–424, title I</ref>, §§ 102(b)(2)(A), 117(d), <date date="1978-10-06">Oct. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/941">92 Stat. 941</ref>, 953; <ref href="/us/pl/96/533/tVII/s702">Pub. L. 96–533, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="1980-12-16">Dec. 16, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/3156">94 Stat. 3156</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/113/tIII/s311/a">Pub. L. 97–113, title III, § 311(a)</ref>, title VII, § 734(a)(1), <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1536">95 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1560.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8f6d26a1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8f6d26a2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8f6d26a3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (d), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, <date date="1961-09-04">Sept. 4, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/424">75 Stat. 424</ref>, known as the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">section 2151 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8f6d26a4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/97/113/s734/a/1">Pub. L. 97–113, § 734(a)(1)</ref>, struck out subsec. (b) which limited contributions to United Nations Development Program and restricted assistance to Cuba. See <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2370/f">section 2370(f) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/97/113/s734/a/1">Pub. L. 97–113, § 734(a)(1)</ref>, struck out par. (3) which required reports by the President and the General Accounting Office of their evaluation of reports of international organizations to United States representatives on those organizations. See <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2394">section 2394 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/97/113/s311/a">Pub. L. 97–113, § 311(a)</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/96/533/s702/a">Pub. L. 96–533, § 702(a)</ref>, required the Comptroller General to report to Congress and the President the results of the audits.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/96/533/s702/b/1">Pub. L. 96–533, § 702(b)(1)</ref>–(3), substituted “organizations of external, professionally” for “organizations a single professionally”, “groups” for “group” in three places, “evaluation, and audits” for “and evaluation”, and “evaluation, or audit” for “and evaluation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/96/533/s702/b/4">Pub. L. 96–533, § 702(b)(4)</ref>, (5), required audits of programs and activities and reports of professionally qualified groups to include such audits.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/96/533/s702/b/6">Pub. L. 96–533, § 702(b)(6)</ref>, required the Comptroller General to include in the reports to Congress and the President his evaluation of the reports received by the United States representatives to the international organizations and related information.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/424">Pub. L. 95–424</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151t/b">section 2151t(b) of this title</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2161/d">section 2161(d) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/95/424">Pub. L. 95–424</ref> added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/94/161">Pub. L. 94–161</ref> added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/93/189">Pub. L. 93–189</ref> added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1969—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/91/175">Pub. L. 91–175</ref> omitted provisions dealing with Israel and Arab governments taking steps toward repatriation of refugees and the extent and success of the United Nations and Arab governments to rectify refugees relief rolls, as criteria for the President to use in determining whether to furnish assistance for such refugees through contributions to the United Nations, omitted provisions dealing with amount of contribution for the fiscal year 1967, and expanded prohibition against the inclusion of members of other guerrilla type organizations or refugees engaged in any act of terrorism.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1967—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/90/137">Pub. L. 90–137</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/89/583/s107/a">Pub. L. 89–583, § 107(a)</ref>, authorized in the case of the Indus Basin Development Executive grants and loans payable as to principal and interest in United States dollars and subject to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2161/d">section 2161(d) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/89/583/s107/b">Pub. L. 89–583, § 107(b)</ref>, substituted “United Nations Development Program” for “United Nations Expanded Program of Technical Assistance and the United States Special Fund” and restricted economic or technical assistance to Cuba.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/89/583/s107/c">Pub. L. 89–583, § 107(c)</ref>, substituted provisions limiting contributions by the United States for fiscal year 1967 to $13,300,000, for provisions limiting contributions for calendar year 1966 to $15,200,000 and prohibited the making of contributions assisting any refugee who is receiving military training as a member of the Palestine Liberation Army.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/89/171">Pub. L. 89–171</ref> limited contributions by the United States to the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East to $15,200,000 for the calendar year 1966.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8f6d26a5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8f6d26a6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References to Subchapter I Deemed To Include Certain Parts of Subchapter II</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References to subchapter I of this chapter are deemed to include parts IV (§ 2346 et seq.), VI (§ 2348 et seq.), and VIII (§ 2349aa et seq.) of subchapter II of this chapter, and references to subchapter II are deemed to exclude such parts. See <ref href="/us/pl/92/226/s202/b">section 202(b) of Pub. L. 92–226</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2346">section 2346 of this title</ref>, and sections 2348c and 2349aa–5 of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id8f6d26a7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/424">Pub. L. 95–424</ref> effective <date date="1978-10-01">Oct. 1, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/424/s605">section 605 of Pub. L. 95–424</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">section 2151 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8f6d26a8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Use of Contributions for Projects in Cuba</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/91/194/tI/s100">Pub. L. 91–194, title I, § 100</ref>, <date date="1970-02-09">Feb. 9, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/5">84 Stat. 5</ref>, provided in part: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/91/194/tI/s100">“That the President shall seek to assure that no contribution to the United Nations Development Program authorized by the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended [section 2151 et seq. of this title], shall be used for projects for economic or technical assistance to the Government of Cuba, so long as Cuba is governed by the Castro regime.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Similar provisions were contained in <ref href="/us/pl/89/691/tI/s100">Pub. L. 89–691, title I, § 100</ref>, <date date="1966-10-15">Oct. 15, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1018">80 Stat. 1018</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/249/tI/s100">Pub. L. 90–249, title I, § 100</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/936">81 Stat. 936</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/581/tI/s100">Pub. L. 90–581, title I, § 100</ref>, <date date="1968-10-17">Oct. 17, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1137">82 Stat. 1137</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id8f6d26a9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id8f6d26aa-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of functions of President under this section, see Ex. Ord. No. 12163, <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 56673, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2381">section 2381 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
