<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8f7208b4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277"><num value="2277">§ 2277.</num><heading> Strategy to advance prosperity, combat corruption, strengthen democratic governance, and improve civilian security in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f7208b5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Elements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2020-12-27">December 27, 2020</date>, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a 5-year strategy to advance economic prosperity, combat corruption, strengthen democratic governance, and improve civilian security in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras and to curb irregular migration from the region.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f7208b6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Consideration</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In developing the strategy required under this section, the Secretary of State should consider the following priorities:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7208b7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Promoting economic prosperity, including by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7208b8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> supporting market-based solutions to eliminate constraints to inclusive economic growth;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7208b9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> addressing the underlying causes of poverty and inequality;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7208ba-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> responding to immediate humanitarian needs by improving humanitarian outcomes, including through access to sanitation, hygiene, and shelter, and by enabling the provision of health resources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7208bb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> supporting conservation and community resilience and strengthening community preparedness for natural disasters;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7208bc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> identifying, as appropriate, a role for relevant United States agencies and the United States private sector in supporting efforts to increase private sector investment and advance economic prosperity; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7208bd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> improving domestic resource mobilization, including by strengthening tax collection and enforcement and legal arbitration mechanisms.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7208be-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Combating corruption, including by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7208bf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> strengthening the capacity of national justice systems and attorneys generals <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002116">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002116"><num>1</num> So in original.</note> to identify and prosecute money laundering and other financial crimes and breaking up financial holdings of organized criminal syndicates, including illegally acquired lands and proceeds from illegal activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7208c0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> strengthening special prosecutorial offices and financial institutions to conduct asset forfeitures and criminal analysis, and to combat corruption, money laundering, financial crimes, extortion, and human rights crimes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7208c1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> implementing transparent, merit-based selection processes for prosecutors and judges and the development of professional and merit-based civil services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7208c2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> establishing or strengthening methods, procedures for internal and external control mechanisms for the security and police services and judiciary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7208c3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> supporting anticorruption efforts through bilateral assistance and complementary support through multilateral anticorruption mechanisms when necessary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7208c4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Advancing democratic governance, including by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7208c5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> strengthening government institutions at the local and national levels to provide services and respond to citizen needs through transparent, inclusive, and democratic processes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7208c6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> strengthening access to information laws and reforming laws that currently limit access to information;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7208c7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> building the capacity of independent media to engage in professional investigative journalism;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7208c8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> ensuring that threats and attacks on journalists, labor leaders, human rights defenders, and other members of civil society are fully investigated and perpetrators are held accountable; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7208c9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> strengthening electoral institutions and processes to ensure free, fair, and transparent elections.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7208ca-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> Improving security conditions, including by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7208cb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> implementing the Central America Regional Security Initiative;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7208cc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> increasing the professionalization of security services, including the civilian police and military units;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7208cd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> combating the illicit activities of transnational criminal organizations through support to fully vetted elements of attorneys general offices, appropriate government institutions, and security services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7208ce-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/b/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> enhancing the capacity of relevant security services and attorneys general to support counternarcotics efforts and combat human trafficking, forcible recruitment of children and youth by gangs, gender-based violence, and other illicit activities, including trafficking of wildlife, and natural resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f7208cf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In developing the strategy required under this section, the Secretary of State may consult with civil society and the private sector in the United States, El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f7208d0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Benchmarks</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The strategy required under this section shall include annual benchmarks to track the strategy’s progress in curbing irregular migration from the region to the United States and improving conditions in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras by measuring progress in key areas, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7208d1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> reducing poverty and unemployment, increasing private sector investment, responding to immediate humanitarian needs, sustainably reintegrating returnees, supporting conservation and community resilience, and addressing forced displacement in accordance with the priorities outlined in subsection (b)(1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7208d2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> strengthening national justice systems and attorneys generals,<sup>1</sup> supporting multilateral anticorruption mechanisms, identifying and prosecuting money laundering and other financial crimes, breaking up financial holdings of organized criminal syndicates, and advancing judicial integrity and investigative capacity of local authorities in accordance with the priorities outlined in subsection (b)(2);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7208d3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> strengthening government institutions at the local and national levels to provide services and respond to citizen needs through transparent, inclusive, and democratic processes, promoting human rights, building the capacity of independent media, developing the capacity of civil society to conduct oversight, affording legal protections for human rights defenders and members of civil society, and strengthening electoral institutions in accordance with priorities outlined in subsection (b)(3); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7208d4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> implementing the objectives stated under the Central America Regional Security Initiative and building the capacity of civilian security services in accordance with the priorities outlined in subsection (b)(4).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f7208d5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Public diplomacy</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The strategy required under this section shall include a public diplomacy strategy for educating citizens of the region about United States assistance and its benefits to them, and informing such citizens of the dangers of irregular migration to the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f7208d6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual progress updates</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after the submission of the strategy required under this section and annually thereafter for 4 years, the Secretary of State shall provide the appropriate congressional committees with a written description of progress made in meeting the benchmarks established in the strategy.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f7208d7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Public availability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The strategy required under this section shall be made publicly available on the website of the Department of State. If appropriate, a classified annex may be submitted to the appropriate congressional committees.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f7208d8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7208d9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7208da-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2277/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8f7208db-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dFF/tIII/s352">Pub. L. 116–260, div. FF, title III, § 352</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3127">134 Stat. 3127</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8f7208dc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8f7208dd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8f7208de-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the United States – Northern Triangle Enhanced Engagement Act, and not as part of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
