<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8f7b7e27-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h"><num value="2291h">§ 2291h.</num><heading> Reporting requirements</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f7b7e28-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> International narcotics control strategy report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than June 1 of each year, the President shall transmit to the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, a report containing the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7b7e29-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> For each country that received assistance under this part for either of the 2 preceding fiscal years, a report on the extent to which the country has—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e2a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> met the goals and objectives of the United Nations Convention Against Illicit Traffic in Narcotic Drugs and Psychotropic Substances, including action on such issues as illicit cultivation, production, distribution, sale, transport, and financing, and money laundering, asset seizure, extradition, mutual legal assistance, law enforcement and transit cooperation, precursor chemical control, and demand reduction;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e2b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> accomplished the goals described in an applicable bilateral narcotics agreement with the United States or a multilateral agreement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e2c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> taken legal and law enforcement measures to prevent and punish public corruption, especially by senior government officials, that facilitates the production, processing, or shipment of narcotic and psychotropic drugs and other controlled substances, or that discourages the investigation or prosecution of such acts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7b7e2d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7b7e2e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A description of the policies adopted, agreements concluded, and programs implemented by the Department of State in pursuit of its delegated responsibilities for international narcotics control, including appropriate information on the status of negotiations between the United States and other countries on updated extradition treaties, mutual legal assistance treaties, precursor chemical controls, money laundering, and agreements pursuant to section 2015 of the International Narcotics Act of 1986 (relating to interdiction procedures for vessels of foreign registry).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7b7e2f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Information on multilateral and bilateral strategies with respect to money laundering pursued by the Department of State, the Department of Justice, the Department of the Treasury, and other relevant United States Government agencies, either collectively or individually, to ensure the cooperation of foreign governments with respect to narcotics-related money laundering and to demonstrate that all United States Government agencies are pursuing a common strategy with respect to major money laundering countries. The report shall include specific detail to demonstrate that all United States Government agencies are pursuing a common strategy with respect to achieving international cooperation against money laundering and are pursuing a common strategy with respect to major money laundering countries, including a summary of United States objectives on a country-by-country basis.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7b7e30-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The identity of those countries which are—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e31-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> major illicit drug producing countries or major drug-transit countries as determined under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2291j/h">section 2291j(h) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e32-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> major sources of precursor chemicals used in the production of illicit narcotics; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e33-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> major money laundering countries.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7b7e34-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> In addition, for each country identified pursuant to paragraph (3),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002125">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002125"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e35-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A description of the plans, programs, and timetables adopted by such country, including efforts to meet the objectives of the United Nations Convention Against Illicit Traffic in Narcotic Drugs and Psychotropic Substances, and a discussion of the adequacy of the legal and law enforcement measures taken and the accomplishments achieved in accord with those plans.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e36-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Whether as a matter of government policy or practice, such country encourages or facilitates the illicit production or distribution of narcotic or psychotropic drugs or other controlled substances or the laundering of proceeds from illegal drug transactions; and whether any senior official of the government of such country engages in, encourages, or facilitates the illicit production or distribution of such drugs or substances, or the laundering of proceeds from illegal drug transactions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7b7e37-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> In addition, for each country identified pursuant to paragraph (3)(A) or (3)(B),<sup>1</sup> a detailed status report, with such information as can be reliably obtained, on the narcotic or psychotropic drugs or other controlled substances which are being cultivated, produced, or processed in or transported through such country, noting significant changes in conditions, such as increases or decreases in the illicit cultivation and manufacture of and traffic in such drugs and substances.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7b7e38-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> In addition, for those countries identified pursuant to paragraph (3)(C)— <sup>1</sup></chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e39-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> which countries are parties to international agreements on a method for maintaining records of transactions of an established list of precursor and essential chemicals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e3a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> which countries have established a procedure by which such records may be made available to United States law enforcement authorities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e3b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> which countries have enacted national chemical control legislation which would impose specific recordkeeping and reporting requirements for listed chemicals, establish a system of permits or declarations for imports and exports of listed chemicals, and authorize government officials to seize or suspend shipments of listed chemicals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7b7e3c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><chapeau> In addition, for those countries identified pursuant to paragraph (3)(C) the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e3d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e3e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Which countries have financial institutions engaging in currency transactions involving international narcotics trafficking proceeds that include significant amounts of United States currency or currency derived from illegal drug sales in the United States or that otherwise significantly affect the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e3f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> which countries identified pursuant to clause (i) have not reached agreement with the United States authorities on a mechanism for exchanging adequate records in connection with narcotics investigations and proceedings; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e40-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><chapeau> which countries identified pursuant to clause (ii)—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e41-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/A/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> are negotiating in good faith with the United States to establish such a record-exchange mechanism, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e42-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/A/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> have adopted laws or regulations that ensure the availability to appropriate United States Government personnel and those of other governments of adequate records in connection with narcotics investigations and proceedings.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e43-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Which countries—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e44-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> have ratified the United Nations Convention Against Illicit Traffic in Narcotic Drugs and Psychotropic Substances and are taking steps to implement that Convention and other applicable agreements and conventions such as the recommendations of the Financial Action Task Force, the policy directive of the European Community, the legislative guidelines of the Organization of American States, and other similar declarations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e45-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> have entered into bilateral agreements for the exchange of information on money-laundering with countries other than the United States.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e46-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> Findings on each country’s adoption of law and regulations considered essential to prevent narcotics-related money laundering. Such findings shall include whether a country has—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e47-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> criminalized narcotics money laundering;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e48-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> required banks and other financial institutions to know and record the identity of customers engaging in significant transactions, including the recording of large currency transactions at thresholds appropriate to that country’s economic situation;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e49-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> required banks and other financial institutions to maintain, for an adequate time, records necessary to reconstruct significant transactions through financial institutions in order to be able to respond quickly to information requests from appropriate government authorities in narcotics-related money laundering cases;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e4a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> required or allowed financial institutions to report suspicious transactions;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e4b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/C/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> established systems for identifying, tracing, freezing, seizing, and forfeiting narcotics-related assets;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e4c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/C/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> enacted laws for the sharing of seized narcotics assets with other governments;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e4d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/C/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> cooperated, when requested, with appropriate law enforcement agencies of other governments investigating financial crimes related to narcotics; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e4e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/C/viii"><num value="viii">(viii)</num><content> addressed the problem on international transportation of illegal-source currency and monetary instruments.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e4f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> Where the information is available, examples of improvements in each country related to the findings described in each of clauses (i) through (viii) of subparagraph (C) including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e50-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> actions taken by the country due to the adoption of law and regulations considered essential to prevent narcotics-related money laundering;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e51-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> enhanced enforcement actions taken by the country, such as regulatory penalties, criminal prosecutions and convictions, and asset seizures and forfeitures;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e52-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> status changes in financial crime-related evaluations by international standards-setting bodies;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e53-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/D/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> efforts to enhance the prevention of narcotics-related money laundering; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e54-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/7/D/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> if applicable, bilateral, multilateral, and regional initiatives that have been undertaken to prevent narcotics-related money laundering.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">The report shall also detail instances of refusals to cooperate with foreign governments, and any actions taken by the United States Government and any international organization to address such obstacles, including the imposition of sanctions or penalties.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7b7e55-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7b7e56-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> A separate section that contains the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e57-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/8/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> An identification of the five countries that exported the largest amount of chemical precursors used in the production of methamphetamine that significantly affected the United States during the preceding calendar year.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e58-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/8/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> An identification of the five countries that imported the largest amount of the chemicals described in clause (i) during the preceding calendar year and have the highest rate of diversion of such chemicals for use in the illicit production of methamphetamine (either in that country or in another country).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e59-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/8/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> An economic analysis of the total worldwide production of the chemicals described in clause (i) as compared to the legitimate demand for such chemicals worldwide.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7b7e5a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> The identification of countries that imported the largest amount of chemicals under subparagraph (A)(ii) shall be based on the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e5b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/8/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> An economic analysis that estimates the legitimate demand for such chemicals in such countries as compared to the actual or estimated amount of such chemicals that is imported into such countries.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e5c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/8/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The best available data and other information regarding the production of methamphetamine in such countries and the diversion of such chemicals for use in the production of methamphetamine.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7b7e5d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7b7e5e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/9/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> An assessment conducted by the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Director of National Intelligence, of the extent to which any diplomatic efforts described in section 7217(a) of the Fentanyl Sanctions Act have been successful.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7b7e5f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/9/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Each assessment required by subparagraph (A) shall include an identification of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e60-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/9/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the countries the governments of which have agreed to undertake measures to apply economic or other financial sanctions to foreign traffickers of illicit opioids and a description of those measures; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e61-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/9/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the countries the governments of which have not agreed to measures described in clause (i), and, with respect to those countries, other measures the Secretary of State recommends that the United States take to apply economic and other financial sanctions to foreign traffickers of illicit opioids.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7b7e62-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> A separate section that contains an identification of all United States Government-supported units funded by the Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs and any Bureau-funded operations by such units in which United States law enforcement personnel have been physically present.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7b7e63-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><chapeau> A separate section that contains the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e64-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/11/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> An identification of the countries, to the extent feasible, that are the most significant sources of illicit fentanyl, xylazine, and fentanyl analogues significantly affecting the United States during the preceding calendar year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e65-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/11/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A description of the extent to which each country identified pursuant to subparagraph (A) has cooperated with the United States to prevent the articles or chemicals described in subparagraph (A) from being exported from such country to the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e66-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/11/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> A description of whether each country identified pursuant to subparagraph (A) has adopted and utilizes scheduling or other procedures for illicit drugs that are similar in effect to the procedures authorized under title II <sup>1</sup> of the Controlled Substances Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s811">21 U.S.C. 811</ref> et seq.) for adding drugs and other substances to the controlled substances schedules;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e67-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/11/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> A description of whether each country identified pursuant to subparagraph (A) is following steps to prosecute individuals involved in the illicit manufacture or distribution of controlled substance analogues (as defined in section 102(32) of the Controlled Substances Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s802/32">21 U.S.C. 802(32)</ref>)); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e68-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/11/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> A description of whether each country identified pursuant to subparagraph (A) requires the registration of tableting machines and encapsulating machines or other measures similar in effect to the registration requirements set forth in part 1310 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations, and has not made good faith efforts, in the opinion of the Secretary, to improve regulation of tableting machines and encapsulating machines.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f7b7e69-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered synthetic drugs and new psychoactive substances.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e6a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/12/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered synthetic drugs</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Information that contains an assessment of the countries significantly involved in the manufacture, production, transshipment, or trafficking of covered synthetic drugs, to include the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e6b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/12/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The scale of legal domestic production and any available information on the number of manufacturers and producers of such drugs in such countries.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e6c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/12/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Information on any law enforcement assessments of the scale of illegal production of such drugs, including a description of the capacity of illegal laboratories to produce such drugs.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e6d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/12/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> The types of inputs used and a description of the primary methods of synthesis employed by illegal producers of such drugs.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e6e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/12/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> An assessment of the policies of such countries to regulate licit manufacture and interdict illicit manufacture, diversion, distribution, shipment, and trafficking of such drugs and an assessment of the effectiveness of the policies’ implementation.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e6f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/12/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">New psychoactive substances</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Information on, to the extent practicable, any policies of responding to new psychoactive substances, to include the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e70-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/12/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Which governments have articulated policies on scheduling of such substances.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e71-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/12/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Any data on impacts of such policies and other responses to such substances.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e72-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/12/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> An assessment of any policies the United States could adopt to improve its response to new psychoactive substances.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e73-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/a/12/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><content>In this paragraph, the terms “covered synthetic drug” and “new psychoactive substance” have the meaning given those terms in section 5558 of the FENTANYL Results Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f7b7e74-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual reports on assistance</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id8f7b7e75-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">At the time that the report required by subsection (a) is submitted each year, the Secretary of State, in consultation with appropriate United States Government agencies, shall report to the appropriate committees of the Congress on the assistance provided or proposed to be provided by the United States Government during the preceding fiscal year, the current fiscal year, and the next fiscal year to support international efforts to combat illicit narcotics production or trafficking.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id8f7b7e76-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Information to be included</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each report pursuant to this subsection shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e77-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> specify the amount and nature of the assistance provided or to be provided;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e78-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> include, for each country identified in subsection (a)(3)(A), information from the Drug Enforcement Administration, the Customs Service, and the Coast Guard describing in detail—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e79-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/b/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the assistance provided or to be provided to such country by that agency, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8f7b7e7a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/b/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the assistance provided or to be provided to that agency by such country,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">with respect to narcotic control efforts during the preceding fiscal year, the current fiscal year, and the next fiscal year; and</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f7b7e7b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2291h/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> list all transfers, which were made by the United States Government during the preceding fiscal year, to a foreign country for narcotics control purposes of any property seized by or otherwise forfeited to the United States Government in connection with narcotics-related activity, including an estimate of the fair market value and physical condition of each item of property transferred.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8f7b7e7c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, pt. I, § 489, as added <ref href="/us/pl/102/583/s5/a">Pub. L. 102–583, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-11-02">Nov. 2, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4917">106 Stat. 4917</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/447/tI/s101/f/1">Pub. L. 103–447, title I, § 101(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4692">108 Stat. 4692</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/tI/s1112/c">Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1112(c)</ref>, <date date="1995-12-21">Dec. 21, 1995</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/109/724">109 Stat. 724</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/177/tVII/s722/a">Pub. L. 109–177, title VII, § 722(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/268">120 Stat. 268</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dF/tLXXII/s7217/b">Pub. L. 116–92, div. F, title LXXII, § 7217(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2269">133 Stat. 2269</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dE/tLI/s5102/b">Pub. L. 117–81, div. E, title LI, § 5102(b)</ref>, div. F, title LXVI, § 6610(c), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/2344">135 Stat. 2344</ref>, 2447; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dE/tLV/s5555/a">Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LV, § 5555(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3342">136 Stat. 3342</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dG/tLXXVIII/s7808">Pub. L. 118–159, div. G, title LXXVIII, § 7808</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2562">138 Stat. 2562</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dH/tLXXXIII/s8312">Pub. L. 119–60, div. H, title LXXXIII, § 8312</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1854">139 Stat. 1854</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8f7b7e7d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8f7b7e7e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8f7b7e7f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 2015 of the International Narcotics Act of 1986, referred to in subsec. (a)(2)(A), probably means section 2015 of the International Narcotics Control Act of 1986, <ref href="/us/pl/99/570">Pub. L. 99–570</ref>, which was set out as a note under section 1902 of the former Appendix to Title 46, Shipping, prior to being repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/103/447/tI/s103/c">Pub. L. 103–447, title I, § 103(c)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4694">108 Stat. 4694</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Paragraph (3), referred to in subsec. (a)(4) to (6), means par. (3) of subsec. (a), which was amended by <ref href="/us/pl/103/447/s101/f/1/B/ii">Pub. L. 103–447, § 101(f)(1)(B)(ii)</ref>, by striking out subpar. (B) relating to sources of narcotics and psychotropic drugs and other controlled substances and redesignating subpars. (C) and (D) as (B) and (C), respectively. See 1994 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 7217(a) of the Fentanyl Sanctions Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(9)(A), is <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s7217/a">section 7217(a) of Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, div. F, title LXXII, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2269">133 Stat. 2269</ref>, which is not classified to the Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Controlled Substances Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(11)(C), is title II of <ref href="/us/pl/91/513">Pub. L. 91–513</ref>, <date date="1970-10-27">Oct. 27, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1242">84 Stat. 1242</ref>, which is classified principally to subchapter I (§ 801 et seq.) of chapter 13 of Title 21, Food and Drugs. Title II of <ref href="/us/pl/91/513">Pub. L. 91–513</ref> does not itself contain a title II, but it does contain a part B, with provisions relating to controlled substance schedules, which is classified generally to part B (§ 811 et seq.) of subchapter I of chapter 13 of Title 21. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s801">section 801 of Title 21</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 5558 of the FENTANYL Results Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(12)(C), is section 5558 of subtitle C of title LV of div. E of <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, which is set out as a note under section 2291<i>l</i> of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id8f7b7e80-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 2291h, <ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, pt. I, § 489, as added <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tIV/s4507">Pub. L. 100–690, title IV, § 4507</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4286">102 Stat. 4286</ref>, related to permissible uses of aircraft and other equipment, prior to amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/583/s4/f/2">Pub. L. 102–583, § 4(f)(2)</ref>, <date date="1992-11-02">Nov. 2, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4917">106 Stat. 4917</ref>, which also transferred subsecs. (a) and (b) to section 2291c(b) and (c) of this title, respectively, and repealed the designation, heading, and subsecs. (c) and (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8f7b7e81-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s8312/1">Pub. L. 119–60, § 8312(1)</ref>, substituted “June 1” for “March 1” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s8312/2">Pub. L. 119–60, § 8312(2)</ref>, substituted “paragraph (3)(C)” for “paragraph (3)(D)” in introductory provisions and added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(8)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s8312/3">Pub. L. 119–60, § 8312(3)</ref>, substituted “chemical precursors used in the production of methamphetamine that significantly affected the United States” for “pseudoephedrine, ephedrine, and phenylpropanolamine (including the salts, optical isomers, or salts of optical isomers of such chemicals, and also including any products or substances containing such chemicals)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (a)(11)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s7808/1">Pub. L. 118–159, § 7808(1)</ref>, inserted “, xylazine,” after “illicit fentanyl”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(11)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s7808/2">Pub. L. 118–159, § 7808(2)</ref>, inserted third closing parenthesis before “; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (a)(10), (11). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s5555/a/1">Pub. L. 117–263, § 5555(a)(1)</ref>, redesignated second par. (10), relating to separate section that contains identification of the countries that are the most significant sources of illicit fentanyl and fentanyl analogues, as (11).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(12). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s5555/a/2">Pub. L. 117–263, § 5555(a)(2)</ref>, added par. (12).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (a)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s6610/c">Pub. L. 117–81, § 6610(c)</ref>, added par. (10) relating to separate section that contains identification of the countries that are the most significant sources of illicit fentanyl and fentanyl analogues.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s5102/b">Pub. L. 117–81, § 5102(b)</ref>, added par. (10) relating to separate section that contains an identification of all United States Government-supported units funded by the Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (a)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Pub. L. 116–92</ref> added par. (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (a)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/109/177">Pub. L. 109–177</ref> added par. (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1995—<ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s1112/c/1">Pub. L. 104–66, § 1112(c)(1)</ref>, struck out “for fiscal year 1995” after “Reporting requirements” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s1112/c/2">Pub. L. 104–66, § 1112(c)(2)</ref>, struck out heading and text of subsec. (c). Text read as follows: “This section applies only during fiscal year 1995. <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2291i">Section 2291i of this title</ref> does not apply during that fiscal year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/447/s101/f/1/A">Pub. L. 103–447, § 101(f)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “for fiscal year 1995” for “for fiscal years 1993 and 1994” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/447/s101/f/1/B/i">Pub. L. 103–447, § 101(f)(1)(B)(i)</ref>, substituted “March 1” for “April 1” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3)(B) to (D). <ref href="/us/pl/103/447/s101/f/1/B/ii">Pub. L. 103–447, § 101(f)(1)(B)(ii)</ref>, redesignated subpars. (C) and (D) as (B) and (C), respectively, and struck out former subpar. (B) which read as follows: “the significant direct or indirect sources of narcotics and psychotropic drugs and other controlled substances significantly affecting the United States;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/447/s101/f/1/D">Pub. L. 103–447, § 101(f)(1)(D)</ref>, (E), redesignated subsec. (d) as (c) and amended heading and text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “This section applies only during fiscal years 1993 and 1994. <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2291i">Section 2291i of this title</ref> does not apply during those fiscal years.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/447/s101/f/1/C">Pub. L. 103–447, § 101(f)(1)(C)</ref>, struck out heading and text of subsec. (c). Text read as follows: “As used in this section—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) the term ‘precursor chemical’ has the same meaning as the term ‘listed chemical’ has under paragraph (33) of <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s802">section 802 of title 21</ref>; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) the term ‘major money laundering country’ means a country whose financial institutions engage in currency transactions involving significant amounts of proceeds from international narcotics trafficking.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/103/447/s101/f/1/D">Pub. L. 103–447, § 101(f)(1)(D)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (d) as (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8f7b7e82-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id8f7b7e83-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s6610/c">section 6610(c) of Pub. L. 117–81</ref> effective 90 days after <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s6610/e">section 6610(e) of Pub. L. 117–81</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2291">section 2291 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8f7b7e84-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Rule of Construction</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Nothing in subtitle C (§§ 5551–5558) of title LV of div. E of <ref href="/us/pl/117/263">Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, or the amendments made by that subtitle, to be construed as affecting the prioritization of extradition requests, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s5557">section 5557 of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, set out as a note under section 2291<i>l</i> of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id8f7b7e85-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the United States Customs Service of the Department of the Treasury, including functions of the Secretary of the Treasury relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 203(1), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>. For establishment of U.S. Customs and Border Protection in the Department of Homeland Security, treated as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref> as of <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>, as amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/114/125">Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/114/125/s802/b">section 802(b) of Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8f7b7e86-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plan To Address Diversion of Precursor Chemicals</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/177/tVII/s722/d">Pub. L. 109–177, title VII, § 722(d)</ref>, <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/269">120 Stat. 269</ref>, required the Secretary of State, not later than 180 days after the date on which the President transmits the report required by subsec. (a) of this section, to submit to Congress a comprehensive plan to address the diversion of the chemicals described in subsec. (a)(8)(A)(i) of this section to the illicit production of methamphetamine for each identified country for which the President has not submitted a certification under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2291j/b">section 2291j(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8f7b7e87-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Statutory References to Annual Reports, Certifications, and Definitions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/583/s6/a">Pub. L. 102–583, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="1992-11-02">Nov. 2, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/4932">106 Stat. 4932</ref>, provided that after <date date="1994-09-30">Sept. 30, 1994</date>, any reference in any provision of law to section 2291h or 2291j of this title would be deemed a reference to the corresponding provision of section 2291i or 2291k of this title, respectively, unless the context required otherwise; any reference in any provision of law enacted before <date date="1992-11-02">Nov. 2, 1992</date>, to section 2291(e) or (i) of this title be deemed a reference to section 2291h or 2291(e) of this title, respectively; and that any reference in any provision of law enacted before <date date="1992-11-02">Nov. 2, 1992</date>, to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2291/h">section 2291(h) of this title</ref> be deemed, as of <date date="1992-10-01">Oct. 1, 1992</date>, to be a reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2291j">section 2291j of this title</ref>, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/103/447/tI/s103/a">Pub. L. 103–447, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4693">108 Stat. 4693</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id8f7b7e88-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id8f7b7e89-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of functions of President under this section, see Ex. Ord. No. 12163, <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 56673, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2381">section 2381 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
