<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8f89d675-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314"><num value="2314">§ 2314.</num><heading> Furnishing of defense articles or related training or other defense service on grant basis</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f89d676-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditions of eligibility</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In addition to such other provisions as the President may require, no defense articles or related training or other defense service shall be furnished to any country on a grant basis unless it shall have agreed that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f89d677-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> it will not, without the consent of the President—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f89d678-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> permit any use of such articles or related training or other defense service by anyone not an officer, employee, or agent of that country,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f89d679-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> transfer, or permit any officer, employee, or agent of that country to transfer such articles or related training or other defense service by gift, sale, or otherwise, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f89d67a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> use or permit the use of such articles or related training or other defense service for purposes other than those for which furnished;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f89d67b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> it will maintain the security of such articles or related training or other defense service, and will provide substantially the same degree of security protection afforded to such articles or related training or other defense service by the United States Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f89d67c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> it will, as the President may require, permit continuous observation and review by, and furnish necessary information to, representatives of the United States Government with regard to the use of such articles or related training or other defense service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f89d67d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> unless the President consents to other disposition, it will return to the United States Government for such use or disposition as the President considers in the best interests of the United States, such articles or related training or other defense service which are no longer needed for the purposes for which furnished.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f89d67e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on amount; exceptions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No defense articles shall be furnished on a grant basis to any country at a cost in excess of $3,000,000 in any fiscal year unless the President determines—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f89d67f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> that such country conforms to the purposes and principles of the Charter of the United Nations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f89d680-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> that such defense articles will be utilized by such country for the maintenance of its own defensive strength, or the defensive strength of the free world;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f89d681-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> that such country is taking all reasonable measures, consistent with its political and economic stability, which may be needed to develop its defense capacities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f89d682-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> that the increased ability of such country to defend itself is important to the security of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f89d683-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Reduction and termination of grants to countries able to maintain adequate military forces without undue economic strain</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall regularly reduce and, with such deliberate speed as orderly procedure and other relevant considerations, including prior commitments, will permit, shall terminate all further grants of military equipment and supplies to any country having sufficient wealth to enable it, in the judgment of the President, to maintain and equip its own military forces at adequate strength, without undue burden to its economy.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f89d684-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination of assistance; report of violation by President; conditions for reinstatement</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f89d685-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Assistance and deliveries of assistance under this part to any country shall be terminated as hereinafter provided, if such country uses defense articles or defense services furnished under this chapter, the Mutual Security Act of 1954, or any predecessor Foreign Assistance Act, in substantial violation (either in terms of quantities or in terms of the gravity of the consequences regardless of the quantities involved) of any agreement entered into pursuant to any such Act (A) by using such articles or services for a purpose not authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2302">section 2302 of this title</ref> or, if such agreement provides that such articles or services may only be used for purposes more limited than those authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2302">section 2302 of this title</ref>, for a purpose not authorized under such agreement; (B) by transferring such articles or services to, or permitting any use of such articles or services by, anyone not an officer, employee, or agent of the recipient country without the consent of the President; or (C) by failing to maintain the security of such articles or services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f89d686-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f89d687-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Assistance and deliveries of assistance shall be terminated pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection if the President so determines and so states in writing to the Congress, or if the Congress so finds by joint resolution.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f89d688-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The President shall report to the Congress promptly upon the receipt of information that a violation described in paragraph (1) of this subsection may have occurred.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f89d689-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Assistance to a country shall remain terminated in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection until such time as—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f89d68a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the President determines that the violation has ceased; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f89d68b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the country concerned has given assurances satisfactory to the President that such violation will not recur.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f89d68c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The authority contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2364/a">section 2364(a) of this title</ref> may not be used to waive the provisions of this section with respect to further assistance under this part.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f89d68d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Consent by President to transfer</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In considering a request for approval of any transfer of any weapon, weapons system, munitions, aircraft, military boat, military vessel, or other implement of war to another country, the President shall not give his consent under subsection (a)(1) or (a)(4) to the transfer unless the United States itself would transfer the defense article under consideration to that country. In addition, the President shall not give his consent under subsection (a)(1) or (a)(4) to the transfer of any significant defense articles on the United States Munitions List unless the foreign country requesting consent to transfer agrees to demilitarize such defense articles prior to transfer, or the proposed recipient foreign country provides a commitment in writing to the United States Government that it will not transfer such defense articles, if not demilitarized, to any other foreign country or person without first obtaining the consent of the President.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f89d68e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Disposition of defense articles furnished on a grant basis; net proceeds to be paid over to the United States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Effective <date date="1974-07-01">July 1, 1974</date>, no defense article shall be furnished to any country on a grant basis unless such country shall have agreed that the net proceeds of sale received by such country in disposing of any weapon, weapons system, munition, aircraft, military boat, military vessel, or other implement of war received under this part will be paid to the United States Government and shall be available to pay all official costs of the United States Government payable in the currency of that country, including all costs relating to the financing of international educational and cultural exchange activities in which that country participates under the programs authorized by the Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2451">22 U.S.C. 2451</ref> et seq.]. In the case of items which were delivered prior to 1985, the President may waive the requirement that such net proceeds be paid to the United States Government if he determines that to do so is in the national interest of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f89d68f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Discrimination on basis of race, religion, national origin, or sex prohibited</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f89d690-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> It is the policy of the United States that no assistance under this part should be furnished to any foreign country, the laws, regulations, official policies, or governmental practices of which prevent any United States person (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7701/a/30">section 7701(a)(30) of title 26</ref>) from participating in the furnishing of defense articles or defense services under this part on the basis of race, religion, national origin, or sex.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f89d691-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f89d692-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/g/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> No agency performing functions under this part shall, in employing or assigning personnel to participate in the performance of any such function, whether in the United States or abroad, take into account the exclusionary policies or practices of any foreign government where such policies or practices are based upon race, religion, national origin, or sex.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f89d693-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/g/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Each contract entered into by any such agency for the performance of any function under this part shall contain a provision to the effect that no person, partnership, corporation, or other entity performing functions pursuant to such contract, shall, in employing or assigning personnel to participate in the performance of any such function, whether in the United States or abroad, take into account the exclusionary policies or practices of any foreign government where such policies or practices are based upon race, religion, national origin, or sex.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f89d694-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The President shall promptly transmit reports to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the chairman of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate concerning any transaction in which any United States person (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7701/a/30">section 7701(a)(30) of title 26</ref>) is prevented by a foreign government on the basis of race, religion, national origin, or sex, from participating in the furnishing of assistance under this part, or education and training under part V of this subchapter, to any foreign country. Such reports shall include (A) a description of the facts and circumstances of any such discrimination, (B) the response thereto on the part of the United States or any agency or employee thereof, and (C) the result of such response, if any.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f89d695-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f89d696-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/g/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Upon the request of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate or the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, the President shall, within 60 days after receipt of such request, transmit to both such committees a statement, prepared with the assistance of the Assistant Secretary of State for Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor, with respect to the country designated in such request, setting forth—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f89d697-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/g/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> all the available information about the exclusionary policies or practices of the government of such country when such policies or practices are based upon race, religion, national origin, or sex and prevent any such person from participating in a transaction involving the furnishing of any assistance under this part or any education and training under part V of this subchapter;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f89d698-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/g/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the response of the United States thereto and the results of such response;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f89d699-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/g/4/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><chapeau> whether, in the opinion of the President, notwithstanding any such policies or practices—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f89d69a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/g/4/A/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> extraordinary circumstances exist which necessitate a continuation of such assistance or education and training transaction, and, if so, a description of such circumstances and the extent to which such assistance or education and training transaction should be continued (subject to such conditions as Congress may impose under this section), and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8f89d69b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/g/4/A/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> on all the facts it is in the national interest of the United States to continue such assistance or education and training transaction; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f89d69c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/g/4/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> such other information as such committee may request.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f89d69d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/g/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> In the event a statement with respect to an assistance or training transaction is requested pursuant to subparagraph (A) of this paragraph but is not transmitted in accordance therewith within 60 days after receipt of such request, such assistance or training transaction shall be suspended unless and until such statement is transmitted.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f89d69e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/g/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f89d69f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/g/4/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> In the event a statement with respect to an assistance or training transaction is transmitted under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, the Congress may at any time thereafter adopt a joint resolution terminating or restricting such assistance or training transaction.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f89d6a0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/g/4/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Any such resolution shall be considered in the Senate in accordance with the provisions of section 601(b) of the International Security Assistance and Arms Export Control Act of 1976.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f89d6a1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2314/g/4/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> The term “certification”, as used in section 601 of such Act, means, for the purposes of this paragraph, a statement transmitted under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8f89d6a2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, pt. II, § 505, formerly § 506, <date date="1961-09-04">Sept. 4, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/436">75 Stat. 436</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/565">Pub. L. 87–565</ref>, pt. II, § 201(a), <date date="1962-08-01">Aug. 1, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/259">76 Stat. 259</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/583">Pub. L. 89–583</ref>, pt. II, § 201(b), <date date="1966-09-19">Sept. 19, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/803">80 Stat. 803</ref>; renumbered § 505, <ref href="/us/pl/90/137">Pub. L. 90–137</ref>, pt. II, § 201(e), <date date="1967-11-14">Nov. 14, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/456">81 Stat. 456</ref> and amended <ref href="/us/pl/92/226">Pub. L. 92–226</ref>, pt. II, § 201(b), (c), <date date="1972-02-07">Feb. 7, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/25">86 Stat. 25</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/189/s12/b/3">Pub. L. 93–189, § 12(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1973-12-17">Dec. 17, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/721">87 Stat. 721</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/329/tII">Pub. L. 94–329, title II</ref>, §§ 203(b), 204(b)(2), title III, §§ 302(a), 304(a), <date date="1976-06-30">June 30, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/735">90 Stat. 735</ref>, 736, 751, 754; <ref href="/us/pl/95/105/tI/s109/a/4">Pub. L. 95–105, title I, § 109(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-17">Aug. 17, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/846">91 Stat. 846</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/83/tI/s123/b">Pub. L. 99–83, title I, § 123(b)</ref>, <date date="1985-08-08">Aug. 8, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/205">99 Stat. 205</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/513/tIII">Pub. L. 101–513, title III</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1998">104 Stat. 1998</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/tI/s162/e/2">Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 162(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/405">108 Stat. 405</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/437/s9/a/6">Pub. L. 103–437, § 9(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4588">108 Stat. 4588</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8f89d6a3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8f89d6a4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8f89d6a5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (d)(1), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, <date date="1961-09-04">Sept. 4, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/424">75 Stat. 424</ref>, known as the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">section 2151 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Mutual Security Act of 1954, referred to in subsec. (d)(1), is <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-26/ch937">act Aug. 26, 1954, ch. 937</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/832">68 Stat. 832</ref>, as amended by acts <ref href="/us/act/1955-07-08/ch301">July 8, 1955, ch. 301</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/283">69 Stat. 283</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1956-07-18/ch627">July 18, 1956, ch. 627</ref>, §§ 2–11, <ref href="/us/stat/70/555">70 Stat. 555</ref>; <date date="1957-08-14">Aug. 14, 1957</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/85/141">Pub. L. 85–141</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/71/355">71 Stat. 355</ref>; <date date="1958-06-30">June 30, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/85/477">Pub. L. 85–477</ref>, ch. 1, §§ 101–103, ch. II, §§ 201–205, ch. III, § 301, ch. IV, § 401, ch. V, § 501, <ref href="/us/stat/72/261">72 Stat. 261</ref>; <date date="1959-07-24">July 24, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/86/108/s2">Pub. L. 86–108, § 2</ref>, ch. 1, § 101, ch. II, §§ 201–205(a)–(i), (k)–(n), ch. III, § 301, ch. IV, § 401(a)–(k), (m), <ref href="/us/stat/73/246">73 Stat. 246</ref>; <date date="1960-05-14">May 14, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/86/472">Pub. L. 86–472</ref>, ch. I to V, <ref href="/us/stat/74/134">74 Stat. 134</ref>, which was principally classified to chapter 24 (§ 1750 et seq.) of this title and which was repealed by <ref href="/us/act/1956-07-18/ch627/s8/m">act July 18, 1956, ch. 627, § 8(m)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/559">70 Stat. 559</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/85/141">Pub. L. 85–141</ref>, §§ 2(e) 3, 4(b), 11(d), <date date="1957-08-14">Aug. 14, 1957</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/71/356">71 Stat. 356</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/86/108">Pub. L. 86–108</ref>, ch. II, §§ 205(j), ch. IV, 401(1), <date date="1959-07-24">July 24, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/250">73 Stat. 250</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/86/472">Pub. L. 86–472</ref>, ch. II, §§ 203(d), 204(k), <date date="1960-05-14">May 14, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/138">74 Stat. 138</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, pt. III, § 642(a)(2), <date date="1961-09-04">Sept. 4, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/460">75 Stat. 460</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/94/329/tII/s212/b/1">Pub. L. 94–329, title II, § 212(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1976-06-30">June 30, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/745">90 Stat. 745</ref>, <ref href="/us/pl/104/127/tII/s228">Pub. L. 104–127, title II, § 228</ref>, <date date="1996-04-04">Apr. 4, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/963">110 Stat. 963</ref>, except for sections 1754, 1783, 1796, 1853, 1928, and 1937 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1754">section 1754 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961, referred to in subsec. (f), is <ref href="/us/pl/87/256">Pub. L. 87–256</ref>, <date date="1961-09-21">Sept. 21, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/5/527">5 Stat. 527</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 33 (§ 2451 et. seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2451">section 2451 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 601 of the International Security Assistance and Arms Export Control Act of 1976, referred to in subsec. (g)(4)(C)(ii), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/329/s601">section 601 of Pub. L. 94–329</ref>, which was not classified to the Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8f89d6a6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (g)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/103/437">Pub. L. 103–437</ref> substituted “Foreign Affairs” for “International Relations” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref> substituted “Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor” for “Human Rights and Humanitarian Affairs” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/101/513">Pub. L. 101–513</ref> substituted “1985” for “1975” in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (g)(1), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> substituted “Internal Revenue Code of 1986” for “Internal Revenue Code of 1954”, which for purposes of codification was translated as “title 26” thus requiring no change in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/99/83">Pub. L. 99–83</ref> inserted provisions relating to waiver for items delivered prior to 1975.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (g)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/95/105">Pub. L. 95–105</ref> substituted “Assistant Secretary of State” for “Coordinator” in provisions preceding cl. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/329/s203/b">Pub. L. 94–329, § 203(b)</ref>, inserted “or related training or other defense service” after “articles” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/94/329/s304/a">Pub. L. 94–329, § 304(a)</ref>, provided that either the President, by so stating in a writing to Congress, or Congress, by joint resolution, terminate assistance upon determining a violation, specified conditions for reinstatement of assistance, and denied the President the power, where a violation has been determined, of granting assistance on the basis of national security.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/94/329/s204/b/2">Pub. L. 94–329, § 204(b)(2)</ref>, struck out provisions relating to the President’s notification of his consent to transfer war implements to another country, in writing, to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate indicating his justification for the transfer and the particular war implement transferred.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/94/329">Pub. L. 94–329</ref> added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—Subsecs. (e), (f). <ref href="/us/pl/93/189">Pub. L. 93–189</ref> added subsecs. (e) and (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1972—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/92/226/s201/b">Pub. L. 92–226, § 201(b)</ref>, substituted “or” for “and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/92/226/s201/c">Pub. L. 92–226, § 201(c)</ref>, repealed provisions respecting conditions of eligibility requiring agreements for use of foreign currencies from sale of surplus commodities for common defense including internal security.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/89/583">Pub. L. 89–583</ref> added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/87/565">Pub. L. 87–565</ref> added subsecs. (c) and (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8f89d6a7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id8f89d6a8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref> applicable with respect to officials, offices, and bureaus of Department of State when executive orders, regulations, or departmental directives implementing the amendments by sections 161 and 162 of <ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref> become effective, or 90 days after <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, whichever comes earlier, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s161/b">section 161(b) of Pub. L. 103–236</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2651a">section 2651a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id8f89d6a9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1985 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/83">Pub. L. 99–83</ref> effective <date date="1985-10-01">Oct. 1, 1985</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/83/s1301">section 1301 of Pub. L. 99–83</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151–1">section 2151–1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id8f89d6aa-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/94/329/tII/s203/b">Pub. L. 94–329, title II, § 203(b)</ref>, <date date="1976-06-30">June 30, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/735">90 Stat. 735</ref>, provided that the amendment made by that section is effective <date date="1976-07-01">July 1, 1976</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id8f89d6ab-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id8f89d6ac-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of functions of President under this section, see Ex. Ord. No. 12163, <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 56673, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2381">section 2381 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
