<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8f8e9117-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2321i"><num value="2321i">§ 2321i.</num><heading> Overseas management of assistance and sales programs</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f8e9118-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2321i/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Assignment of military personnel for performance of enumerated functions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to carry out his responsibilities for the management of international security assistance programs conducted under this part, part V of this subchapter, and the Arms Export Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.], the President may assign members of the Armed Forces of the United States to a foreign country to perform one or more of the following functions:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f8e9119-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2321i/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> equipment and services case management;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f8e911a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2321i/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> training management;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f8e911b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2321i/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> program monitoring;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f8e911c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2321i/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> evaluation and planning of the host government’s military capabilities and requirements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f8e911d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2321i/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> administrative support;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f8e911e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2321i/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> promoting rationalization, standardization, interoperability, and other defense cooperation measures; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f8e911f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2321i/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> liaison functions exclusive of advisory and training assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f8e9120-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2321i/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Furnishing of advisory and training assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0"> Advisory and training assistance conducted by military personnel assigned under this section shall be kept to an absolute minimum. It is the sense of the Congress that advising and training assistance in countries to which military personnel are assigned under this section shall be provided primarily by other personnel who are not assigned under this section and who are detailed for limited periods to perform specific tasks.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f8e9121-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2321i/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Number of personnel assigned; waiver; procedures applicable</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f8e9122-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2321i/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The number of members of the Armed Forces assigned to a foreign country under this section may not exceed six unless specifically authorized by the Congress. The president may waive this limitation if he determines and reports to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, 30 days prior to the introduction of the additional military personnel, that United States national interests require that more than six members of the Armed Forces be assigned under this section to carry out international security assistance programs in a country not specified in this paragraph. Pakistan, Tunisia, El Salvador, Honduras, Colombia, Indonesia, the Republic of Korea, the Philippines, Thailand, Egypt, Jordan, Morocco, Saudi Arabia, Greece, Portugal, Spain, and Turkey are authorized to have military personnel strengths larger than six under this section to carry out international security assistance programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f8e9123-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2321i/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The total number of members of the Armed Forces assigned under this section to a foreign country in a fiscal year may not exceed the number justified to the Congress for that country in the congressional presentation materials for that fiscal year, unless the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives are notified 30 days in advance of the introduction of the additional military personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f8e9124-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2321i/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Costs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0"> Effective <date date="1989-10-01">October 1, 1989</date>, the entire costs (excluding salaries of the United States military personnel other than the Coast Guard) of overseas management of international security assistance programs under this section shall be charged to or reimbursed from funds made available to carry out this part or the Arms Export Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.], other than any such costs which are either paid directly for such defense services under section 21(a) of the Arms Export Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2761/a">22 U.S.C. 2761(a)</ref>] or reimbursed from charges for services collected from foreign governments pursuant to section 21(e) [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2761/e">22 U.S.C. 2761(e)</ref>] and section 43(b) [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2792/b">22 U.S.C. 2792(b)</ref>] of that Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f8e9125-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2321i/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Direction and supervision of assigned personnel</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0"> Members of the Armed Forces assigned to a foreign country under this section shall serve under the direction and supervision of the Chief of the United States Diplomatic Mission to that country.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f8e9126-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2321i/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Presidential directive respecting purchase by foreign country of United States-made military equipment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0"> The President shall continue to instruct United States diplomatic and military personnel in the United States missions abroad that they should not encourage, promote, or influence the purchase by any foreign country of United States-made military equipment, unless they are specifically instructed to do so by an appropriate official of the executive branch.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8f8e9127-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, pt. II, § 515, as added <ref href="/us/pl/93/559/s16">Pub. L. 93–559, § 16</ref>, <date date="1974-12-30">Dec. 30, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1799">88 Stat. 1799</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/94/329/tI/s104">Pub. L. 94–329, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1976-06-30">June 30, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/731">90 Stat. 731</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/92/s7/a">Pub. L. 95–92, § 7(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-04">Aug. 4, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/615">91 Stat. 615</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/384/s9">Pub. L. 95–384, § 9</ref>, <date date="1978-09-26">Sept. 26, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/732">92 Stat. 732</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/92/s7">Pub. L. 96–92, § 7</ref>, <date date="1979-10-29">Oct. 29, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/703">93 Stat. 703</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/533/tI/s114">Pub. L. 96–533, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="1980-12-16">Dec. 16, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/3139">94 Stat. 3139</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/113/tI/s112">Pub. L. 97–113, title I, § 112</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1527">95 Stat. 1527</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/83/tI/s125">Pub. L. 99–83, title I, § 125</ref>, <date date="1985-08-08">Aug. 8, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/205">99 Stat. 205</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tIV/s4305/a">Pub. L. 100–690, title IV, § 4305(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4273">102 Stat. 4273</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/165/tIX/s9104/a">Pub. L. 101–165, title IX, § 9104(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1152">103 Stat. 1152</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/167/tIII">Pub. L. 101–167, title III</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1213">103 Stat. 1213</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/391/tV/s556/c">Pub. L. 102–391, title V, § 556(c)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1675">106 Stat. 1675</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/164/tI/s143">Pub. L. 104–164, title I, § 143</ref>, <date date="1996-07-21">July 21, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1434">110 Stat. 1434</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8f8e9128-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8f8e9129-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8f8e912a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Arms Export Control Act, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (d), is <ref href="/us/pl/90/629">Pub. L. 90–629</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1320">82 Stat. 1320</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 39 (§ 2751 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8f8e912b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/104/164">Pub. L. 104–164</ref> struck out “among members of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization and with the Armed Forces of Japan, Australia, and New Zealand” after “defense cooperation measures”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/102/391">Pub. L. 102–391</ref>, which directed the substitution of “(excluding salaries of the United States military personnel other than the Coast Guard)” for “(excluding salaries of the United States military personnel)”, was executed by making the substitution for “(excluding salaries of United States military personnel)”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/167">Pub. L. 101–167</ref> inserted “or the Arms Export Control Act” after “this part”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/165">Pub. L. 101–165</ref> changed effective date from <date date="1982-10-01">Oct. 1, 1982</date>, to <date date="1989-10-01">Oct. 1, 1989</date>, and provided that costs would exclude rather than include salaries of U.S. military personnel.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690">Pub. L. 100–690</ref> inserted “Colombia,” after “Honduras,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/83">Pub. L. 99–83</ref> substituted “Pakistan, Tunisia, El Salvador, Honduras” for “For the fiscal year 1982 and the fiscal year 1983”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"> 1981—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/113">Pub. L. 97–113</ref> substituted provision authorizing the President to assign members of the Armed Forces of the United States to a foreign country to perform one or more enumerated functions for provision requiring specific Congressional authorization for military assistance groups, etc., to operate in a foreign country, with exception of regular units of the Armed Forces of the United States engaged in routine functions designed to bring about standardization of military operation and procedures between United States forces and defense treaty allies.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/97/113">Pub. L. 97–113</ref> substituted provision directing that advisory and training assistance conducted by military personnel assigned under this section be kept to an absolute minimum for provision authorizing the President to assign military personnel under international security programs to Portugal, Spain, Jordan, the Philippines, the Republic of Korea, Panama, Greece, Turkey, Indonesia, Thailand, Morocco, Egypt, and Saudi Arabia to perform logistics management, transportation, fiscal management, and contract administration of country programs, designated the maximum number assignable, and provided for reimbursement from Saudi Arabia. See subsec. (a) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/113">Pub. L. 97–113</ref> substituted provision designating the maximum number of personnel assignable, waiver of this limitation, and the procedures applicable for provision relating to assignment of military personnel to countries not specified in former subsec. (b) of this section for performance of accounting and other management functions, the maximum number assignable, and an exception to that number if the Chief of the Diplomatic Mission so requests.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/113">Pub. L. 97–113</ref> substituted provision directing that, effective <date date="1982-10-01">Oct. 1, 1982</date>, the entire costs of overseas management of international security assistance programs be charged or reimbursed from funds made available to carry out this part, other than costs paid directly for defense services under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2761/a">section 2761(a) of this title</ref> or reimbursed from charges for services collected from foreign governments pursuant to sections 2761(e) and 2792(b) of this title, for provision that the maximum number of members of the Armed Forces assignable for fiscal year 1979 to all countries not exceed 790.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/97/113">Pub. L. 97–113</ref> substituted “under this section” for “under subsection (b) or (c) of this section” and “to that country” for “in that country”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/97/113">Pub. L. 97–113</ref> redesignated subsec. (h) as (f). Former subsec. (f), relating to performance of management functions by defense attaché’s if that President determined it was the most economic and efficient means of performing those functions, was struck out.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/97/113">Pub. L. 97–113</ref> struck out subsec. (g) which provided that the entire cost of overseas management of international security assistance programs under this section be charged or reimbursed from funds made available to carry out this part, including costs reimbursed from charges for services collected from foreign governments pursuant to sections 2761(e) and 2792(b) of this title, and that the prohibition of former subsec. (a) of this section and the numerical limitations of former subsecs. (b), (c), and (d) of this section not apply to Armed Forces members performing services for specific purposes and for fixed periods of time on a fully reimbursable basis under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2761/a">section 2761(a) of this title</ref>. See subsec. (d) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/97/113">Pub. L. 97–113</ref> redesignated subsec. (h) as (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/96/533/s114/1">Pub. L. 96–533, § 114(1)</ref>, substituted “fiscal year 1981” for “fiscal year 1980”, substituted “Portugal, Spain, Jordan, the Philippines,” for “the countries specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2312/a">section 2312(a) of this title</ref> and in”, authorized assignment of military personnel for programs in Egypt, and deleted from the list of countries eligible for such programs Iran and Kuwait.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/96/533/s114/2">Pub. L. 96–533, § 114(2)</ref>, substituted “assigned to Saudi Arabia” for “assigned to Iran, Kuwait, and Saudi Arabia”, “assigned to such country” for “assigned to such countries” and “assigned to such country exceeds” for “assigned to each such country exceeds”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/96/533/s114/3">Pub. L. 96–533, § 114(3)</ref>, substituted “may not exceed six more than the number of defense attachés” for “may not exceed the number of defense attachés” and “<date date="1979-12-31">December 31, 1979</date>” for “<date date="1978-12-31">December 31, 1978</date>”, and inserted “such countries and countries to which military personnel have been assigned pursuant to subsection (c) of this section” after “such countries”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/96/92/s7/1">Pub. L. 96–92, § 7(1)</ref>, substituted “fiscal year 1980” for “fiscal year 1979” and authorized assignment of military personnel for programs in Greece.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/96/92/s7/2">Pub. L. 96–92, § 7(2)</ref>, substituted “<date date="1978-12-31">December 31, 1978</date>” for “<date date="1977-12-31">December 31, 1977</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/95/384/s9/a">Pub. L. 95–384, § 9(a)</ref>, substituted “fiscal year 1979” for “fiscal year 1978” and “Turkey, Indonesia, Thailand” for “Brazil”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/384/s9/b">Pub. L. 95–384, § 9(b)</ref>, substituted “, including any such members serving on a reimbursable basis pursuant to subsection (b)(3) of this section, may not exceed 790 for the fiscal year 1979” for “may not exceed 865 for the fiscal year 1978”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/95/384/s9/c">Pub. L. 95–384, § 9(c)</ref>, substituted “<date date="1977-12-31">December 31, 1977</date>, except that the President may assign an aggregate total of not to exceed eight additional defense attachés to such countries in order to perform overseas management functions under this subsection” for “<date date="1976-12-31">December 31, 1976</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/95/384/s9/d">Pub. L. 95–384, § 9(d)</ref>, inserted “for fixed” after “for specific purposes and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/95/384/s9/e">Pub. L. 95–384, § 9(e)</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/92">Pub. L. 95–92</ref> substituted provisions requiring specific Congressional authorization for a military assistance advisory group, etc., to operate in any foreign country and set forth exceptions to such requirement, for provisions authorizing deductions of expenditures from military assistance appropriations during the period beginning <date date="1976-07-01">July 1, 1976</date>, and ending <date date="1977-09-30">Sept. 30, 1977</date>, under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2312">section 2312 of this title</ref> where under this section reimbursement is requested by the expending government agency or if the available funds are deposited in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/92">Pub. L. 95–92</ref> substituted provisions relating to assignment of military personnel to specified countries by President for implementation of management responsibilities during fiscal year 1978 under international security assistance programs, for provisions requiring specific Congressional authority for assignment of any military assistance advisory group, etc., to operate in any foreign country after <date date="1977-09-30">Sept. 30, 1977</date>, and provisions relating to assignment by the President of military personnel to diplomatic missions of the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/92">Pub. L. 95–92</ref> substituted provisions relating to assignment of military personnel to nonspecified countries by President for performance of accounting and other management functions under international security assistance programs, for provisions limiting after <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, the number of military missions and groups to not more than 34.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/92">Pub. L. 95–92</ref> substituted provisions setting forth maximum number of military personnel assignable under subsecs. (b) and (c) of this section for fiscal year 1978 as 865, for provisions defining “military assistance advisory group, military mission, or other organization of United States military personnel performing similar military advisory functions under this chapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e) to (g). <ref href="/us/pl/95/92">Pub. L. 95–92</ref> added subsecs. (e) to (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/329/s104/1">Pub. L. 94–329, § 104(1)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and substituted “During the period beginning <date date="1976-07-01">July 1, 1976</date>, and ending <date date="1977-09-30">September 30, 1977</date>” for “Effective <date date="1976-07-01">July 1, 1976</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b) to (d). <ref href="/us/pl/94/329/s104/2">Pub. L. 94–329, § 104(2)</ref>, added subsecs. (b) to (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8f8e912c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id8f8e912d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1985 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/83">Pub. L. 99–83</ref> effective <date date="1985-10-01">Oct. 1, 1985</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/83/s1301">section 1301 of Pub. L. 99–83</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151–1">section 2151–1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id8f8e912e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id8f8e912f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id8f8e9130-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of functions of President under this section, see Ex. Ord. No. 12163, <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 56673, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2381">section 2381 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
