<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8f937342-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2347c"><num value="2347c">§ 2347c.</num><heading> Exchange training; reciprocity agreement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f937343-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2347c/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Attendance of foreign military personnel at professional military education institutions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out this part, the President is authorized to provide for attendance of foreign military personnel at professional military education institutions in the United States (other than service academies) without charge, and without charge to funds available to carry out this part (notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2392/d">section 2392(d) of this title</ref>), if such attendance is pursuant to an agreement providing for the exchange of students on a one-for-one, reciprocal basis each fiscal year between those United States professional military education institutions and comparable institutions of foreign countries and international organizations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f937344-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2347c/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Attendance of foreign military and civilian defense personnel at flight training schools and programs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President may provide for the attendance of foreign military and civilian defense personnel at flight training schools and programs (including test pilot schools) in the United States without charge, and without charge to funds available to carry out this part (notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2392/d">section 2392(d) of this title</ref>), if such attendance is pursuant to an agreement providing for the exchange of students on a one-for-one basis each fiscal year between those United States flight training schools and programs (including test pilot schools) and comparable flight training schools and programs of foreign countries.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f937345-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2347c/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Post-undergraduate flying training and tactical leadership programs at training locations in Southwest Asia</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f937346-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2347c/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The President is authorized to enter into cooperative arrangements providing for the participation of foreign and United States military and civilian defense personnel in post-undergraduate flying training and tactical leadership programs and integrated air and missile defense programs at training locations in Southwest Asia without charge to participating foreign countries, and without charge to funds available to carry out this part (notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2392/d">section 2392(d) of this title</ref>). Such training must satisfy common requirements with the United States for post-undergraduate flying and tactical leadership training and integrated air and missile defense training.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f937347-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2347c/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Cooperative arrangements under this subsection shall require an equitable contribution of support and services from each participating country. The President may waive the requirement for an equitable contribution of a participating foreign country if he determines that to do so is important to the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f937348-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2347c/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Costs incurred by the United States shall be charged to the current applicable appropriations accounts or funds of the participating United States Government agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f937349-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2347c/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The President shall report to the appropriate congressional committees (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2416/e">section 2416(e) of this title</ref>) annually on the activities undertaken in the programs authorized under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8f93734a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, pt. II, § 544, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/83/tI/s126">Pub. L. 99–83, title I, § 126</ref>, <date date="1985-08-08">Aug. 8, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/205">99 Stat. 205</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/104/164/tI/s112/b">Pub. L. 104–164, title I, § 112(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-07-21">July 21, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1427">110 Stat. 1427</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/228/dB/tXII/s1213">Pub. L. 107–228, div. B, title XII, § 1213</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1429">116 Stat. 1429</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tXII/s1233">Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title XII, § 1233</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/920">127 Stat. 920</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/276/tII/s203">Pub. L. 113–276, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2990">128 Stat. 2990</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8f93734b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8f93734c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8f93734d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/113/276">Pub. L. 113–276</ref> added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66">Pub. L. 113–66</ref> inserted “and integrated air and missile defense programs” after “tactical leadership programs” and “and integrated air and missile defense training” after “tactical leadership training”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/107/228">Pub. L. 107–228</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—<ref href="/us/pl/104/164">Pub. L. 104–164</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8f93734e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id8f93734f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1985-10-01">Oct. 1, 1985</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/83/s1301">section 1301 of Pub. L. 99–83</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1985 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151–1">section 2151–1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8f937350-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Authority for Exchange Training Through Specified Professional Military Education Institution Outside United States</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tIX/s935">Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title IX, § 935</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1538">103 Stat. 1538</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/189/dA/tIX/s935">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The United States Army Russian Institute in Garmisch-Partenkirchen, Federal Republic of Germany, shall be treated for purposes of section 544 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2347c">22 U.S.C. 2347c</ref>) as if it were located in the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Expiration of Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>Subsection (a) shall cease to be in effect upon the enactment in foreign assistance authorizing legislation of an amendment to section 544 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 that provides the same authority as is provided by subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id8f937351-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id8f937352-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of functions of President under this section, see Ex. Ord. No. 12163, <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 56673, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2381">section 2381 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
