<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8f95bc8f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2349a"><num value="2349a">§ 2349a.</num><heading> Authorization and utilization of funds</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f95bc90-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2349a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the President to carry out this part not to exceed $800,000,000, which may be made available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f95bc91-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2349a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Presidential authority to incur obligations and enter into contracts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon agreement by the Government of Israel to provide to the Government of the United States funds equal to the difference between the amount required to complete the agreed construction work and the amount appropriated pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, and to make those funds available, in advance of the time when payments are due, in such amounts and at such times as may be required by the Government of the United States to meet those additional costs of construction, the President may incur obligations and enter into contracts to the extent necessary to complete the agreed construction work, except that this authority shall be effective only to such extent or in such amounts as are provided in advance in appropriation Acts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f95bc92-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2349a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Crediting of funds to proper appropriation account</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Funds made available by the Government of Israel pursuant to subsection (b) of this section may be credited to the appropriation account established to carry out the purposes of this section for the payment of obligations incurred and for refund to the Government of Israel if they are unnecessary for that purpose, as determined by the President. Credits and the proceeds of guaranteed loans made available to the Government of Israel pursuant to the Arms Export Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.], as well as any other source of financing available to it, may be used by Israel to carry out its undertaking to provide such additional funds.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8f95bc93-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, pt. II, § 562, as added <ref href="/us/pl/96/35/s3">Pub. L. 96–35, § 3</ref>, <date date="1979-07-20">July 20, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/90">93 Stat. 90</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8f95bc94-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8f95bc95-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8f95bc96-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Arms Export Control Act, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/pl/90/629">Pub. L. 90–629</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1320">82 Stat. 1320</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 39 (§ 2751 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id8f95bc97-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id8f95bc98-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of functions of President under this section, see Ex. Ord. No. 12163, <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 56673, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2381">section 2381 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
