<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8f9a7812-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2357"><num value="2357">§ 2357.</num><heading> Furnishing of services and commodities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f9a7813-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2357/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Advance-of-funds or reimbursement basis</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever the President determines it to be consistent with and in furtherance of the purposes of subchapter I of this chapter and within the limitations of this chapter, any agency of the United States Government is authorized to furnish services and commodities on an advance-of-funds or reimbursement basis to friendly countries, international organizations, the American Red Cross, and voluntary nonprofit relief agencies registered with and approved by the Agency for International Development (including foreign voluntary nonprofit relief agencies so registered and approved when no United States voluntary nonprofit relief agency is available). Such advances or reimbursements may be credited to the currently applicable appropriation, account, or fund of the agency concerned and shall be available for the purposes for which such appropriation, account, or fund is authorized to be used, under the following circumstances:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f9a7814-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2357/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Advances or reimbursements which are received under this section within one hundred and eighty days after the close of the fiscal year in which such services and commodities are delivered.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f9a7815-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2357/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Advances or reimbursements received pursuant to agreements executed under this section in which reimbursement will not be completed within one hundred and eighty days after the close of the fiscal year in which such services and commodities are delivered: <i>Provided</i>, That such agreements require the payment of interest at the current rate established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/1/B">section 635(b)(1)(B) of title 12</ref>, and repayment of such principal and interest does not exceed a period of three years from the date of signing of the agreement to provide the service: <i>Provided further</i>, That funds available for this paragraph in any fiscal year shall not exceed $1,000,000 of the total funds authorized for use in such fiscal year by part I of subchapter I of this chapter, and shall be available only to the extent provided in appropriation Acts. Interest shall accrue as of the date of disbursement to the agency or organization providing such services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f9a7816-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2357/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Agency contracts with individuals to perform services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">When any agency of the United States Government provides services on an advance-of-funds or reimbursable basis under this section, such agency may contract with individuals for personal service abroad or in the United States to perform such services or to replace officers or employees of the United States Government who are assigned by the agency to provide such services. Such individuals shall not be regarded as employees of the United States Government for the purpose of any law administered by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f9a7817-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2357/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Excess property</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f9a7818-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2357/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in subsection (d), no Government-owned excess property shall be made available under this section, <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2358">section 2358 of this title</ref>, or otherwise in furtherance of the purposes of subchapter I of this chapter, unless, before the shipment of such property for use in a specified country (or transfer, if the property is already in such country), the agency administering such subchapter I has approved such shipment (or transfer) and made a written determination—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f9a7819-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2357/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> that there is a need for such property in the quantity requested and that such property is suitable for the purpose requested;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f9a781a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2357/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> as to the status and responsibility of the designated end-user and his ability effectively to use and maintain such property; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f9a781b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2357/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> that the residual value, serviceability, and appearance of such property would not reflect unfavorably on the image of the United States and would justify the costs of packing, crating, handling, transportation, and other accessorial costs, and that the residual value at least equals the total of these costs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8f9a781c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2357/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> For purposes of transferring property described in this subsection in furtherance of the provisions of part VIII of subchapter I of this chapter, the phrase “the agency administering such subchapter I” shall be considered to refer to the Department of State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f9a781d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2357/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of Government-owned excess property to enhance environmental protection in foreign countries</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of State, acting through the Assistant Secretary of State for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs, is authorized to transfer to any friendly country, international organization, the American Red Cross, or other voluntary nonprofit relief agency described in subsection (a), Government-owned excess property made available under this section or <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2358">section 2358 of this title</ref> in order to support activities carried out under subchapter I of this chapter which are designed to enhance environmental protection in foreign countries if the Secretary of State makes a written determination—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f9a781e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2357/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> that there is a need for such property in the quantity requested and that such property is suitable for the purpose requested;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f9a781f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2357/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> as to the status and responsibility of the designated end-user and his ability effectively to use and maintain such property; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8f9a7820-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2357/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> that the residual value, serviceability, and appearance of such property would not reflect unfavorably on the image of the United States and would justify the costs of packing, crating, handling, transportation, and other accessorial costs, and that the residual value at least equals the total of these costs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8f9a7821-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, pt. III, § 607, <date date="1961-09-04">Sept. 4, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/441">75 Stat. 441</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/554">Pub. L. 90–554</ref>, pt. III, § 301(b), <date date="1968-10-08">Oct. 8, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/963">82 Stat. 963</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/161/tIII/s315">Pub. L. 94–161, title III, § 315</ref>, <date date="1975-12-20">Dec. 20, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/867">89 Stat. 867</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/88/tI/s122/a">Pub. L. 95–88, title I, § 122(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-03">Aug. 3, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/541">91 Stat. 541</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/424/tV/s503">Pub. L. 95–424, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="1978-10-06">Oct. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/959">92 Stat. 959</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3783">92 Stat. 3783</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/53/tI/s121">Pub. L. 96–53, title I, § 121</ref>, <date date="1979-08-14">Aug. 14, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/366">93 Stat. 366</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/93/tI/s129">Pub. L. 99–93, title I, § 129</ref>, <date date="1985-08-16">Aug. 16, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/419">99 Stat. 419</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8f9a7822-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8f9a7823-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8f9a7824-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, <date date="1961-09-04">Sept. 4, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/424">75 Stat. 424</ref>, known as the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">section 2151 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8f9a7825-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/93/s129/1/A">Pub. L. 99–93, § 129(1)(A)</ref>, (B), designated existing provisions of subsec. (c) as par. (1), redesignated existing pars. (1), (2), and (3) as subpars. (A), (B), and (C), respectively, and in introductory provisions of par. (1) as so designated substituted “Except as provided in subsection (d), no” for “No”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/93/s129/1/C">Pub. L. 99–93, § 129(1)(C)</ref>, added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/99/93/s129/2">Pub. L. 99–93, § 129(2)</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/96/53">Pub. L. 96–53</ref> substituted “Agency for International Development” for “Advisory Committee on Voluntary Foreign Aid”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsecs. (b), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/424">Pub. L. 95–424</ref> added subsec. (b) and redesignated former subsec. (b) as (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/88">Pub. L. 95–88</ref> inserted “(including foreign voluntary nonprofit relief agencies so registered and approved when no United States voluntary nonprofit relief agency is available)” after “and voluntary nonprofit relief agencies registered with and approved by the Advisory Committee on Voluntary Foreign Aid” in provisions preceding par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/161">Pub. L. 94–161</ref> substituted “currently” for “current”, incorporated text following “Such advances or reimbursements” in provisions designated cl. (1) and added cl. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—<ref href="/us/pl/90/554">Pub. L. 90–554</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8f9a7826-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8f9a7827-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References to Subchapter I Deemed To Include Certain Parts of Subchapter II</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References to subchapter I of this chapter are deemed to include parts IV (§ 2346 et seq.), VI (§ 2348 et seq.), and VIII (§ 2349aa et seq.) of subchapter II of this chapter, and references to subchapter II are deemed to exclude such parts. See <ref href="/us/pl/92/226/s202/b">section 202(b) of Pub. L. 92–226</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2346">section 2346 of this title</ref>, and sections 2348c and 2349aa–5 of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8f9a7828-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References to Part I Deemed To Include Section 2293</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References to part I of subchapter I of this chapter are deemed to include a reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2293">section 2293 of this title</ref>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2293/d/1">section 2293(d)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id8f9a7829-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1979 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/96/53">Pub. L. 96–53</ref> effective <date date="1979-10-01">Oct. 1, 1979</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/53/s512/a">section 512(a) of Pub. L. 96–53</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">section 2151 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id8f9a782a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/424">Pub. L. 95–424</ref> effective <date date="1978-10-01">Oct. 1, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/424/s605">section 605 of Pub. L. 95–424</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">section 2151 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8f9a782b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/88/tI/s122/b">Pub. L. 95–88, title I, § 122(b)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-03">Aug. 3, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/541">91 Stat. 541</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/88/tI/s122/b">“For purposes of implementing the amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section], the President shall issue regulations governing registration with and approval by the Advisory Committee on Voluntary Foreign Aid of foreign voluntary nonprofit agencies.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8f9a782c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Authority of Secretary of State</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided, Secretary of State to have and exercise any authority vested by law in any official or office of Department of State and references to such officials or offices deemed to refer to Secretary of State or Department of State, as appropriate, see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2651a">section 2651a of this title</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s161/d">section 161(d) of Pub. L. 103–236</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2651a">section 2651a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8f9a782d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Advisory Committees</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Advisory committees in existence on <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period following <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, unless, in the case of a committee established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such committee is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a committee established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided by law. See <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1013">section 1013 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id8f9a782e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id8f9a782f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Director of the Office of Personnel Management” substituted for “Civil Service Commission” in subsec. (b) pursuant to Reorg. Plan No. 2 of 1978, § 102, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3783">92 Stat. 3783</ref>, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1101">section 1101 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees, which transferred all functions vested by statute in the United States Civil Service Commission to the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (except as otherwise specified), effective <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, as provided by section 1–102 of Ex. Ord. No. 12107, <date date="1978-12-28">Dec. 28, 1978</date>, 44 F.R. 1055, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1101">section 1101 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id8f9a7830-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of functions of President under this section, see Ex. Ord. No. 12163, <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 56673, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2381">section 2381 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8f9a7831-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Authority</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="1995-02-16">Feb. 16, 1995</date>, 60 F.R. 10793, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum for the Secretary of State [and] the Administrator of the Agency for International Development</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and laws of the United States of America, including <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref> of the United States Code, I hereby delegate as follows certain authorities vested in the President:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(A) the functions under section 607 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended (FAA) [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2357">22 U.S.C. 2357</ref>], to the Secretary of State and to the Administrator of the Agency for International Development, respectively, for matters within their respective areas of responsibility; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(B) the functions in the first proviso under the heading “Population, Development Assistance,” contained in title II of the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1995 (<ref href="/us/pl/103/306">Public Law 103–306</ref>) [<ref href="/us/stat/108/1611">108 Stat. 1611</ref>], and in comparable provisions in successor legislation, to the Secretary of State relating to those organizations and programs for which the Secretary of State has funding responsibility.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The delegations of authority described in subparagraph (A) are in addition to other delegations of such authority to the International Development Cooperation Agency.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The delegation of authority described above in subparagraph (B) shall be exercised in lieu of the delegation of the comparable authority to the Administrator of the Agency for International Development by section 1–102(a)(7) of Executive Order No. 12163, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2381">22 U.S.C. 2381</ref> note].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Any reference in this memorandum to any Act, order, determination, or delegation of authority shall be deemed to be a reference to such Act, order, determination, or delegation of authority as amended from time to time.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The functions delegated by this memorandum may be redelegated within the Department of State or the Agency for International Development, as appropriate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Secretary of State is authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the Federal Register.</p>
<signature>
<name>William J. Clinton.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
