<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8f9a7832-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2358"><num value="2358">§ 2358.</num><heading> Foreign and domestic excess property</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f9a7833-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2358/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Advance acquisition of property; special account for payment of costs; limitation; use of property</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that in furnishing assistance under subchapter I of this chapter excess personal property, or (if a substantial savings would occur) other property already owned by an agency of the United States Government, shall be utilized wherever practicable in lieu of or supplementary to the procurement of new items for United States-assisted projects and programs. The President is authorized to maintain in a separate account, which shall, notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1535/d">section 1535(d) of title 31</ref>, be free from fiscal year limitation, $5,000,000 of funds made available under part I of subchapter I of this chapter, which may be used to pay costs (including personnel costs) of acquisition, storage, renovation and rehabilitation, packing, crating, handling, transportation, and related costs of property classified as domestic or foreign excess property pursuant to chapters 1 to 11 of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41, any property available from an agency of the United States Government, or other property, in advance of known requirements therefor for use in furtherance of the purposes of subchapter I of this chapter: <i>Provided</i>, That the amount of property classified as domestic excess property pursuant to chapters 1 to 11 of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41 held at any one time pursuant to this section shall not exceed $15,000,000 in total original acquisition cost. Property acquired pursuant to the preceding sentence may be furnished (1) pursuant to any provision of subchapter I of this chapter for which funds are authorized for the furnishing of assistance, in which case the separate account established pursuant to this section shall be repaid from funds made available for such provision for all costs incurred, or (2) pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2357">section 2357 of this title</ref>, in which case such separate account shall be repaid in accordance with the provisions of that section for all costs incurred.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8f9a7834-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2358/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of domestic excess property</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Property classified as domestic excess property under chapters 1 to 11 of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41 shall not be transferred to the agency primarily responsible for administering subchapter I of this chapter for use pursuant to the provisions of subchapter I of this chapter or <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2357">section 2357 of this title</ref> unless (1) such property is transferred for use exclusively by an agency of the United States Government, or (2) it has been determined in the same manner as provided for surplus property in section 549(a) to (e) of title 40, that such property is not needed for donation pursuant to those subsections. The foregoing restrictions shall not apply to the transfer in any fiscal year for use pursuant to the provisions of subchapter I of this chapter of amounts of such property with a total original acquisition cost to the United States Government not exceeding $45,000,000.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8f9a7835-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, pt. III, § 608, <date date="1961-09-04">Sept. 4, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/441">75 Stat. 441</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/583">Pub. L. 89–583</ref>, pt. III, § 301(c), <date date="1966-09-19">Sept. 19, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/804">80 Stat. 804</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/137">Pub. L. 90–137</ref>, pt. III, § 301(b), <date date="1967-11-14">Nov. 14, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/458">81 Stat. 458</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/424/tI/s102/g/2/C">Pub. L. 95–424, title I, § 102(g)(2)(C)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-06">Oct. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/942">92 Stat. 942</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/113/tVII/s701">Pub. L. 97–113, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1543">95 Stat. 1543</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8f9a7836-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8f9a7837-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8f9a7838-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In text, “chapters 1 to 11 of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41” substituted for references to the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949, as amended, on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s5/c">Pub. L. 107–217, § 5(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1303">116 Stat. 1303</ref>, which Act enacted Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, and <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s6/c">Pub. L. 111–350, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3854">124 Stat. 3854</ref>, which Act enacted Title 41, Public Contracts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (a), “<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1535/d">section 1535(d) of title 31</ref>” substituted for “section 1210 of the General Appropriation Act, 1951 (<ref href="/us/stat/64/765">64 Stat. 765</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s686–1">31 U.S.C. 686–1</ref>]” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s4/b">Pub. L. 97–258, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1067">96 Stat. 1067</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 31, Money and Finance.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (b), “section 549(a) to (e) of title 40” substituted for “section 203(j) of the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949, as amended” and “those subsections” substituted for “that subsection” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s5/c">Pub. L. 107–217, § 5(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1303">116 Stat. 1303</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8f9a7839-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/113">Pub. L. 97–113</ref> authorized for subchapter I assistance use of property already owned by an agency of the United States (if a substantial savings would occur) as supplementary to procurement of new items for United States-assisted projects and programs and use of separate account funds for payment of costs of any property available from an agency of the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/424">Pub. L. 95–424</ref> substituted “part 1 of subchapter 1 of this chapter” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2172">section 2172 of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1967—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/90/137">Pub. L. 90–137</ref> required, in furnishing assistance under subchapter I of this chapter, utilization of excess personal property wherever practicable in lieu of new items for United States-assisted projects and programs.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/89/583">Pub. L. 89–583</ref> permitted personnel costs attributable to the excess property program to be charged to the separate account for the advance acquisition of property.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8f9a783a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8f9a783b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References to Subchapter I Deemed To Include Certain Parts of Subchapter II</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References to subchapter I of this chapter are deemed to include parts IV (§ 2346 et seq.), VI (§ 2348 et seq.), and VIII (§ 2349aa et seq.) of subchapter II of this chapter, and references to subchapter II are deemed to exclude such parts. See <ref href="/us/pl/92/226/s202/b">section 202(b) of Pub. L. 92–226</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2346">section 2346 of this title</ref>, and sections 2348c and 2349aa–5 of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8f9a783c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References to Part I Deemed To Include Section 2293</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References to part I of subchapter I of this chapter are deemed to include a reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2293">section 2293 of this title</ref>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2293/d/1">section 2293(d)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id8f9a783d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/424">Pub. L. 95–424</ref> effective <date date="1978-10-01">Oct. 1, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/424/s605">section 605 of Pub. L. 95–424</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">section 2151 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id8f9a783e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id8f9a783f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of functions of President under this section, see Ex. Ord. No. 12163, <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 56673, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2381">section 2381 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
