<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8fa8cfb3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2381"><num value="2381">§ 2381.</num><heading> Exercise of functions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fa8cfb4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2381/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Delegation by President; rules and regulations; utilization of goods and services from private enterprise, and facilities and resources of Federal agencies when not competitive with private enterprise</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President may exercise any functions conferred upon him by this chapter through such agency or officer of the United States Government as he shall direct. The head of any such agency or such officer may from time to time promulgate such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out such functions, and may delegate authority to perform any such functions, including, if he shall so specify, the authority successively to redelegate any of such functions to any of his subordinates. In providing technical assistance under this chapter, the head of any such agency or such officer shall utilize, to the fullest extent practicable, goods and professional and other services from private enterprise on a contract basis. In such fields as education, health, housing, or agriculture, the facilities and resources of other Federal agencies shall be utilized when such facilities are particularly or uniquely suitable for technical assistance, are not competitive with private enterprise, and can be made available without interfering unduly with domestic programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fa8cfb5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2381/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility of suppliers; debarment period; causes for debarment; conditions for reinstatement; periodic review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall issue and enforce regulations determining the eligibility of any person to receive funds made available under this chapter. A person may be suspended under such regulations for a temporary period pending the completion of an investigation and any resulting judicial or debarment proceedings, upon cause for belief that such person or an affiliate thereof probably has undertaken conduct which constitutes a cause for debarment; and, after an opportunity has been afforded to such person for a hearing, he may be debarred for an additional period, not to exceed three years. Among the causes for debarment shall be (1) offering or accepting a bribe or other illegal payment or credit in connection with any transaction financed with funds made available under this chapter; or (2) committing a fraud in the procurement or performance of any contract financed with funds made available under this chapter; or (3) acting in any other manner which shows a lack of integrity or honesty in connection with any transaction financed with funds made available under this chapter. Reinstatement of eligibility in each particular case shall be subject to such conditions as the President shall direct. Each person whose eligibility is denied or suspended under this subsection shall, upon request, be entitled to a review of his eligibility not less often than once every two years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8fa8cfb6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, pt. III, § 621, <date date="1961-09-04">Sept. 4, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/445">75 Stat. 445</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/565">Pub. L. 87–565</ref>, pt. III, § 302(a), <date date="1962-08-01">Aug. 1, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/262">76 Stat. 262</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/205">Pub. L. 88–205</ref>, pt. III, § 302(a), <date date="1963-12-16">Dec. 16, 1963</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/77/388">77 Stat. 388</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/554">Pub. L. 90–554</ref>, pt. III, § 302(a), <date date="1968-10-08">Oct. 8, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/964">82 Stat. 964</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8fa8cfb7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8fa8cfb8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8fa8cfb9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, <date date="1961-09-04">Sept. 4, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/424">75 Stat. 424</ref>, known as the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">section 2151 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8fa8cfba-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—<ref href="/us/pl/90/554">Pub. L. 90–554</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1963—<ref href="/us/pl/88/205">Pub. L. 88–205</ref> provided that goods and professional and other services from private enterprise should be utilized on a contract basis, and that Federal agencies be utilized only when not competitive with private enterprise and available without interfering unduly with domestic programs.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—<ref href="/us/pl/87/565">Pub. L. 87–565</ref> struck out designation “(a)” from provisions of subsec. (a), and repealed subsecs. (b) to (e) which related to the abolition of the Development Loan Fund, International Cooperation Administration, and the Office of Inspector General and Comptroller, the transfer of their functions, and the transfer of the function of the Export-Import Bank under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1704/e">section 1704(e) of title 7</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8fa8cfbb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fa8cfbc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">AID Office of Security</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dA/s101/d/tV/s587">Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(d) [title V, § 587]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-150">112 Stat. 2681–150</ref>, 2681–204, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/106/31/tV/s5002/b">Pub. L. 106–31, title V, § 5002(b)</ref>, <date date="1999-05-21">May 21, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/109">113 Stat. 109</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/31/tV/s5002/b">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Office</inline>.—</heading><content>There shall be established within the Office of the Administrator of the Agency for International Development, an Office of Security. Such Office of Security shall, notwithstanding any other provision of law except section 207 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3927">22 U.S.C. 3927</ref>] and <ref href="/us/pl/99/339/s103">section 103 of Public Law 99–339</ref> [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4802">22 U.S.C. 4802</ref>], have the responsibility for the supervision, direction, and control of all security activities relating to the programs and operations of that Agency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transfer and Allocation of Appropriations and Personnel</inline>.—</heading><content>There are transferred to the Office of Security all security functions exercised by the Office of Inspector General of the Agency for International Development exercised before the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>]. The Administrator shall transfer from the Office of the Inspector General of such Agency to the Office of Security established by subsection (a), the personnel (including the Senior Executive Service position designated for the Assistant Inspector General for Security), assets, liabilities, grants, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, and other funds held, used, available to, or to be made available in connection with such functions. Unexpended balances of appropriations, and other funds made available or to be made available in connection with such functions, shall be transferred to and merged with funds appropriated by this Act under the heading ‘Operating Expenses of the Agency for International Development’ [<ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-157">112 Stat. 2681–157</ref>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transfer of Employees</inline>.—</heading><content>Any employee in the career service who is transferred pursuant to this section shall be placed in a position in the Office of Security established by subsection (a) which is comparable to the position the employee held in the Office of the Inspector General of the Agency for International Development.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fa8cfbd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Agency for International Development Budget Submission</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/429/s101/a/tV/s576">Pub. L. 106–429, § 101(a) [title V, § 576]</ref>, <date date="2000-11-06">Nov. 6, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1900">114 Stat. 1900</ref>, 1900A–54, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/429/s101/a/tV/s576">“The Agency for International Development shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations a detailed budget justification that is consistent with the requirements of section 515 [<ref href="/us/stat/114/1900">114 Stat. 1900</ref>A–26], for each fiscal year. The Agency shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations a proposed budget justification format no later than <date date="2000-11-15">November 15, 2000</date>, or 30 days after the enactment of this Act [<date date="2000-11-06">Nov. 6, 2000</date>], whichever occurs later. The proposed format shall include how the Agency’s budget justification will address: (1) estimated levels of obligations for the current fiscal year and actual levels for the 2 previous fiscal years; (2) the President’s request for new budget authority and estimated carryover obligational authority for the budget year; (3) the disaggregation of budget data and staff levels by program and activity for each bureau, field mission, and central office; and (4) the need for a user-friendly, transparent budget narrative.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/2/tV/s581">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(2) [title V, § 581]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1535">113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–116, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/2/tV/s581">“Beginning with the fiscal year 2001 budget, the Agency for International Development shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations a detailed budget for each fiscal year. The Agency shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations a proposed budget format no later than <date date="1999-10-31">October 31, 1999</date>, or 30 days after the enactment of this Act [<date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>], whichever occurs later. The proposed format shall include how the Agency’s budget submission will address: (1) estimated levels of obligations for the current fiscal year and actual levels for the two previous fiscal years; (2) the President’s request for new budget authority and estimated carryover obligational authority for the budget year; (3) the disaggregation of budget data by program and activity for each bureau, field mission, and central office; and (4) staff levels identified by program.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/102/391/tV/s599E">Pub. L. 102–391, title V, § 599E</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1698">106 Stat. 1698</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/391/tV/s599E">“The President shall include with each budget for a fiscal year submitted to the Congress under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105">section 1105 of title 31</ref>, United States Code, materials that shall identify clearly and separately the amounts requested in the budget for appropriation for that fiscal year for salaries and expenses related to administrative activities of the Agency for International Development.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fa8cfbe-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Repeal of Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1979</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1979, 44 F.R. 41165, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1378">93 Stat. 1378</ref>, which established the United States International Development Cooperation Agency, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dG">Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIV, §§ 1401, 1422(a)(1), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-790">112 Stat. 2681–790</ref>, 2681–792, effective <date date="1999-04-01">Apr. 1, 1999</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id8fa8cfbf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id8fa8cfc0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of functions of President under this section, see Ex. Ord. No. 12163, <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 56673, as amended, set out below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id8fa8cfc1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 10973</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 10973, <date date="1961-11-03">Nov. 3, 1961</date>, 26 F.R. 10469, as amended, which related to the administration of foreign assistance and related functions, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 12163, § 1–903(a)(1), <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 56679, eff. <date date="1979-10-01">Oct. 1, 1979</date>, set out below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 10973, <date date="1961-11-03">Nov. 3, 1961</date>, 26 F.R. 10469, as amended, was superseded insofar as any provision therein was in conflict with any provision of Ex. Ord. No. 11579, <date date="1971-01-19">Jan. 19, 1971</date>, 36 F.R. 969, formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2191">section 2191 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id8fa8cfc2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 12163. Administration of Foreign Assistance and Related Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 12163, <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 56673, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 12226, <date date="1980-07-22">July 22, 1980</date>, 45 F.R. 49235; Ex. Ord. No. 12292, <date date="1981-02-23">Feb. 23, 1981</date>, 46 F.R. 13968; Ex. Ord. No. 12321, <date date="1981-09-14">Sept. 14, 1981</date>, 46 F.R. 46109; Ex. Ord. No. 12365, <date date="1982-05-24">May 24, 1982</date>, 47 F.R. 22933; Ex. Ord. No. 12423, <date date="1983-05-26">May 26, 1983</date>, 48 F.R. 24025; Ex. Ord. No. 12458, <date date="1984-01-14">Jan. 14, 1984</date>, 49 F.R. 1977; Ex. Ord. No. 12500, <date date="1985-01-24">Jan. 24, 1985</date>, 50 F.R. 3733; Ex. Ord. No. 12560, <date date="1986-05-24">May 24, 1986</date>, 51 F.R. 19159; Ex. Ord. No. 12608, <date date="1987-09-09">Sept. 9, 1987</date>, 52 F.R. 34617; Ex. Ord. No. 12620, <date date="1987-12-24">Dec. 24, 1987</date>, 52 F.R. 49135; Ex. Ord. No. 12639, <date date="1988-05-06">May 6, 1988</date>, 53 F.R. 16691; Ex. Ord. No. 12680, <date date="1989-07-05">July 5, 1989</date>, 54 F.R. 28995; Ex. Ord. No. 12695, <date date="1989-11-01">Nov. 1, 1989</date>, 54 F.R. 46589; Ex. Ord. No. 12738, §§ 1–6, <date date="1990-12-14">Dec. 14, 1990</date>, 55 F.R. 52033; Ex. Ord. No. 13030, § 1, <date date="1996-12-12">Dec. 12, 1996</date>, 61 F.R. 66187; Ex. Ord. No. 13091, § 2, <date date="1998-06-29">June 29, 1998</date>, 63 F.R. 36153; <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dG">Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIV, § 1422(a)(2), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-792">112 Stat. 2681–792</ref>; Ex. Ord. No. 13118, §§ 1–9, <date date="1999-03-31">Mar. 31, 1999</date>, 64 F.R. 16595–16598; Ex. Ord. No. 13346, § 3, <date date="2004-07-08">July 8, 2004</date>, 69 F.R. 41905; Ex. Ord. No. 13361, <date date="2004-11-16">Nov. 16, 2004</date>, 69 F.R. 67633; Ex. Ord. No. 13656, § 6, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, 79 F.R. 4263, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By virtue of the authority vested in me by the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [this chapter], Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1979 [set out above], the International Development Cooperation Act of 1979 [see Short Title of 1979 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">section 2151 of this title</ref>], and <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref> of the United States Code, and as President of the United States, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I71" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fa8cfc3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered">1–1. <inline class="small-caps">Department of State</inline></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–100. <i>Delegation of Functions</i>. (a) Exclusive of the functions otherwise delegated, or reserved to the President, by this order, Executive Order 12884 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s5812">22 U.S.C. 5812</ref> note], Executive Order 11579 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2191">22 U.S.C. 2191</ref> note], and Executive Order 12757 [former <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1738">7 U.S.C. 1738</ref> note], and subject to the provisions of such orders, there are hereby delegated to the Secretary of State (referred to in this Part as the “Secretary”) all functions conferred upon the President by:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(1) the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> <i>et seq</i>.) (“Act”);</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">(i) except that with respect to section 505(a) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2314/a">22 U.S.C. 2314(a)</ref>], such functions only insofar as those functions relate to other provisions which may be required by the President or only insofar as they relate to consent;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">(ii) except that with respect to section 505(b) of the Act, such functions only insofar as those functions pertain to countries that agree to the conditions set forth therein;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(2) section 1205(b) of the International Security and Development Cooperation Act of 1985 (“ISDCA of 1985”) [<ref href="/us/pl/99/83">Pub. L. 99–83</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2346">22 U.S.C. 2346</ref> note];</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(3) <ref href="/us/act/1971-01-12/s8/d">section 8(d) of the Act of January 12, 1971</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2321b/d">22 U.S.C. 2321b(d)</ref>);</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(4) section 607 of the International Security Assistance and Arms Export Control Act of 1976 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2394a">22 U.S.C. 2394a</ref>);</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(5) <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s402/b/2">section 402(b)(2) of title 10</ref>, United States Code, which shall be exercised in consultation with the Secretary of Defense;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(6) the third proviso under the heading “Development Assistance” contained in title II of the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1999 (as contained in <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Public Law 105–277</ref>) [<ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-153">112 Stat. 2681–153</ref>];</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(7) section 572 of the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1989 (<ref href="/us/pl/100/461">Public Law 100–461</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151v">22 U.S.C. 2151v</ref> note];</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(8) sections 508, 517 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s5814">22 U.S.C. 5814</ref> note], 518, 528(a), 535 [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note], 539 [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note], 544, 561, 563, 572, 574, 575, 585, 594 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2753">22 U.S.C. 2753</ref> note] of the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1999 (as contained in <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Public Law 105–277</ref>) [<ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-150">112 Stat. 2681–150</ref>, 2681–171, 2681–174, 2681–176, 2681–178, 2681–181, 2681–182, 2681–185, 2681–191, 2681–193, 2681–198, 2681–199, 2681–203, 2681–215];</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(9) section 523 of the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1999 (as contained in <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Public Law 105–277</ref>) [<ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-177">112 Stat. 2681–177</ref>], which shall be exercised in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(10) section 551 of the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1999 (as contained in <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Public Law 105–277</ref>) [<ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-187">112 Stat. 2681–187</ref>];</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(11) section 591 of the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1998 (<ref href="/us/pl/105/118">Public Law 105–118</ref>) [<ref href="/us/stat/111/2439">111 Stat. 2439</ref>], and the provisions of law referenced therein;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(12) section 821(b) of the Western Hemisphere Drug Elimination Act (as contained in <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Public Law 105–277</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2291">22 U.S.C. 2291</ref> note];</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(13) title II of the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2002 (<ref href="/us/pl/107/115">Public Law 107–115</ref>), under the heading “Assistance for the Independent States of the Former Soviet Union, [sic]” in subsections (g)(4) and (6) [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s5812">22 U.S.C. 5812</ref> note];</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(14) section 512 of Division D of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2004 (<ref href="/us/pl/108/199">Public Law 108–199</ref>) [<ref href="/us/stat/118/170">118 Stat. 170</ref>];</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(15) sections 5(c) and 6 of the Anglo-Irish Agreement Support Act of 1986 (<ref href="/us/pl/99/415">Public Law 99–415</ref>), as amended [<ref href="/us/stat/100/948">100 Stat. 948</ref>, 949];</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(16) the United States Leadership Against HIV/AIDS, Tuberculosis, and Malaria Act of 2003 (<ref href="/us/pl/108/25">Public Law 108–25</ref>) (the “HIV/AIDS Act”), as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7601">22 U.S.C. 7601</ref> et seq.], and amendments made by the HIV/AIDS Act, which the Secretary shall perform, in the case of section 304 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7634">22 U.S.C. 7634</ref>], after consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The functions under section 653 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2413">22 U.S.C. 2413</ref>] delegated to the Secretary shall be exercised in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, insofar as they relate to functions under the Act administered by the Department of Defense, and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The functions under sections 239(f), 620(e), 620(g), 620(j), 620(q), and 620(s) of the Act [former <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2199/f">22 U.S.C. 2199(f)</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2370/e">22 U.S.C. 2370(e)</ref>, (g), (j), (q), (s)] delegated to the Secretary shall be exercised in consultation with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The Secretary shall perform all public information functions abroad with respect to the foreign assistance, aid, and development programs of the United States Government, to the extent such functions are not specifically assigned by statute to be performed by a different officer.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) The Secretary may redelegate to any other officer or agency of the Executive branch functions delegated to the Secretary by this order to the extent such delegation is not otherwise prohibited by law.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I71" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fa8cfc4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered">1–2. <inline class="small-caps">United States Agency for International Development</inline></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–200. <i>United States Agency for International Development.</i></p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) The United States Agency for International Development is an independent establishment within the Executive branch. Any reference in the Act to the agency primarily responsible for administering part I of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.], or to the Administrator of such agency, shall be deemed to be a reference to the United States Agency for International Development or to the Administrator of that agency, as appropriate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The United States Agency for International Development shall be headed by an Administrator appointed pursuant to section 624(a) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2384/a">22 U.S.C. 2384(a)</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The officers provided for in section 624(a) of the Act shall serve in the United States Agency for International Development.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The Office of Small Business provided for in section 602(b) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2352/b">22 U.S.C. 2352(b)</ref>] shall be in the United States Agency for International Development.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) To the extent practicable, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development will exercise functions relating to Foreign Service personnel in a manner that will assure maximum compatibility among agencies authorized by law to utilize the Foreign Service personnel system. To this end, the Administrator shall consult regularly with the Secretary of State.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I71" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fab40c5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered">1–3. <inline class="small-caps">Department of Defense</inline></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–301. <i>Delegation of Functions</i>. Subject to the provisions of this order, there are hereby delegated to the Secretary of Defense:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) The functions conferred upon the President by Part II [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2301">22 U.S.C. 2301</ref> et seq.] (except chapters 4, 6 and 8 thereof) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2346">22 U.S.C. 2346</ref> et seq., 2348 et seq., 2349aa et seq.] not otherwise delegated or reserved to the President.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) To the extent that they relate to other functions under the Act [this chapter] administered by the Department of Defense, the functions conferred upon the President by sections 602(a), 605(a), 625(a), 625(d)(1), 625(h), 627, 628, 630(3), 631(a), 634(B), 635(b) (except with respect to negotiation, conclusion, and termination of international agreements), 635(d), 635(g), and 636(i) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2352/a">22 U.S.C. 2352(a)</ref>, 2355(a), 2385(a), (d)(1), (h), 2387, 2388, 2390(3), 2391(a), 2394–1a, 2395(b), (d), (g), and 2396(i)].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) Those functions under section 634A of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2394–1">22 U.S.C. 2394–1</ref>], to the extent they relate to notifications to the Congress concerning changes in programs under chapters 2 and 5 of part II of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2311">22 U.S.C. 2311</ref> et seq., 2347 et seq.] and under the Arms Export Control Act, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.], subject to prior consultation with the Secretary of State.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The functions under sections 627, 628, and 630(3) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2387">22 U.S.C. 2387</ref>, 2388, and 2390(3)] delegated to the Secretary of Defense shall be exercised in consultation with the Secretary of State.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) the functions under section 655 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2415">22 U.S.C. 2415</ref>] insofar as they relate to defense articles, defense services, and international military education and training furnished by grant or sale by the Secretary of Defense, except to the extent otherwise delegated.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(f) Those functions conferred upon the President under section 616 of the ISDCA of 1985 [<ref href="/us/pl/99/83">Pub. L. 99–83</ref>, <date date="1985-08-08">Aug. 8, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/232">99 Stat. 232</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(g) The functions conferred upon the President under section 573 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2321j">22 U.S.C. 2321j</ref> note] and section 581(b)(2) of the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1990 (<ref href="/us/pl/101/167">Public Law 101–167</ref>) [<date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1246">103 Stat. 1246</ref>, 1250].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(h) The functions conferred upon the President under section 3 of the International Narcotics Control Act of 1989 (<ref href="/us/pl/101/231">Public Law 101–231</ref>) [<date date="1989-12-13">Dec. 13, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1955">103 Stat. 1955</ref>], which shall be exercised in consultation with the Secretary of State.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–302. <i>Reports and Information</i>. In carrying out the functions under section 514 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2321h">22 U.S.C. 2321h</ref>] delegated to him by section 301 of this order, the Secretary of Defense shall consult with the Secretary of State.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I71" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fab40c6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered">1–4. <inline class="small-caps">Institute for Scientific and Technological Cooperation</inline></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 13118, § 4, <date date="1999-03-31">Mar. 31, 1999</date>, 64 F.R. 16596]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I71" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fab40c7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered">1–5. <inline class="small-caps">Other Agencies</inline></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–501. <i>Department of the Treasury</i>. (a) There are delegated to the Secretary of the Treasury the functions conferred upon the President by:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(1) section 305 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2225">22 U.S.C. 2225</ref>], insofar as it relates to the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, the International Development Association, the International Finance Corporation, the Inter-American Development Bank, the Asian Development Bank, the African Development Fund, and the International Monetary Fund;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(2) the second sentence of section 612(a) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2362/a">22 U.S.C. 2362(a)</ref>];</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(3) section 502 of the Mutual Security Act of 1954 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1754">22 U.S.C. 1754</ref>); and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(4) section 655(c) of the Act [former <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2415/c">22 U.S.C. 2415(c)</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Secretary of the Treasury shall continue to administer any open special foreign country accounts established pursuant to former section 514 of the Act as enacted by <ref href="/us/pl/92/226/s201/f">section 201(f) of Public Law 92–226</ref> (<ref href="/us/stat/86/25">86 Stat. 25</ref>) and repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/93/189/s12/b/5">Section 12(b)(5) of Public Law 93–189</ref> (<ref href="/us/stat/87/722">87 Stat. 722</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2321g">22 U.S.C. 2321g</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The functions under section 305 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2225">22 U.S.C. 2225</ref>] delegated to the Secretary of the Treasury shall be exercised in consultation with the Secretary of State.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–502. <i>Department of Commerce</i>. There is hereby delegated to the Secretary of Commerce so much of the functions conferred upon the President by section 601(b)(1) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2351/b/1">22 U.S.C. 2351(b)(1)</ref>] as consists of drawing the attention of private enterprise to opportunities for investment and development in less developed friendly countries and areas.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–503. <i>Office of Personnel Management</i>. There is hereby delegated to the Director of the Office of Personnel Management the function of prescribing regulations conferred upon the President by the proviso contained in section 625(b) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2385/b">22 U.S.C. 2385(b)</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[1–504. Revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 13118, § 5(2), <date date="1999-03-31">Mar. 31, 1999</date>, 64 F.R. 16597.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–505. Trade and Development Agency. There is delegated to the Director of the Trade and Development Agency the functions conferred upon the President by section 661(d) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2421/d">22 U.S.C. 2421(d)</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[1–506. Revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 13118, § 5(4), <date date="1999-03-31">Mar. 31, 1999</date>, 64 F.R. 16597.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I71" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fab40c8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered">1–6. <inline class="small-caps">Additional Delegations and Limitations of Authority; Consultation</inline></heading><p>1–601. <i>General Delegation of Functions</i>. There are hereby delegated to the heads of agencies having responsibilities for carrying out the provisions of the Act [this chapter] all functions conferred upon the President by:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) section 654 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2414">22 U.S.C. 2414</ref>] (except as reserved to the President); and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) those provisions of acts appropriating funds under the authority of the Act [this chapter] that relate to the Act, or other acts authorizing such funds, insofar as they relate to the functions delegated by this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–602. <i>Personnel</i>. (a) In carrying out the functions conferred upon the President by the provisions of section 625(d) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2385/d">22 U.S.C. 2385(d)</ref>], and by this order delegated to the Secretary of State, the Secretary shall authorize such of the agencies that administer programs under the Act [this chapter] as he may deem appropriate to perform any of the functions under section 625(d) of the Act to the extent that the said functions relate to the programs administered by the respective agencies.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Persons appointed, employed, or assigned after <date date="1959-05-19">May 19, 1959</date>, under section 527(c) of the Mutual Security Act of 1954 [former <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1787/c">22 U.S.C. 1787(c)</ref>] or section 625(d) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2385/d">22 U.S.C. 2385(d)</ref>] for the purpose of performing functions under such Acts outside the United States shall not, unless otherwise agreed by the agency in which such benefits may be exercised, be entitled to the benefits provided by section 310 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3950">22 U.S.C. 3950</ref>) in cases in which their service under the appointment, employment, or assignment exceeds thirty months.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–603. <i>Special Missions and Staffs Abroad</i>. The maintenance of special missions or staffs abroad, the fixing of the ranks of the chiefs thereof after the chiefs of the United States diplomatic missions, and the authorization of the same compensation and allowances authorized for a chief of mission as defined in section 102(a)(3) of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3902/a/3">22 U.S.C. 3902(a)(3)</ref>), all under section 631 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2391">22 U.S.C. 2391</ref>], shall be subject to the approval of the Secretary of State.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–604. <i>International Agreements</i>. The negotiation, conclusion, and termination of international agreements pursuant to the Act [this chapter] shall be subject to the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s112b">1 U.S.C. 112b</ref> and to applicable regulations and procedures.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–605. <i>Interagency Consultation</i>. Each officer to whom functions are delegated by this order, shall, in carrying out such functions, consult with the heads of other departments and agencies, including the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, on matters pertaining to the responsibilities of departments and agencies other than his or her own.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I71" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fab40c9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered">1–7. <inline class="small-caps">Reserved Functions</inline></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–701. <i>Reservation of Functions to the President</i>. There are hereby excluded from the functions delegated by the foregoing provisions of this order:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) The functions conferred upon the President by sections 122(e), 298(a), 493, 504(b), 613(a), 614(a), 620(a), 620(d), 620(x), 620A, 620C(c), 621(a), 622(b), 622(c), 633(a), 633(b), 640B, and 663(b) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151t/e">22 U.S.C. 2151t(e)</ref>, 2220c(a), 2292b, 2312(b), 2363(a), 2364(a), 2370(a), (d), (x), 2371, 2373(c), 2381(a), 2382(b), (c), 2393(a), (b), 2399c, and 2423(b)].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The functions conferred upon the President by the Act [this chapter] and section 408(b) of the Mutual Security Act of 1954 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1928">22 U.S.C. 1928</ref>] with respect to the appointment of officers required to be appointed by and with the advice and consent of the Senate and with respect to the appointment of officers pursuant to sections 233(b) and 624(c) of the Act [former <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2193/b">22 U.S.C. 2193(b)</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2384/c">22 U.S.C. 2384(c)</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The functions conferred upon the President with respect to determinations, certifications, directives, or transfers of funds, as the case may be, by sections 209(d), 303, 465(b), 490(h), 505(d)(2)(A), 505(d)(3), 506(a), 552(c), 552(e), 610, 614(c), 620E, 632(b), 633A, 663(a) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2169/d">22 U.S.C. 2169(d)</ref>, 2223, 2275(b), 2291j(h), 2314(d)(2)(A), (d)(3), 2318(a), 2348a(c), (e), 2360, 2364(c), 2375, 2392(b), 2393a, 2423(a)].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[(d) Redesignated (c).]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) The following-described functions conferred upon the President:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(1) Those under section 503(a) [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2311/a">22 U.S.C. 2311(a)</ref>] that relate to findings: <i>Provided</i>, that the Secretary of State, in the implementation of the functions delegated to him under section 505(a)(1), (a)(4), and (e) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2314/a/1">22 U.S.C. 2314(a)(1)</ref>, (a)(4), and (e)], is authorized to find, in the case of a proposed transfer of a defense article or related training or a related defense service by a foreign country or international organization to a foreign country or international organization not otherwise eligible under section 503(a) of the Act, whether the proposed transfer will strengthen the security of the United States and promote world peace.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(2) Those under section 505(b) [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2314/b">22 U.S.C. 2314(b)</ref>] in respect of countries that do not agree to the conditions set forth therein.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(3) That under section 614(b) [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2364/b">22 U.S.C. 2364(b)</ref>] with respect to determining any provisions of law to be disregarded to achieve the purpose of that section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(4) That under the second sentence of section 654(c) [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2414/c">22 U.S.C. 2414(c)</ref>] with respect to the publication in the Federal Register of any findings or determination reserved to the President: <i>Provided</i>, that any officer to whom there is delegated the function of making any finding or determination within the purview of section 654(a) [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2414/a">22 U.S.C. 2414(a)</ref>] is also authorized to reach the conclusion specified in performance of the function delegated to him.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(f) That under section 523(d) of the Mutual Security Act of 1954 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1783/d">22 U.S.C. 1783(d)</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(g) Those under sections 130 [<ref href="/us/pl/99/83">Pub. L. 99–83</ref>, <date date="1985-08-08">Aug. 8, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/207">99 Stat. 207</ref>], 504 and 505 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2349aa–8">22 U.S.C. 2349aa–8</ref>, 2349aa–9] of the ISDCA of 1985[.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(h) Those functions conferred by section 1(f)(1) and section 1(f)(2)(B)(ii)(VII) [now IX] of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2651a">22 U.S.C. 2651a</ref>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) Those functions conferred by section 202(d)(4)(C)(i) and (ii) of the HIV/AIDS Act, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7622/d/4/C/i">22 U.S.C. 7622(d)(4)(C)(i)</ref>, (ii)].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–702. <i>Subsequent Amendments</i>. Functions conferred upon the President by subsequent amendments to the Act [this chapter] are delegated to the Secretary only insofar as they do not relate directly and necessarily to the conduct of programs and activities that either the President or an agency other than the Department of State is authorized to administer pursuant to express reservation or delegation of authorities in a statute or in this or another Executive order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–703. <i>Office of Management and Budget</i>. In this order the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall retain all authorities related to the implementation of his budgetary and policy coordination functions, including the authority to:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(a) request and receive information from any agency that is subject to this delegation;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(b) carry out all responsibilities associated with implementing the Government Performance and Results Act [<ref href="/us/pl/103/62">Pub. L. 103–62</ref>, see Short Title of 1993 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1101">section 1101 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance], the Government Management Reform Act [<ref href="/us/pl/103/356">Pub. L. 103–356</ref>, see Short Title of 1994 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3301">section 3301 of Title 31</ref>], and other comparable government-wide statutes dealing with management; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(c) carry out all statutory budget and policy coordination responsibilities assigned to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget by statute or Executive order.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I71" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fab40ca-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered">1–8. <inline class="small-caps">Funds</inline></heading><p>1–800. <i>Allocation of Funds</i>. Funds described below that are appropriated or otherwise made available to the President shall be deemed to be allocated without any further action of the President, as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c), there are allocated to the Secretary all funds made available for carrying out the Act, including any funds appropriated under the heading “Nonproliferation, Anti-Terrorism, Demining and Related Programs”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) There are allocated to the Secretary of Defense all funds made available for carrying out chapters 2 and 5 of Part II of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2311">22 U.S.C. 2311</ref> et seq., 2347 et seq.].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) There are allocated to the Secretary of the Treasury all funds made available for carrying out section 129 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151aa">22 U.S.C. 2151aa</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of the Treasury may allocate or transfer as appropriate any funds received under subsections (a), (b), and (c) of this section, respectively, to any agency or part thereof for obligation or expenditure thereby consistent with applicable law.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I71" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fab40cb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered">1–9. <inline class="small-caps">General Provisions</inline></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–901. <i>Definition</i>. As used in this order, the word “function” includes any duty, obligation, power, authority, responsibility, right, privilege, discretion, or activity.</p>
<p>1–902. <i>References to Orders and Acts</i>. Except as may for any reason be inappropriate:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) References in this order or in any other Executive order to (1) the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [this chapter] (including references herein to “the Act”), (2) unrepealed provisions of the Mutual Security Act of 1954 [<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-26/ch937">act Aug. 26, 1954, ch. 937</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/832">68 Stat. 832</ref>, as amended], or (3) any other act that relates to the subject of this order shall be deemed to include references to any subsequent amendments thereto.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) References in any prior Executive order to the Mutual Security Act of 1954 [<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-26/ch937">act Aug. 26, 1954, ch. 937</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/832">68 Stat. 832</ref>, as amended] or any provisions thereof shall be deemed to be references to the Act [this chapter] or the corresponding provision, if any, thereof.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) References in this order to provisions of any Act, and references in any other Executive order or in any memorandum delegation to provisions of any Act related to the subject of this order shall be deemed to include references to any provision of law that is the same or substantially the same as such provisions, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) References in this order or in any other Executive order to this order or to any provision thereof shall be deemed to include references thereto, respectively, as amended from time to time.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) References in any prior Executive order not superseded by this order to any provisions of any Executive order so superseded shall hereafter be deemed to be references to the corresponding provisions, if any, of this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–903. <i>Prior Executive Orders</i>. (a) The following are revoked:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(1) Executive Order No. 10973 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2381">22 U.S.C. 2381</ref> note] of <date date="1961-11-03">November 3, 1961</date>, as amended;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(2) section 2(a) of Executive Order No. 11579 [former <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2191">22 U.S.C. 2191</ref> note], of <date date="1971-01-19">January 19, 1971</date>; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(3) Executive Order No. 10893 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2382">22 U.S.C. 2382</ref> note] of <date date="1960-11-08">November 8, 1960</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The following are amended:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(1) section 3(a) of Executive Order No. 11846 of <date date="1975-03-27">March 27, 1975</date>, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2111">19 U.S.C. 2111</ref> note], by adding the following new paragraph (12) after paragraph (11):</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(12) The Director of the United States International Development Cooperation Agency”;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(2) section 1–202 of [former] Executive Order 12065 of <date date="1978-06-28">June 28, 1978</date>, by striking out “The Administrator, Agency for International Development” and inserting in lieu thereof “The Director of the United States International Development Cooperation Agency”;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(3) section 2(a) of Executive Order No. 11958 of <date date="1977-01-18">January 18, 1977</date> [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> note], by striking out “the Administrator of the Agency for International Development” and inserting in lieu thereof “the Director of the United States International Development Cooperation Agency”;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(4) section 3 of Executive Order 10900 of <date date="1961-01-05">January 5, 1961</date> [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1691">7 U.S.C. 1691</ref> note], by adding thereto the following new subsection:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(d) The Secretary of State may redelegate to the Director of the United States International Development Cooperation Agency, or to any other officer or agency of the Executive branch, functions delegated to such Secretary by this order.”;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(5) section 4 of Executive Order 11223 of <date date="1965-05-12">May 12, 1965</date> [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2393">22 U.S.C. 2393</ref> note], by inserting immediately following “the Secretary of State” the words “or the Director of the United States International Development Cooperation Agency (with respect to functions vested in or delegated to the Director)”; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(6) the President’s memorandum of <date date="1961-10-18">October 18, 1961</date>, entitled “Determination Under Section 604(a) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961” (26 FR 10543) is amended by inserting after “the Secretary of State” each time it appears in such memorandum the words “or the Director of the United States International Development Cooperation Agency (with respect to non-military programs administered by such Agency)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[(c), (d) Revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 13118, § 9, <date date="1999-03-31">Mar. 31, 1999</date>, 64 F.R. 16598.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–904. <i>Saving Provisions</i>. Except to the extent inconsistent with this order, all delegations of authority, determinations, authorizations, regulations, rulings, certificates, orders, directives, contracts, agreements, and other actions made, issued, or entered into with respect to any function affected by this order and not revoked, superseded, or otherwise made inapplicable before the date of this order, shall continue in full force and effect until amended, modified, or terminated by appropriate authority.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1–905. <i>Effective Date</i>. The provisions of this order shall become effective as of <date date="1979-10-01">October 1, 1979</date>.</p>
<p>1–906. <i>Implementation</i>. In carrying out this order, officers of the United States shall ensure that all actions taken by them are consistent with the President’s constitutional authority to: (a) conduct the foreign affairs of the United States; (b) withhold information the disclosure of which could impair the foreign relations, the national security, the deliberative processes of the Executive, or the performance of the Executive’s constitutional duties; (c) recommend for congressional consideration such measures as the President may judge necessary and expedient; and (d) supervise the unitary executive branch.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[<ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dG">Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIV, § 1422(a)(2), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-792">112 Stat. 2681–792</ref>, provided that sections 1–101 through 1–103, 1–401 through 1–403, and 1–801(a), and other provisions of Ex. Ord. No. 12163 that relate to the United States International Development Cooperation Agency or the Director thereof were repealed.]</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
