<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8fab410e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2385"><num value="2385">§ 2385.</num><heading> Employment of personnel</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fab410f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2385/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any agency or officer of the United States Government carrying out functions under this chapter is authorized to employ such personnel as the President deems necessary to carry out the provisions and purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fab4110-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2385/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointments excepted from civil-service laws; super­grade positions; reinstatement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Of the personnel employed in the United States to carry out subchapter I of this chapter or coordinate subchapter I and subchapter II of this chapter, not to exceed one hundred and ten may be appointed, compensated, or removed without regard to the provisions of any law, of whom not to exceed fifty-one may be compensated at rates higher than those provided for grade 15 of the general schedule established by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5332">section 5332 of title 5</ref>, but not in excess of the highest rate of grade 18 of such general schedule: <i>Provided</i>, That, under such regulations as the President shall prescribe, officers and employees of the United States Government who are appointed to any of the above positions may be entitled, upon removal from such position, to reinstatement to the position occupied at the time of appointment or to a position of comparable grade and salary. Such positions shall be in addition to those authorized by law to be filled by Presidential appointment, and in addition to the number authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5108">section 5108 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fab4111-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2385/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional supergrade positions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Of the personnel employed in the United States to carry out subchapter II of this chapter, or any Act superseding subchapter II of this chapter in whole or in part, not to exceed eight may be compensated at rates higher than those provided for grade 15 of the general schedule established by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5332">section 5332 of title 5</ref>, but not in excess of the highest rate of grade 18 of such general schedule. Such positions shall be in addition to those authorized by law to be filled by Presidential appointment, and in addition to the number authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5108">section 5108 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fab4112-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2385/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Employment or assignment of officers and employees to perform functions outside United States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of performing functions under this chapter outside the United States, the President may employ or assign individuals, or may authorize the employment or assignment of officers or employees by agencies of the United States Government which are not authorized to utilize the Foreign Service personnel system, who shall receive compensation at any of the rates provided for under section 402 or section 403 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3962">22 U.S.C. 3962</ref>, 3963], or under chapter 53 of title 5, or at any other rate authorized by law, together with allowances and benefits under the Foreign Service Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3901">22 U.S.C. 3901</ref> et seq.]. Individuals so employed or assigned shall be entitled, except to the extent that the President may specify otherwise in cases in which the period of employment or assignment exceeds thirty months, to the same benefits as are provided by section 310 of that Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3950">22 U.S.C. 3950</ref>] for individuals appointed to the Foreign Service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fad8a03-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2385/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/96/465/tII/s2205/8">Pub. L. 96–465, title II, § 2205(8)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2160">94 Stat. 2160</ref></heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fad8a04-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2385/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Funds for personnel services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Funds provided for in agreements with foreign countries for the furnishing of services under this chapter with respect to specific projects shall be deemed to be obligated for the services of personnel employed by agencies of the United States Government (other than the agencies primarily responsible for administering subchapter I or II of this chapter) as well as personnel not employed by the United States Government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fad8a05-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2385/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/96/465/tII/s2205/8">Pub. L. 96–465, title II, § 2205(8)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2160">94 Stat. 2160</ref></heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fad8a06-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2385/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Acceptance of compensation or other benefits from foreign countries; arrangements for reimbursement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, officers and employees of the United States Government performing functions under this chapter shall not accept from any foreign country any compensation or other benefits. Arrangements may be made by the President with such countries for reimbursement to the United States Government or other sharing of the cost of performing such functions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fad8a07-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2385/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Assignment based on competency</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To the maximum extent practicable officers and employees performing functions under this chapter abroad shall be assigned to countries and positions for which they have special competence, such as appropriate language and practical experience.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fad8a08-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2385/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Reemployment of annuitants under the Civil Service Retirement System and the Federal Employees’ Retirement System</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fad8a09-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2385/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fad8a0a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2385/j/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> To facilitate the assignment of persons to Iraq, Pakistan, and Afghanistan or to posts vacated by members of the Service assigned to Iraq, Pakistan, and Afghanistan, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development may waive the application of the provisions of section 8344 or 8468 of title 5 on a case-by-case basis for employment of an annuitant in a position in the United States Agency for International Development for which there is exceptional difficulty in recruiting or retaining a qualified employee, or when a temporary emergency hiring need exists.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fad8a0b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2385/j/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The authority of the Administrator under subparagraph (A) shall terminate on <date date="2010-10-01">October 1, 2010</date>.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002148">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002148"><num>1</num> See Extension of Authority note below.</note> An annuitant reemployed pursuant to such authority prior to such termination date may be employed for a period ending not later than one year after such date.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fad8a0c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2385/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Administrator should prescribe procedures for the exercise of any authority under this subsection, including criteria for any exercise of authority and procedures for a delegation of authority.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fad8a0d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2385/j/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> An employee for whom a waiver under this section is in effect shall not be considered an employee for purposes of subchapter III of chapter 83, or chapter 84 of title 5.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fad8a0e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2385/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Crisis operations and disaster surge staffing</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fad8a0f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2385/k/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The United States Agency for International Development is authorized to appoint personnel in the excepted service using funds authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available under the heading “Transition Initiatives” in an Act making appropriations for the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs and to carry out the provisions of subchapter I and part IV of subchapter II of this chapter of <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002149">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002149"><num>2</num> So in original.</note> and <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9808/b">section 9808(b) of this title</ref> to prevent or respond to foreign crises.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fad8a10-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2385/k/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Funds authorized to carry out such purposes may be made available for the operating expenses and administrative costs of such personnel and may remain attributed to any minimum funding requirement for which they were originally made available.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fad8a11-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2385/k/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall coordinate with the Office of Personnel Management on implementation of the appointment authority under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fad8a12-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2385/k/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Not later than one year after <date date="2024-12-23">December 23, 2024</date>, and annually thereafter for 3 years, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, the Committee on Oversight and Accountability of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report regarding the continued need for and utilization of the authority pursuant to this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8fad8a13-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, pt. III, § 625, <date date="1961-09-04">Sept. 4, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/449">75 Stat. 449</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/565">Pub. L. 87–565</ref>, pt. III, § 302(c), <date date="1962-08-01">Aug. 1, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/262">76 Stat. 262</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/793">Pub. L. 87–793</ref>, pt. II, § 1001(k), <date date="1962-10-11">Oct. 11, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/865">76 Stat. 865</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/663">Pub. L. 88–663</ref>, pt. III, § 302(a), <date date="1964-10-07">Oct. 7, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/1014">78 Stat. 1014</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/171">Pub. L. 89–171</ref>, pt. III, § 302(c), <date date="1965-09-06">Sept. 6, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/660">79 Stat. 660</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/137">Pub. L. 90–137</ref>, pt. III, § 302(b)–(d), <date date="1967-11-14">Nov. 14, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/460">81 Stat. 460</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/554/tIII/s302/c">Pub. L. 90–554, title III, § 302(c)</ref>, <date date="1968-10-08">Oct. 8, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/965">82 Stat. 965</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/189/s16">Pub. L. 93–189, § 16</ref>, <date date="1973-12-17">Dec. 17, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/722">87 Stat. 722</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/88/tI/s125">Pub. L. 95–88, title I, § 125</ref>, <date date="1977-08-03">Aug. 3, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/542">91 Stat. 542</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/465/tII">Pub. L. 96–465, title II</ref>, §§ 2203(a), 2205(8), <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2158">94 Stat. 2158</ref>, 2160; <ref href="/us/pl/97/113/tVII/s703">Pub. L. 97–113, title VII, § 703</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1544">95 Stat. 1544</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/234/tI/s1602/b/2">Pub. L. 109–234, title I, § 1602(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/442">120 Stat. 442</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/32/tXI/s1115/c/3">Pub. L. 111–32, title XI, § 1115(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2009-06-24">June 24, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1905">123 Stat. 1905</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dG/tLXXVI/s7602">Pub. L. 118–159, div. G, title LXXVI, § 7602</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2552">138 Stat. 2552</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8fad8a14-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8fad8a15-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8fad8a16-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a), (d), (f), (h), and (i), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, <date date="1961-09-04">Sept. 4, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/424">75 Stat. 424</ref>, known as the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">section 2151 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Foreign Service Act of 1980, referred to in subsec. (d), is <ref href="/us/pl/96/465">Pub. L. 96–465</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2071">94 Stat. 2071</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 52 (§ 3901 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3901">section 3901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="2024-12-23">December 23, 2024</date>, referred to in subsec. (k)(4), was in the original “the date of the enactment of this Act”, and was translated as meaning the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/118/159">Pub. L. 118–159</ref>, which added subsec. (k), to reflect the probable intent of Congress. See 2024 Amendment note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8fad8a17-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/118/159">Pub. L. 118–159</ref> added subsec. (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—Subsec. (j)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/32">Pub. L. 111–32</ref> inserted “, Pakistan,” after “Iraq” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/111/32">Pub. L. 111–32</ref> substituted “2010” for “2008”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/109/234">Pub. L. 109–234</ref> added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/113">Pub. L. 97–113</ref> substituted “or under chapter 53 of title 5, or at any other rate authorized by law, together with allowances and benefits under the Foreign Service Act of 1980” for “together with allowances and benefits under that Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/96/465/s2203/a">Pub. L. 96–465, § 2203(a)</ref>, substituted references to the Foreign Service Act of 1980, for references to the Foreign Service Act of 1946, and struck out provisions relating to the applicability of section 1005 of the Foreign Service Act of 1946 and relating to the utilization of Presidential authority under the Foreign Service Act of 1946 to carry out the functions of this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/96/465/s2205/8">Pub. L. 96–465, § 2205(8)</ref>, struck out subsec. (e) which set forth requirement of standards or other criteria for maintenance of adequate performance levels for personnel. See sections 4007 and 4008 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/96/465/s2205/8">Pub. L. 96–465, § 2205(8)</ref>, struck out subsec. (g) which related to competency in foreign languages. See <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4022">section 4022 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/96/465/s2205/8">Pub. L. 96–465, § 2205(8)</ref>, struck out subsec. (j) which related to appointment and compensation of an Inter-American Committee representative.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/96/465/s2205/8">Pub. L. 96–465, § 2205(8)</ref>, struck out subsec. (k) which related to applicability, etc., of Foreign Service Retirement and Disability System. See sections 3922 and 4043 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/95/88">Pub. L. 95–88</ref> struck out a numerical limitation of fifty on the number of persons which the President may assign, at any one time, to duty within the United States for the purpose of preparation for assignments outside the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/93/189">Pub. L. 93–189</ref> added subsec. (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/90/554">Pub. L. 90–554</ref> inserted “or any Act superseding subchapter II of this chapter in whole or in part” after “to carry out subchapter II of this chapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1967—Subsecs. (b), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/90/137/s302/b">Pub. L. 90–137, § 302(b)</ref>, (c), substituted references to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5332">section 5332 of title 5</ref> for former references to the Classification Act of 1949, as amended, and to section 5108 for former <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1105">section 1105 of title 5</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/90/137/s302/d">Pub. L. 90–137, § 302(d)</ref>, authorized an increase in the assignment of foreign personnel from forty to fifty persons.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/89/171">Pub. L. 89–171</ref> substituted “forty” for “twenty”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1964—Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/88/633/s302/a/1">Pub. L. 88–633, § 302(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “the assignment to such duty of more than twenty persons at any one time” for “more than thirty persons in the aggregate”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/88/633/s302/a/2">Pub. L. 88–633, § 302(a)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/87/793/s1001/k/1">Pub. L. 87–793, § 1001(k)(1)</ref>, substituted “but not in excess of the highest rate of grade 18 of such general schedule” for “and of these, not to exceed eight may be compensated at a rate in excess of the highest rate provided for grades of such general schedule but not in excess of $19,000 per year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/87/565/s302/c/1">Pub. L. 87–565, § 302(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “one hundred and ten” for “seventy-six”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/87/793/s1001/k/2">Pub. L. 87–793, § 1001(k)(2)</ref>, substituted “but not in excess of the highest rate of grade 18 of such general schedule” for “and of these, not to exceed three may be compensated at a rate in excess of the highest rate provided for grades of such general schedule but not in excess of $19,000 per year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/87/565/s302/c/2">Pub. L. 87–565, § 302(c)(2)</ref>, authorized the President to initially assign personnel, not exceeding 30 persons in the aggregate, for duty within the United States for a period not exceeding two years for preparation for duty outside the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/87/565/s302/c/3">Pub. L. 87–565, § 302(c)(3)</ref>, inserted “with respect to specific projects”, and “agencies of”, and excluded services of employees of agencies primarily responsible for administering subchapter I or II of this chapter from the purview of this subsection.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8fad8a18-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fad8a19-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References to Subchapter I Deemed To Include Certain Parts of Subchapter II, and References to Subchapter II Deemed To Exclude Such Parts</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References to subchapter I of this chapter are deemed to include parts IV (§ 2346 et seq.), VI (§ 2348 et seq.), and VIII (§ 2349aa et seq.) of subchapter II of this chapter, and references to subchapter II are deemed to exclude such parts. See <ref href="/us/pl/92/226/s202/b">section 202(b) of Pub. L. 92–226</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2346">section 2346 of this title</ref>, and sections 2348c and 2349aa–5 of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id8fad8a1a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1980 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment of subsec. (d) and repeal of subsecs. (e), (g), and (j) by <ref href="/us/pl/96/465">Pub. L. 96–465</ref> effective <date date="1981-02-15">Feb. 15, 1981</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/465/s2403">section 2403 of Pub. L. 96–465</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3901">section 3901 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Repeal of subsec. (k) by <ref href="/us/pl/96/465">Pub. L. 96–465</ref> effective <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/465/tII/s2403/d/1">Pub. L. 96–465, title II, § 2403(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2169">94 Stat. 2169</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id8fad8a1b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1962 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/87/793">Pub. L. 87–793</ref> effective on first day of first pay period which begins on or after <date date="1962-10-11">Oct. 11, 1962</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/87/793">Pub. L. 87–793</ref>, pt. II, § 1008, <date date="1962-10-11">Oct. 11, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/868">76 Stat. 868</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fad8a1c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Additional Personnel To Address Backlogs in Hiring and Investigations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dI/tXCII/s9204">Pub. L. 117–263, div. I, title XCII, § 9204</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3864">136 Stat. 3864</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dI/tXCII/s9204">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary [of State] shall seek to increase the number of personnel within the Bureau of Global Talent Management and the Office of Civil Rights to address backlogs in hiring and investigations into complaints conducted by the Office of Civil Rights.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Employment Targets</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall seek to employ—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> not fewer than 15 additional personnel in the Bureau of Global Talent Management and the Office of Civil Rights (compared to the number of personnel so employed as of the day before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>]) by the date that is 180 days after such date of enactment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> not fewer than 15 additional personnel in such Bureau and Office (compared to the number of personnel so employed as of the day before the date of the enactment of this Act) by the date that is 1 year after such date of enactment.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fad8a1d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Extension of Authority</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dG/tLXXVIII/s7812/a">Pub. L. 118–159, div. G, title LXXVIII, § 7812(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2565">138 Stat. 2565</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/159/dG/tLXXVIII/s7812/a">“Section 625(j)(1)(B) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2385/j/1/B">22 U.S.C. 2385(j)(1)(B)</ref>) shall be applied by striking ‘<date date="2010-10-01">October 1, 2010</date>’ and inserting ‘<date date="2026-09-30">September 30, 2026</date>’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>Prior extensions were contained in the following prior acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/118/83/dB/tI/s111">Pub. L. 118–83, div. B, title I, § 111</ref>, <date date="2024-09-26">Sept. 26, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1537">138 Stat. 1537</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dI/tXCVIII/s9802/b">Pub. L. 117–263, div. I, title XCVIII, § 9802(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3924">136 Stat. 3924</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dK/tVII/s7034">Pub. L. 117–103, div. K, title VII, § 7034</ref>(<i>l</i>)(3), <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/623">136 Stat. 623</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dK/tVII/s7034">Pub. L. 116–260, div. K, title VII, § 7034</ref>(<i>l</i>)(3), <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/1749">134 Stat. 1749</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dG/tVII/s7034">Pub. L. 116–94, div. G, title VII, § 7034</ref>(<i>l</i>)(3), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2872">133 Stat. 2872</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/6/dF/tVII/s7034/m/3">Pub. L. 116–6, div. F, title VII, § 7034(m)(3)</ref>, <date date="2019-02-15">Feb. 15, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/327">133 Stat. 327</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/115/141/dK/tVII/s7034">Pub. L. 115–141, div. K, title VII, § 7034</ref>(<i>l</i>)(3), <date date="2018-03-23">Mar. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/895">132 Stat. 895</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/115/31/dJ/tVII/s7034/k/3">Pub. L. 115–31, div. J, title VII, § 7034(k)(3)</ref>, <date date="2017-05-05">May 5, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/651">131 Stat. 651</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/114/113/dK/tVII/s7034/k/6">Pub. L. 114–113, div. K, title VII, § 7034(k)(6)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-18">Dec. 18, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/2765">129 Stat. 2765</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/113/235/dJ/tVII/s7034">Pub. L. 113–235, div. J, title VII, § 7034</ref>(<i>l</i>)(6), <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2625">128 Stat. 2625</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/113/76/dK/tVII/s7034/m/6">Pub. L. 113–76, div. K, title VII, § 7034(m)(6)</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/515">128 Stat. 515</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/112/74/dI/tVII/s7034/m/6">Pub. L. 112–74, div. I, title VII, § 7034(m)(6)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1216">125 Stat. 1216</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fad8a1e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Other Laws to GS–16, 17, or 18 Pay Rates</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References in laws to the rates of pay for GS–16, 17, or 18, or to maximum rates of pay under the General Schedule, to be considered references to rates payable under specified sections of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, see section 529 [title I, § 101(c)(1)] of <ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref>, set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5376">section 5376 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id8fad8a1f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id8fad8a20-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of functions of President under this section, see Ex. Ord. No. 12163, <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 56673, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2381">section 2381 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fad8a21-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Entitlement to Benefits for Services Performed Outside United States; Service Exceeding Thirty Months</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Persons appointed, employed, or assigned after <date date="1959-05-19">May 19, 1959</date>, under former <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1787/c">section 1787(c) of this title</ref> or subsec. (d) of this section for the purpose of performing functions under the Mutual Security Act of 1954 (see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1754">section 1754 of this title</ref>) and this chapter, outside the United States, shall not, unless otherwise agreed by the agency in which such benefits may be exercised, be entitled to the benefits provided for by <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3950">section 3950 of this title</ref> in cases in which their service under the appointment, employment, or assignment exceeds thirty months, see Ex. Ord. No. 12163, § 1–602(b), <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 56677, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2381">section 2381 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
