<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8fb26c5f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c"><num value="2394c">§ 2394c.</num><heading> Information on covered United States foreign assistance programs</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fb26c60-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Publication of information</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id8fb26c61-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Update of existing website</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2016-07-15">July 15, 2016</date>, the Secretary of State shall update the Department of State’s website, “ForeignAssistance.gov”, to make publicly available comprehensive, timely, and comparable information on covered United States foreign assistance programs, including all information required under subsection (b) that is available to the Secretary of State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id8fb26c62-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Information sharing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2016-07-15">July 15, 2016</date>, and quarterly thereafter, the head of each Federal department or agency that administers covered United States foreign assistance shall provide the Secretary of State with comprehensive information about the covered United States foreign assistance programs carried out by such department or agency.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id8fb26c63-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Updates to website</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2016-07-15">July 15, 2016</date>, and quarterly thereafter, the Secretary of State shall publish, on the “ForeignAssistance.gov” website or through a successor online publication, the information provided under subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fb26c64-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Matters to be included</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id8fb26c65-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The information described in subsection (a)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8fb26c66-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall be published for each country on a detailed basis, such as award-by-award; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8fb26c67-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> if assistance is provided on a regional level, shall be published for each such region on a detailed basis, such as award-by-award.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id8fb26c68-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Types of information</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id8fb26c69-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/b/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">To ensure the transparency, accountability, and effectiveness of covered United States foreign assistance programs, the information described in subsection (a) shall include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8fb26c6a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/b/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> links to all regional, country, and sector assistance strategies, annual budget documents, congressional budget justifications, and evaluations in accordance with section 3(c)(2)(J);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8fb26c6b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/b/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> basic descriptive summaries for covered United States foreign assistance programs and awards under such programs; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8fb26c6c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/b/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> obligations and expenditures.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id8fb26c6d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/b/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Publication</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Each type of information described in subparagraph (A) shall be published or updated on the appropriate website not later than 90 days after the date on which the information is issued.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id8fb26c6e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/b/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to require a Federal department or agency that administers covered United States foreign assistance to provide any information that does not relate to, or is not otherwise required by, the covered United States foreign assistance programs carried out by such department or agency.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id8fb26c6f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Report in lieu of inclusion</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id8fb26c70-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/b/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Health or security of implementing partners</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the head of a Federal department or agency, in consultation with the Secretary of State, makes a determination that the inclusion of a required item of information online would jeopardize the health or security of an implementing partner or program beneficiary or would require the release of proprietary information of an implementing partner or program beneficiary, the head of the Federal department or agency shall provide such determination in writing to the appropriate congressional committees, including the basis for such determination.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id8fb26c71-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/b/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> National interests of the United States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the Secretary of State makes a determination that the inclusion of a required item of information online would be detrimental to the national interests of the United States, the Secretary of State shall provide such determination, including the basis for such determination, in writing to the appropriate congressional committees.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id8fb26c72-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/b/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Form</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Information provided under this paragraph may be provided in classified form, as appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id8fb26c73-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to comply</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If a Federal department or agency fails to comply with the requirements under paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (a), or subsection (c), with respect to providing information described in subsection (a), and the information is not subject to a determination under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (3) not to make the information publicly available, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the head of such department or agency, not later than one year after <date date="2016-07-15">July 15, 2016</date>, shall submit a consolidated report to the appropriate congressional committees that includes, with respect to each required item of information not made publicly available—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8fb26c74-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a detailed explanation of the reason for not making such information publicly available; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8fb26c75-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> a description of the department’s or agency’s plan and timeline for—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8fb26c76-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/b/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> making such information publicly available; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8fb26c77-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/b/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> ensuring that such information is made publicly available in subsequent years.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fb26c78-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Scope of information</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The online publication required under subsection (a) shall, at a minimum—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fb26c79-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> in each of the fiscal years 2016 through 2019, provide the information required under subsection (b) for fiscal years 2015 through the current fiscal year; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fb26c7a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> for fiscal year 2020 and each fiscal year thereafter, provide the information required under subsection (b) for the immediately preceding 5 fiscal years in a fully searchable form.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fb26c7b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2394c/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development should coordinate the consolidation of processes and data collection and presentation for the Department of State’s website, “ForeignAssistance.gov”, and the United States Agency for International Development’s website, “Explorer.USAID.gov”, to the extent that is possible to maximize efficiencies, no later than the end of fiscal year 2018.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8fb26c7c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/114/191/s4">Pub. L. 114–191, § 4</ref>, <date date="2016-07-15">July 15, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/669">130 Stat. 669</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8fb26c7d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8fb26c7e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8fb26c7f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 3(c)(2)(J), referred to in subsec. (b)(2)(A)(i), is <ref href="/us/pl/114/191/s3/c/2/J">section 3(c)(2)(J) of Pub. L. 114–191</ref>, which is set out as a note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8fb26c80-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2016, and not as part of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8fb26c81-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fb26c82-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Guidelines for Covered United States Foreign Assistance Programs</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/191/s3">Pub. L. 114–191, § 3</ref>, <date date="2016-07-15">July 15, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/667">130 Stat. 667</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/191/s3">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purposes</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The purposes of this section are to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> evaluate the performance of covered United States foreign assistance and its contribution to the policies, strategies, projects, program goals, and priorities undertaken by the Federal Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> support and promote innovative programs to improve effectiveness; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> coordinate the monitoring and evaluation processes of Federal departments and agencies that administer covered United States foreign assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Guidelines</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2016-07-15">July 15, 2016</date>], the President shall set forth guidelines, according to best practices of monitoring and evaluation studies and analyses, for the establishment of measurable goals, performance metrics, and monitoring and evaluation plans that can be applied with reasonable consistency to covered United States foreign assistance.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Objectives of Guidelines.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The guidelines established pursuant to subsection (b) shall provide direction to Federal departments and agencies that administer covered United States foreign assistance on—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> monitoring the use of resources;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> evaluating the outcomes and impacts of covered United States foreign assistance projects and programs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> applying the findings and conclusions of such evaluations to proposed project and program design.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Objectives</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The guidelines established pursuant to subsection (b) shall provide direction to Federal departments and agencies that administer covered United States foreign assistance on how to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> establish annual monitoring and evaluation objectives and timetables to plan and manage the process of monitoring, evaluating, analyzing progress, and applying learning toward achieving results;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> develop specific project monitoring and evaluation plans, including measurable goals and performance metrics, and to identify the resources necessary to conduct such evaluations, which should be covered by program costs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> apply rigorous monitoring and evaluation methodologies to such programs, including through the use of impact evaluations, ex-post evaluations, or other methods, as appropriate, that clearly define program logic, inputs, outputs, intermediate outcomes, and end outcomes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> disseminate guidelines for the development and implementation of monitoring and evaluation programs to all personnel, especially in the field, who are responsible for the design, implementation, and management of covered United States foreign assistance programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> establish methodologies for the collection of data, including baseline data to serve as a reference point against which progress can be measured;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> evaluate, at least once in their lifetime, all programs whose dollar value equals or exceeds the median program size for the relevant office or bureau or an equivalent calculation to ensure the majority of program resources are evaluated;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> conduct impact evaluations on all pilot programs before replicating, or conduct performance evaluations and provide a justification for not conducting an impact evaluation when such an evaluation is deemed inappropriate or impracticable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> develop a clearinghouse capacity for the collection, dissemination, and preservation of knowledge and lessons learned to guide future programs for United States foreign assistance personnel, implementing partners, the donor community, and aid recipient governments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> internally distribute evaluation reports;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="J">“(J)</num><content> publicly report each evaluation, including an executive summary, a description of the evaluation methodology, key findings, appropriate context, including quantitative and qualitative data when available, and recommendations made in the evaluation within 90 days after the completion of the evaluation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="K">“(K)</num><content> undertake collaborative partnerships and coordinate efforts with the academic community, implementing partners, and national and international institutions, as appropriate, that have expertise in program monitoring, evaluation, and analysis when such partnerships provide needed expertise or significantly improve the evaluation and analysis;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="L">“(L)</num><content> ensure verifiable, reliable, and timely data, including from local beneficiaries and stakeholders, are available to monitoring and evaluation personnel to permit the objective evaluation of the effectiveness of covered United States foreign assistance programs, including an assessment of assumptions and limitations in such evaluations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="M">“(M)</num><content> ensure that standards of professional evaluation organizations for monitoring and evaluation efforts are employed, including ensuring the integrity and independence of evaluations, permitting and encouraging the exercise of professional judgment, and providing for quality control and assurance in the monitoring and evaluation process.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">President’s Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2016-07-15">July 15, 2016</date>], the President shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that contains a detailed description of the guidelines established pursuant to subsection (b). The report shall be submitted in unclassified form, but it may contain a classified annex.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Comptroller General’s Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Comptroller General of the United States shall, not later than 18 months after the report required by subsection (d) is submitted to Congress, submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> analyzes the guidelines established pursuant to subsection (b); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> assesses the implementation of the guidelines by the agencies, bureaus, and offices that implement covered United States foreign assistance as outlined in the President’s budget request.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For delegation of functions of President under section 3(b) and (d) of <ref href="/us/pl/114/191">Pub. L. 114–191</ref>, set out above, see Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2017-11-21">Nov. 21, 2017</date>, 82 F.R. 56529, set out below.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="id8fb26c83-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/114/191/s2">Pub. L. 114–191, § 2</ref>, <date date="2016-07-15">July 15, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/666">130 Stat. 666</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/dF/tVI/s1470">Pub. L. 115–254, div. F, title VI, § 1470</ref>(<i>l</i>), <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3517">132 Stat. 3517</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/214/s7">Pub. L. 117–214, § 7</ref>, <date date="2022-10-19">Oct. 19, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2255">136 Stat. 2255</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dE/tLV/s5564/b">Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LV, § 5564(b)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3361">136 Stat. 3361</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dE/tLV/s5564/b">
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“In this Act [enacting this section and provisions set out as notes under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">section 2151 of this title</ref>]:</p>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate congressional committees</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘appropriate congressional committees’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Evaluation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘evaluation’ means, with respect to a covered United States foreign assistance program, the systematic collection and analysis of information about the characteristics and outcomes of the program, including projects conducted under such program, as a basis for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> making judgments and evaluations regarding the program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> improving program effectiveness; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> informing decisions about current and future programming.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered united states foreign assistance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘covered United States foreign assistance’ means assistance authorized under—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.), except for chapter 3 of such part [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2221">22 U.S.C. 2221</ref> et seq.] (relating to International Organizations and Programs);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2346">22 U.S.C. 2346</ref> et seq.; relating to Economic Support Fund);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the Millennium Challenge Act of 2003 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7701">22 U.S.C. 7701</ref> et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> the Food for Peace Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1721">7 U.S.C. 1721</ref> [1691] et seq.);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> the Better Utilization of Investments Leading to Development Act of 2018 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9601">22 U.S.C. 9601</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> the Global Malnutrition Prevention and Treatment Act of 2021 [<ref href="/us/pl/117/214">Pub. L. 117–214</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9301">22 U.S.C. 9301</ref> note]; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> the Global Health Security and International Pandemic Prevention, Preparedness and Response Act of 2022 [<ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dE/tLV">Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LV</ref>, subtitle D; <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151b">22 U.S.C. 2151b</ref> note].”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Amendment by section 1470(<i>l</i>) of <ref href="/us/pl/115/254">Pub. L. 115–254</ref>, adding first par. (3)(E) to <ref href="/us/pl/114/191/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 114–191</ref>, set out above, effective at the end of the transition period, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9681">section 9681 of this title</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/254/s1470/w">section 1470(w) of Pub. L. 115–254</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s905">section 905 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress. Another par. (3)(E) was added by <ref href="/us/pl/117/214/s7">section 7 of Pub. L. 117–214</ref>. <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s5564/b/2">Section 5564(b)(2) of Pub. L. 117–263</ref>, which directed substitution of “; and” for period at end of subpar. (E) of <ref href="/us/pl/114/191/s2/3">section 2(3) of Pub. L. 114–191</ref>, was executed by making the substitution in the second subpar. (E).]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id8fb26c84-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fb26c85-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Authority Under the Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2016</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2017-11-21">Nov. 21, 2017</date>, 82 F.R. 56529, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum for the Director of the Office of Management and Budget</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref>, United States Code, I hereby delegate to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget the functions and authorities vested in the President by sections 3(b) and 3(d) of the Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2016 (<ref href="/us/pl/114/191">Public Law 114–191</ref>) (the “Act”), including updating the guidelines required by section 3(b) as he may think proper, in accordance with the Act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The delegation in this memorandum shall apply to any provision of any future public law that is the same or substantially the same as sections 3(b) and 3(d) of the Act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <i>Federal Register</i>.</p>
<signature>
<name>Donald J. Trump.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
