<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8fb26cb6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2395a"><num value="2395a">§ 2395a.</num><heading> International agreements concerning debt relief; transmittal to congressional committees</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fb26cb7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2395a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/97/113/tVII/s734/a/5">Pub. L. 97–113, title VII, § 734(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1560">95 Stat. 1560</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fb26cb8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2395a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary of State shall transmit to such committees a copy of the text of any agreement with any foreign government which would result in any such debt relief no less than thirty days prior to its entry into force, together with a detailed justification of the interest of the United States in the proposed debt relief. The requirements of this paragraph shall not apply with respect to an agreement if a statutory requirement exists that the amount of the debt relief provided by the agreement may not exceed the amount approved for such purposes in advance in an appropriation Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id8fb26cb9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/424/tVI/s603/a">Pub. L. 95–424, title VI, § 603(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-06">Oct. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/960">92 Stat. 960</ref>; H. Res. 89, <date date="1979-02-05">Feb. 5, 1979</date>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/113/tVII/s734/a/5">Pub. L. 97–113, title VII, § 734(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1560">95 Stat. 1560</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8fb26cba-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8fb26cbb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8fb26cbc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Such committees” and “such debt relief”, referred to in par. (2), mean the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Appropriations of each House of Congress named as the ongoing recipients of any information respecting debt relief negotiations with foreign governments regarding any debts owing to the United States in par. (1) provisions prior to repeal thereof by <ref href="/us/pl/97/113/s734/a/1">section 734(a)(1) of Pub. L. 97–113</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8fb26cbd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section enacted as part of the International Development and Food Assistance Act of 1978, and not as part of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8fb26cbe-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Par. (1). <ref href="/us/pl/97/113">Pub. L. 97–113</ref> struck out par. (1) which required Secretary of State keep the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Appropriations of each House of Congress informed respecting any debt relief negotiations with foreign governments regarding any debts owing to the United States.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8fb26cbf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id8fb26cc0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1978-10-01">Oct. 1, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/424/s605">section 605 of Pub. L. 95–424</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1978 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">section 2151 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fb26cc1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Actions To Provide Bilateral Debt Relief</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/5/tV/s501">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(5) [title V, § 501]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–311, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/108/447/dD/tV/s591/b">Pub. L. 108–447, div. D, title V, § 591(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-12-08">Dec. 8, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3037">118 Stat. 3037</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/102/tV/s578">Pub. L. 109–102, title V, § 578</ref>, <date date="2005-11-14">Nov. 14, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2232">119 Stat. 2232</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/161/dJ/tVI/s699H/b/1">Pub. L. 110–161, div. J, title VI, § 699H(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2007-12-26">Dec. 26, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/2372">121 Stat. 2372</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dJ/tIX/s904/b">Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title IX, § 904(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3086">133 Stat. 3086</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dK/tVII/s7042/j/2">Pub. L. 116–260, div. K, title VII, § 7042(j)(2)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/1772">134 Stat. 1772</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/260/dK/tVII/s7042/j/2">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cancellation of Debt</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to the availability of amounts provided in advance in appropriations Acts, the President shall cancel all amounts owed to the United States (or any agency of the United States) by any country eligible for debt reduction under this section, as a result of loans made or credits extended prior to <date date="1999-06-20">June 20, 1999</date>, under any of the provisions of law specified in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Provisions of Law</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The provisions of law referred to in subsection (a) are the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Sections 221 and 222 of the Foreign Assistance Act [of 1961] [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2181">22 U.S.C. 2181</ref>, 2182].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Arms Export Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Section 5(f) of the Commodity Credit Corporation Charter Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s714c/f">15 U.S.C. 714c(f)</ref>], section 201 of the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s5621">7 U.S.C. 5621</ref>), or section 202 of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s5622">7 U.S.C. 5622</ref>), or predecessor provisions under the Food for Peace Act of 1966.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Title I of the Agricultural Trade Development and Assistance Act of 1954 [now Food for Peace Act] (<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s1701">7 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> The Act of <date date="1941-03-11">March 11, 1941</date> (chapter 11; <ref href="/us/stat/55/31">55 Stat. 31</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s411">22 U.S.C. 411</ref> et seq.; commonly known as the ‘Lend-Lease Act’).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other Debt Reduction Authorities</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority provided in this section is in addition to any other debt relief authority and does not in any way limit such authority.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible Countries</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A country that is performing satisfactorily under an economic reform program shall be eligible for cancellation of debt under this section if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the country, as of <date date="2000-12-31">December 31, 2000</date>, is eligible to borrow from the International Development Association;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the country, as of <date date="2000-12-31">December 31, 2000</date>, is not eligible to borrow from the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the country has outstanding public and publicly guaranteed debt, the net present value of which on <date date="1996-12-31">December 31, 1996</date>, was at least 150 percent of the average annual value of the exports of the country for the period 1994 through 1996; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the country has outstanding public and publicly guaranteed debt, the net present value of which, as of the date the President determines that the country is eligible for debt relief under this section, is at least 150 percent of the annual value of the exports of the country; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the country has outstanding public and publicly guaranteed debt, the net present value of which, as of the date the President determines that the country is eligible for debt relief under this section, is at least 250 percent of the annual fiscal revenues of the country, and has minimum ratios of exports to Gross Domestic Product of 30 percent, and of fiscal revenues to Gross Domestic Product of 15 percent.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Priority</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out subsection (a), the President should seek to leverage scarce foreign assistance and give priority to heavily indebted poor countries with demonstrated need and the capacity to use such relief effectively.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A country shall not be eligible for cancellation of debt under this section if the government of the country—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> has an excessive level of military expenditures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism, as determined by the Secretary of State under [former] section 6(j)(1) of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (50 U.S.C. App. 2405(j)(1)) [former <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4605/j/1">50 U.S.C. 4605(j)(1)</ref>] or section 620A(a) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2371/a">22 U.S.C. 2371(a)</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> is failing to cooperate on international narcotics control matters; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> (including its military or other security forces), engages in a consistent pattern of gross violations of internationally recognized human rights.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional Requirement</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A country which is otherwise eligible to receive cancellation of debt under this section may receive such cancellation only if the country has committed, in connection with a social and economic reform program—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to enable, facilitate, or encourage the implementation of policy changes and institutional reforms under economic reform programs, in a manner that ensures that such policy changes and institutional reforms are designed and adopted through transparent and participatory processes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to adopt an integrated development strategy of the type described in section 1624(a) of the International Financial Institutions Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s262p–7">22 U.S.C. 262p–7</ref>], to support poverty reduction through economic growth, that includes monitorable poverty reduction goals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> to take steps so that the financial benefits of debt relief are applied to programs to combat poverty (in particular through concrete measures to improve economic infrastructure, basic services in education, nutrition, and health, particularly treatment and prevention of the leading causes of mortality) and to redress environmental degradation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> to take steps to strengthen and expand the private sector, encourage increased trade and investment, support the development of free markets, and promote broad-scale economic growth;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> to implement transparent policy making and budget procedures, good governance, and effective anticorruption measures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> to broaden public participation and popular understanding of the principles and goals of poverty reduction, particularly through economic growth, and good governance; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> to promote the participation of citizens and nongovernmental organizations in the economic policy choices of the government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certain Prohibitions Inapplicable</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as the President may otherwise determine for reasons of national security, a cancellation of debt under this section shall not be considered to be assistance for purposes of any provision of law limiting assistance to a country. The authority to provide for cancellation of debt under this section may be exercised notwithstanding section 620(r) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2370/r">22 U.S.C. 2370(r)</ref>], or any similar provision of law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>For the cost (as defined in section 502(5) of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990 [<ref href="/us/usc/t2/s661a/5">2 U.S.C. 661a(5)</ref>]) of the cancellation of any debt under this section, there are authorized to be appropriated to the President such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2000–2025, which shall remain available until expended.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="j">“(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Reports to the Congress</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than December 31 of each year, the President shall prepare and transmit to the Committees on Banking and Financial Services [now Committee on Financial Services], Appropriations, and International Relations [now Committee on Foreign Affairs] of the House of Representatives, and the Committees on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, Foreign Relations, and Appropriations of the Senate a report, which shall be made available to the public, concerning the cancellation of debt under subsection (a), and a detailed description of debt relief provided by the United States as a member of the Paris Club of Official Creditors for the prior fiscal year.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[<ref href="/us/pl/108/447/s591/b">Pub. L. 108–447, § 591(b)</ref>, which directed amendment of <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s501/i">section 501(i) of Public Law 106–113</ref> by substituting “2000–2006” for “2003–2004”, was executed in section 1000(a)(5) [title V, § 501] of div. B of <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref>, set out above, by making substitution for “2000 through 2004”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fb4b6b2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Notification to Congress on Debt Relief Agreements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/391/tV/s548">Pub. L. 102–391, title V, § 548</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1673">106 Stat. 1673</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/391/tV/s548">“The Secretary of State shall transmit to the Appropriations Committees of the Congress and to such other Committees as appropriate, a copy of the text of any agreement with any foreign government which would result in any debt relief no less than thirty days prior to its entry into force, other than one entered into pursuant to this Act, together with a detailed justification of the interest of the United States in the proposed debt relief: <i>Provided</i>, That the term ‘debt relief’ shall include any and all debt prepayment, debt rescheduling, and debt restructuring proposals and agreements: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Secretary of State and the Secretary of the Treasury should in every feasible instance notify the Appropriations Committees of the Congress and such other Committees as appropriate not less than 15 days prior to any formal multilateral or bilateral negotiation for official debt restructuring, rescheduling, or relief: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Secretary of State or the Secretary of the Treasury, as appropriate, shall report not later than February 1 of each year a consolidated statement of the budgetary implications of all debt-related agreements entered into force during the preceding fiscal year.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>Similar provisions were contained in the following prior appropriation acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/513/tV/s550">Pub. L. 101–513, title V, § 550</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2020">104 Stat. 2020</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/167/tV/s555">Pub. L. 101–167, title V, § 555</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1237">103 Stat. 1237</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/461/tV/s557">Pub. L. 100–461, title V, § 557</ref>, <date date="1988-10-01">Oct. 1, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2268-38">102 Stat. 2268–38</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101/e/tV/s563">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(e) [title V, § 563]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1329-131">101 Stat. 1329–131</ref>, 1329–172.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
