<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8fb998e6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2415"><num value="2415">§ 2415.</num><heading> Annual military assistance report</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fb998e7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2415/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Report required</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than February 1 of each year, the President shall transmit to the Congress an annual report for the fiscal year ending the previous September 30.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fb998e8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2415/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Information relating to military assistance and military exports</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each such report shall show the aggregate dollar value and quantity of defense articles (including excess defense articles), defense services, and international military education and training activities authorized by the United States and of such articles, services, and activities provided by the United States, excluding any activity that is reportable under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3091">50 U.S.C. 3091</ref> et seq.], to each foreign country and international organization. The report shall specify, by category, whether such defense articles—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fb998e9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2415/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> were furnished by grant under part II or part V of subchapter II of this chapter or under any other authority of law or by sale under chapter 2 of the Arms Export Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2761">22 U.S.C. 2761</ref> et seq.];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fb998ea-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2415/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> were furnished with the financial assistance of the United States Government, including through loans and guarantees; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fb998eb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2415/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> were licensed for export under section 38 of the Arms Export Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2778">22 U.S.C. 2778</ref>] and, if so, a specification of those defense articles that were exported during the fiscal year covered by the report, including, in the case of defense articles that are firearms controlled under category I of the United States Munitions List, a statement of the aggregate dollar value and quantity of semiautomatic assault weapons, or spare parts for such weapons, the manufacture, transfer, or possession of which is unlawful under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s922">section 922 of title 18</ref>, that were licensed for export during the period covered by the report.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fb998ec-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2415/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability on Internet</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All unclassified portions of such report shall be made available to the public on the Internet through the Department of State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8fb998ed-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, pt. III, § 655, as added <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tXIII/s1324/c">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XIII, § 1324(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/481">110 Stat. 481</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/104/164/tI/s148">Pub. L. 104–164, title I, § 148</ref>, <date date="1996-07-21">July 21, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1435">110 Stat. 1435</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/7/dB/tXIII/s1306">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(7) [div. B, title XIII, § 1306]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–512; <ref href="/us/pl/106/280/tVII/s702">Pub. L. 106–280, title VII, § 702</ref>, <date date="2000-10-06">Oct. 6, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/861">114 Stat. 861</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/228/dB/tXII">Pub. L. 107–228, div. B, title XII</ref>, §§ 1205(c), 1262(b), <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1428">116 Stat. 1428</ref>, 1434.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8fb998ee-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8fb998ef-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8fb998f0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Security Act of 1947, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343">act July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/495">61 Stat. 495</ref>, which was formerly classified principally to chapter 15 (§ 401 et seq.) of Title 50, War and National Defense, prior to editorial reclassification in chapter 44 (§ 3001 et seq.) of Title 50. Title V of the Act is now classified generally to subchapter III (§ 3091 et seq.) of chapter 44 of Title 50. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Arms Export Control Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), is <ref href="/us/pl/90/629">Pub. L. 90–629</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1320">82 Stat. 1320</ref>. Chapter 2 of the Act is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 2761 et seq.) of chapter 39 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id8fb998f1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 2415, <ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, pt. III, § 655, as added <ref href="/us/pl/92/226">Pub. L. 92–226</ref>, pt. III, § 304(b), <date date="1972-02-07">Feb. 7, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/29">86 Stat. 29</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/93/559/s39/a">Pub. L. 93–559, § 39(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-12-30">Dec. 30, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1810">88 Stat. 1810</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/329/tIV/s413/a">Pub. L. 94–329, title IV, § 413(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-06-30">June 30, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/761">90 Stat. 761</ref>, related to limitation in amounts to be expended for assistance to Cambodia, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/95/424/tVI">Pub. L. 95–424, title VI</ref>, §§ 604, 605, <date date="1978-10-06">Oct. 6, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/961">92 Stat. 961</ref>, effective <date date="1978-10-01">Oct. 1, 1978</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8fb998f2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/107/228/s1205/c">Pub. L. 107–228, § 1205(c)</ref>, inserted before period at end “, including, in the case of defense articles that are firearms controlled under category I of the United States Munitions List, a statement of the aggregate dollar value and quantity of semiautomatic assault weapons, or spare parts for such weapons, the manufacture, transfer, or possession of which is unlawful under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s922">section 922 of title 18</ref>, that were licensed for export during the period covered by the report”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/107/228/s1262/b">Pub. L. 107–228, § 1262(b)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (d) as (c) and struck out heading and text of former subsec. (c). Text read as follows: “Each such report shall also include the total amount of military items manufactured outside the United States that were imported into the United States during the fiscal year covered by the report. For each country of origin the report shall show the type of item being imported and the total amount of the items.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/106/280">Pub. L. 106–280</ref> inserted before the period at end “and, if so, a specification of those defense articles that were exported during the fiscal year covered by the report”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/7/tXIII/s1306/a">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(7) [title XIII, § 1306(a)]</ref>, reenacted heading without change and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Each such report shall show the aggregate dollar value and quantity of defense articles (including excess defense articles), defense services, and international military education and training authorized by the United States, excluding that which is pursuant to activies reportable under title V of the National Security Act of 1947, to each foreign country and international organization. The report shall specify, by category, whether such defense articles—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) were furnished by grant under part II or part V of subchapter II of this chapter or under any other authority of law or by sale under chapter 2 of the Arms Export Control Act; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) were licensed for export under section 38 of the Arms Export Control Act.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/7/tXIII/s1306/b">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(7) [title XIII, § 1306(b)]</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—<ref href="/us/pl/104/164">Pub. L. 104–164</ref> substituted “Annual military assistance report” for “Annual report on military assistance, military exports, and military imports” in section catchline and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(a) <inline class="small-caps">Report Required</inline>.—Not later than February 1 of each of 1996 and 1997, the President shall transmit to Congress a report concerning military assistance authorized or furnished for the fiscal year ending the previous September 30.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(b) <inline class="small-caps">Information Relating to Military Assistance and Military Exports</inline>.—Each such report shall show the aggregate dollar value and quantity of defense articles (including excess defense articles) and defense services, and of military education and training, authorized or furnished by the United States to each foreign country and international organization. The report shall specify, by category, whether those articles and services, and that education and training, were furnished by grant under part II or part V of subchapter II of this chapter or by sale under chapter 2 of the Arms Export Control Act or were authorized by commercial sale licensed under section 38 of the Arms Export Control Act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(c) <inline class="small-caps">Information Relating to Military Imports</inline>.—Each such report shall also include the total amount of military items of non-United States manufacture that were imported into the United States during the fiscal year covered by the report. The report shall show the country of origin, the type of item being imported, and the total amount of items.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id8fb998f3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id8fb998f4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of functions of President under this section, see Ex. Ord. No. 12163, <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 56673, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2381">section 2381 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
