<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8fbbe283-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f"><num value="2421f">§ 2421f.</num><heading> Sustainability requirements for certain capital projects in connection with overseas contingency operations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fbbe284-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id8fbbe285-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Commencing 60 days after <date date="2013-01-02">January 2, 2013</date>—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8fbbe286-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> amounts authorized to be appropriated for the Department of Defense may not be obligated or expended for a capital project described in subsection (b) unless the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the United States commander of military operations in the country in which the project will be carried out, completes an assessment on the necessity and sustainability of the project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8fbbe287-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> amounts authorized to be appropriated for the Department of State may not be obligated or expended for a capital project described in subsection (b) unless the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Chief of Mission in the country in which the project will be carried out, completes an assessment on the necessity and sustainability of the project; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8fbbe288-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> amounts authorized to be appropriated for the United States Agency for International Development may not be obligated or expended for a capital project described in subsection (b) unless the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, in consultation with the Mission Director and the Chief of Mission in the country in which the project will be carried out, completes an assessment on the necessity and sustainability of the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id8fbbe289-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Elements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each assessment on a capital project under this subsection shall include, but not be limited to, the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8fbbe28a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> An estimate of the total cost of the completed project to the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8fbbe28b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> An estimate of the financial and other requirements necessary for the host government to sustain the project on an annual basis after completion of the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8fbbe28c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> An assessment whether the host government has the capacity (in both financial and human resources) to maintain and use the project after completion.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8fbbe28d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/a/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> A description of any arrangements for the sustainment of the project following its completion if the host government lacks the capacity (in financial or human resources) to maintain the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8fbbe28e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/a/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> An assessment whether the host government has requested or expressed its need for the project, and an explanation of the decision to proceed with the project absent such request or need.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8fbbe28f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/a/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> An assessment by the Secretary of Defense, where applicable, of the effect of the project on the military mission of the United States in the country concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fbbe290-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Covered capital projects</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id8fbbe291-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraph (2), a capital project described in this subsection is any capital project overseas for an overseas contingency operation for the benefit of a host country and funded by the Department of Defense, the Department of State, or the United States Agency for International Development, as applicable, if the capital project—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8fbbe292-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in the case of a project that directly supports building the capacity of indigenous security forces in the host country, has an estimated value in excess of $10,000,000;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8fbbe293-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case of any project not covered by subparagraph (A) that is to be funded by the Department of State or the United States Agency for International Development, has an estimated value in excess of $5,000,000; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8fbbe294-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> in the case of any other project, has an estimated value in excess of $2,000,000.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id8fbbe295-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Exclusion</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A capital project described in this subsection does not include any project for military construction (as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s114/b">section 114(b) of title 10</ref>) or a military family housing project under section 2821 of such title.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fbbe296-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of State, or the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, as applicable, may waive the limitation in subsection (a) in order to initiate a capital project if such Secretary or the Administrator, as the case may be, determines that the project is in the national security, diplomatic, or humanitarian interests of the United States. In the first report submitted under subsection (d) after any waiver under this subsection, such Secretary or the Administrator shall include a detailed justification of such waiver. Not later than 90 days after issuing a waiver under this subsection, such Secretary or the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress the assessment described in subsection (a) with respect to the capital project concerned.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fbbe297-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Semi-annual reports</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id8fbbe298-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 30 days after the end of any fiscal-year half-year in which the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of State, or the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development conducts an assessment under subsection (a), such Secretary or the Administrator, as the case may be, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report setting forth each assessment so conducted during such fiscal-year half-year, including the elements of each capital project so assessed specified in subsection (a)(2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id8fbbe299-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional elements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In addition to the matters provided for in paragraph (1), each report under that paragraph shall include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8fbbe29a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> For each capital project covered by such report, an evaluation (other than by amount of funds expended) of the effectiveness of such project, including, at a minimum, the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8fbbe29b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/d/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The stated goals of the project.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8fbbe29c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/d/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The actions taken to assess and verify whether the project has met the stated goals of the project or is on track to meet such goals when completed.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8fbbe29d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/d/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> The current and anticipated levels of involvement of local governments, communities, and individuals in the project.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8fbbe29e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> For each country or region in which a capital project covered by such report is being carried out, an assessment of the current and anticipated risks of corruption or fraud in connection with such project.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id8fbbe29f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Form</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each report shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fbbe2a0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fbbe2a1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8fbbe2a2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8fbbe2a3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fbbe2a4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “capital project” has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2421e">section 2421e of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fbbe2a5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2421f/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The term “overseas contingency operation” means a military operation outside the United States and its territories and possessions that is a contingency operation (as that term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s101/a/13">section 101(a)(13) of title 10</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8fbbe2a6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dA/tXII/s1273">Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XII, § 1273</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2023">126 Stat. 2023</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8fbbe2a7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8fbbe2a8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8fbbe2a9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013, and not as part of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8fbbe2aa-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id8fbbe2ab-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Reform of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Sixteenth Congress, <date date="2019-01-09">Jan. 9, 2019</date>. Committee on Oversight and Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Accountability of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Eighteenth Congress, <date date="2023-01-09">Jan. 9, 2023</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
