<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8fbbe2ec-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2428b"><num value="2428b">§ 2428b.</num><heading> Special security assistance for modernization of Armed Forces of Korea</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fbbe2ed-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2428b/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer authority of President of defense articles and services located in Korea; applicable terms and conditions; reimbursement</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fbbe2ee-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2428b/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The President is authorized until <date date="1982-12-31">December 31, 1982</date>—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fbbe2ef-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2428b/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to transfer, without reimbursement, to the Republic of Korea, only in conjunction with the withdrawal of the 2d Infantry Division and support forces from Korea, such United States Government-owned defense articles as he may determine which are located in Korea in the custody of units of the United States Army scheduled to depart from Korea; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fbbe2f0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2428b/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to furnish to the Republic of Korea, without reimbursement, defense services (including technical and operational training) in Korea directly related to the United States Government-owned defense articles transferred to the Republic of Korea under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fbbe2f1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2428b/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any transfer under the authority of this section shall be made in accordance with all the terms and conditions of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.] applicable to the furnishing of defense articles and defense services under chapter 2 of part II of that Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2311">22 U.S.C. 2311</ref> et seq.], except that no funds heretofore or hereafter appropriated under that Act shall be available to reimburse any agency of the United States Government for any such transfer or related services.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fbbe2f2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2428b/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional transfer authority of President of defense articles located outside of Korea; prerequisites for determinations respecting transfers; report by President to Congress of determinations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order that transfers of defense articles under subsection (a) will not cause significant adverse impact on the readiness of the Armed Forces of the United States, the President is authorized, in lieu of such transfers, to transfer additional defense articles from the stocks of the Department of Defense, wherever located, to the Republic of Korea to compensate for the military capability of defense articles withdrawn from Korea in any case where he determines that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fbbe2f3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2428b/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the transfer of specific defense articles located in Korea would have a significant adverse impact on the readiness of the United States Armed Forces;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fbbe2f4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2428b/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the defense capability provided by those defense articles is needed by the Armed Forces of the Republic of Korea in order to maintain the military balance on the Korean peninsula; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fbbe2f5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2428b/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a comparable defense capability could be provided by less advanced defense articles in the stocks of the Department of Defense which could be transferred without significant adverse impact on the readiness of the United States Armed Forces.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The President shall report to the Congress each determination made under this subsection prior to the transfer of the defense articles described in such determination.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fbbe2f6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2428b/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Report by President to Congress of types, etc., of transferred defense articles</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall transmit to the Congress, together with the presentation materials for security assistance programs proposed for each fiscal year through and including the fiscal year 1983, a report describing the types, quantities, and value of defense articles furnished or intended to be furnished to the Republic of Korea under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fbbe2f7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2428b/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/97/113/tVII/s734/a/12">Pub. L. 97–113, title VII, § 734(a)(12)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1560">95 Stat. 1560</ref></heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fbbe2f8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2428b/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Congressional policy respecting further troop withdrawals</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fbbe2f9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2428b/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> It is the sense of the Congress that further withdrawal of ground forces of the United States from the Republic of Korea may seriously risk upsetting the military balance in that region and requires full advance consultation with the Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fbbe2fa-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2428b/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/97/113/tVII/s734/a/12">Pub. L. 97–113, title VII, § 734(a)(12)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1560">95 Stat. 1560</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8fbbe2fb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/384/s23">Pub. L. 95–384, § 23</ref>, <date date="1978-09-26">Sept. 26, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/743">92 Stat. 743</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/113/tVII/s734/a/12">Pub. L. 97–113, title VII, § 734(a)(12)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1560">95 Stat. 1560</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8fbbe2fc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8fbbe2fd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8fbbe2fe-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, <date date="1961-09-04">Sept. 4, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/424">75 Stat. 424</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter (§ 2151 et seq.). Chapter 2 of part II of that Act is classified generally to part II (§ 2311 et seq.) of subchapter II of this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">section 2151 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8fbbe2ff-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the International Security Assistance Act of 1978, and not as part of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8fbbe300-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/113">Pub. L. 97–113</ref> struck out subsec. (d) which required Presidential reports to Congress respecting viability of troop withdrawals from Korea.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/97/113">Pub. L. 97–113</ref> struck out par. (2) which required Presidential reports to Congress respecting effect of further troop withdrawals from Korea.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
