<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8fcef523-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2507"><num value="2507">§ 2507.</num><heading> Training program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fcef524-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2507/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicants for enrollment and enrolled volunteers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall make provision for such training, including training under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2507a">section 2507a of this title</ref>, as the President deems appropriate for each applicant for enrollment as a volunteer and each enrolled volunteer. All of the provisions of this chapter applicable respectively to volunteers and volunteer leaders shall be applicable to applicants for enrollment as such during any period of training occurring prior to enrollment, and the respective terms “volunteers” and “volunteer leaders” shall include such applicants during any such period of training. As part of the training provided to all volunteers under subsection (a), and in coordination with the Inspector General of the Peace Corps, the President shall provide all volunteers with information regarding the mandate of the Inspector General and the availability (including contact information) of the Inspector General and the Office of Victim Advocacy as a resource for volunteers. The President shall ensure that volunteers receive such information at least once during training that occurs prior to enrollment and at least once during each significant instance of training after enrollment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fcef525-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2507/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Citizen trainees for voluntary programs; foreign nationals as trainees; advances of funds or reimbursement basis; use of credits</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President may also make provision, on the basis of advances of funds or reimbursement to the United States, for training for citizens of the United States, other than those referred to in subsection (a) of this section, who have been selected for service abroad in programs not carried out under authority of this chapter which are similar to those authorized by this chapter. The provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2508">section 2508 of this title</ref> shall apply, on a similar advance of funds or a reimbursement basis, with respect to persons while within the United States for training under authority of this subsection. Advances or reimbursements received under this subsection may be credited to the current applicable appropriation, fund, or account and shall be available for the purposes for which such appropriation, fund, or account is authorized to be used.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fcef526-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2507/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Training records</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall implement procedures to maintain a record verifying each individual completing training provided to meet each requirement in this section and sections 2507a, 2507b, 2507f, and 2507g(b) of this title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8fcef527-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/293/tI/s8">Pub. L. 87–293, title I, § 8</ref>, <date date="1961-09-22">Sept. 22, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/616">75 Stat. 616</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/511/tIX/s904">Pub. L. 102–511, title IX, § 904</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3356">106 Stat. 3356</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/57/s8/a/2">Pub. L. 112–57, § 8(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-11-21">Nov. 21, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/745">125 Stat. 745</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/256/tII/s201">Pub. L. 115–256, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2018-10-09">Oct. 9, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3654">132 Stat. 3654</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8fcef528-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8fcef529-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8fcef52a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/87/293">Pub. L. 87–293</ref>, <date date="1961-09-22">Sept. 22, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/612">75 Stat. 612</ref>, known as the Peace Corps Act. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2501">section 2501 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8fcef52b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/115/256/s201/1">Pub. L. 115–256, § 201(1)</ref> substituted “the President deems” for “he deems” and inserted at end “As part of the training provided to all volunteers under subsection (a), and in coordination with the Inspector General of the Peace Corps, the President shall provide all volunteers with information regarding the mandate of the Inspector General and the availability (including contact information) of the Inspector General and the Office of Victim Advocacy as a resource for volunteers. The President shall ensure that volunteers receive such information at least once during training that occurs prior to enrollment and at least once during each significant instance of training after enrollment.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/115/256/s201/2">Pub. L. 115–256, § 201(2)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/112/57">Pub. L. 112–57</ref> inserted “, including training under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2507a">section 2507a of this title</ref>,” after “for such training”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/511">Pub. L. 102–511</ref> struck out subsec. (c) which read as follows: “Training hereinabove provided for shall include instruction in the philosophy, strategy, tactics, and menace of communism.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id8fcef52c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id8fcef52d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of President under this section delegated to Director of Peace Corps by section 1–103 of Ex. Ord. No. 12137, <date date="1979-05-16">May 16, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 29023, eff. <date date="1979-05-16">May 16, 1979</date>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2501">section 2501 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
