<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8fcef5d7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2509"><num value="2509">§ 2509.</num><heading> Presidential powers and authorities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fcef5d8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2509/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Contract authority; assignment of volunteers; acceptance of voluntary services and gifts and transfers of property; personal service contracts</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In furtherance of the purposes of this chapter, the President may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fcef5d9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2509/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> enter into, perform, and modify contracts and agreements and otherwise cooperate with any agency of the United States Government or of any State or any subdivision thereof, other governments and departments and agencies thereof, and educational institutions, voluntary agencies, farm organizations, labor unions, and other organizations, individuals and firms;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fcef5da-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2509/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> assign volunteers in special cases to temporary duty with international organizations and agencies when the Secretary of State determines that such assignment would serve the purposes of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fcef5db-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2509/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> assign volunteers to duty or otherwise make them available to any entity referred to in paragraph (1), in order to assist such organizations and agencies in providing development or other relief assistance to displaced persons and refugees in any country, if the government of the country agrees to such assignment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fcef5dc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2509/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> accept in the name of the Peace Corps and employ or transfer in furtherance of the purposes of this chapter (A) voluntary services notwithstanding the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1342">section 1342 of title 31</ref>, and (B) any money or property (real, personal or mixed, tangible or intangible) received by gift, devise, bequest, or otherwise; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fcef5dd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2509/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> contract with individuals for personal services abroad, and with aliens (abroad or within the United States) for personal services within the United States: <i>Provided</i>, That no such person shall be deemed an officer or employee or otherwise in the service or employment of the United States Government for the purposes of any law administered by the Office of Personnel Management (except that the President may determine the applicability to such individuals of provisions of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3901">22 U.S.C. 3901</ref> et seq.)).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fcef5de-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2509/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Claim settlements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, whenever the President determines that it will further the purposes of this chapter, the President, under such regulations as he may prescribe, may settle and pay, in an amount not exceeding $20,000, any claim against the United States, for loss of or damage to real or personal property (including loss of occupancy or use thereof) belonging to, or for personal injury or death of, any person not a citizen or resident of the United States, where such claim arises abroad out of the act or omission of any Peace Corps employee or out of the act or omission of any volunteer, but only if such claim is presented in writing within one year after it accrues. Any amount paid in settlement of any claim under this subsection shall be accepted by the claimant in full satisfaction thereof and shall bar any further action or proceeding thereon.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fcef5df-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2509/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Five-year contract authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to any future action of the Congress, a contract or agreement which entails commitments for the expenditure of funds available for the purposes of this chapter, including commitments for the purpose of paying or providing for allowances and other benefits of volunteers authorized by sections 2504 and 2505 of this title, may extend at any time for not more than five years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fcef5e0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2509/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver of certain Federal laws</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever the President determines it to be in furtherance of the purposes of this chapter, functions authorized by this chapter may be performed without regard to such provisions of law (other than sections 3101(a) and (c), 3104, 3106, 3301(b)(2), and 6101 of title 41, and the Renegotiation Act of 1951, as amended) regulating the making, performance, amendment, or modification of contracts and the expenditure of Government funds as the President may specify.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fcef5e1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2509/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Allocation of funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President may allocate or transfer to any agency of the United States Government any funds available for carrying out the purposes of this chapter including any advance received by the United States from any country or international organization under authority of this chapter, but not to exceed 20 per centum in the aggregate of such funds may be allocated or transferred to agencies other than the Peace Corps. Such funds shall be available for obligation and expenditure for the purposes of this chapter in accordance with authority granted in this chapter or under authority governing the activities of the agencies of the United States Government to which such funds are allocated or transferred.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fcef5e2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2509/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Utilization of other Government agency services and facilities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any officer of the United States Government carrying out functions under this chapter may utilize the services and facilities of, or procure commodities from, any agency of the United States Government as the President shall direct, or with the consent of the head of such agency, and funds allocated pursuant to this subsection to any such agency may be established in separate appropriation accounts on the books of the Treasury.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fd165e3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2509/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Reimbursement for commodities, services, and facilities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of any commodity, service, or facility procured from any agency of the United States Government under this chapter, reimbursement or payment shall be made to such agency from funds available under this chapter. Such reimbursement or payment shall be at replacement cost, or, if required by law, at actual cost, or at any other price authorized by law and agreed to by the owning or disposing agency. The amount of any such reimbursement or payment shall be credited to current applicable appropriations, funds, or accounts from which there may be procured replacements of similar commodities, services, or facilities, except that where such appropriations, funds, or accounts are not reimbursable except by reason of this subsection, and when the owning or disposing agency determines that such replacement is not necessary, any funds received in payment therefor shall be covered into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fd165e4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2509/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Hospitalization and medical treatment for Foreign Service local employees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President may provide hospitalization and medical treatment to Foreign Service local employees who are within the United States for training related to their employment under this chapter, for illnesses, injuries, or conditions other than those arising out of and in the course of employment, which, in the judgment of the President, began during such employee’s travel related to such training or so near to the beginning of such travel that the onset of the illness, injury, or condition could not have been known, and for which immediate medical treatment or hospitalization is reasonably required.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fd165e5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2509/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Procurement of legal services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of the Peace Corps shall have the same authority as is available to the Secretary of State under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2698/a">section 2698(a) of this title</ref>. For purposes of this subsection, the reference in such <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2698/a">section 2698(a) of this title</ref> to a principal officer of the Foreign Service shall be deemed to be a reference to a Peace Corps representative and the reference in such section to a member of the Foreign Service shall be deemed to be a reference to a person employed, appointed, or assigned under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fd165e6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2509/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Malpractice protection</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2702">section 2702 of this title</ref> shall apply to volunteers and persons employed, appointed, or assigned under this chapter, and to individuals employed under personal services contracts to furnish medical services abroad pursuant to subsection (a)(5) of this section..<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002174">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002174"><num>1</num> So in original.</note> For purposes of this subsection, references to the Secretary in subsection (b) of such section shall be deemed to be references to the Director of the Peace Corps, references to the Secretary in subsection (f) of such section shall be deemed to be references to the President, and the reference in subsection (g) of such section to a principal representative of the United States shall be deemed to be a reference to a Peace Corps representative.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fd165e7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2509/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Opening or closing overseas offices and country programs</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fd165e8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2509/k/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Director of the Peace Corps may not open, close, significantly reduce, or suspend a domestic or overseas office or country program unless the Director has notified and consulted with the appropriate congressional committees at least 15 days in advance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fd165e9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2509/k/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Director of the Peace Corps may waive the application of paragraph (1) for a period of not more than 5 days after an action described in such paragraph if the Director determines such action is necessary to ameliorate a substantial security risk to Peace Corps volunteers or other Peace Corps personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fd165ea-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2509/k/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> For the purposes of this subsection, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fd165eb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2509/k/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fd165ec-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2509/k/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8fd165ed-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/293/tI/s10">Pub. L. 87–293, title I, § 10</ref>, <date date="1961-09-22">Sept. 22, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/617">75 Stat. 617</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/200/s5">Pub. L. 88–200, § 5</ref>, <date date="1963-12-13">Dec. 13, 1963</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/77/360">77 Stat. 360</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/134/s6">Pub. L. 89–134, § 6</ref>, <date date="1965-08-24">Aug. 24, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/551">79 Stat. 551</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/572/s6">Pub. L. 89–572, § 6</ref>, <date date="1966-09-13">Sept. 13, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/765">80 Stat. 765</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/49/s2">Pub. L. 93–49, § 2</ref>, <date date="1973-06-25">June 25, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/99">87 Stat. 99</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/331/s5/a">Pub. L. 95–331, § 5(a)</ref>, (c), <date date="1978-08-02">Aug. 2, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/414">92 Stat. 414</ref>, 415; <ref href="/us/pl/97/113/tVI/s604/a">Pub. L. 97–113, title VI, § 604(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1543">95 Stat. 1543</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/tVI/s602">Pub. L. 103–236, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/491">108 Stat. 491</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/30/s2/b/4">Pub. L. 106–30, § 2(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="1999-05-21">May 21, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/56">113 Stat. 56</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/112/57/s5/2">Pub. L. 112–57, § 5(2)</ref>, <date date="2011-11-21">Nov. 21, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/744">125 Stat. 744</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/256/tII/s203">Pub. L. 115–256, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2018-10-09">Oct. 9, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3655">132 Stat. 3655</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8fd165ee-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8fd165ef-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8fd165f0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/87/293">Pub. L. 87–293</ref>, <date date="1961-09-22">Sept. 22, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/612">75 Stat. 612</ref>, known as the Peace Corps Act. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2501">section 2501 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Foreign Service Act of 1980, referred to in subsec. (a)(5), is <ref href="/us/pl/96/465">Pub. L. 96–465</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2071">94 Stat. 2071</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 52 (§ 3901 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3901">section 3901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Renegotiation Act of 1951, as amended, referred to in subsec. (d), is <ref href="/us/act/1951-03-23/ch15">act Mar. 23, 1951, ch. 15</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/65/7">65 Stat. 7</ref>, which was classified principally to section 1211 et seq. of the former Appendix to Title 50, War and National Defense, prior to its omission from the Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8fd165f1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (d), “sections 3101(a) and (c), 3104, 3106, 3301(b)(2), and 6101 of title 41” substituted for “section 3709 of the Revised Statutes of the United States, as amended, section 302 of the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949,” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s6/c">Pub. L. 111–350, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3854">124 Stat. 3854</ref>, which Act enacted Title 41, Public Contracts.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8fd165f2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/115/256">Pub. L. 115–256</ref> added subsec. (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/112/57">Pub. L. 112–57</ref> substituted “the purposes of any law administered by the Office of Personnel Management (except that the President may determine the applicability to such individuals of provisions of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3901">22 U.S.C. 3901</ref> et seq.))” for “any purpose”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/106/30">Pub. L. 106–30</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1342">section 1342 of title 31</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s665/b">31 U.S.C. 665(b)</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s602/a">Pub. L. 103–236, § 602(a)</ref>, which directed amendment of subsec. (c) by substituting “five years” for “thirty six months”, was executed by making the substitution for “thirty-six months” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s602/b">Pub. L. 103–236, § 602(b)</ref>, inserted before period at end of first sentence “, and to individuals employed under personal services contracts to furnish medical services abroad pursuant to subsection (a)(5) of this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsecs. (i), (j). <ref href="/us/pl/97/113">Pub. L. 97–113</ref> added subsecs. (i) and (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/95/331/s5/a/1">Pub. L. 95–331, § 5(a)(1)</ref>, struck out proviso limiting to no more than 125 Peace Corps volunteers or volunteer leaders the number assignable to the described organizations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3) to (5). <ref href="/us/pl/95/331/s5/c">Pub. L. 95–331, § 5(c)</ref>, added par. (3) and redesignated former pars. (3) and (4) as (4) and (5), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/331/s5/a/2">Pub. L. 95–331, § 5(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “$20,000” for “$10,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/95/331/s5/a/3">Pub. L. 95–331, § 5(a)(3)</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/93/49">Pub. L. 93–49</ref> excepted from waiver of Federal laws the application of sections 5 and 252 of title 41.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/89/572">Pub. L. 89–572</ref> inserted “or transfer” after “and employ” and struck out “, and transfer such money or property to the government or other entities of the country or area with which the volunteers are serving, when such transfers would further the general purposes of the chapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/89/134">Pub. L. 89–134</ref> inserted “money or” after “and transfer such”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1963—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/88/200">Pub. L. 88–200</ref> inserted provision for transfer of property.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8fd165f3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id8fd165f4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/331/s5/b">Pub. L. 95–331, § 5(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-08-02">Aug. 2, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/415">92 Stat. 415</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/331/s5/b">“The amendment made by paragraph (2) of subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to claims made after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1978-08-02">Aug. 2, 1978</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fd165f5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prohibition Against Use of Funds Appropriated After <date date="1981-02-15">February 15, 1981</date>, and Before <date date="1981-12-29">December 29, 1981</date>, for Legal Services or Malpractice Protection</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/113/tVI/s604/c">Pub. L. 97–113, title VI, § 604(c)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1543">95 Stat. 1543</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/113/tVI/s604/c">“To the extent that the authorities provided by the amendments made by subsection (a) [enacting subsecs. (i) and (j) of this section] are authorities which are not applicable with respect to the Peace Corps immediately before the enactment of this Act [<date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>] and which require the expenditure of funds, those authorities may not be exercised using any funds appropriated after <date date="1981-02-15">February 15, 1981</date>, and before the date of the enactment of this Act.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id8fd165f6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id8fd165f7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions; Allocation of Funds</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Funds available to President under this chapter allocated to and functions of President under this section, except subsec. (d) and those functions under subsec. (f) relating to directing agencies to provide services, facilities, and commodities to officers carrying out functions under this chapter, were delegated to Director of Peace Corps by sections 1–103 and 1–301(a), (d) of Ex. Ord. No. 12137, <date date="1979-05-16">May 16, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 29203, eff. <date date="1979-05-16">May 16, 1979</date>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2501">section 2501 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fd165f8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Waiver of Certain Laws by President Under Subsec. (d)</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For determination under subsec. (d) of this section that it is in the furtherance of the purposes of this chapter and that the functions under this chapter may be performed without regard to the applicable laws specified in section 1 and 2 of Ex. Ord. No. 11223, <date date="1965-05-12">May 12, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 6635, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2393">section 2393 of this title</ref>, with certain limitations see section 1–402 of Ex. Ord. No. 12137, <date date="1979-05-16">May 16, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 29203, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2501">section 2501 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
