<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8fd165fd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511"><num value="2511">§ 2511.</num><heading> Peace Corps National Advisory Council</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fd165fe-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A Peace Corps National Advisory Council (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Council”) shall be established in accordance with the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fd165ff-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Functions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fd16600-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Council shall advise and consult with the President and the Director of the Peace Corps with regard to policies and programs designed to further the purposes of this chapter and shall, as the Council considers appropriate, periodically report to the Congress with regard to the Peace Corps.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fd16601-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Members of the Council shall (subject to subsection (d)(1)) conduct on-site inspections, and make examinations, of the activities of the Peace Corps in the United States and in other countries in order to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fd16602-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> evaluate the accomplishments of the Peace Corps;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fd16603-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> assess the potential capabilities and the future role of the Peace Corps;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fd16604-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> make recommendations to the President, the Director of the Peace Corps, and, as the Council considers appropriate, the Congress, for the purpose of guiding the future direction of the Peace Corps and of helping to ensure that the purposes and programs of the Peace Corps are carried out in ways that are economical, efficient, responsive to changing needs in developing countries and to changing relationships among people, and in accordance with law; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fd16605-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> make such other evaluations, assessments, and recommendations as the Council considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fd16606-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Council may provide for public participation in its activities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fd16607-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Membership</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fd16608-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Persons appointed as members of the Council shall be broadly representative of the general public, including educational institutions, private volunteer agencies, private industry, farm organizations, labor unions, different regions of the United States, different educational, economic, racial, and national backgrounds and age groupings, and both sexes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fd16609-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fd1660a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Council shall consist of fifteen voting members who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. At least seven of such members shall be former Peace Corps volunteers, and not more than eight of such members shall be members of the same political party.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fd1660b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The first appointments of members of the Council under this paragraph shall be made not more than sixty days after <date date="1985-08-08">August 8, 1985</date>, and, solely for purposes of determining the expiration of their terms, shall be deemed to take effect on the sixtieth day after <date date="1985-08-08">August 8, 1985</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fd1660c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> No member appointed under this paragraph may be an officer or employee of the United States Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fd1660d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/c/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Of the members initially appointed under this paragraph, eight shall be appointed to 1-year terms and seven shall be appointed to 2-year terms. Thereafter, all appointed members shall be appointed to 2-year terms.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fd1660e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/c/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> A member of the Council appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term for which the member’s predecessor was appointed shall be appointed only for the remainder of that term.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fd1660f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/c/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> No member of the Council may serve for more than two consecutive 2-year terms.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fd16610-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/c/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> Members of the Council shall serve at the pleasure of the President.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fd16611-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/c/2/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> An appointed member of the Council may be removed by a vote of nine members for malfeasance in office, for persistent neglect of or inability to discharge duties, or for offenses involving moral turpitude, and for no other cause.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fd16612-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/c/2/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> Within thirty days after any vacancy occurs in the office of an appointed member of the Council, the President shall nominate an individual to fill the vacancy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fd16613-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In addition to the voting members of the Council, the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the Agency for International Development, or their designees, and the Director and Deputy Director of the Peace Corps, shall be non-voting members, ex officio, of the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fd16614-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fd16615-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (2), a member of the Council who is not an officer or employee of the United States Government—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fd16616-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall be paid compensation out of funds made available for the purposes of this chapter at the daily equivalent of the highest rate payable under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5332">section 5332 of title 5</ref> for each day (including travel time) during which the member is engaged in the actual performance of duties as a Council member, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8fd16617-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> while away from his or her home or regular place of business on necessary travel, as determined by the Director of the Peace Corps, in the actual performance of duties as a Council member, shall be paid per diem, travel, and transportation expenses in the same manner as is provided under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fd16618-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A member of the Council may not be paid compensation under paragraph (1)(A) for more than twenty days in any calendar year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fd16619-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Quorum</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A majority of the voting members of the Council shall constitute a quorum for the purposes of transacting any business.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fd1661a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Financial interests of members</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A member of the Council shall disclose to the Council the existence of any direct or indirect financial interest of that member in any particular matter before the Council and may not vote or otherwise participate as a Council member with respect to that particular matter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fd1661b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Chair and Vice Chair</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">At its first meeting and at its first regular meeting in each calendar year thereafter, the Council shall elect a Chair and Vice Chair from among its appointed members who are citizens of the United States. The Chair and Vice Chair may not both be members of the same political party.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fd1661c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Meetings, bylaws, and regulations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fd1661d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Council shall hold a regular meeting during each calendar quarter and shall meet at the call of the President, the Director of the Peace Corps, the Council’s Chair, or one-fourth of its members.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8fd1661e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Council shall prescribe such bylaws and regulations as it considers necessary to carry out its functions. Such bylaws and regulations shall include procedures for fixing the time and place of meetings, giving or waiving of notice of meetings, and keeping of minutes of meetings.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fd1661f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports to the President and the Director</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than <date date="1988-01-01">January 1, 1988</date>, and not later than January 1 of each second year thereafter, the Council shall submit to the President and the Director of the Peace Corps a report on its views on the programs and activities of the Peace Corps. Each report shall contain a summary of the advice and recommendations provided by the Council to the President and the Director during the period covered by the report and such recommendations (including recommendations for administrative or legislative action) as the Council considers appropriate to make to the Congress. Within ninety days after receiving each such report, the President shall submit to the Congress a copy of the report, together with any comments concerning the report that the President or the Director considers appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8fd16620-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2511/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrative assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of the Peace Corps shall make available to the Council such personnel, administrative support services, and technical assistance as are necessary to carry out its functions effectively.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8fd16621-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/293/tI/s12">Pub. L. 87–293, title I, § 12</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/83/tXI/s1104/a">Pub. L. 99–83, title XI, § 1104(a)</ref>, <date date="1985-08-08">Aug. 8, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/273">99 Stat. 273</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8fd16622-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8fd16623-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8fd16624-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (b)(1) and (d)(1)(A), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/87/293">Pub. L. 87–293</ref>, <date date="1961-09-22">Sept. 22, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/612">75 Stat. 612</ref>, known as the Peace Corps Act. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2501">section 2501 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id8fd16625-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 2511, <ref href="/us/pl/87/293/tI/s12">Pub. L. 87–293, title I, § 12</ref>, <date date="1961-09-22">Sept. 22, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/619">75 Stat. 619</ref>, established Peace Corps National Advisory Council and set forth its composition, functions, and terms of members, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/92/352/tIV/s403">Pub. L. 92–352, title IV, § 403</ref>, <date date="1972-07-13">July 13, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/495">86 Stat. 495</ref>, effective 90 days after <date date="1972-07-13">July 13, 1972</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8fd16626-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id8fd16627-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1985-10-01">Oct. 1, 1985</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/83/s1301">section 1301 of Pub. L. 99–83</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1985 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151–1">section 2151–1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fd16628-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, of provisions in subsec. (i) of this section relating to requirement that the President submit to Congress a copy of each report received under subsec. (i), see <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, and page 14 of House Document No. 103–7.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fd16629-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Advisory Councils</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Advisory councils established after <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on the date of their establishment, unless, in the case of a council established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such council is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a council established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided for by law. See sections 1001(2) and 1013 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fd1662a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Similar Advisory Body</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/83/tXI/s1104/b">Pub. L. 99–83, title XI, § 1104(b)</ref>, <date date="1985-08-08">Aug. 8, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/275">99 Stat. 275</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/83/tXI/s1104/b">“Any advisory body carrying out functions similar to those assigned to the Peace Corps National Advisory Council provided for in subsection (a) [enacting this section] shall cease to exist sixty days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1985-08-08">Aug. 8, 1985</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
