<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8e884455-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s254c–1"><num value="254c–1">§ 254c–1.</num><heading> Policy toward certain agents of foreign governments</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8e884456-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s254c–1/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> It is the sense of the Congress that the numbers, status, privileges and immunities, travel, accommodations, and facilities within the United States of official representatives to the United States of any foreign government that engages in intelligence activities within the United States harmful to the national security of the United States should not exceed the respective numbers, status, privileges and immunities, travel accommodations, and facilities within such country of official representatives of the United States to such country.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8e884457-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s254c–1/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The Secretary of State, in negotiating agreements with foreign governments regarding reciprocal privileges and immunities of United States diplomatic personnel, shall consult with the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the Director of National Intelligence in achieving the sense of Congress in subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8e884458-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s254c–1/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><chapeau> Not later than 90 days after <date date="2025-12-18">December 18, 2025</date>, and annually thereafter for 5 years, the Secretary of State, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the Select Committee on Intelligence, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report on each foreign government that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8e884459-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s254c–1/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> engages in intelligence activities within the United States harmful to the national security of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8e88445a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s254c–1/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> possesses numbers, status, privileges and immunities, travel accommodations, or facilities within the United States of official representatives to the United States that exceed the respective numbers, status, privileges and immunities, travel accommodations, or facilities within such country of official representatives of the United States to such country.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8e88445b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/618/tVI/s601/a">Pub. L. 98–618, title VI, § 601(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3303">98 Stat. 3303</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dF/tLXVII/s6712/1">Pub. L. 119–60, div. F, title LXVII, § 6712(1)</ref>, (3), <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1649">139 Stat. 1649</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8e88445c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8e88445d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8e88445e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b) of this section, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/98/618/tVI/s601/b">Pub. L. 98–618, title VI, § 601(b)</ref>, which required the President to prepare and transmit to the Committee on Foreign Relations and Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs and Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives a report on the numbers, status, privileges and immunities, travel, accommodations, and facilities within the United States of official representatives to the United States of any foreign government that engages in intelligence activities within the United States harmful to the national security of the United States and the respective numbers, status, privileges and immunities, travel, accommodations, and facilities within such country of official representatives of the United States to such country, and any action which may have been taken with respect thereto, terminated, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance. See, also, page 33 of House Document No. 103–7.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8e88445f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6712/1">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6712(1)</ref>, (3), added subsec. (b) and struck out former subsec. (b). See Codification note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s6712/3">Pub. L. 119–60, § 6712(3)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
