<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8e8d26be-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262b"><num value="262b">§ 262b.</num><heading> Commitments for United States contributions to international organizations; limitations; consultation with Congressional committees</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No representative of the United States Government in any international organization hereafter shall make any commitment requiring the appropriation of funds for a contribution by the United States in excess of 33⅓ per centum of the budget of any international organization for which the appropriation for the United States contribution is contained in this Act: <i>Provided</i>, That in exceptional circumstances necessitating a contribution by the United States in excess of 33⅓ per centum of the budget, a commitment requiring a United States appropriation of a larger proportion may be made after consultation by United States representatives in the organization or other appropriate officials of the Department of State with the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and House of Representatives: <i>Provided, however</i>, That this section shall not apply to the United States representatives to the Inter-American organizations, Caribbean Commission and the Joint Support program of the International Civil Aviation Organization.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8e8d26bf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1951-10-22/ch533">Oct. 22, 1951, ch. 533</ref>, title VI, § 602, <ref href="/us/stat/65/599">65 Stat. 599</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1953-08-05/ch328">Aug. 5, 1953, ch. 328</ref>, title I, <ref href="/us/stat/67/368">67 Stat. 368</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8e8d26c0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8e8d26c1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8e8d26c2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1951-10-22/ch533/tVI">act Oct. 22, 1951, ch. 533, title VI</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/65/599">65 Stat. 599</ref>, popularly known as the Departments of State, Justice, Commerce and Judiciary Appropriation Act of 1952. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8e8d26c3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of first paragraph of section 602 of act <date date="1951-10-22">Oct. 22, 1951</date>. Second par. of such section 602 contained a fiscal year provision.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8e8d26c4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1953—Act <date date="1953-08-05">Aug. 5, 1953</date>, inserted proviso that this section is not to apply to the United States representatives to the Caribbean Commission and the Joint Support program of the International Civil Aviation Organization.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8e8d26c5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="similarProvisions" id="id8e8d26c6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Similar Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to this section were contained in <ref href="/us/act/1952-07-10/ch651/tI">act July 10, 1952, ch. 651, title I</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/550">66 Stat. 550</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
