<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8ea03952-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–7"><num value="262p–7">§ 262p–7.</num><heading> Reform of the Enhanced Structural Adjustment Facility</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Directors at the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (World Bank) and the International Monetary Fund (IMF) to use the voice and vote of the United States to promote the establishment of poverty reduction strategy policies and procedures at the World Bank and the IMF that support countries’ efforts under programs developed and jointly administered by the World Bank and the IMF that have the following components:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ea03953-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–7/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The development of country-specific poverty reduction strategies (Poverty Reduction Strategies) under the leadership of such countries that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8ea03954-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–7/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> will be set out in poverty reduction strategy papers (PRSPs) that provide the basis for the lending operations of the International Development Association (IDA) and the reformed Enhanced Structural Adjustment Facility (ESAF);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8ea03955-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–7/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> will reflect the World Bank’s role in poverty reduction and the IMF’s role in macroeconomic issues;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8ea03956-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–7/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> will make the IMF’s and the World Bank’s advice and operations fully consistent with the objectives of poverty reduction through broad-based economic growth; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8ea03957-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–7/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> should include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8ea03958-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–7/1/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> implementation of transparent budgetary procedures and mechanisms to help ensure that the financial benefits of debt relief under the modified Heavily Indebted Poor Countries Initiative (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s262p–6">section 262p–6 of this title</ref>) are applied to programs that combat poverty; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id8ea03959-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–7/1/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> monitorable indicators of progress in poverty reduction.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ea0395a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–7/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The adoption of procedures for periodic comprehensive reviews of reformed ESAF and IDA programs to help ensure progress toward longer-term poverty goals outlined in the Poverty Reduction Strategies and to allow adjustments in such programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ea0395b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–7/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The publication of the PRSPs prior to Executive Board review of related programs under IDA and the reformed ESAF.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ea0395c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–7/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> The establishment of a standing evaluation unit at the IMF, similar to the Operations Evaluation Department of the World Bank, that would report directly to the Executive Board of the IMF and that would undertake periodic reviews of IMF operations, including the operations of the reformed ESAF, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8ea0395d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–7/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> assessments of experience under the reformed ESAF programs in the areas of poverty reduction, economic growth, and access to basic social services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8ea0395e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–7/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> assessments of the extent and quality of participation in program design by citizens;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8ea0395f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–7/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> verifications that reformed ESAF programs are designed in a manner consistent with the Poverty Reduction Strategies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8ea03960-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–7/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> prompt release to the public of all reviews by the standing evaluation unit.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ea03961-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–7/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The promotion of clearer conditionality in IDA and reformed ESAF programs that focuses on reforms most likely to support poverty reduction through broad-based economic growth.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ea03962-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–7/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The adoption by the IMF of policies aimed at reforming ESAF so that reformed ESAF programs are consistent with the Poverty Reduction Strategies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ea03963-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–7/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The adoption by the World Bank of policies to help ensure that its lending operations in countries eligible for debt relief under the modified Heavily Indebted Poor Countries Initiative are consistent with the Poverty Reduction Strategies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ea03964-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–7/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> Strengthening the linkage between borrower country performance and lending operations by IDA and the reformed ESAF on the basis of clear and monitorable indictors.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002012">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002012"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “indicators”.</note></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ea03965-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–7/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> Full public disclosure of the proposed objectives and financial organization of the successor to the ESAF at least 90 days before any decision by the Executive Board of the IMF to consider its adoption.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id8ea03966-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/118/tXVI/s1624">Pub. L. 95–118, title XVI, § 1624</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/5/tV/s502">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(5) [title V, § 502]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–314.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8ea03967-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8ea03968-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="id8ea03969-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The definitions in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s262p–5">section 262p–5 of this title</ref> apply to this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
