<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8ea039d3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–15"><num value="262p–15">§ 262p–15.</num><heading> United States policy on Burma at the International Monetary Fund, the World Bank Group, and the Asian Development Bank</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ea039d4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–15/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Policy of the United States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Directors at the International Monetary Fund, the World Bank Group, and the Asian Development Bank to inform the respective institution that it is the policy of the United States to oppose, and to use the voice and vote of the United States to vote against, any loan or financial assistance to Burma through the State Administration Council, or any successor entity controlled by the military, except for humanitarian assistance channeled through an implementing agency not controlled by the Burmese military.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ea039d5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–15/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission of written statements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No later than 60 calendar days after a meeting of the Board of Directors of the World Bank Group or the Asian Development Bank, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate any written statement presented at the meeting by the United States Executive Director concerning the United States policy described in subsection (a) or the United States position on any strategy, policy, loan, extension of financial assistance, or technical assistance related to Burma considered by the Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ea282c6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–15/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President of the United States may waive the application of subsection (a) on a case-by-case basis upon certifying to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate that the waiver—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ea282c7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–15/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> substantially promotes the objective of delivering humanitarian assistance to the civilian population of Burma, including a detailed explanation as to the need for such a waiver, the nature of the humanitarian assistance, the mechanisms through which such assistance will be delivered, and the oversight safeguards that will accompany such assistance; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ea282c8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–15/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> is otherwise in the national interest of the United States, with a detailed explanation of the reasons therefor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ea282c9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–15/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> World Bank Group defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “World Bank Group” means the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, the International Development Association, the International Finance Corporation, and the Multilateral Investment Guarantee Agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8ea282ca-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/118/tXVI/s1631">Pub. L. 95–118, title XVI, § 1631</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dF/tLXI/s6104/b">Pub. L. 117–81, div. F, title LXI, § 6104(b)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/2385">135 Stat. 2385</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8ea282cb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I84" topic="prospectiveAmendment" id="id8ea282cc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered fontsize8 smallCaps">Repeal of Section</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">For repeal of section by <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s6104/c">section 6104(c) of Pub. L. 117–81</ref>, see Effective Date of Repeal note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8ea282cd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id8ea282ce-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of Repeal</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dF/tLXI/s6104/c">Pub. L. 117–81, div. F, title LXI, § 6104(c)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/2386">135 Stat. 2386</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/81/dF/tLXI/s6104/c">
<inline>“Section 1631 of the International Financial Institutions Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s262p–15">22 U.S.C. 262p–15</ref>], as added by subsection (b), is repealed on the earlier of—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> the date the President of the United States submits to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a certification that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Burmese military has released all political prisoners;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> an elected government has been instated following free and fair elections; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> all government institutions involved in the provision of multilateral assistance are fully under civilian control; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>].”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="id8ea282cf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The definitions in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s262p–5">section 262p–5 of this title</ref> apply to this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
