<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8e9dc901-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262p–4n"><num value="262p–4n">§ 262p–4n.</num><heading> Equal employment opportunities</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Directors of the multilateral development banks and of the International Monetary Fund to use the voices and votes of the Executive Directors to urge their respective banks and the Fund to adopt a policy which provides, and implement procedures which ensure, that such banks and the Fund, and the affiliates of such banks and of the Fund, shall not discriminate against any person on the basis of race, ethnicity, gender, color, or religious affiliation in any determination related to employment.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8e9dc902-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/118/tXVI/s1619">Pub. L. 95–118, title XVI, § 1619</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/513/tV/s562/b/1">Pub. L. 101–513, title V, § 562(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2033">104 Stat. 2033</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8e9dc903-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8e9dc904-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id8e9dc905-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/95/118/s1619">section 1619 of Pub. L. 95–118</ref> was renumbered section 1622 and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s262p–5">section 262p–5 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8e9dc906-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8e9dc907-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Fairness for Taiwan Nationals Regarding Employment at International Financial Institutions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dH/tXCVII/s9724">Pub. L. 116–283, div. H, title XCVII, § 9724</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4842">134 Stat. 4842</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/283/dH/tXCVII/s9724">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sense of Congress</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Taiwan is responsible for remarkable achievements in economic and democratic development, with its per capita gross domestic product rising in purchasing power parity terms from $3,470 in 1980 to more than $55,000 in 2018;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the experience of Taiwan in creating a vibrant and advanced economy under democratic governance and the rule of law can inform the work of the international financial institutions, including through the contributions and insights of Taiwan nationals; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Taiwan nationals who seek employment at the international financial institutions should not be held at a disadvantage in hiring because the economic success of Taiwan has rendered it ineligible for financial assistance from such institutions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Director at each international financial institution to use the voice and vote of the United States to seek to ensure that Taiwan nationals are not discriminated against in any employment decision by the institution, including employment through consulting or part-time opportunities, on the basis of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> whether they are citizens or nationals of, or holders of a passport issued by, a member country of, or a state or other jurisdiction that receives assistance from, the international financial institution; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> any other consideration that, in the determination of the Secretary, unfairly disadvantages Taiwan nationals with respect to employment at the institution.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Waiver Authority</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of the Treasury may waive subsection (b) for not more than 1 year at a time after reporting to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate that providing the waiver—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> will substantially promote the objective of equitable treatment for Taiwan nationals at the international financial institutions; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> is in the national interest of the United States, with a detailed explanation of the reasons therefor.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Progress Report</inline>.—</heading><content>The Chairman of the National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Policies shall submit to the committees specified in subsection (c) an annual report, in writing, that describes the progress made toward advancing the policy described in subsection (b), and a summary of employment trends with respect to Taiwan nationals at the international financial institutions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">International Financial Institution Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘international financial institutions’ has the meaning given the term in section 1701(c)(2) of the International Financial Institutions Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s262r/c/2">22 U.S.C. 262r(c)(2)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sunset</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The preceding provisions of this section shall have no force or effect beginning on the earlier of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the date that is 7 years after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>]; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the date that the Secretary of the Treasury reports to the committees specified in subsection (c) that each international financial institution has adopted the policy described in subsection (b).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="id8e9dc908-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The definitions in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s262p–5">section 262p–5 of this title</ref> apply to this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
