<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8ea4f47d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262s–2"><num value="262s–2">§ 262s–2.</num><heading> Commercial Service Officers and multilateral development bank procurement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ea4f47e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262s–2/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment of Commercial Service Officers to serve with Executive Directors</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall appoint a procurement officer, who is a representative of the International Trade Administration or a Commercial Service Officer of the United States and Foreign Commercial Service, to serve, on a full-time or part-time basis, with each of the Executive Directors of the multilateral development banks in which the United States participates.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ea4f47f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262s–2/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Functions of officers</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each procurement officer appointed under subsection (a) shall assist the United States Executive Director with respect to whom such officer is appointed in promoting opportunities for exports of goods and services from the United States by doing the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ea4f480-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262s–2/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Acting as the liaison between the business community and the multilateral development bank involved, whether or not the bank has offices in the United States. The Secretary of Commerce shall ensure that the procurement officer has access to, and disseminates to United States businesses, information relating to projects which are being proposed by the multilateral development bank, and bid specifications and deadlines for projects about to be developed by the bank. The procurement officer shall make special efforts to disseminate such information to small and medium-sized businesses interested in participating in such projects. The procurement officer shall explore opportunities for disseminating such information through private sector, nonprofit organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ea4f481-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262s–2/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Taking actions to assure that United States businesses are fully informed of bidding opportunities for projects for which loans have been made by the multilateral development bank involved.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ea4f482-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s262s–2/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Taking actions to assure that United States businesses can focus on projects in which they have a particular interest or competitive advantage, and to permit them to compete and have an equal opportunity in submitting timely and conforming bidding documents.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8ea4f483-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/118/tXVIII/s1803">Pub. L. 95–118, title XVIII, § 1803</ref>, formerly <ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tII/s2302">Pub. L. 100–418, title II, § 2302</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1341">102 Stat. 1341</ref>; renumbered <ref href="/us/pl/95/118/s1803">§ 1803 of Pub. L. 95–118</ref>, and amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/240/tV/s541/b/2">Pub. L. 101–240, title V, § 541(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2517">103 Stat. 2517</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8ea4f484-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8ea4f485-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8ea4f486-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s4722">section 4722 of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade, prior to renumbering by <ref href="/us/pl/101/240">Pub. L. 101–240</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8ea4f487-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/101/240">Pub. L. 101–240</ref> struck out subsec. (c) which defined “multilateral development bank” for purposes of this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8ea4f488-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8ea4f489-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Additional Procurement Officers</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/549/tV/s501">Pub. L. 102–549, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3663">106 Stat. 3663</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/549/tV/s501">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appointment</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall appoint one or more full-time additional procurement officers, for each multilateral development bank, to promote exports of goods and services from the United States by doing the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Acting as the liaison between the business community and one or more multilateral development banks, whether or not the banks have offices in the United States. The Secretary of Commerce shall ensure that the procurement officer has access to, and disseminates to United States businesses, information relating to projects which are being proposed by the multilateral development bank involved, and bid specifications and deadlines for projects about to be developed by the bank. The procurement officer shall make special efforts to disseminate such information to small- and medium-sized businesses interested in participating in such projects. The procurement officer shall explore opportunities for disseminating such information through private sector, nonprofit organizations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Taking actions to assure that United States businesses are fully informed of bidding opportunities for projects for which loans have been made by the multilateral development bank involved.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Taking actions to assure that United States businesses can focus on projects in which they have a particular interest or competitive advantage, and to permit them to compete and have an equal opportunity in submitting timely and conforming bidding documents.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading><content>As used in this section, the term ‘multilateral development bank’ has the meaning given that term in section 1701(c) of the International Financial Institutions Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s262r/c">22 U.S.C. 262r(c)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Commerce $1,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1993 and 1994 to carry out this section. Amounts appropriated pursuant to this subsection shall be available only for the purpose of making the appointment of additional procurement officers required by subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="id8ea4f48a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The definitions in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s262r">section 262r of this title</ref> apply to this section.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
