<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8fe6c2c8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2656"><num value="2656">§ 2656.</num><heading> Management of foreign affairs</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall perform such duties as shall from time to time be enjoined on or intrusted to him by the President relative to correspondences, commissions, or instructions to or with public ministers or consuls from the United States, or to negotiations with public ministers from foreign states or princes, or to memorials or other applications from foreign public ministers or other foreigners, or to such other matters respecting foreign affairs as the President of the United States shall assign to the Department, and he shall conduct the business of the Department in such manner as the President shall direct.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8fe6c2c9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(R.S. § 202.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8fe6c2ca-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8fe6c2cb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8fe6c2cc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">R.S. § 202 derived from acts <ref href="/us/act/1789-07-27/ch4/s1">July 27, 1789, ch. 4, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/1/28">1 Stat. 28</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1789-09-15/ch14/s1">Sept. 15, 1789, ch. 14, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/1/68">1 Stat. 68</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s156">section 156 of Title 5</ref> prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s1">Pub. L. 89–554, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/378">80 Stat. 378</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8fe6c2cd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe6c2ce-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Construction</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/409/s412">Pub. L. 115–409, § 412</ref>, <date date="2018-12-31">Dec. 31, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5411">132 Stat. 5411</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/409/s412">“Nothing in this Act [see Short Title of 2018 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2651">section 2651 of this title</ref>] may be construed as authorizing the use of military force.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe6c2cf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Establishing an Inner Mongolia Section Within the United States Mission in China</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dE/tVI/s5605">Pub. L. 119–60, div. E, title VI, § 5605</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1604">139 Stat. 1604</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dE/tVI/s5605">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inner Mongolia Section in the United States Mission in China.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary [of State] may establish an Inner Mongolia team within the United States Mission in China, to follow political, economic, and social developments in the Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region and other areas designated by the People’s Republic of China as autonomous for Mongolians, with due consideration given to hiring Mongolians as Locally Employed Staff.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading><content>Responsibilities of a team devoted to Inner Mongolia should include reporting on internationally recognized human rights issues, monitoring developments in critical minerals mining, environmental degradation, and PRC space capabilities, and access to areas designated as autonomous for Mongolians by United States Government officials, journalists, nongovernmental organizations, and the Mongolian diaspora.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Language requirements</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary should ensure that the Department [of State] has sufficient proficiency in the Mongolian language in order to carry out paragraph (1), and that the United States Mission in China has sufficient resources to hire Local Employed Staff proficient in the Mongolian language, as appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>], the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees [Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives] a report on the staffing described in subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe6c2d0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Expedited Opening of Diplomatic Missions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dG/tLXXII/s7210">Pub. L. 118–159, div. G, title LXXII, § 7210</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2533">138 Stat. 2533</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/159/dG/tLXXII/s7210">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Increasing the United States’ global diplomatic footprint is imperative to advance United States’ national security interests, particularly in the face of a massive diplomatic expansion of our strategic competitors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Opening or re-opening diplomatic missions, often in small island nations where there is no United States Government presence, but one is needed to advance United States strategic objectives.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Diplomatic missions should be resourced and equipped for success upon opening to allow diplomats to focus on advancing United States national interests in-country.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The United States can and should move more swiftly to open new diplomatic missions and provide United States diplomats and locally employed staff with a workplace that meets locally appropriate quality, safety, and security standards.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> To do this, the Department [of State] must streamline and support the process of opening new posts to identify efficiencies and remove obstacles that are unduly complicating the opening of new diplomatic missions, particularly in small island states and similarly situated locations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>], the Secretary [of State] shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees [Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives] and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report on how the Department is creating a new framework to provide such diplomatic missions the needed resources and authorities to quickly and efficiently stand up and operate from the moment United States personnel arrive, or even before the opening of a new mission, particularly in small island nations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The report required under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a list of authorities and processes related to the opening of new diplomatic missions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a list of authorities and processes related to the opening of new diplomatic missions that the Department can waive to expediently stand up new diplomatic missions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> essential functions that each new diplomatic mission should be able to carry out independently upon opening;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> a description of functions that another post or support center will need to carry out to support the new mission;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> a list of essential equipment and access to facilities, including to support secure communications, that should be provided to each new diplomatic mission, the approval of which should be handled prior to or shortly after the opening of the new diplomatic mission, including arrangements for basic office equipment, vehicles, and housing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> the number of recommended locally engaged staff and United States direct hires resident in-country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> the number of non-resident support staff who are assigned to the new diplomatic mission, such as from another post or regional support center;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> a description of how medical and consular support services could be provided;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> procedures for requesting an expansion or renovation of the post’s functions or physical platform after opening, should that be needed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="J">“(J)</num><content> any other authorities or processes that may be required to successfully and quickly stand up a new diplomatic mission, including any new authorities the Department may need;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="K">“(K)</num><content> a list of incentives, in addition to pay differentials, being considered for such posts;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="L">“(L)</num><content> a description of any specialized training, including for management and security personnel supporting the establishment of such new embassies that may be required; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="M">“(M)</num><content> a list of what steps the Department is taking to expedite embassy construction in Dublin, Ireland, consulate build-out in Nuuk, Greenland, and embassy renovations in Buenos Aires, Argentina, and projected new posts in the Caribbean and Pacific Islands.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Senior Official to Lead New Embassy Expansion.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Designation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall designate an assistant secretary-level senior official to expedite and make recommendations for the reform of procedures for opening new diplomatic missions abroad, particularly in small island states.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The senior official designated pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be responsible for proposing policy and procedural changes to the Secretary to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> expediting the resourcing of new diplomatic missions by waiving or reducing when possible mandatory processes required to open new diplomatic missions, taking into account the threat environment and circumstances in the host country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> when necessary, quickly adjudicating within the Department any decision points that arise during the planning and execution phases of the establishment of a new mission;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> ensuring new missions receive the management and operational support needed, including by designating such support be undertaken by another post, regional support center, or Department entities based in the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> ensuring that the authorities provided in the Secure Embassy Construction and Counterterrorism Act of 1999 (title VI of division A of appendix G of <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Public Law 106–113</ref> [<ref href="/us/stat/113/1501">113 Stat. 1501</ref>A–451; see Short Title of 1999 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4801">section 4801 of this title</ref>]), as amended by the Secure Embassy Construction and Counterterrorism Act of 2022 (<ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s9301">section 9301 of Public Law 117–263</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/136/3879">136 Stat. 3879</ref>), are fully utilized in the planning for all new diplomatic missions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">New Diplomatic Mission Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘new diplomatic mission’ means any bilateral diplomatic mission opened since <date date="2020-01-01">January 1, 2020</date>, in a country where there had not been a bilateral diplomatic mission since the date that is 20 years before the date of the enactment of this Act.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sunset</inline>.—</heading><content>The authorities and requirements of this section shall terminate 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe6c2d1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">United States-Africa Leaders Summit and Related Matters</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dG/tLXXVIII/s7803">Pub. L. 118–159, div. G, title LXXVIII, § 7803</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2558">138 Stat. 2558</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/159/dG/tLXXVIII/s7803">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">United States-Africa Leaders Summit.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>], and biennially thereafter, the President shall convene a United States-Africa Leaders Summit to strengthen ties and promote cooperation with African leaders, as well as civil society, business, diaspora, women, and youth leaders.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Participation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each summit convened pursuant to this subsection shall have participation, including in meetings with United States officials, from—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> leaders of civilian-led governments of African countries in good standing with the African Union, provided that such leaders—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> are not sanctioned by the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> have not been found, by credible international observers or other international bodies, to have undermined democratic elections;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> heads of transitional governments that are implementing a roadmap to hold credible elections and who are unaffiliated with actions that were related to an unconstitutional change of administration; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> civil society from each of the African countries represented at the Summit.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Non-payment of au membership fees not basis for disqualification</inline>.—</heading><content>For the purposes of this subsection, non-payment of membership fees to the African Union shall not disqualify a country’s leader.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">United States-Africa City Summit (‘mini Summit’)</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary [of State] should, not later than one year after each summit hosted under subsection (a) host a United States-Africa City Summit (‘Mini Summit’) across cities in Africa or the United States to promote subregional cooperation and serve as a catalyst in fostering engagement with representatives of government, civil society, business, academia, youth, culture and the arts, the African diaspora community, and underrepresented groups.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">United States-Africa Leaders Summit Implementation Unit.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall establish within the Bureau for African Affairs of the Department of State a United States-Africa Leaders Summit implementation unit responsible for coordinating, planning and implementing summits, which should include robust interagency consultation and may include, on a temporary basis, personnel seconded from USAID [United States Agency for International Development] and other Federal agencies as appropriate, and which shall be led by an individual who has previously been appointed by the President and confirmed by the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The duties of the implementation unit authorized by this subsection shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> using lessons learned from the 2022 African Leaders Summit and subsequent summits to inform planning of future summits;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> leading interagency efforts to provide guidance to United States embassies in African countries related to planning each summit and engagement with governments and civil society in advance of each summit;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> tracking and ensuring implementation of commitments made during United States-Africa Leaders Summits;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> liaising with interagency partners and the National Security Council regarding implementation of summit commitments;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> facilitating meetings and engagement with African Diaspora communities and stakeholders; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> reporting quarterly on a public website of the Department [of State] regarding progress to accomplish summit commitments and status of commitments across Federal departments and agencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement for consultation</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter, the implementation unit shall consult with the appropriate congressional committees [Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives] on summit planning and the fulfillment of commitments and any relevant follow on issues in the wake of each summit.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>There is authorized to be appropriated $28,000,000 in fiscal year 2025 and $14,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029. Such sums shall remain available for three fiscal years.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe6c2d2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Summit of the Americas</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dG/tLXXVIII/s7804">Pub. L. 118–159, div. G, title LXXVIII, § 7804</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2559">138 Stat. 2559</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/159/dG/tLXXVIII/s7804">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Statement of Policy</inline>.—</heading><content>It shall be the policy of the United States to work with the Summit of the Americas Secretariat to support the organization of a Summit of the Americas every 4 years, or more frequently as appropriate, subject to the availability of funds, to strengthen ties and promote cooperation between the United States and countries in the Western Hemisphere, as well as civil society, business, diaspora, women, and youth leaders.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary [of State] is authorized to carry out the policy described in subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cities Summit of the Americas.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Subnational diplomacy strengthens democratic governance by enhancing the ability of local leader to tackle shared challenges and deepens United States ties with regional partners by localizing bilateral and multilateral partnerships and connections.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The first-ever Cities Summit of the Americas in 2023 promoted a valuable exchange of best practices and lessons learned between city, State, municipal, and regional leaders and should be held as part of the Summit of the Americas process.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary is authorized to work with the Summit of the Americas Secretariat to support the organization of Cities Summit of the Americas, across cities in the Western Hemisphere, including the United States, to take place as a part of each Summit of the Americas described in subsection (a), to promote subnational cooperation and serve as a catalyst in fostering engagement with representatives of government, civil society, faith-based organizations, business, academia, youth, culture and the arts, Latin American and Caribbean diaspora communities, and underrepresented groups.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary is authorized to designate an existing official to serve within the Department [of State] as senior-level coordinator to coordinate, in conjunction with other relevant agencies, matters related to the implementation of Summit of [the] Americas commitments, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> tracking and ensuring implementation of commitments made during Summits of the Americas; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> liaising with interagency partners and the National Security Council regarding implementation of summit commitments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>], and annually thereafter for 5 years, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees [Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives] a report on the implementation of this section, including the status of commitments of the United States and participating partners for the prior year and upcoming year.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe6c2d3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Global Cooperative Framework to End Human Rights Abuses in Sourcing Critical Minerals</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dE/tLIV/s5411">Pub. L. 118–31, div. E, title LIV, § 5411</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/948">137 Stat. 948</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/31/dE/tLIV/s5411">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of State shall seek to convene a meeting of foreign leaders to establish a multilateral framework to end human rights abuses, including the exploitation of forced labor and child labor, related to the mining and sourcing of critical minerals.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation Report</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall lead the development of an annual global report on the implementation of the framework under subsection (a), including progress and recommendations to fully end human rights abuses, including the exploitation of forced labor and child labor, related to the extraction of critical minerals around the world.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall consult closely on a timely basis with the following with respect to developing and implementing the framework under subsection (a):</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The Forced Labor Enforcement Task Force established under section 741 of the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement Implementation Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s4681">19 U.S.C. 4681</ref>); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Relationship to United States Law</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Nothing in the framework under subsection (a) shall be construed—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to amend or modify any law of the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to limit any authority conferred under any law of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Extractive Industries Transparency Initiative and Certain Provisions of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Nothing in this section shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> affect the authority of the President to take any action to join and subsequently comply with the terms and obligations of the Extractive Industries Transparency Initiative (EITI); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> affect section 1502 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act [<ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Pub. L. 111–203</ref>] (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78m">15 U.S.C. 78m</ref> note), or subsection (q) of section 13 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78m">15 U.S.C. 78m</ref>), as added by section 1504 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<ref href="/us/pl/111/203">Public Law 111–203</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/124/2220">124 Stat. 2220</ref>), or any rule prescribed under either such section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Critical Mineral Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘critical mineral’ has the meaning given the term in section 7002(a) of the Energy Act of 2020 (<ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1606/a">30 U.S.C. 1606(a)</ref>).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe6c2d4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">US-ASEAN Center</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dF/tLXVII/s6705">Pub. L. 118–31, div. F, title LXVII, § 6705</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/1017">137 Stat. 1017</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/31/dF/tLXVII/s6705">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Defined Term</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘ASEAN’ means the Association of Southeast Asian Nations.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary [of State] is authorized to enter into a public-private partnership for the purposes of establishing a US-ASEAN Center in the United States to support United States economic and cultural engagement with Southeast Asia.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Functions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the US-ASEAN Center established pursuant to subsection (b) may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> provide grants for research to support and elevate the importance of the US-ASEAN partnership;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> facilitate activities to strengthen US-ASEAN trade and investment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> expand economic and technological relationships between ASEAN countries and the United States into new areas of cooperation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> provide training to United States citizens and citizens of ASEAN countries that improve people-to-people ties;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> develop educational programs to increase awareness for the United States and ASEAN countries on the importance of relations between the United States and ASEAN countries; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> carry out other activities the Secretary considers necessary to strengthen ties between the United States and ASEAN countries and achieve the objectives of the US-ASEAN Center.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Parameters</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall ensure that the activities of the US-ASEAN Center do not duplicate current lines of effort being conducted by the United States Government or its grantees.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe6c2d5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Establishment of United States Embassies in Solomon Islands, Kiribati, and Tonga and a Diplomatic Presence in Vanuatu</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dI/tXCIII/s9303">Pub. L. 117–263, div. I, title XCIII, § 9303</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3890">136 Stat. 3890</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dI/tXCIII/s9303">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The Pacific Islands are vital to United States national security and national interests in the Indo-Pacific region and globally.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Pacific Islands region spans 15 percent of the world’s surface area and controls access to open waters in the Central Pacific, sea lanes to the Western Hemisphere, supply lines to United States forward-deployed forces in East Asia, and economically important fisheries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The Pacific Islands region is home to the State of Hawaii, 11 United States territories, United States Naval Base Guam, and United States Andersen Air Force Base.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Pacific Island countries cooperate with the United States and United States partners on maritime security and efforts to stop illegal, unreported, and destructive fishing.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> The Pacific Islands are rich in biodiversity and are on the frontlines of environmental challenges and climate issues.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> The People’s Republic of China seeks to increase its influence in the Pacific Islands region, including through infrastructure development under the People’s Republic of China’s One Belt, One Road Initiative and its new security agreement with the Solomon Islands.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> The United States closed its embassy in the Solomon Islands in 1993.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> The United States Embassy in Papua New Guinea manages the diplomatic affairs of the United States to the Republic of Vanuatu and the Solomon Islands, and the United States Embassy in Fiji manages the diplomatic affairs of the United States to the Republic of Kiribati and the Kingdom of Tonga.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> The United States requires a physical and more robust diplomatic presence in the Republic of Vanuatu, the Republic of Kiribati, the Solomon Islands, and the Kingdom of Tonga, to ensure the physical and operational security of our efforts in those countries to deepen relations, protect United States national security, and pursue United States national interests.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="10">“(10)</num><content> Increasing the number of United States embassies dedicated solely to a Pacific Island country demonstrates the United States’ ongoing commitment to the region and to the Pacific Island countries.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Embassies.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>As soon as possible, the Secretary [of State] should—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> establish physical United States embassies in the Republic of Kiribati and in the Kingdom of Tonga;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> upgrade the United States consular agency in the Solomon Islands to an embassy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> establish a physical United States Government presence in the Republic of Vanuatu.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Other strategies.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Physical infrastructure</inline>.—</heading><content>In establishing embassies pursuant to paragraph (1) and creating the physical infrastructure to ensure the physical and operational safety of embassy personnel, the Secretary may pursue rent or purchase existing buildings or co-locate personnel in embassies of like-minded partners, such as Australia and New Zealand.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Personnel</inline>.—</heading><content>In establishing a physical presence in the Republic of Vanuatu pursuant to paragraph (1), the Secretary may assign 1 or more United States Government personnel to the Republic of Vanuatu as part of the United States mission in Papua New Guinea.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Waiver authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The President may waive the requirements under paragraph (1) for a period of one year if the President determines and reports to Congress in advance that such waiver is necessary to protect the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated to the Department of State for Embassy Security, Construction, and Maintenance—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> $40,200,000 is authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 2023—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> to establish and maintain the 3 embassies authorized to be established under subsection (b); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> to establish a physical United States Government presence in the Republic of Vanuatu;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> $3,000,000 is authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 2024—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> to maintain such embassies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> to establish a physical United States Government presence in the Republic of Vanuatu;[.]</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Defined term</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subsection, the term ‘appropriate committees of Congress’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Progress report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days following the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>], the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that includes—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a description of the status of activities carried out to achieve the objectives described in this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> an estimate of when embassies and a physical presence will be fully established pursuant to subsection (b)(1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> an update on events in the Pacific Islands region relevant to the establishment of United States embassies, including activities by the People’s Republic of China.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report on final disposition</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit a report to the appropriate committees of Congress that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> confirms the establishment of the 3 embassies and the physical presence required under subsection (b)(1); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> if the embassies and physical presence required in subsection (b)(1) have not been established, a justification for such failure to comply with such requirement.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe6c2d6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Mitigation and Prevention of Atrocities in High-Risk Countries</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXII/s1210D">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1210D</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3916">134 Stat. 3916</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXII/s1210D">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Statement of Policy</inline>.—</heading><content>It is the policy of the United States that the Department of State, in coordination with the Department of Defense and the United States Agency for International Development, should address global fragility, as required by the Global Fragility Act of 2019 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9801">22 U.S.C. 9801</ref> et seq.] and, to the extent practicable, incorporate efforts to identify, prevent, and respond to the causes of atrocities, as required by section 3 of the Elie Wiesel Genocide and Atrocities Prevention Act of 2018 [<ref href="/us/pl/115/441">Pub. L. 115–441</ref>] (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2656">22 U.S.C. 2656</ref> note), into security assistance and cooperation planning and implementation for covered foreign countries.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of State, in consultation with chiefs of mission and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, shall ensure that the Department of State’s Atrocity Assessment Framework is factored into the Integrated Country Strategy and the Country Development Cooperation Strategy where appropriate for covered foreign countries.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><note topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe6c2d7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<p>[Amended <ref href="/us/pl/115/441/s5">section 5 of Pub. L. 115–441</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5587">132 Stat. 5587</ref>.]</p></note>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effective date</inline>.—</heading><content>The amendment made by paragraph (1) shall take effect and apply beginning with the first report required under section 5 of the Elie Wiesel Genocide and Atrocities Prevention Act of 2018 that is required after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Stakeholder Consultation</inline>.—</heading><content>Consistent with section 504(b) of the Global Fragility Act of 2019 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9803/b">22 U.S.C. 9803(b)</ref>), the Secretary of State and other relevant agencies should consult with credible representatives of civil society with experience in atrocities prevention and national and local governance entities, as well as relevant international development organizations with experience implementing programs in fragile and violence-affected communities, multilateral organizations and donors, and relevant private, academic, and philanthropic entities, as appropriate, in identifying covered foreign countries as defined in this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate congressional committees</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘appropriate congressional committees’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Covered foreign country</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘covered foreign country’ means a foreign country that is not listed as a priority country under section 505 of the Global Fragility Act of 2019 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9804">22 U.S.C. 9804</ref>) but remains among the top 30 most at risk countries for new onset of mass killing, according to the Department of State’s internal assessments, and in consultation with the appropriate congressional committees.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe6c2d8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of National Intelligence Authority and Central Intelligence Group</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">National Intelligence Authority and Central Intelligence Group, established by Presidential Directive, <date date="1946-02-01">Feb. 1, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 1337, to coordinate Federal foreign intelligence activities, ceased to exist upon creation of Central Intelligence Agency; personnel, property and records of the group were transferred to the Agency; and unexpended funds of the group were made available to the Agency, by <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343/tI/s102">act July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title I, § 102</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/497">61 Stat. 497</ref>, formerly set out as <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s403">section 403 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense. See Prior Provisions note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3023">section 3023 of Title 50</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe6c2d9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Genocide and Atrocities Prevention</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/441">Pub. L. 115–441</ref>, §§ 3, 6, 7, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5586">132 Stat. 5586</ref>, 5588, 5589, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/441">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="3">“SEC. 3.</num><heading> STATEMENT OF POLICY.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“It shall be the policy of the United States to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> regard the prevention of atrocities as in its national interest;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> work with partners and allies, including to build their capacity, and enhance the capacity of the United States, to identify, prevent, and respond to the causes of atrocities, including insecurity, mass displacement, violent conflict, and other conditions that may lead to such atrocities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> pursue a United States Government-wide strategy to identify, prevent, and respond to the risk of atrocities by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> strengthening the diplomatic, risk analysis and monitoring, strategic planning, early warning, and response capacities of the Government;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> improving the use of foreign assistance to respond early, effectively, and urgently in order to address the causes of atrocities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> strengthening diplomatic response and the effective use of foreign assistance to support appropriate transitional justice measures, including criminal accountability, for past atrocities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> supporting and strengthening local civil society, including human rights defenders and others working to help prevent and respond to atrocities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> promoting financial transparency and enhancing anti-corruption initiatives as part of addressing causes of conditions that may lead to atrocities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><chapeau> employing a variety of unilateral, bilateral, and multilateral means to prevent and respond to atrocities by—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> placing a high priority on timely, preventive diplomatic efforts; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> exercising leadership in promoting international efforts to prevent atrocities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="6">“SEC. 6.</num><heading> DEFINITIONS.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“In this Act [see Short Title of 2019 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2651">section 2651 of this title</ref>]—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the term ‘genocide’ means an offense under subsection (a) of <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1091">section 1091 of title 18</ref>, United States Code;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the term ‘atrocities’ means war crimes, crimes against humanity, and genocide;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the term ‘transitional justice’ means the range of judicial, nonjudicial, formal, informal, retributive, and restorative measures employed by countries transitioning out of armed conflict or repressive regimes to redress legacies of atrocities and to promote long-term, sustainable peace; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the term ‘war crime’ has the meaning given the term in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s2441/c">section 2441(c) of title 18</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="7">“SEC. 7.</num><heading> RULE OF CONSTRUCTION.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Nothing in this Act shall be construed as authorizing the use of military force.”</p>
</content>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe6c2da-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">United States Policy and Diplomatic Strategy in the Indo-Pacific Region</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/409/tI">Pub. L. 115–409, title I</ref>, <date date="2018-12-31">Dec. 31, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5389">132 Stat. 5389</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/409/tI">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="101">“SEC. 101.</num><heading> POLICY.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“It is the policy of the United States to develop and commit to a long-term strategic vision and a comprehensive, multifaceted, and principled United States policy for the Indo-Pacific region that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> secures the vital national security interests of the United States and our allies and partners;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> promotes American prosperity and economic interests by advancing economic growth and development of a rules-based Indo-Pacific economic community;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> advances American influence by reflecting the values of the American people and universal human rights;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> supports functional problem-solving regional architecture; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> accords with and supports the rule of law and international norms.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="102">“SEC. 102.</num><heading> DIPLOMATIC STRATEGY.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“It is the diplomatic strategy of the United States—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> to work with United States allies—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> to confront common challenges;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> to improve information sharing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> to increase defense investment and trade;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> to ensure interoperability; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> to strengthen shared capabilities;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> to strengthen relationships with partners who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> share mutual respect for the rule of law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> agree with fair and reciprocal trade; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> understand the importance of civil society, the rule of law, the free and reliable flow of information, and transparent governance;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> to support functional problem-solving regional architecture, including through the Association of Southeast Asian Nations, Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation, and the East Asia Summit;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><chapeau> to emphasize the commitment of the United States—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> to freedom of navigation under international law;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> to promote peaceful resolutions of maritime and territorial disputes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> to expand security and defense cooperation with allies and partners, as appropriate;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> to pursue diplomatic measures to achieve complete, verifiable, and irreversible denuclearization of North Korea;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> to improve civil society, strengthen the rule of law, and advocate for transparent governance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> to develop and grow the economy through private sector partnerships between the United States and Indo-Pacific partners;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> to pursue multilateral and bilateral trade agreements in a free, fair, and reciprocal manner and build a network of partners in the Indo-Pacific committed to free markets;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><chapeau> to work with and encourage Indo-Pacific countries—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> to pursue high-quality and transparent infrastructure projects;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> to maintain unimpeded commerce, open sea lines or air ways, and communication; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> to seek the peaceful resolution of disputes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="10">“(10)</num><content> to sustain a strong military presence in the Indo-Pacific region and strengthen security relationships with allies and partners throughout the region.”</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Nothing in title I of <ref href="/us/pl/115/409">Pub. L. 115–409</ref>, set out above, to be construed as authorizing the use of military force, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/409/s412">section 412 of Pub. L. 115–409</ref>, set out as a note above.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe933db-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Iraq and Syria Genocide Relief and Accountability</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/300">Pub. L. 115–300</ref>, <date date="2018-12-11">Dec. 11, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4390">132 Stat. 4390</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/300">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1">“SECTION 1.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This Act may be cited as the ‘Iraq and Syria Genocide Relief and Accountability Act of 2018’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="2">“SEC. 2.</num><heading> FINDINGS.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Congress finds the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The Secretary of State of State [sic] declared on <date date="2016-03-17">March 17, 2016</date>, and on <date date="2017-08-15">August 15, 2017</date>, that Daesh (also known as the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria or ISIS) is responsible for genocide, crimes against humanity, and other atrocity crimes against religious and ethnic minority groups in Iraq and Syria, including Christians, Yezidis, and Shia, among other religious and ethnic groups.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> According to the Department of State’s annual reports on international religious freedom—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the number of Christians living in Iraq has dropped from an estimated 800,000 to 1,400,000 in 2002 to fewer than 250,000 in 2017; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the number of Yezidis living in Iraq has fluctuated from 500,000 in 2013, to between 350,000 and 400,000 in 2016, and between 600,000 and 750,000 in 2017.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> The annual reports on international religious freedom further suggest that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Christian communities living in Syria, which had accounted for between 8 and 10 percent of Syria’s total population in 2010, are now ‘considerably’ smaller as a result of the civil war, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> there was a population of approximately 80,000 Yezidis before the commencement of the conflict in Syria.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Local communities and entities have sought to mitigate the impact of violence directed against religious and ethnic minorities in Iraq and Syria, including the Chaldean Catholic Archdiocese of Erbil (Kurdistan Region of Iraq), which has used predominantly private funds to provide assistance to internally displaced Christians, Yezidis, and Muslims throughout the greater Erbil region, while significant needs and diminishing resources have made it increasingly difficult to continue these efforts.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="3">“SEC. 3.</num><heading> DEFINITIONS.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“In this Act:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate congressional committees</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘appropriate congressional committees’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="I">“(I)</num><content> the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="J">“(J)</num><content> the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Foreign terrorist organization</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘foreign terrorist organization’ mean an organization designated by the Secretary of State as a foreign terrorist organization pursuant to section 219(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1189/a">8 U.S.C. 1189(a)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Humanitarian, stabilization, and recovery needs</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘humanitarian, stabilization, and recovery needs’, with respect to an individual, includes water, sanitation, hygiene, food security and nutrition, shelter and housing, reconstruction, medical, education, psychosocial needs, and other assistance to address basic human needs, including stabilization assistance (as defined by the Stabilization Assistance Review in ‘A Framework for Maximizing the Effectiveness of U.S. Government Efforts to Stabilize Conflict-Affected Areas, 2018[’]).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Hybrid court</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘hybrid court’ means a court with a combination of domestic and international lawyers, judges, and personnel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Internationalized domestic court</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘internationalized domestic court’ means a domestic court with the support of international advisers.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="4">“SEC. 4.</num><heading> STATEMENT OF POLICY.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“It is the policy of the United States to ensure that assistance for humanitarian, stabilization, and recovery needs of individuals who are or were nationals and residents of Iraq or Syria, and of communities in and from those countries, is directed toward those individuals and communities with the greatest need, including those individuals from communities of religious and ethnic minorities, and communities of religious and ethnic minorities, that the Secretary of State declared were targeted for genocide, crimes against humanity, or war crimes, and have been identified as being at risk of persecution, forced migration, genocide, crimes against humanity, or war crimes.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="5">“SEC. 5.</num><heading> ACTIONS TO PROMOTE ACCOUNTABILITY IN IRAQ FOR GENOCIDE, CRIMES AGAINST HUMANITY, AND WAR CRIMES.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assistance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development are authorized to provide assistance, including financial and technical assistance, as necessary and appropriate, to support the efforts of entities, including nongovernmental organizations with expertise in international criminal investigations and law, to address genocide, crimes against humanity, or war crimes, and their constituent crimes by ISIS in Iraq by—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> conducting criminal investigations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> developing indigenous investigative and judicial skills, including by partnering, directly mentoring, and providing necessary equipment and infrastructure to effectively adjudicating cases consistent with due process and respect for the rule of law; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> collecting and preserving evidence and the chain of evidence, including for use in prosecutions in domestic courts, hybrid courts, and internationalized domestic courts, consistent with the activities described in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Actions by Foreign Governments</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Director of National Intelligence, and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, shall encourage governments of foreign countries—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to include information in appropriate security databases and security screening procedures of such countries to identify suspected ISIS members for whom credible evidence exists of having committed genocide, crimes against humanity, or war crimes, and their constituent crimes, in Iraq; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to apprehend and prosecute such ISIS members for genocide, crimes against humanity, or war crimes, as appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of State shall consult with and consider credible information from entities described in such subsection.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="6">“SEC. 6.</num><heading> IDENTIFICATION OF AND ASSISTANCE TO ADDRESS HUMANITARIAN, STABILIZATION, AND RECOVERY NEEDS OF CERTAIN PERSONS IN IRAQ AND SYRIA.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Identification</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, and Director of National Intelligence, shall seek to identify—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> threats of persecution and other early-warning indicators of genocide, crimes against humanity, and war crimes against individuals who are or were nationals and residents of Iraq or Syria, are members of religious or ethnic minority groups in such countries, and against whom the Secretary of State has determined ISIS has committed genocide, crimes against humanity, or war crimes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the religious and ethnic minority groups in Iraq or Syria identified pursuant to paragraph (1) that are at risk of forced migration, within or across the borders of Iraq, Syria, or a country of first asylum, and the primary reasons for such risk;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> the humanitarian, stabilization, and recovery needs of individuals described in paragraphs (1) and (2), including the assistance provided by the United States and by the United Nations, respectively—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> to address the humanitarian, stabilization, and recovery needs of such individuals; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> to mitigate the risks of forced migration of such individuals; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> assistance provided through the Funding Facility for Immediate Stabilization and Funding Facility for Expanded Stabilization; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><chapeau> to the extent practicable and appropriate—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the entities, including faith-based entities, that are providing assistance to address the humanitarian, stabilization, and recovery needs of individuals described in paragraphs (1) and (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the extent to which the United States is providing assistance to or through the entities referred to in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional Consultation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of State shall consult with, and consider credible information from—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> individuals described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of such subsection; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the entities described in paragraph (4)(A) of such subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assistance</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development are authorized to provide assistance, including financial and technical assistance as necessary and appropriate, to support the entities described in subsection (a)(4)(A).</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="7">“SEC. 7.</num><heading> REPORT.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-12-11">Dec. 11, 2018</date>], the Secretary of State shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that includes—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> a detailed description of the efforts taken, and efforts proposed to be taken, to implement the provisions of this Act;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> an assessment of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the feasibility and advisability of prosecuting ISIS members for whom credible evidence exists of having committed genocide, crimes against humanity, or war crimes in Iraq, including in domestic courts in Iraq, hybrid courts, and internationalized domestic courts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> the measures needed—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> to ensure effective criminal investigations of such individuals; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> to effectively collect and preserve evidence, and preserve the chain of evidence, for prosecution; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> recommendations for legislative remedies and administrative actions to facilitate the implementation of this Act.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Form</inline>.—</heading><content>The report required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex, if necessary.”</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe933dc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Human Rights Sanctions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tXII">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII</ref>, subtitle F, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2533">130 Stat. 2533</ref>, known as the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act and formerly set out as a note under this section, was transferred to chapter 108 (§ 10101 et seq.) of this title. <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1265">Section 1265 of Pub. L. 114–328</ref>, which terminated the authority to impose sanctions under the Act 6 years after <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/117/110/s6/a">Pub. L. 117–110, § 6(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-04-08">Apr. 8, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/1165">136 Stat. 1165</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe933dd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Global Engagement Center</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dA/tXII/s1231">Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XII, § 1231</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/458">137 Stat. 458</ref>, required Secretary of Defense to report to Congress not later than 30 days after making funds or personnel available to the Global Engagement Center.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dE/tLIII/s5320">Pub. L. 117–81, div. E, title LIII, § 5320</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/2368">135 Stat. 2368</ref>, authorized Secretary of State to appoint employees of Department of State to carry out functions of the Global Engagement Center.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tXII/s1287">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1287</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2546">130 Stat. 2546</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tXII/s1284">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1284</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/2076">132 Stat. 2076</ref>, which established a Global Engagement Center within the Department of State to direct, lead, synchronize, integrate, and coordinate efforts of the Federal Government to recognize, understand, expose, and counter foreign state and non-state propaganda and disinformation efforts aimed at undermining or influencing the policies, security, or stability of the United States and United States allies and partner nations, terminated 8 years after <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe933de-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Strategy for the United States Relationship With Saudi Arabia</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/53/tXX/s2043">Pub. L. 110–53, title XX, § 2043</ref>, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/524">121 Stat. 524</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/53/tXX/s2043">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Congressional Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Congress finds that:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The National Commission on Terrorist Attacks Upon the United States concluded that the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia has ‘been a problematic ally in combating Islamic extremism. At the level of high policy, Saudi Arabia’s leaders cooperated with American diplomatic initiatives aimed at the Taliban or Pakistan before 9/11. At the same time, Saudi Arabia’s society was a place where al Qaeda raised money directly from individuals and through charities. It was the society that produced 15 of the 19 hijackers.’.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Saudi Arabia has an uneven record in the fight against terrorism, especially with respect to terrorist financing, support for radical madrassas, a lack of political outlets for its citizens, and restrictions on religious pluralism, that poses a threat to the security of the United States, the international community, and Saudi Arabia itself.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The National Commission on Terrorist Attacks Upon the United States concluded that the ‘problems in the U.S.-Saudi relationship must be confronted, openly’. It recommended that the two countries build a relationship that includes a ‘shared commitment to political and economic reform . . . and a shared interest in greater tolerance and cultural respect, translating into a commitment to fight the violent extremists who foment hatred’.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The United States has a national security interest in working with the Government of Saudi Arabia to combat international terrorists that operate within that country or that operate outside Saudi Arabia with the support of citizens of Saudi Arabia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> The United States and Saudi Arabia established a Strategic Dialogue in 2005, which provides a framework for the two countries to discuss a range of bilateral issues at high levels, including counterterrorism policy and political and economic reforms.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> It is in the national security interest of the United States to support the Government of Saudi Arabia in undertaking a number of political and economic reforms, including increasing anti-terrorism operations conducted by law enforcement agencies, providing more political and religious rights to its citizens, increasing the rights of women, engaging in comprehensive educational reform, enhancing monitoring of charitable organizations, and promulgating and enforcing domestic laws and regulation on terrorist financing.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Statement of Policy</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>It is the policy of the United States—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to engage with the Government of Saudi Arabia to openly confront the issue of terrorism, as well as other problematic issues such as the lack of political freedoms;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to enhance counterterrorism cooperation with the Government of Saudi Arabia; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> to support the efforts of the Government of Saudi Arabia to make political, economic, and social reforms, including greater religious freedom, throughout the country.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Progress in Counterterrorism and Other Cooperation.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>], the President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> describes the long-term strategy of the United States—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> to engage with the Government of Saudi Arabia to facilitate political, economic, and social reforms, including greater religious freedom, that will enhance the ability of the Government of Saudi Arabia to combat international terrorism; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> to work with the Government of Saudi Arabia to combat terrorism, including through effective measures to prevent and prohibit the financing of terrorists by Saudi institutions and citizens; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> provides an assessment of the progress made by Saudi Arabia since 2001 on the matters described in subparagraph (A), including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> whether Saudi Arabia has become a party to the International Convention for the Suppression of the Financing of Terrorism; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the activities and authority of the Saudi Nongovernmental National Commission for Relief and Charity Work Abroad.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Form</inline>.—</heading><content>The report required by paragraph (1) shall be transmitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex, if necessary.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definition of “appropriate congressional committees” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/110/53/s2043">section 2043 of Pub. L. 110–53</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/53/s2002">section 2002 of Pub. L. 110–53</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">section 2151 of this title</ref>.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For assignment of functions of President under <ref href="/us/pl/110/53/s2043/c/1">section 2043(c)(1) of Pub. L. 110–53</ref>, set out above, see Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2007-09-28">Sept. 28, 2007</date>, 72 F.R. 56871, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2228">section 2228 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe933df-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Findings</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tVII/s7101">Pub. L. 108–458, title VII, § 7101</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3775">118 Stat. 3775</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/458/tVII/s7101">
<inline>“Consistent with the report of the National Commission on Terrorist Attacks Upon the United States, Congress makes the following findings:</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Long-term success in the war on terrorism demands the use of all elements of national power, including diplomacy, military action, intelligence, covert action, law enforcement, economic policy, foreign aid, public diplomacy, and homeland defense.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> To win the war on terrorism, the United States must assign to economic and diplomatic capabilities the same strategic priority that is assigned to military capabilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The legislative and executive branches of the Government of the United States must commit to robust, long-term investments in all of the tools necessary for the foreign policy of the United States to successfully accomplish the goals of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The investments referred to in paragraph (3) will require increased funding to United States foreign affairs programs in general, and to priority areas as described in this title [see Tables for classification] in particular.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe933e0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Comprehensive Coalition Strategy for Fighting Terrorism</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tVII/s7117">Pub. L. 108–458, title VII, § 7117</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3799">118 Stat. 3799</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/458/tVII/s7117">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Consistent with the report of the National Commission on Terrorist Attacks Upon the United States, Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Almost every aspect of the counterterrorism strategy of the United States relies on international cooperation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Since <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>, the number and scope of United States Government contacts with foreign governments concerning counterterrorism have expanded significantly, but such contacts have often been ad hoc and not integrated as a comprehensive and unified approach to counterterrorism.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of State is authorized in consultation with relevant United States Government agencies, to negotiate on a bilateral or multilateral basis, as appropriate, international agreements under which parties to an agreement work in partnership to address and interdict acts of international terrorism.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">International Contact Group on Counterterrorism.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sense of congress</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>It is the sense of Congress that the President—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> should seek to engage the leaders of the governments of other countries in a process of advancing beyond separate and uncoordinated national counterterrorism strategies to develop with those other governments a comprehensive multilateral strategy to fight terrorism; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> to that end, should seek to establish an international counterterrorism policy contact group with the leaders of governments providing leadership in global counterterrorism efforts and governments of countries with sizable Muslim populations, to be used as a ready and flexible international means for discussing and coordinating the development of important counterterrorism policies by the participating governments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The President is authorized to establish an international counterterrorism policy contact group with the leaders of governments referred to in paragraph (1) for the following purposes:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> To meet annually, or more frequently as the President determines appropriate, to develop in common with such other governments important policies and a strategy that address the various components of international prosecution of the war on terrorism, including policies and a strategy that address military issues, law enforcement, the collection, analysis, and dissemination of intelligence, issues relating to interdiction of travel by terrorists, counterterrorism-related customs issues, financial issues, and issues relating to terrorist sanctuaries.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> To address, to the extent (if any) that the President and leaders of other participating governments determine appropriate, long-term issues that can contribute to strengthening stability and security in the Middle East.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe933e1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">International Agreements To Track and Curtail Terrorist Travel Through the Use of Fraudulently Obtained Documents</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/458/tVII/s7204">Pub. L. 108–458, title VII, § 7204</ref>, <date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/3814">118 Stat. 3814</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/458/tVII/s7204">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> International terrorists travel across international borders to raise funds, recruit members, train for operations, escape capture, communicate, and plan and carry out attacks.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The international terrorists who planned and carried out the attack on the World Trade Center on <date date="1993-02-26">February 26, 1993</date>, the attack on the embassies of the United States in Kenya and Tanzania on <date date="1998-08-07">August 7, 1998</date>, the attack on the USS Cole on <date date="2000-10-12">October 12, 2000</date>, and the attack on the World Trade Center and the Pentagon on <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>, traveled across international borders to plan and carry out these attacks.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The international terrorists who planned other attacks on the United States, including the plot to bomb New York City landmarks in 1993, the plot to bomb the New York City subway in 1997, and the millennium plot to bomb Los Angeles International Airport on <date date="1999-12-31">December 31, 1999</date>, traveled across international borders to plan and carry out these attacks.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Many of the international terrorists who planned and carried out large-scale attacks against foreign targets, including the attack in Bali, Indonesia, on <date date="2002-10-11">October 11, 2002</date>, and the attack in Madrid, Spain, on <date date="2004-03-11">March 11, 2004</date>, traveled across international borders to plan and carry out these attacks.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Throughout the 1990s, international terrorists, including those involved in the attack on the World Trade Center on <date date="1993-02-26">February 26, 1993</date>, the plot to bomb New York City landmarks in 1993, and the millennium plot to bomb Los Angeles International Airport on <date date="1999-12-31">December 31, 1999</date>, traveled on fraudulent passports and often had more than 1 passport.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> Two of the <date date="2001-09-11">September 11, 2001</date>, hijackers were carrying passports that had been manipulated in a fraudulent manner.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> The National Commission on Terrorist Attacks Upon the United States, (commonly referred to as the 9/11 Commission), stated that ‘Targeting travel is at least as powerful a weapon against terrorists as targeting their money.’.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">International Agreements To Track and Curtail Terrorist Travel.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">International agreement on lost, stolen, or falsified documents</inline>.—</heading><content>The President should lead efforts to track and curtail the travel of terrorists by supporting the drafting, adoption, and implementation of international agreements, and relevant United Nations Security Council resolutions to track and stop international travel by terrorists and other criminals through the use of lost, stolen, or falsified documents to augment United Nations and other international anti-terrorism efforts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents of international agreement</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The President should seek, as appropriate, the adoption or full implementation of effective international measures to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> share information on lost, stolen, and fraudulent passports and other travel documents for the purposes of preventing the undetected travel of persons using such passports and other travel documents that were obtained improperly;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> establish and implement a real-time verification system of passports and other travel documents with issuing authorities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> share with officials at ports of entry in any such country information relating to lost, stolen, and fraudulent passports and other travel documents;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><chapeau> encourage countries—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><chapeau> to criminalize—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> the falsification or counterfeiting of travel documents or breeder documents for any purpose;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> the use or attempted use of false documents to obtain a visa or cross a border for any purpose;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="III">     “(III)</num><content> the possession of tools or implements used to falsify or counterfeit such documents;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="IV">     “(IV)</num><content> the trafficking in false or stolen travel documents and breeder documents for any purpose;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="V">     “(V)</num><content> the facilitation of travel by a terrorist; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="VI">     “(VI)</num><content> attempts to commit, including conspiracies to commit, the crimes specified in subclauses (I) through (V);</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> to impose significant penalties to appropriately punish violations and effectively deter the crimes specified in clause (i); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><chapeau> to limit the issuance of citizenship papers, passports, identification documents, and similar documents to persons—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> whose identity is proven to the issuing authority;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> who have a bona fide entitlement to or need for such documents; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="III">     “(III)</num><content> who are not issued such documents principally on account of a disproportional payment made by them or on their behalf to the issuing authority;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> provide technical assistance to countries to help them fully implement such measures; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><chapeau> permit immigration and border officials—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> to confiscate a lost, stolen, or falsified passport at ports of entry;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> to permit the traveler to return to the sending country without being in possession of the lost, stolen, or falsified passport; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> to detain and investigate such traveler upon the return of the traveler to the sending country.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">International civil aviation organization</inline>.—</heading><content>The United States shall lead efforts to track and curtail the travel of terrorists by supporting efforts at the International Civil Aviation Organization to continue to strengthen the security features of passports and other travel documents.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2004-12-17">Dec. 17, 2004</date>], and at least annually thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on progress toward achieving the goals described in subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading><content>Paragraph (1) shall cease to be effective when the President certifies to the Committee on International Relations [now Committee on Foreign Affairs] of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate that the goals described in subsection (b) have been fully achieved.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Functions of President under subsec. (c) of <ref href="/us/pl/108/458/s7204">section 7204 of Pub. L. 108–458</ref>, set out above, assigned to Secretary of State by section 1 of Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2005-04-21">Apr. 21, 2005</date>, 70 F.R. 48633, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref>, The President.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe933e2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">East Timor Transition to Independence</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/228/dA/tVI">Pub. L. 107–228, div. A, title VI</ref>, subtitle C, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1399">116 Stat. 1399</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/228/dA/tVI">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="631">“SEC. 631.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This subtitle may be cited as the ‘East Timor Transition to Independence Act of 2002’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="632">“SEC. 632.</num><heading> BILATERAL ASSISTANCE.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The President, acting through the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, is authorized to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> support the development of civil society, including nongovernmental organizations in East Timor;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> promote the development of an independent news media;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> support job creation, including support for small business and microenterprise programs, environmental protection, sustainable development, development of East Timor’s health care infrastructure, educational programs, and programs strengthening the role of women in society;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> promote reconciliation, conflict resolution, and prevention of further conflict with respect to East Timor, including establishing accountability for past gross human rights violations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> support the voluntary and safe repatriation and reintegration of refugees into East Timor;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> support political party development, voter education, voter registration, and other activities in support of free and fair elections in East Timor; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> promote the development of the rule of law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>There is authorized to be appropriated to the President to carry out this section $25,000,000 for the fiscal year 2003.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Availability</inline>.—</heading><content>Amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under paragraph (1) are authorized to remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="633">“SEC. 633.</num><heading> MULTILATERAL ASSISTANCE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States executive director at each international financial institution to which the United States is a member to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States to support economic and democratic development in East Timor.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="634">“SEC. 634.</num><heading> TRADE AND INVESTMENT ASSISTANCE.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">OPIC</inline>.—</heading><content>The President should initiate negotiations with the Government of East Timor to enter into a new agreement authorizing the Overseas Private Investment Corporation [now the United States International Development Finance Corporation] to carry out programs with respect to East Timor in order to expand United States investment in East Timor, emphasizing partnerships with local East Timorese enterprises.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Trade and Development Agency.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of the Trade and Development Agency is authorized to carry out projects in East Timor under section 661 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2421">22 U.S.C. 2421</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of appropriations.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Trade and Development Agency to carry out this subsection $1,000,000 for fiscal year 2003.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Availability</inline>.—</heading><content>Amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under subparagraph (A) are authorized to remain available until expended.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Export-Import Bank</inline>.—</heading><content>The Export-Import Bank of the United States should expand its activities in connection with exports to East Timor to the extent such activities are requested and to the extent there is a reasonable assurance of repayment.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="635">“SEC. 635.</num><heading> GENERALIZED SYSTEM OF PREFERENCES.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“As soon as possible after the enactment of this Act [<date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>], the United States Trade Representative and the Commissioner of Customs should send an assessment team to East Timor to compile a list of duty-free eligible products so that the Government of East Timor can begin the process of applying for General System of Preference benefits.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="636">“SEC. 636.</num><heading> AUTHORITY FOR RADIO BROADCASTING.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“The Broadcasting Board of Governors [now United States Agency for Global Media] should broadcast to East Timor in an appropriate language or languages.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="637">“SEC. 637.</num><heading> SECURITY ASSISTANCE FOR EAST TIMOR.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study and Report.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The President shall conduct a study to determine—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the extent to which East Timor’s security needs can be met by the transfer of excess defense articles under section 516 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2321j">22 U.S.C. 2321j</ref>];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the extent to which international military education and training (IMET) assistance will enhance professionalism of the armed forces of East Timor, provide training in human rights, and promote respect for human rights and humanitarian law; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the terms and conditions under which such defense articles or training, as appropriate, should be provided.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>], the President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains the findings of the study conducted under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Assistance.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Beginning on the date on which Congress receives the report transmitted under subsection (a)(2), or the date on which Congress receives the certification transmitted under paragraph (2), whichever occurs later, the President is authorized—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> to transfer excess defense articles under section 516 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2321j">22 U.S.C. 2321j</ref>) to East Timor in accordance with such section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> to provide military education and training under chapter 5 of part II of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2347">22 U.S.C. 2347</ref> et seq.) for the armed forces of East Timor in accordance with such chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certification</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A certification described in this paragraph is a certification that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> East Timor has established an independent armed forces; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> the assistance proposed to be provided pursuant to paragraph (1)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> is in the national security interests of the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> will promote both human rights in East Timor and the professionalization of the armed forces of East Timor.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="638">“SEC. 638.</num><heading> REPORTING REQUIREMENT.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>], and every 12 months thereafter for the next five years, the Secretary shall prepare and transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains the information described in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Information</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The report required by subsection (a) shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> developments in East Timor’s political and economic situation in the period covered by the report, including an evaluation of any elections which have occurred in East Timor and the refugee reintegration process in East Timor;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> in the initial report, a 3-year plan for United States foreign assistance to East Timor in accordance with section 632, prepared by the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, which outlines the goals for United States foreign assistance to East Timor during the 3-year period;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> a description of the activities undertaken in East Timor by the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, the Asian Development Bank, and other international financial institutions, and an evaluation of the effectiveness of these activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> an assessment of the status of United States trade and investment relations with East Timor, including a detailed analysis of any trade and investment-related activity supported by the Overseas Private Investment Corporation [now the United States International Development Finance Corporation], the Export-Import Bank of the United States, or the Trade and Development Agency during the period of time since the previous report;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> a comprehensive study and report on local agriculture in East Timor, emerging opportunities for producing, processing, and exporting indigenous agricultural products, and recommendations for appropriate technical assistance from the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> statistical data drawn from other sources on economic growth, health, education, and distribution of resources in East Timor.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the United States Customs Service of the Department of the Treasury, including functions of the Secretary of the Treasury relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 203(1), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>. For establishment of U.S. Customs and Border Protection in the Department of Homeland Security, treated as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref> as of <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>, as amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/114/125">Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/114/125/s802/b">section 802(b) of Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “appropriate congressional committees” and “Secretary” as used in subtitle C of title VI of div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/107/228">Pub. L. 107–228</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/228/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 107–228</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2651">section 2651 of this title</ref>.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For Presidential certification authorizing security assistance to East Timor pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/107/228/s637/b/2">section 637(b)(2) of Pub. L. 107–228</ref>, set out above, see Presidential Determination No. 2003–19, set out below.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe933e3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pacific Charter Commission</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/570/tIV">Pub. L. 106–570, title IV</ref>, <date date="2000-12-27">Dec. 27, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/3047">114 Stat. 3047</ref>, known as the Pacific Charter Commission Act of 2000, provided for the establishment of the Pacific Charter Commission to promote United States foreign policy, support democratization, rule of law, and human rights, promote United States exports, assist in combating terrorism and spread of illicit narcotics, and advocate for United States diplomacy, all in the Asia-Pacific region, with authority to establish the Commission to expire <date date="2002-12-31">Dec. 31, 2002</date>, and termination of the Commission to occur not later than six years after the date of establishment.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe933e4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Record of War Criminals and Sanctioned Countries, Entities, and Municipalities; Role of Human Rights Organizations and Government Agencies</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/429/s101/a/tV/s564/e">Pub. L. 106–429, § 101(a) [title V, § 564(e), (g), (j), (k)]</ref>, <date date="2000-11-06">Nov. 6, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1900">114 Stat. 1900</ref>, 1900A–48 to 1900A–50, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/112/74/dI/tVII/s7034/n">Pub. L. 112–74, div. I, title VII, § 7034(n)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1217">125 Stat. 1217</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/74/dI/tVII/s7034/n">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sanctioned Country, Entity, or Municipality</inline>.—</heading><content>A sanctioned country, entity, or municipality described in this section [<ref href="/us/stat/114/1900">114 Stat. 1900</ref>A–46] is one whose competent authorities have failed, as determined by the Secretary of State, to take necessary and significant steps to apprehend and transfer to the Tribunal all persons who have been publicly indicted by the Tribunal.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Current Record of War Criminals and Sanctioned Countries, Entities, and Municipalities.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of State shall establish and maintain a current record of the location, including the municipality, if known, of publicly indicted war criminals and a current record of sanctioned countries, entities, and municipalities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Information of the dci and the secretary of defense</inline>.—</heading><content>The Director of Central Intelligence and the Secretary of Defense should collect and provide to the Secretary of State information concerning the location, including the municipality, of publicly indicted war criminals.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Information of the tribunal</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of State shall request that the Tribunal and other international organizations and governments provide the Secretary of State information concerning the location, including the municipality, of publicly indicted war criminals and concerning country, entity and municipality authorities known to have obstructed the work of the Tribunal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1" status="repealed"><num value="4">“[(4)</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/112/74/dI/tVII/s7034/n">Pub. L. 112–74, div. I, title VII, § 7034(n)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1217">125 Stat. 1217</ref>.]</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Information to congress</inline>.—</heading><content>Upon the request of the chairman or ranking minority member of any of the appropriate congressional committees, the Secretary of State shall make available to that committee the information recorded under paragraph (1) in a report submitted to the committee in classified and unclassified form.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="j">“(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>As used in this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Country</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘country’ means Bosnia-Herzegovina, Croatia, and Serbia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Entity</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘entity’ refers to the Federation of Bosnia and Herzegovina, Kosova, Montenegro, and the Republika Srpska.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Dayton agreement</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Dayton Agreement’ means the General Framework Agreement for Peace in Bosnia and Herzegovina, together with annexes relating thereto, done at Dayton, November 10 through 16, 1995.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Tribunal</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Tribunal’ means the International Criminal Tribunal for the Former Yugoslavia.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="k">“(k)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Role of Human Rights Organizations and Government Agencies</inline>.—</heading><content>In carrying out this section, the Secretary of State, the Administrator of the Agency for International Development, and the executive directors of the international financial institutions shall consult with representatives of human rights organizations and all government agencies with relevant information to help prevent publicly indicted war criminals from benefiting from any financial or technical assistance or grants provided to any country or entity described in subsection (e).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Reference to the Director of Central Intelligence or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency in the Director’s capacity as the head of the intelligence community deemed to be a reference to the Director of National Intelligence. Reference to the Director of Central Intelligence or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency in the Director’s capacity as the head of the Central Intelligence Agency deemed to be a reference to the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency. See section 1081(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/108/458">Pub. L. 108–458</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3001">section 3001 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Similar provisions were contained in the following prior appropriation act:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/2/tV/s566/e">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(2) [title V, § 566(e), (g), (j), (k)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1535">113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–107 to 1501A–109.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe933e5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report Concerning Financial Disadvantages for Administrative and Technical Personnel</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/7/dA/tIII/s338">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(7) [div. A, title III, § 338]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–443, provided findings regarding financial disadvantages of administrative and technical personnel posted to United States missions abroad who do not have diplomatic status and required related report to Congress by the Secretary of State not later than one year after <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe933e6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prisoner Information Registry for the People’s Republic of China</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/7/dA/tVIII/s873">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(7) [div. A, title VIII, § 873]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–474, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/7/dA/tVIII/s873">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of State shall establish and maintain a registry which shall, to the extent practicable, provide information on all political prisoners, prisoners of conscience, and prisoners of faith in the People’s Republic of China. The registry shall be known as the ‘Prisoner Information Registry for the People’s Republic of China’.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Information in Registry</inline>.—</heading><content>The registry required by subsection (a) shall include information on the charges, judicial processes, administrative actions, uses of forced labor, incidents of torture, lengths of imprisonment, physical and health conditions, and other matters associated with the incarceration of prisoners in the People’s Republic of China referred to in that subsection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Availability of Funds</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may make a grant to nongovernmental organizations currently engaged in monitoring activities regarding political prisoners in the People’s Republic of China in order to assist in the establishment and maintenance of the registry required by subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe933e7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report to Congress on Activities of North Korean Armed Forces</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tI/s101/c/tV/s585">Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(c) [title V, § 585]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-121">110 Stat. 3009–121</ref>, 3009–171, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/107/228/dB/tXIII/s1308/g/1/D">Pub. L. 107–228, div. B, title XIII, § 1308(g)(1)(D)</ref>, (2), <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1441">116 Stat. 1441</ref>, which required the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, to provide semiannual reports relating to the military forces of the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/113/76/dK/tVII/s7034/i">Pub. L. 113–76, div. K, title VII, § 7034(i)</ref>, <date date="2014-01-17">Jan. 17, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/514">128 Stat. 514</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe933e8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Reports to War Crimes Tribunal for Former Yugoslavia</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/2/tV/s552">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(2) [title V, § 552]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1535">113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–99, provided in part: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/2/tV/s552">“That 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>], and every 180 days thereafter, the Secretary of State shall submit a report to the Committees on Appropriations describing the steps the United States Government is taking to collect information regarding allegations of genocide or other violations of international law in the former Yugoslavia and to furnish that information to the United Nations War Crimes Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia”.</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>Similar provisions were contained in the following appropriation acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/429/s101/a/tV/s552">Pub. L. 106–429, § 101(a) [title V, § 552]</ref>, <date date="2000-11-06">Nov. 6, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1900">114 Stat. 1900</ref>, 1900A–41.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dA/s101/d/tV/s554">Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(d) [title V, § 554]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-150">112 Stat. 2681–150</ref>, 2681–188.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/118/tV/s553">Pub. L. 105–118, title V, § 553</ref>, <date date="1997-11-26">Nov. 26, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2422">111 Stat. 2422</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tI/s101/c/tV/s555">Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(c) [title V, § 555]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-121">110 Stat. 3009–121</ref>, 3009–160.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/107/tV/s556">Pub. L. 104–107, title V, § 556</ref>, <date date="1996-02-12">Feb. 12, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/743">110 Stat. 743</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/306/tV/s575">Pub. L. 103–306, title V, § 575</ref>, <date date="1994-08-23">Aug. 23, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1653">108 Stat. 1653</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe933e9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Reporting Requirements on Occupied Tibet</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/236/tV/s536">Pub. L. 103–236, title V, § 536</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/481">108 Stat. 481</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/236/tV/s536">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report on United States-Tibet Relations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Because Congress has determined that Tibet is an occupied sovereign country under international law and that its true representatives are the Dalai Lama and the Tibetan Government in exile—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> it is the sense of the Congress that the United States should seek to establish a dialogue with those recognized by Congress as the true representatives of the Tibetan people, the Dalai Lama, his representatives and the Tibetan Government in exile, concerning the situation in Tibet and the future of the Tibetan people and to expand and strengthen United States-Tibet cultural and educational relations, including promoting bilateral exchanges arranged directly with the Tibetan Government in exile; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>], and every 12 months thereafter, the Secretary of State shall transmit to the Chairman of the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Speaker of the House of Representatives a report on the state of relations between the United States and those recognized by Congress as the true representatives of the Tibetan people, the Dalai Lama, his representatives and the Tibetan Government in exile, and on conditions in Tibet.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Separate Tibet Reports.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> It is the sense of the Congress that whenever a report is transmitted to the Congress on a country-by-country basis there should be included in such report, where applicable, a separate report on Tibet listed alphabetically with its own state heading.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The reports referred to in paragraph (1) include, but are not limited to, reports transmitted under sections 116(d) and 502B(b) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151n/d">22 U.S.C. 2151n(d)</ref>, 2304(b)] (relating to human rights).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8fe933ea-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Cambodian Genocide</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/236/tV/ptD">Pub. L. 103–236, title V, part D</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/486">108 Stat. 486</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/236/tV/ptD">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="571">“SEC. 571.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This part may be cited as the ‘Cambodian Genocide Justice Act’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="572">“SEC. 572.</num><heading> POLICY.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Consistent with international law, it is the policy of the United States to support efforts to bring to justice members of the Khmer Rouge for their crimes against humanity committed in Cambodia between <date date="1975-04-17">April 17, 1975</date>, and <date date="1979-01-07">January 7, 1979</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Specific Actions Urged</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>To that end, the Congress urges the President—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to collect, or assist appropriate organizations and individuals to collect relevant data on crimes of genocide committed in Cambodia;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> in circumstances which the President deems appropriate, to encourage the establishment of a national or international criminal tribunal for the prosecution of those accused of genocide in Cambodia; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> as necessary, to provide such national or international tribunal with information collected pursuant to paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="573">“SEC. 573.</num><heading> ESTABLISHMENT OF STATE DEPARTMENT OFFICE.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> None of the funds authorized to be appropriated by this Act for ‘Diplomatic and Consular Programs’ shall be available for obligation or expenditure during fiscal years 1994 and 1995 unless, not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>], the Secretary of State has established within the Department of State under the Assistant Secretary for East Asia and Pacific Affairs (or any successor Assistant Secretary) the Office of Cambodian Genocide Investigation (hereafter in this part referred to as the ‘Office’).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Office may carry out its activities inside or outside of Cambodia, except that not less than 75 percent of the funds made available for the Office and its activities shall be used to carry out activities within Cambodia.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The purpose of the Office shall be to support, through organizations and individuals with whom the Secretary of State may contract to carry out the operations of the Office, as appropriate, efforts to bring to justice members of the Khmer Rouge for their crimes against humanity committed in Cambodia between <date date="1975-04-17">April 17, 1975</date>, and <date date="1979-01-07">January 7, 1979</date>, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to investigate crimes against humanity committed by national Khmer Rouge leaders during that period;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to provide the people of Cambodia with access to documents, records, and other evidence held by the Office as a result of such investigation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> to submit the relevant data to a national or international penal tribunal that may be convened to formally hear and judge the genocidal acts committed by the Khmer Rouge; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> to develop the United States proposal for the establishment of an international criminal tribunal for the prosecution of those accused of genocide in Cambodia.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contracting Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of State shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, contract with appropriate individuals and organizations to carry out the purpose of the Office.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notification to Congress</inline>.—</heading><content>The Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives shall be notified of any exercise of the authority of section 34 of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2706">22 U.S.C. 2706</ref>] with respect to the Office or any of its programs, projects, or activities at least 15 days in advance in accordance with procedures applicable to notifications under that section.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="574">“SEC. 574.</num><heading> REPORTING REQUIREMENT.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Beginning 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>], and every 6 months thereafter, the President shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> that describes the activities of the Office, and sets forth new facts learned about past Khmer Rouge practices, during the preceding 6-month period; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> that describes the steps the President has taken during the preceding 6-month period to promote human rights, to support efforts to bring to justice the national political and military leadership of the Khmer Rouge, and to prevent the recurrence of human rights abuses in Cambodia through actions which are not related to United Nations activities in Cambodia.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this section, the term ‘appropriate congressional committees’ means the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.”</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Functions of President under <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s574">section 574 of Pub. L. 103–236</ref>, set out above, delegated to Secretary of State by Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="1994-07-26">July 26, 1994</date>, 59 F.R. 40205, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2370a">section 2370a of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8feba4eb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Broadening Cultural, Geographic, and Ethnic Representation of Foreign Service and Department of State; Plan</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/246/tI/s153/a">Pub. L. 101–246, title I, § 153(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1990-02-16">Feb. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/43">104 Stat. 43</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/101/302/tIII/s320/b/2">Pub. L. 101–302, title III, § 320(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-05-25">May 25, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/247">104 Stat. 247</ref>, required the Secretary of State to submit, not later than 120 days after <date date="1990-02-16">Feb. 16, 1990</date>, and to implement, not later than <date date="1991-01-01">Jan. 1, 1991</date>, a plan to assure equal efforts in recruiting certain employees from different regions in the United States.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8feba4ec-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prohibition on Use of Funds for Political Purposes</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/204/tI/s109">Pub. L. 100–204, title I, § 109</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1339">101 Stat. 1339</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/204/tI/s109">
<inline>“No funds authorized to be appropriated by this Act or by any other Act authorizing funds for any entity engaged in any activity concerning the foreign affairs of the United States shall be used—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> for publicity or propaganda purposes designed to support or defeat legislation pending before Congress;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to influence in any way the outcome of a political election in the United States; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> for any publicity or propaganda purposes not authorized by Congress.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8feba4ed-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Consular and Diplomatic Posts Abroad</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/204/tI/s122">Pub. L. 100–204, title I, § 122</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1339">101 Stat. 1339</ref>, prohibited use of appropriated funds for closing United States consular or diplomatic posts abroad, or for paying expenses related to Bureau of Administration of Department of State if a post was closed after <date date="1987-01-01">Jan. 1, 1987</date>, and not reopened, provided funding for certain consulates, provided exceptions for prohibition on use of appropriated funds, permitted Secretary of State, in case of a sequestration order, to submit a report proposing a list of consular posts to be downgraded or closed in order to comply with sequestration order, and provided that the prohibitions were to be effective 180 days after <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/102/138/tI/s112/b">Pub. L. 102–138, title I, § 112(b)</ref>, <date date="1991-10-28">Oct. 28, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/655">105 Stat. 655</ref>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2720">section 2720 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8feba4ee-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Closing of Diplomatic and Consular Posts in Antigua and Barbuda</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/204/tI/s123">Pub. L. 100–204, title I, § 123</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1339">101 Stat. 1339</ref>, directed that none of the funds made available for the Department of State for any fiscal year be used for expenses of maintaining a United States diplomatic or consular post in Antigua and Barbuda and provided that such prohibition take effect 60 days after <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, unless the President made a determination that such closing would not be in the national security interest of the United States and informed both the Chairman of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee and the House Foreign Affairs Committee of such determination, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/101/246/tI/s121">Pub. L. 101–246, title I, § 121</ref>, <date date="1990-02-16">Feb. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/27">104 Stat. 27</ref>. Such a determination had been made by Determination of President of the United States, No. 88–9, <date date="1988-02-09">Feb. 9, 1988</date>, 53 F.R. 5749.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8feba4ef-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Assignment of Drug Enforcement Administration Agents Abroad</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/204/tVIII/s801">Pub. L. 100–204, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1397">101 Stat. 1397</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/204/tVIII/s801">“If the Secretary of State, in exercising his authority to establish overseas staffing levels for Federal agencies with activities abroad, authorizes the assignment of any Drug Enforcement Administration agent to a particular United States mission abroad, the Secretary shall authorize the assignment of at least two such agents to that mission.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8feba4f0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Waiver of Provisions of <ref href="/us/pl/100/204">Public Law 100–204</ref> During Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101/a/tIII/s305">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(a) [title III, § 305]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1329">101 Stat. 1329</ref>, 1329–23, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/202/s101/a/tIII/s305">“The following sections of H.R. 1777 (the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989 [<ref href="/us/pl/100/204">Pub. L. 100–204</ref>]) are waived during Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989 in the event that H.R. 1777 is enacted into law: Sec. 122 [set out above], Sec. 151, and Sec. 204 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1461">22 U.S.C. 1461</ref> note].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8feba4f1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report to Congress on Soviet Breach of Duties Obligations to United States Diplomats or Missions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/500/s101/b/tIII/s300">Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(b) [title III, § 300]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1783-39">100 Stat. 1783–39</ref>, 1783–58, and <ref href="/us/pl/99/591/s101/b/tIII/s300">Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(b) [title III, § 300]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3341-39">100 Stat. 3341–39</ref>, 3341–58, which required the Secretary of State to report every six months to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate on failures by Soviet agencies to perform obligations to United States diplomats or United States missions to the Soviet Union and on actions undertaken by the Department of State to redress these failures, terminated, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance. See, also, page 127 of House Document No. 103–7.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8feba4f2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Responsibility of United States Missions To Promote Freedom of Press Abroad</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/93/tI/s138">Pub. L. 99–93, title I, § 138</ref>, <date date="1985-08-16">Aug. 16, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/422">99 Stat. 422</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/93/tI/s138">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Responsibility</inline>.—</heading><content>The United States chief of mission to a foreign country in which there is not respect for freedom of the press shall actively promote respect for freedom of the press in that country.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>As used in this section, the term ‘respect for freedom of the press’ means that a government—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> allows foreign news correspondents into the country and does not subject them to harassment or restrictions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> allows nongovernment-owned press to operate in the country; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> does not subject the press in the country to systematic censorship.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8feba4f3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Emergency Telephone Service at United States Consular Offices</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/93/tI/s139">Pub. L. 99–93, title I, § 139</ref>, <date date="1985-08-16">Aug. 16, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/422">99 Stat. 422</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/93/tI/s139">“It is the sense of the Congress that the Secretary of State should ensure that all United States consular offices are equipped with 24-hour emergency telephone service through which United States citizens can contact a member of the staff of any such office. The Secretary should publicize the telephone number of each such service for the information of United States citizens. Not more than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1985-08-16">Aug. 16, 1985</date>], the Secretary shall submit a report to the Congress on steps taken in accordance with this section.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8feba4f4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Torture by Foreign Governments; United States Policy in Opposition; Implementation</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/447">Pub. L. 98–447</ref>, <date date="1984-10-04">Oct. 4, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1721">98 Stat. 1721</ref>, provided: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/447">
<inline>“That the Congress reaffirms that it is the continuing policy of the United States Government to oppose the practice of torture by foreign governments through public and private diplomacy and, when necessary and appropriate, through the enactment and vigorous implementation of laws intended to reinforce United States policies with respect to torture. The United States Government opposes acts of torture wherever they occur, without regard to ideological or regional considerations, and will make every effort to work cooperatively with other governments and with nongovernmental organizations to combat the practice of torture worldwide.</inline>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="2">“Sec. 2.</num><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a"> (a)</num><chapeau> The President is requested—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to instruct the Permanent Representative of the United States to the United Nations to continue to raise the issue of torture practiced by governments; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to continue to involve the United States Government in the formulation of international standards and effective implementing mechanisms, particularly the draft Convention Against Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman or Degrading Treatment or Punishment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><chapeau> In order to implement the policy expressed in the first section of this resolution, the Secretary of State is requested to issue formal instructions to each United States chief of mission regarding United States policy with respect to torture, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> instructions—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> to examine allegations of the practice of torture, particularly allegations concerning the existence of secret detention, extended incommunicado detention, and restrictions on access by family members, lawyers, and independent medical personnel to detainees; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> to forward such information as may be gathered, including information regarding any efforts made by the host government to reduce and eliminate the practice of torture, to the Assistant Secretary of State for Human Rights and Humanitarian Affairs for analysis in preparing the Department’s annual country reports on human rights practices;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> in the case of a chief of mission assigned to a country where torture is regularly practiced, instructions to report on a periodic basis as circumstances require to the Assistant Secretary of State for Human Rights and Humanitarian Affairs regarding efforts made by the respective United States diplomatic mission to implement United States policy with respect to combating torture;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> instructions to meet with indigenous human rights monitoring groups knowledgeable about the practice of torture for the purpose of gathering information about such practice; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> instructions to express concern in individual cases of torture brought to the attention of a United States diplomatic mission including, whenever feasible, sending United States observers to trials when there is reason to believe that torture has been used against the accused.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> The Secretary of Commerce should continue to enforce vigorously the current restrictions on the export of crime control equipment pursuant to the Export Administration Act of 1979 [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4601">50 U.S.C. 4601</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><content> The heads of the appropriate departments of the United States Government that furnish military and law enforcement training to foreign personnel, particularly personnel from countries where the practice of torture has been a documented concern, shall include in such training, when relevant, instruction regarding international human rights standards and the policy of the United States with respect to torture.”</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Except as otherwise provided, Secretary of State to have and exercise any authority vested by law in any official or office of Department of State and references to such officials or offices deemed to refer to Secretary of State or Department of State, as appropriate, see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2651a">section 2651a of this title</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s161/d">section 161(d) of Pub. L. 103–236</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2651a">section 2651a of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8feba4f5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">United States Diplomatic Relations With the Vatican</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/164/tI/s134">Pub. L. 98–164, title I, § 134</ref>, <date date="1983-11-22">Nov. 22, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1029">97 Stat. 1029</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/164/tI/s134">“In order to provide for the establishment of United States diplomatic relations with the Vatican, the Act entitled ‘An Act making Appropriations for the Consular and Diplomatic Expenses of the Government for the Year ending thirtieth June, eighteen hundred and sixty-eight, and for other purposes’, approved <date date="1867-02-28">February 28, 1867</date>, is amended by repealing the following sentence (<ref href="/us/stat/14/413">14 Stat. 413</ref>): ‘And no money hereby or otherwise appropriated shall be paid for the support of an American legation at Rome, from and after the thirtieth day of June, eighteen hundred and sixty-seven.’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8feba4f6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Reopening Certain United States Consulates</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/241/tI/s103/b">Pub. L. 97–241, title I, § 103(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/273">96 Stat. 273</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/98/164/tI/s137">Pub. L. 98–164, title I, § 137</ref>, <date date="1983-11-22">Nov. 22, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1030">97 Stat. 1030</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/tI/s139/8">Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 139(8)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/398">108 Stat. 398</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/236/tI/s139/8">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> None of the funds made available under this [<ref href="/us/pl/97/241">Pub. L. 97–241</ref>] or any other Act for ‘Administration of Foreign Affairs’ may be used for the establishment or operation of any United States consulate that did not exist on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>] (other than the consulates specified in subsection (c)) until all the United States consulates specified in subsection (c) have been reopened as required by section 108 of the Department of State Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1980 and 1981 [<ref href="/us/pl/96/60/s108">section 108 of Pub. L. 96–60</ref>, set out as a note below], to the extent such reopening is authorized by the foreign government involved.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> The consulates referred to in subsections (a) [<ref href="/us/pl/97/241/s103/a">section 103(a) of Pub. L. 97–241</ref>, which was not classified to the Code] and (b) of this section are the consulates in the following locations: Turin, Italy; Salzburg, Austria; Goteborg, Sweden; Bremen, Germany; Nice, France; Mandalay, Burma; and Brisbane, Australia.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8feba4f7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">United States Consulates</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/96/60/tI/s108">Pub. L. 96–60, title I, § 108</ref>, <date date="1979-08-15">Aug. 15, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/397">93 Stat. 397</ref>, provided that U.S. consulates in Salzburg, Austria; Bremen, Germany; Nice, France; Turin, Italy; Goteborg, Sweden; Adana, Turkey; Tangier, Morocco; Mandalay, Burma; Brisbane, Australia; and Surabaya, Indonesia, would not be closed or, if closed as of <date date="1979-08-15">Aug. 15, 1979</date>, would be reopened as soon as possible after such date.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8feba4f8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Action With Regard to International Journalistic Freedom</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/426/tVI/s603">Pub. L. 95–426, title VI, § 603</ref>, <date date="1978-10-07">Oct. 7, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/985">92 Stat. 985</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/97/241/tV/s505/a/2">Pub. L. 97–241, title V, § 505(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/299">96 Stat. 299</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/241/tV/s505/a/2">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><chapeau> The Congress finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> news dissemination and the free flow of information across national boundaries are vital to international understanding and to healthy relations among countries; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> recurring and reliable reports strongly indicate that in many countries foreign news correspondents are subject to governmental harassment and restriction, including the denial of access to legitimate news sources, the imposition of censorship, and detention, incarceration, and expulsion.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><chapeau> It is therefore the sense of the Congress that the President should—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> advise the appropriate officials of any foreign government which subjects foreign news correspondents to harassment and restrictions that the United States considers such mistreatment a significant and potentially damaging factor in overall relations of the United States with such country; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> raise in appropriate international forums the issue of the treatment of foreign news correspondents, with a view toward gaining multilateral support for the legitimate rights of such correspondents.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> [Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/97/241/tV/s505/a/2">Pub. L. 97–241, title V, § 505(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/299">96 Stat. 299</ref>.]</heading><content>”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8feba4f9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Diplomatic Relations With Foreign Government Not Indication of Approval of Such Government</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/426/tVI/s607">Pub. L. 95–426, title VI, § 607</ref>, <date date="1978-10-07">Oct. 7, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/988">92 Stat. 988</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/426/tVI/s607">“The Congress finds that the conduct of diplomatic relations with a foreign government has as its principal purpose the discussion and negotiation with that government of outstanding issues and, like the recognition of a foreign government, does not in itself imply approval of that government or of the political-economic system it represents.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id8feba4fa-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id8feba4fb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of President respecting certain facilities constructed and maintained on United States borders delegated to Secretary of State, see Ex. Ord. No. 11423, <date date="1968-08-16">Aug. 16, 1968</date>, 33 F.R. 11741, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of Title 3</ref>, The President.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id8feba4fc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 13584</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 13584, <date date="2011-09-09">Sept. 9, 2011</date>, 76 F.R. 56945, which related to developing an integrated strategic counterterrorism communications initiative and establishing a temporary organization to support certain government-wide communications activities directed abroad, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 13721, § 2, <date date="2016-03-17">Mar. 17, 2016</date>, 81 F.R. 14685, set out below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id8feba4fd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 13721. Developing an Integrated Global Engagement Center To Support Government-wide Counterterrorism Communications Activities Directed Abroad and Revoking Executive Order 13584</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 13721, <date date="2016-03-14">Mar. 14, 2016</date>, 81 F.R. 14685, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2656">section 2656 of title 22</ref>, United States Code, and <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3161">section 3161 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Establishment of the Global Engagement Center</i>. The Secretary of State (Secretary) shall establish the Global Engagement Center (Center) which shall lead the coordination, integration, and synchronization of Government-wide communications activities directed at foreign audiences abroad in order to counter the messaging and diminish the influence of international terrorist organizations, including the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL), al Qa’ida, and other violent extremists abroad, with specific responsibilities as set forth in section 3 of this order. The executive director of the Center shall be the Special Envoy and Coordinator for Global Engagement Communications (Coordinator), who shall report to the Secretary through the Under Secretary of State for Public Diplomacy.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. <i>Revocation</i>. Executive Order 13584 of <date date="2011-09-09">September 9, 2011</date> (Developing an Integrated Strategic Counterterrorism Communications Initiative and Establishing a Temporary Organization to Support Certain Government-Wide Communications Activities Directed Abroad), is revoked.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. <i>Responsibilities Assigned to the Center</i>. Recognizing the need for innovation and new approaches to counter the messaging and diminish the influence of international terrorist organizations, including ISIL, al Qa’ida, and other violent extremists abroad, and in order to protect the vital national interests of the United States, while also recognizing the importance of protections for freedom of expression, including those under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States and international human rights obligations, the responsibilities and functions of the Center shall include the following:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) coordinating, integrating, and synchronizing all public communications of the United States Government directed toward foreign audiences abroad in order to counter the messaging and diminish the influence of international terrorist organizations and other violent extremists abroad;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) developing and promulgating throughout the executive branch, on the basis of rigorous research and modern data analysis, the U.S. strategic counterterrorism narratives, guidance, and associated communications strategies directed toward foreign audiences abroad in order to counter the messaging and diminish the influence of international terrorist organizations and other violent extremists abroad;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) consulting and engaging, in coordination with agencies and the Countering Violent Extremism Task Force, as appropriate, with a range of communications-related actors and entities, within the United States and abroad, including governments, private sector and civil society entities, in order to contribute to U.S. Government efforts to counter the communications-related radicalization to violence and recruitment activities of international terrorist organizations and other violent extremists abroad, while also building the capacity of partners to create resonant positive alternative narratives and to diminish the influence of such international terrorist organizations and other violent extremists abroad;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) identifying, engaging, employing, or acquiring the best available talent across the U.S. and from global private sectors, academia, and elsewhere to support the Center’s mission;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) identifying shortfalls in any U.S. capabilities in any areas relevant to the Center’s mission and implementing or recommending, as appropriate, necessary enhancements or changes; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(f) developing, supporting, and sustaining networks of governmental and non-governmental partners, to provide original content and disseminate messaging products to foreign audiences abroad and to create, develop, and sustain effective positive alternative narratives consistent with U.S. policy objectives.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 4. <i>Establishment of a Steering Committee</i>. The Secretary shall establish a Steering Committee composed of senior representatives of agencies relevant to the Center’s mission to provide advice to the Secretary on the operations and strategic orientation of the Center and to ensure adequate support for the Center. The Steering Committee shall be chaired by the Under Secretary of State for Public Diplomacy. The Steering Committee shall include one senior representative designated by the head of each of the following agencies: the Department of Defense, the Department of Justice, the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of the Treasury, the Small Business Administration, the National Counterterrorism Center, the Joint Chiefs of Staff, the Counterterrorism Center of the Central Intelligence Agency, the Broadcast Board of Governors, and the United States Agency for International Development. Other agencies may be invited to participate in the Steering Committee at the discretion of the Chair.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 5. <i>Interagency Support</i>. Agencies are hereby directed, consistent with budget priorities and mission constraints, upon request by the Secretary and to the extent permitted by law and consistent with the need to protect intelligence and law enforcement sources, methods, operations, and investigations, to provide to the Center, and the Center is authorized to use, for the purpose of carrying out the responsibilities outlined in this order:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) details or assignments of personnel, which shall be based on reasonable requests in light of the need for specific domain expertise, and after consultation with the relevant agency to ensure that such requests align with their authorities and resources;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) the use of physical premises, equipment, and logistical or administrative support;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) relevant information, research, intelligence, and analysis; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) such other resources and assistance as the Coordinator may request for the purpose of carrying out the responsibilities outlined in this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 6. <i>Establishment of a Temporary Organization</i>. (a) There is established within the Department of State, in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3161">section 3161 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, a temporary organization to be known as the Global Engagement Center Coordination Office (GECCO).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The purpose of the GECCO shall be to perform the specific project of providing technical, marketing, management, and operational support to the Center in its efforts to build and maintain a network of partners outside the U.S. Government, including private sector entities and non-governmental organizations, and to develop research and analytics to enable measurement and evaluation of the activities of the Center and related activities conducted by other agencies.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) In carrying out the purposes set forth in subsection (b) of this section, the GECCO shall:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) provide technical, marketing, management, and operational support for the management of contracts, grants, and cooperative agreements;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) assist the Center in building and maintaining partnerships with private sector entities, non-governmental organizations, and others as appropriate in support of the Center’s mission;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iii) design and develop sustained campaigns, in coordination with and primarily for use by private sector entities and non-governmental organizations, on specific areas of interest to foreign audiences abroad in support of the Center’s mission;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(iv) conduct or commission baseline research to establish the basis for evaluation of the activities of the Center and related activities conducted by other agencies;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(v) develop analytical models and metrics, consistent with the Center’s responsibilities, in order to enable measurement and evaluation of the activities of the Center in coordinating effective strategies to counter the messaging and diminish the influence of international terrorist organizations and other violent extremists abroad, and related activities conducted by other agencies; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(vi) perform such other functions related to the specific project set forth in subsection (b) of this section as the Secretary may assign.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The GECCO shall be headed by the Coordinator. Its staff may include, as determined by the Coordinator: (1) personnel with relevant expertise detailed on a non-reimbursable basis from other agencies; (2) senior and other technical advisers; (3) executive-level personnel; and (4) such other personnel as the Secretary may request to support the GECCO. To accomplish this mission, the heads of agencies shall, upon request, provide to the GECCO, on a non-reimbursable basis, assistance, services, and other support including but not limited to logistical and administrative support and details of personnel to the extent permitted by law. Non-reimbursable details to the GECCO shall be based on reasonable requests from the Coordinator in light of the need for specific expertise, and after consultation with the relevant agency, to the extent permitted by law.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) The GECCO shall terminate at the end of the maximum period permitted by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3161/a/1">section 3161(a)(1) of title 5</ref>, United States Code, unless sooner terminated by the Secretary consistent with section 3161(a)(2) of such title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(f) The termination of the GECCO as required by subsection (e) of this section shall not be interpreted to imply the termination, attenuation or amendment of any other authority or provision of this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 7. <i>General Provisions</i>. (a) Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) authority granted by law to an agency, or the head thereof; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>
<signature>
<name>Barack Obama.</name>
</signature>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id8feba4fe-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 14089</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 14089, <date date="2022-12-13">Dec. 13, 2022</date>, 87 F.R. 77459, establishing the President’s Advisory Council on African Diaspora Engagement in the United States, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 14148, § 2(aaa), <date date="2025-01-20">Jan. 20, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 8239.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8feba4ff-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Extension of Term of President’s Advisory Council on African Diaspora Engagement in the United States</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Term of President’s Advisory Council on African Diaspora Engagement in the United States extended until <date date="2025-09-30">Sept. 30, 2025</date>, by Ex. Ord. No. 14109, <date date="2023-09-29">Sept. 29, 2023</date>, 88 F.R. 68447, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1013">section 1013 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id8feba500-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 14150. America First Policy Directive to the Secretary of State</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 14150, <date date="2025-01-20">Jan. 20, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 8337, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, it is hereby ordered:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Purpose</i>. From this day [<date date="2025-01-20">Jan. 20, 2025</date>] forward, the foreign policy of the United States shall champion core American interests and always put America and American citizens first.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 2. <i>Policy</i>. As soon as practicable, the Secretary of State shall issue guidance bringing the Department of State’s policies, programs, personnel, and operations in line with an America First foreign policy, which puts America and its interests first.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 3. <i>General Provisions</i>. (a) Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>
<signature>
<name>Donald J. Trump.</name>
</signature>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8feba501-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Presidential Certification Authorizing Security Assistance to East Timor</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Determination of President of the United States, No. 2003–19, <date date="2003-03-28">Mar. 28, 2003</date>, 68 F.R. 16167, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum for the Secretary of State</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Pursuant to the authority vested in me by the Constitution and laws of the United States, including section 637(b)(2) of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 2003 [<ref href="/us/pl/107/228/s637/b/2">Pub. L. 107–228, § 637(b)(2)</ref>, set out above], I hereby certify that East Timor has established an independent armed forces; and that the provision to East Timor of military assistance in the form of excess defense articles and international military education and training is in the national security interests of the United States, and will promote both human rights in East Timor and the professionalization of the armed forces of East Timor.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">You are hereby authorized and directed to report this certification, accompanying memorandum of justification [not set out in the Code], and report on East Timor security assistance to the Congress, and to arrange for the publication of this memorandum in the Federal Register.</p>
<signature>
<name>George W. Bush.</name>
</signature>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8feba502-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">National Security Memorandum–4—Advancing the Human Rights of Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, Queer, and Intersex Persons Around the World</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">National Security Memorandum–4, <date date="2021-02-04">Feb. 4, 2021</date>, 86 F.R. 11843, relating to advancing the human rights of lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, and intersex persons around the world, wasrevoked by Ex. Ord. No. 14236, § 2(c), <date date="2025-03-14">Mar. 14, 2025</date>, 90 F.R. 13037.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
