<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8ff51b45-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2685"><num value="2685">§ 2685.</num><heading> Reimbursement for detailed State Department personnel</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8ff51b46-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2685/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> An Executive agency to which any officer or employee of the Department of State is detailed, assigned, or otherwise made available, shall reimburse the Department for the salary and allowances of each such officer or employee for the period the officer or employee is so detailed, assigned, or otherwise made available. However, if the Department of State has an agreement with an Executive agency or agencies providing for the detailing, assigning, or otherwise making available, of substantially the same numbers of officers and employees between the Department and the Executive agency or agencies, and such numbers with respect to a fiscal year are so detailed, assigned, or otherwise made available, or if the period for which the officer or employee is so detailed, assigned, or otherwise made available does not exceed one year, or if the number of officers and employees so detailed, assigned, or otherwise made available at any one time does not exceed fifteen and the period of any such detail, assignment, or availability of an officer or employee does not exceed two years, no reimbursement shall be required to be made under this section. Officers and employees of the Department of State who are detailed, assigned, or otherwise made available to another Executive agency for a period of not to exceed one year shall not be counted toward any personnel ceiling for the Department of State established by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8ff51b47-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2685/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> For purposes of this section, “Executive agency” has the same meaning given that term by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s105">section 105 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8ff51b48-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/93/126/s11">Pub. L. 93–126, § 11</ref>, <date date="1973-10-18">Oct. 18, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/453">87 Stat. 453</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/426/tI/s118">Pub. L. 95–426, title I, § 118</ref>, <date date="1978-10-07">Oct. 7, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/969">92 Stat. 969</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/93/tI/s117">Pub. L. 99–93, title I, § 117</ref>, <date date="1985-08-16">Aug. 16, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/412">99 Stat. 412</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8ff51b49-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8ff51b4a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8ff51b4b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/93">Pub. L. 99–93</ref> inserted “or if the number of officers and employees so detailed, assigned, or otherwise made available at any one time does not exceed fifteen and the period of any such detail, assignment, or availability of an officer or employee does not exceed two years,” after “does not exceed one year,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/426">Pub. L. 95–426</ref> substituted “does not exceed one year” for “does not exceed ninety days”, and inserted provision excepting from any personnel ceiling for the Department of State any officers and employees who are detailed, etc., to another Executive agency for a period of not to exceed one year.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
