<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8ff78b85-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2695"><num value="2695">§ 2695.</num><heading> Administrative services</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ff78b86-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2695/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Agreements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever the head of any Federal agency performing any foreign affairs functions (including, but not limited to, the Department of State, the Broadcasting Board of Governors, and the Agency for International Development) determines that administrative services performed in common by the Department of State and one or more other such agencies may be performed more advantageously and more economically on a consolidated basis, the Secretary of State and the heads of the other agencies concerned may, subject to the approval of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, conclude an agreement which provides for the transfer to and consolidation within the Department or within one of the other agencies concerned of so much of the functions, personnel, property, records, and funds of the Department and of the other agencies concerned as may be necessary to enable the performance of those administrative services on a consolidated basis for the benefit of all agencies concerned. Agreements for consolidation of administrative services under this section shall provide for reimbursement or advances of funds from the agency receiving the service to the agency performing the service in amounts which will approximate the expense of providing administrative services for the serviced agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ff78b87-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2695/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8ff78b88-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2695/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A Federal agency which obtains administrative services from the Department of State pursuant to an agreement authorized under subsection (a) shall make full and prompt payment for such services through advance of funds or reimbursement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8ff78b89-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2695/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary of State shall bill each Federal agency for amounts due for services provided pursuant to subsection (a). The Secretary shall notify a Federal agency which has not made full payment for services within 90 days after billing that services to the agency will be suspended or terminated if full payment is not made within 180 days after the date of notification. Except as provided under paragraph (3), the Secretary shall suspend or terminate services to a Federal agency which has not made full payment for services under this section 180 days after the date of notification. Any costs associated with a suspension or termination of services shall be the responsibility of, and shall be billed to, the Federal agency.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8ff78b8a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2695/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary of State may waive the requirement for suspension or termination under paragraph (2) with respect to such services as the Secretary determines are necessary to ensure the protection of life and the safety of United States Government property. A waiver may be issued for a period not to exceed one year and may be renewed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8ff78b8b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1956-08-01/ch841">Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title I, § 23, as added <ref href="/us/pl/95/426/tI/s111/a">Pub. L. 95–426, title I, § 111(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-07">Oct. 7, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/967">92 Stat. 967</ref>; renumbered title I and amended <ref href="/us/pl/97/241/tII/s202/a">Pub. L. 97–241, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, title III, § 303(b), <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/282">96 Stat. 282</ref>, 291; <ref href="/us/pl/102/138/tI/s118">Pub. L. 102–138, title I, § 118</ref>, <date date="1991-10-28">Oct. 28, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/657">105 Stat. 657</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dG">Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1225(f), title XIII, § 1335(<i>l</i>)(1), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-775">112 Stat. 2681–775</ref>, 2681–789.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8ff78b8c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8ff78b8d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8ff78b8e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1335">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1335</ref>(<i>l</i>)(1), substituted “Broadcasting Board of Governors” for “United States Information Agency”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1225/f">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1225(f)</ref>, substituted “and the Agency for International Development” for “the Agency for International Development, and the Arms Control and Disarmament Agency”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—<ref href="/us/pl/102/138">Pub. L. 102–138</ref> inserted section catchline, designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and inserted heading, and added subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8ff78b8f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id8ff78b90-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Broadcasting Board of Governors renamed United States Agency for Global Media pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/21">section 6204(a)(21) of this title</ref>. The renaming was effectuated by notice to congressional appropriations committees dated <date date="2018-05-24">May 24, 2018</date>, and became effective <date date="2018-08-22">Aug. 22, 2018</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id8ff78b91-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1225/f">section 1225(f) of Pub. L. 105–277</ref> effective <date date="1999-04-01">Apr. 1, 1999</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1201">section 1201 of Pub. L. 105–277</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6511">section 6511 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 1335(<i>l</i>)(1) of <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref> effective <date date="1999-10-01">Oct. 1, 1999</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1301">section 1301 of Pub. L. 105–277</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6531">section 6531 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id8ff78b92-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/426/tI/s111/b">Pub. L. 95–426, title I, § 111(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-07">Oct. 7, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/967">92 Stat. 967</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/426/tI/s111/b">“The amendment made by this section [enacting this section] shall take effect on <date date="1978-10-01">October 1, 1978</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
