<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8ff78be2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2701"><num value="2701">§ 2701.</num><heading> Educational facilities</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever the Secretary of State determines that educational facilities are not available, or that existing educational facilities are inadequate, to meet the needs of children of United States citizens stationed outside the United States who are engaged in carrying out Government activities, the Secretary may, in such manner as he deems appropriate and under such regulations as he may prescribe, establish, operate, and maintain primary schools, and school dormitories and related educational facilities for primary and secondary schools, outside the United States, make grants of funds for such purposes, or otherwise provide for such educational facilities. The authorities of the Foreign Service Buildings Act, 1926 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s292">22 U.S.C. 292</ref> et seq.], and of paragraphs (h) and (i) of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2670">section 2670 of this title</ref>, may be utilized by the Secretary in providing assistance for educational facilities. Such assistance may include physical security enhancements and hiring, transporting, and payment of teachers and other necessary personnel. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, where the child of a United States citizen employee of an agency of the United States Government who is stationed outside the United States attends an educational facility assisted by the Secretary of State under this section, the head of that agency is authorized to reimburse, or credit with advance payment, the Department of State for funds used in providing assistance to such educational facilities, by grant or otherwise, under this section.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8ff78be3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1956-08-01/ch841">Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title I, § 29, as added <ref href="/us/pl/96/465/tII/s2201/a">Pub. L. 96–465, title II, § 2201(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2154">94 Stat. 2154</ref>; renumbered title I, <ref href="/us/pl/97/241/tII/s202/a">Pub. L. 97–241, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/282">96 Stat. 282</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dG">Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. B, title XXII, § 2201, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-804">112 Stat. 2681–804</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/323/tI/s114">Pub. L. 114–323, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1911">130 Stat. 1911</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8ff78be4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8ff78be5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8ff78be6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Foreign Service Buildings Act, 1926, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1926-05-07/ch250">act May 7, 1926, ch. 250</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/403">44 Stat. 403</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 8 (§ 292 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s299">section 299 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8ff78be7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—<ref href="/us/pl/114/323">Pub. L. 114–323</ref> inserted “physical security enhancements and” after “may include”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—<ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref> inserted at end “Notwithstanding any other provision of law, where the child of a United States citizen employee of an agency of the United States Government who is stationed outside the United States attends an educational facility assisted by the Secretary of State under this section, the head of that agency is authorized to reimburse, or credit with advance payment, the Department of State for funds used in providing assistance to such educational facilities, by grant or otherwise, under this section.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8ff78be8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id8ff78be9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1981-02-15">Feb. 15, 1981</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/465/s2403">section 2403 of Pub. L. 96–465</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3901">section 3901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
