<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8ff78c03-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2703"><num value="2703">§ 2703.</num><heading> Services and facilities for employees at posts abroad</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ff78c04-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2703/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Non-Government-operated services; applicability of other provisions of law</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of State may authorize and assist in the establishment, maintenance, and operation by civilian officers and employees of the Government of non-Government-operated services and facilities at posts abroad, including the furnishing of space, utilities, and properties owned or leased by the Government for use by its diplomatic, consular, and other missions and posts abroad. The provisions of the Foreign Service Buildings Act, 1926 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s292–300">22 U.S.C. 292–300</ref>) and <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2684">section 2684 of this title</ref> may be utilized by the Secretary in providing such assistance.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ff78c05-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2703/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Emergency commissary and mess services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may establish and maintain emergency commissary or mess services in places abroad where, in the judgment of the Secretary, such services are necessary temporarily to insure the effective and efficient performance of official duties and responsibilities. Reimbursements incident to the maintenance and operation of commissary or mess service under this subsection shall be at not less than cost as determined by the Secretary and shall be used as working funds, except that an amount equal to the amount expended for such services shall be covered into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ff78c06-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2703/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability; duplication of facilities and services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Services and facilities established under this section shall be made available, insofar as practicable, to officers and employees of all agencies and their dependents who are stationed in the locality abroad, and, where determined by the Secretary to be appropriate due to exceptional circumstances, to United States citizens hired outside of the host country to serve as teaching staff for such dependents abroad. Such services and facilities shall not be established in localities where another agency operates similar services or facilities unless the Secretary determines that additional services or facilities are necessary. Other agencies shall to the extent practicable avoid duplicating the facilities and services provided or assisted by the Secretary under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ff78c07-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2703/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Charges</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Charges at any post abroad for a service or facility provided, authorized or assisted under this section shall be at the same rate for all civilian personnel of the Government serviced thereby, and all charges for supplies furnished to such a service or facility abroad by any agency shall be at the same rate as that charged by the furnishing agency to its comparable civilian services and facilities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ff78c08-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2703/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Child care facilities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of State may make grants to child care facilities, to offset in part the cost of such care, in Moscow and at no more than five other posts abroad where the Secretary determines that due to extraordinary circumstances such facilities are necessary to the efficient operation of the post. In making that determination, the Secretary shall take into account factors such as—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ff78c09-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2703/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> whether Foreign Service spouses are encouraged to work at the post because—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8ff78c0a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2703/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the number of members of the post is subject to a ceiling imposed by the receiving country; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8ff78c0b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2703/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Foreign Service nationals are not employed at the post; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ff78c0c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2703/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> whether local child care is available.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8ff78c0d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1956-08-01/ch841">Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title I, § 31, as added <ref href="/us/pl/96/465/tII/s2201/a">Pub. L. 96–465, title II, § 2201(a)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2156">94 Stat. 2156</ref>; renumbered title I, <ref href="/us/pl/97/241/tII/s202/a">Pub. L. 97–241, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/282">96 Stat. 282</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/246/tI/s147">Pub. L. 101–246, title I, § 147</ref>, <date date="1990-02-16">Feb. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/38">104 Stat. 38</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/138/tI">Pub. L. 102–138, title I</ref>, §§ 121, 144, <date date="1991-10-28">Oct. 28, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/658">105 Stat. 658</ref>, 668; <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/tI/s124">Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 124</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/393">108 Stat. 393</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8ff78c0e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8ff78c0f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8ff78c10-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Foreign Service Buildings Act, 1926, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1926-05-07/ch250">act May 7, 1926, ch. 250</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/403">44 Stat. 403</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 8 (§ 292 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s299">section 299 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8ff78c11-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref> substituted “The” for “For the fiscal years 1992 and 1993, the” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/102/138/s144">Pub. L. 102–138, § 144</ref>, inserted before period at end of first sentence “, and, where determined by the Secretary to be appropriate due to exceptional circumstances, to United States citizens hired outside of the host country to serve as teaching staff for such dependents abroad”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/102/138/s121">Pub. L. 102–138, § 121</ref>, substituted “1992 and 1993” for “1990 and 1991” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/246">Pub. L. 101–246</ref> added subsec. (e).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8ff78c12-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id8ff78c13-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1981-02-15">Feb. 15, 1981</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/465/s2403">section 2403 of Pub. L. 96–465</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3901">section 3901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8ff78c14-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Authority To Provide Accommodation and Subsistence to Individuals Serving in Iraq and Afghanistan</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/234/tI/s1602/e">Pub. L. 109–234, title I, § 1602(e)</ref>, <date date="2006-06-15">June 15, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/442">120 Stat. 442</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/234/tI/s1602/e">“The Secretary of State may provide during any fiscal year, with or without reimbursement, accommodation and subsistence to personnel in Iraq and Afghanistan for whom the Chief of Mission is responsible.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
