<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8ffc476e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2715a"><num value="2715a">§ 2715a.</num><heading> Provision of information on certain violent crimes abroad to victims and victims’ families</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ffc476f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2715a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ffc4770-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2715a/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> it is in the national interests of the United States to provide information regarding the killing, abduction, torture, or other serious mistreatment of United States citizens abroad to the victims of such crimes, or the families of victims of such crimes if they are United States citizens; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ffc4771-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2715a/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the provision of such information is sufficiently important that the discharge of the responsibility for identifying and disseminating such information should be vested in a cabinet-level officer of the United States Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ffc4772-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2715a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Responsibility</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall take appropriate actions to ensure that the United States Government takes all appropriate actions to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ffc4773-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2715a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> identify promptly information (including classified information) in the possession of the departments and agencies of the United States Government regarding the killing, abduction, torture, or other serious mistreatment of United States citizens abroad; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ffc4774-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2715a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> subject to subsection (c), promptly make such information available to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8ffc4775-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2715a/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the victims of such crimes; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8ffc4776-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2715a/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> when appropriate, the family members of the victims of such crimes if such family members are United States citizens.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ffc4777-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2715a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall work with the heads of appropriate departments and agencies of the United States Government in order to ensure that information relevant to a crime covered by subsection (b) is promptly reviewed and, to the maximum extent practicable, without jeopardizing sensitive sources and methods or other vital national security interests, or without jeopardizing an on-going criminal investigation or proceeding, made available under that subsection unless such disclosure is specifically prohibited by law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8ffeb778-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/105/107/tIII/s307">Pub. L. 105–107, title III, § 307</ref>, <date date="1997-11-20">Nov. 20, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2252">111 Stat. 2252</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
