<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8ea9af5e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s274a"><num value="274a">§ 274a.</num><heading> International biological program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ea9af5f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s274a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Congressional findings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress hereby finds and declares that the international biological program, which was established under the auspices of the International Council of Scientific Unions and the International Union of Biological Sciences and is sponsored in the United States by the National Academy of Sciences and the National Academy of Engineering, deals with one of the most crucial situations to face this or any other civilization—the immediate or near potential of mankind to damage, possibly beyond repair, the earth’s ecological system on which all life depends. The Congress further finds and declares that the international biological program provides an immediate and effective means available of meeting this situation, through its stated objectives of increased study and research related to biological productivity and human welfare in a changing world environment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ea9af60-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s274a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Congressional support</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress therefore commends and endorses the international biological program and expresses its support of the United States National Committee and the Interagency Coordinating Committee, which together have the responsibility for planning, coordinating, and carrying out the program in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ea9af61-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s274a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Priority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In view of the urgency of the problem, the Congress finds and declares that the provision by the United States of adequate financial and other support for the international biological program is a matter of first priority.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8ea9af62-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/438/s1">Pub. L. 91–438, § 1</ref>, <date date="1970-10-07">Oct. 7, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/889">84 Stat. 889</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
