<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id900ce886-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2755"><num value="2755">§ 2755.</num><heading> Discrimination prohibited if based on race, religion, national origin, or sex</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce887-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2755/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Congressional declaration of policy</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States that no sales should be made, and no credits (including participations in credits) or guaranties extended to or for any foreign country, the laws, regulations, official policies, or governmental practices of which prevent any United States person (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7701/a/30">section 7701(a)(30) of title 26</ref>) from participating in the furnishing of defense articles or defense services under this chapter on the basis of race, religion, national origin, or sex.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce888-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2755/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Employment of personnel; required contractual provision</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce889-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2755/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> No agency performing functions under this chapter shall, in employing or assigning personnel to participate in the performance of any such function, whether in the United States or abroad, take into account the exclusionary policies or practices of any foreign government where such policies or practices are based upon race, religion, national origin, or sex.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce88a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2755/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Each contract entered into by any such agency for the performance of any function under this chapter shall contain a provision to the effect that no person, partnership, corporation, or other entity performing functions pursuant to such contract, shall, in employing or assigning personnel to participate in the performance of any such function, whether in the United States or abroad, take into account the exclusionary policies or practices of any foreign government where such policies or practices are based upon race, religion, national origin, or sex.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce88b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2755/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Report by President; contents</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall promptly transmit reports to the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the chairman of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate concerning any instance in which any United States person (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7701/a/30">section 7701(a)(30) of title 26</ref>) is prevented by a foreign government on the basis of race, religion, national origin, or sex, from participating in the performance of any sale or licensed transaction under this chapter or any import or export under a treaty referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2778/j/1/C/i">section 2778(j)(1)(C)(i) of this title</ref>. Such reports shall include (1) a description of the facts and circumstances of any such discrimination, (2) the response thereto on the part of the United States or any agency or employee thereof, and (3) the result of such response, if any.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce88c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2755/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Congressional request for information from President; information required; 60 day period; failure to supply information; termination or restriction of sale</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce88d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2755/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Upon the request of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate or the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, the President shall, within 60 days after receipt of such request, transmit to both such committees a statement, prepared with the assistance of the Secretary of State, with respect to the country designated in such request, setting forth—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce88e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2755/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> all the available information about the exclusionary policies or practices of the government of such country when such policies or practices are based upon race, religion, national origin or sex and prevent any such person from participating in the performance of any sale or licensed transaction under this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce88f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2755/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the response of the United States thereto and the results of such response;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce890-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2755/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> whether, in the opinion of the President, notwithstanding any such policies or practices—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id900ce891-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2755/d/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> extraordinary circumstances exist which necessitate a continuation of such sale or licensed transaction, and, if so, a description of such circumstances and the extent to which such sale or licensed transaction should be continued (subject to such conditions as Congress may impose under this section), and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id900ce892-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2755/d/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> on all the facts it is in the national interest of the United States to continue such sale or licensed transaction; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce893-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2755/d/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> such other information as such committee may request.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce894-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2755/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In the event a statement with respect to a sale or licensed transaction is requested pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection but is not transmitted in accordance therewith within 60 days after receipt of such request, such sale or licensed transaction shall be suspended unless and until such statement is transmitted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce895-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2755/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce896-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2755/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In the event a statement with respect to a sale or licensed transaction is transmitted under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Congress may at any time thereafter adopt a joint resolution terminating or restricting such sale or licensed transaction.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce897-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2755/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any such resolution shall be considered in the Senate in accordance with the provisions of section 601(b) of the International Security Assistance and Arms Export Control Act of 1976.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce898-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2755/d/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The term “certification”, as used in section 601 of such Act, means, for the purposes of this paragraph, a statement transmitted under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id900ce899-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/629">Pub. L. 90–629</ref>, ch. 1, § 5, as added <ref href="/us/pl/94/329/tIII/s302/b">Pub. L. 94–329, title III, § 302(b)</ref>, <date date="1976-06-30">June 30, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/752">90 Stat. 752</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/105/tI/s109/a/5">Pub. L. 95–105, title I, § 109(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-17">Aug. 17, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/846">91 Stat. 846</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/tI/s162/f">Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 162(f)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/405">108 Stat. 405</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/437/s9/a/7">Pub. L. 103–437, § 9(a)(7)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4588">108 Stat. 4588</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/266/tI/s104/b">Pub. L. 111–266, title I, § 104(b)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-08">Oct. 8, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2799">124 Stat. 2799</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/276/tII/s208/a/1">Pub. L. 113–276, title II, § 208(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2992">128 Stat. 2992</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id900ce89a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id900ce89b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id900ce89c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/90/629">Pub. L. 90–629</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1321">82 Stat. 1321</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 601(b) of the International Security Assistance and Arms Export Control Act of 1976, referred to in subsec. (d)(3)(B), (C), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/329/s601/b">section 601(b) of Pub. L. 94–329</ref>, <date date="1976-06-30">June 30, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/729">90 Stat. 729</ref>, which made provision for expedited procedures in the Senate, and was not classified to the Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id900ce89d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/113/276">Pub. L. 113–276</ref> substituted “the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and” for “the Speaker of the House of Representatives and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/111/266">Pub. L. 111–266</ref> inserted “or any import or export under a treaty referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2778/j/1/C/i">section 2778(j)(1)(C)(i) of this title</ref>” after “under this chapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/437">Pub. L. 103–437</ref> substituted “Foreign Affairs” for “International Relations” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref> substituted “Secretary of State” for “Assistant Secretary of State for Human Rights and Humanitarian Affairs” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsecs. (a), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> substituted “Internal Revenue Code of 1986” for “Internal Revenue Code of 1954”, which for purposes of codification was translated as “title 26” thus requiring no change in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/95/105">Pub. L. 95–105</ref> substituted “Assistant Secretary of State” for “Coordinator” in introductory provisions.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id900ce89e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id900ce89f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref> applicable with respect to officials, offices, and bureaus of Department of State when executive orders, regulations, or departmental directives implementing the amendments by sections 161 and 162 of <ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref> become effective, or 90 days after <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, whichever comes earlier, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s161/b">section 161(b) of Pub. L. 103–236</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2651a">section 2651a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id900ce8a0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id900ce8a1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of functions of the President under this section, see section 1(b) of Ex. Ord. No. 13637, <date date="2013-03-08">Mar. 8, 2013</date>, 78 F.R. 16129, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of this title</ref>. Functions were previously delegated by Ex. Ord. No. 11958, which was formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of this title</ref> and was revoked, subject to a savings provision, by section 4 of Ex. Ord. No. 13637.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
