<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id900ce8a9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761"><num value="2761">§ 2761.</num><heading> Sales from stocks</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce8aa-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible countries or international organizations; basis of payment; valuation of certain defense articles</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce8ab-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The President may sell defense articles and defense services from the stocks of the Department of Defense and the Coast Guard to any eligible country or international organization if such country or international organization agrees to pay in United States dollars—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8ac-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in the case of a defense article not intended to be replaced at the time such agreement is entered into, not less than the actual value thereof;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8ad-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case of a defense article intended to be replaced at the time such agreement is entered into, the estimated cost of replacement of such article, including the contract or production costs less any depreciation in the value of such article; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8ae-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> in the case of the sale of a defense service, the full cost to the United States Government of furnishing such service, except that in the case of training sold to a purchaser who is concurrently receiving assistance under chapter 5 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2347">22 U.S.C. 2347</ref> et seq.] or to any high-income foreign country (as described in that chapter), only those additional costs that are incurred by the United States Government in furnishing such assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce8af-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> For purposes of subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1), the actual value of a naval vessel of 3,000 tons or less and 20 years or more of age shall be considered to be not less than the greater of the scrap value or fair value (including conversion costs) of such vessel, as determined by the Secretary of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce8b0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Time of payment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as provided by subsection (d) of this section, payment shall be made in advance or, if the President determines it to be in the national interest, upon delivery of the defense article or rendering of the defense service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce8b1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Personnel performing defense services sold as prohibited from performing combat activities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce8b2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Personnel performing defense services sold under this chapter may not perform any duties of a combatant nature, including any duties related to training and advising that may engage United States personnel in combat activities, outside the United States in connection with the performance of those defense services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce8b3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Within forty-eight hours of the existence of, or a change in status of significant hostilities or terrorist acts or a series of such acts, which may endanger American lives or property, involving a country in which United States personnel are performing defense services pursuant to this chapter or the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.], the President shall submit to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and to the President pro tempore of the Senate a report, in writing, classified if necessary, setting forth—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8b4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the identity of such country;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8b5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a description of such hostilities or terrorist acts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8b6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the number of members of the United States Armed Forces and the number of United States civilian personnel that may be endangered by such hostilities or terrorist acts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce8b7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Billings; interest after due date, rates of interest and extension of due date</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the President determines it to be in the national interest pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, billings for sales made under letters of offer issued under this section after <date date="1976-06-30">June 30, 1976</date>, may be dated and issued upon delivery of the defense article or rendering of the defense service and shall be due and payable upon receipt thereof by the purchasing country or international organization. Interest shall be charged on any net amount due and payable which is not paid within sixty days after the date of such billing. The rate of interest charged shall be a rate not less than a rate determined by the Secretary of the Treasury taking into consideration the current average market yield on outstanding short-term obligations of the United States as of the last day of the month preceding the billing and shall be computed from the date of billing. The President may extend such sixty-day period to one hundred and twenty days if he determines that emergency requirements of the purchaser for acquisition of such defense articles or defense services exceed the ready availability to the purchaser of funds sufficient to pay the United States in full for them within such sixty-day period and submits that determination to the Congress together with a special emergency request for the authorization and appropriation of additional funds to finance such purchases under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce8b8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Charges; reduction or waiver</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce8b9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> After <date date="1976-09-30">September 30, 1976</date>, letters of offer for the sale of defense articles or for the sale of defense services that are issued pursuant to this section or pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2762">section 2762 of this title</ref> shall include appropriate charges for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8ba-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> administrative services, calculated on an average percentage basis to recover the full estimated costs (excluding a pro rata share of fixed base operation costs) of administration of sales made under this chapter to all purchasers of such articles and services as specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2792/b">section 2792(b) of this title</ref> and <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2792/c">section 2792(c) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8bb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a proportionate amount of any nonrecurring costs of research, development, and production of major defense equipment (except for equipment wholly paid for either from funds transferred under section 503(a)(3) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2311/a/3">22 U.S.C. 2311(a)(3)</ref>] or from funds made available on a nonrepayable basis under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2763">section 2763 of this title</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8bc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the recovery of ordinary inventory losses associated with the sale from stock of defense articles that are being stored at the expense of the purchaser of such articles.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce8bd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce8be-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The President may reduce or waive the charge or charges which would otherwise be considered appropriate under paragraph (1)(B) for particular sales that would, if made, significantly advance United States Government interests in North Atlantic Treaty Organization standardization, standardization with the Armed Forces of Japan, Australia, the Republic of Korea, Israel, or New Zealand in furtherance of the mutual defense treaties between the United States and those countries, or foreign procurement in the United States under coproduction arrangements.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce8bf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> The President may waive the charge or charges which would otherwise be considered appropriate under paragraph (1)(B) for a particular sale if the President determines that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8c0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/e/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> imposition of the charge or charges likely would result in the loss of the sale; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8c1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/e/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in the case of a sale of major defense equipment that is also being procured for the use of the Armed Forces, the waiver of the charge or charges would (through a resulting increase in the total quantity of the equipment purchased from the source of the equipment that causes a reduction in the unit cost of the equipment) result in a savings to the United States on the cost of the equipment procured for the use of the Armed Forces that substantially offsets the revenue foregone by reason of the waiver of the charge or charges.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce8c2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The President may waive, for particular sales of major defense equipment, any increase in a charge or charges previously considered appropriate under paragraph (1)(B) if the increase results from a correction of an estimate (reasonable when made) of the production quantity base that was used for calculating the charge or charges for purposes of such paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce8c3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce8c4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> The President may waive the charges for administrative services that would otherwise be required by paragraph (1)(A) in connection with any sale to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Support and Procurement Organization and its executive agencies in support of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8c5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/e/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> a support or procurement partnership agreement; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8c6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/e/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a NATO/SHAPE project.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce8c7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary of Defense may reimburse the fund established to carry out <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2792/b">section 2792(b) of this title</ref> in the amount of the charges waived under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph. Any such reimbursement may be made from any funds available to the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce8c8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/e/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> As used in this paragraph—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8c9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/e/3/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> the term “support or procurement partnership agreement” means an agreement between two or more member countries of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Support and Procurement Organization and its executive agencies that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id900ce8ca-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/e/3/C/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> is entered into pursuant to the terms of the charter of that organization; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id900ce8cb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/e/3/C/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> is for the common logistic support of activities common to the participating countries; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8cc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/e/3/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the term “NATO/SHAPE project” means a common-funded project supported by allocated credits from North Atlantic Treaty Organization bodies or by host nations with NATO Infrastructure funds.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce8cd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Public inspection of contracts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any contracts entered into between the United States and a foreign country under the authority of this section or <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2762">section 2762 of this title</ref> shall be prepared in a manner which will permit them to be made available for public inspection to the fullest extent possible consistent with the national security of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce8ce-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> North Atlantic Treaty Organization standardization agreements, similar agreements; reimbursement for costs; transmittal to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President may enter into North Atlantic Treaty Organization standardization agreements in carrying out <ref href="/us/act/1975-10-07/s814">section 814 of the Act of October 7, 1975</ref> (<ref href="/us/pl/94/106">Public Law 94–106</ref>), and may enter into similar agreements with countries which are major non-NATO allies, for the cooperative furnishing of training on bilateral or multilateral basis, if the financial principles of such agreements are based on reciprocity. Such agreements shall include reimbursement for all direct costs but may exclude reimbursement for indirect costs, administrative surcharges, and costs of billeting of trainees (except to the extent that members of the United States Armed Forces occupying comparable accommodations are charged for such accommodations by the United States). Each such agreement shall be transmitted promptly to the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committees on Appropriations, Armed Services, and Foreign Relations of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce8cf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Reciprocal quality assurance, inspection, contract administrative services, and contract audit defense services; catalog data and services</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce8d0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The President is authorized to provide (without charge) quality assurance, inspection, contract administration services, and contract audit defense services under this section—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8d1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in connection with the placement or administration of any contract or subcontract for defense articles, defense services, or design and construction services entered into after <date date="1979-10-29">October 29, 1979</date>, by, or under this chapter on behalf of, a foreign government which is a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization or the Governments of Australia, New Zealand, Japan, the Republic of Korea, or Israel, if such government provides such services in accordance with an agreement on a reciprocal basis, without charge, to the United States Government; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8d2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in connection with the placement or administration of any contract or subcontract for defense articles, defense services, or design and construction services pursuant to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment program in accordance with an agreement under which the foreign governments participating in such program provide such services, without charge, in connection with similar contracts or subcontracts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce8d3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In carrying out the objectives of this section, the President is authorized to provide cataloging data and cataloging services, without charge, to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, to any member government of that Organization, or to the Governments of the Republic of Korea, Australia, New Zealand, Japan, or Israel if that Organization, member government, or the Governments of the Republic of Korea, Australia, New Zealand, Japan, or Israel provides such data and services in accordance with an agreement on a reciprocal basis, without charge, to the United States Government.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce8d4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Sales affecting combat readiness of Armed Forces; statement to Congress; limitation on delivery</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce8d5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Sales of defense articles and defense services which could have significant adverse effect on the combat readiness of the Armed Forces of the United States shall be kept to an absolute minimum. The President shall transmit to the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Committees on Foreign Affairs and Armed Services of the House of Representatives, and the Committees on Armed Services and Foreign Relations of the Senate on the same day a written statement giving a complete explanation with respect to any proposal to sell, under this section or under authority of subchapter II–B, any defense articles or defense services if such sale could have a significant adverse effect on the combat readiness of the Armed Forces of the United States. Each such statement shall be unclassified except to the extent that public disclosure of any item of information contained therein would be clearly detrimental to the security of the United States. Any necessarily classified information shall be confined to a supplemental report. Each such statement shall include an explanation relating to only one such proposal to sell and shall set forth—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8d6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/i/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the country or international organization to which the sale is proposed to be made;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8d7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/i/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the amount of the proposed sale;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8d8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/i/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a description of the defense article or service proposed to be sold;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8d9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/i/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> a full description of the impact which the proposed sale will have on the Armed Forces of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8da-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/i/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> a justification for such proposed sale, including a certification that such sale is important to the security of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">A certification described in subparagraph (E) shall take effect on the date on which such certification is transmitted and shall remain in effect for not to exceed one year.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900ce8db-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> No delivery may be made under any sale which is required to be reported under paragraph (1) of this subsection unless the certification required to be transmitted by paragraph <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002215">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002215"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “subparagraph”.</note> (E) of paragraph (1) is in effect.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce8dc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tI/s112">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title I, § 112</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/206">110 Stat. 206</ref></heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce8dd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Effect of sales of excess defense articles on national technology and industrial base</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Before entering into the sale under this chapter of defense articles that are excess to the stocks of the Department of Defense, the President shall determine that the sale of such articles will not have an adverse impact on the national technology and industrial base and, particularly, will not reduce the opportunities of entities in the national technology and industrial base to sell new or used equipment to the countries to which such articles are transferred.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce8de-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Repair of defense articles</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce8df-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/l/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President may acquire a repairable defense article from a foreign country or international organization if such defense article—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id900ce8e0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/l/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> previously was transferred to such country or organization under this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id900ce8e1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/l/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is not an end item; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id900ce8e2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/l/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> will be exchanged for a defense article of the same type that is in the stocks of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce8e3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/l/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President may exercise the authority provided in paragraph (1) only to the extent that the Department of Defense—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id900ce8e4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/l/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id900ce8e5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/l/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> has a requirement for the defense article being returned; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id900ce8e6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/l/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> has available sufficient funds authorized and appropriated for such purpose; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id900ce8e7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/l/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id900ce8e8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/l/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> is accepting the return of the defense article for subsequent transfer to another foreign government or international organization pursuant to a letter of offer and acceptance implemented in accordance with this chapter; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id900ce8e9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/l/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> has available sufficient funds provided by or on behalf of such other foreign government or international organization pursuant to a letter of offer and acceptance implemented in accordance with this chapter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce8ea-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/l/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8eb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/l/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The foreign government or international organization receiving a new or repaired defense article in exchange for a repairable defense article pursuant to paragraph (1) shall, upon the acceptance by the United States Government of the repairable defense article being returned, be charged the total cost associated with the repair and replacement transaction.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id900ce8ec-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/l/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The total cost charged pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall be the same as that charged the United States Armed Forces for a similar repair and replacement transaction, plus an administrative surcharge in accordance with subsection (e)(1)(A) of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce8ed-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/l/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Relationship to certain other provisions of law</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The authority of the President to accept the return of a repairable defense article as provided in subsection (a) shall not be subject to chapter 137 legacy provisions (as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3016">section 3016 of title 10</ref>) of title 10 or any other provision of law relating to the conclusion of contracts.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce8ee-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/m"><num value="m" class="bold">(m)</num><heading class="bold"> Return of defense articles</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce8ef-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/m/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President may accept the return of a defense article from a foreign country or international organization if such defense article—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id900ce8f0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/m/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> previously was transferred to such country or organization under this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id900ce8f1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/m/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is not significant military equipment (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2794/9">section 2794(9) of this title</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id900ce8f2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/m/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> is in fully functioning condition without need of repair or rehabilitation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce8f3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/m/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President may exercise the authority provided in paragraph (1) only to the extent that the Department of Defense—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id900ce8f4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/m/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id900ce8f5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/m/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> has a requirement for the defense article being returned; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id900ce8f6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/m/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> has available sufficient funds authorized and appropriated for such purpose; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id900ce8f7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/m/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id900ce8f8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/m/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> is accepting the return of the defense article for subsequent transfer to another foreign government or international organization pursuant to a letter of offer and acceptance implemented in accordance with this chapter; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id900ce8f9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/m/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> has available sufficient funds provided by or on behalf of such other foreign government or international organization pursuant to a letter of offer and acceptance implemented in accordance with this chapter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce8fa-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/m/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Credit for transaction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon acquisition and acceptance by the United States Government of a defense article under paragraph (1), the appropriate Foreign Military Sales account of the provider shall be credited to reflect the transaction.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id900ce8fb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2761/m/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Relationship to certain other provisions of law</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The authority of the President to accept the return of a defense article as provided in paragraph (1) shall not be subject to chapter 137 legacy provisions (as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3016">section 3016 of title 10</ref>) of title 10 or any other provision of law relating to the conclusion of contracts.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id900ce8fc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/629">Pub. L. 90–629</ref>, ch. 2, § 21, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1323">82 Stat. 1323</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/329/tII">Pub. L. 94–329, title II</ref>, §§ 205, 206, <date date="1976-06-30">June 30, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/736">90 Stat. 736</ref>, 738; <ref href="/us/pl/95/384/s16">Pub. L. 95–384, § 16</ref>, <date date="1978-09-26">Sept. 26, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/740">92 Stat. 740</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/92/s12">Pub. L. 96–92, § 12</ref>, <date date="1979-10-29">Oct. 29, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/705">93 Stat. 705</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/533/tI">Pub. L. 96–533, title I</ref>, §§ 102, 103, 105(b)(1), 115(b)(2), <date date="1980-12-16">Dec. 16, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/3132">94 Stat. 3132</ref>, 3134, 3140; <ref href="/us/pl/97/113/tI">Pub. L. 97–113, title I</ref>, §§ 103, 104, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1521">95 Stat. 1521</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/392/s3">Pub. L. 97–392, § 3</ref>, <date date="1982-12-29">Dec. 29, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1963">96 Stat. 1963</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/473/tI/s101/1">Pub. L. 98–473, title I, § 101(1)</ref> [title III, § 301], <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1884">98 Stat. 1884</ref>, 1895; <ref href="/us/pl/99/83/tI">Pub. L. 99–83, title I</ref>, §§ 107(a), 108–111, <date date="1985-08-08">Aug. 8, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/196">99 Stat. 196</ref>, 197; <ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101/e/tV/s580">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(e) [title V, § 580]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1329-131">101 Stat. 1329–131</ref>, 1329–181; <ref href="/us/pl/100/456/dA/tX/s1002">Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title X, § 1002</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2037">102 Stat. 2037</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/165/tIX/s9104/c">Pub. L. 101–165, title IX, § 9104(c)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1152">103 Stat. 1152</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/25/tVII/s705/d/1">Pub. L. 102–25, title VII, § 705(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1991-04-06">Apr. 6, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/120">105 Stat. 120</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/484/dA/tI/s114">Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="1992-10-23">Oct. 23, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2333">106 Stat. 2333</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/tVII/s731/d">Pub. L. 103–236, title VII, § 731(d)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/503">108 Stat. 503</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tI/s112">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title I, § 112</ref>, div. D, title XLIII, § 4303(a), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/206">110 Stat. 206</ref>, 658; <ref href="/us/pl/104/164/tI">Pub. L. 104–164, title I</ref>, §§ 104(b)(1), 112(c)(2), 147(a)(3)(A), (b), 152(a), (b), <date date="1996-07-21">July 21, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1426">110 Stat. 1426</ref>, 1428, 1435, 1438, 1439; <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dB/tXXVIII/s2802/d/2">Pub. L. 104–201, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2802(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2787">110 Stat. 2787</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/7/dB/tXII/s1222">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(7) [div. B, title XII, § 1222]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–498; <ref href="/us/pl/109/102/tV/s534">Pub. L. 109–102, title V, § 534</ref>(<i>l</i>)(1), (2), <date date="2005-11-14">Nov. 14, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2211">119 Stat. 2211</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/429/tII/s203/b/1">Pub. L. 110–429, title II, § 203(b)(1)</ref>, (3), (4), <date date="2008-10-15">Oct. 15, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4845">122 Stat. 4845</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/266/tIII/s301/1">Pub. L. 111–266, title III, § 301(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-10-08">Oct. 8, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/2804">124 Stat. 2804</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tXII/s1250/b">Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title XII, § 1250(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/926">127 Stat. 926</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/276/tII/s208/a/1">Pub. L. 113–276, title II, § 208(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2992">128 Stat. 2992</ref>, 2993; <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tXII/s1279/b">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XII, § 1279(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/2072">132 Stat. 2072</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tXVII/s1702">Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1702</ref>(<i>l</i>)(3), <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/2160">135 Stat. 2160</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id900ce8fd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id900ce8fe-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id900ce8ff-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/90/629">Pub. L. 90–629</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1321">82 Stat. 1321</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1)(C) and (c)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, <date date="1961-09-04">Sept. 4, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/424">75 Stat. 424</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 32 (§ 2151 et seq.) of this title. Chapter 5 of part II of such Act is classified generally to part V of subchapter II (§ 2347 et seq.) of chapter 32 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">section 2151 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1975-10-07/s814">Section 814 of the act of October 7, 1975</ref> (<ref href="/us/pl/94/106">Public Law 94–106</ref>), referred to in subsec. (g), is not classified to the Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id900ce900-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/473">Pub. L. 98–473</ref> is based on section 102 of S. 2346, Ninety-eighth Congress, as introduced in the Senate <date date="1984-02-27">Feb. 27, 1984</date>, which was enacted into permanent law by <ref href="/us/pl/98/473">Pub. L. 98–473</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id900ce901-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsecs. (<i>l</i>)(4), (m)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81">Pub. L. 117–81</ref> substituted “chapter 137 legacy provisions (as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3016">section 3016 of title 10</ref>)” for “chapter 137”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (e)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s1279/b/1/A">Pub. L. 115–232, § 1279(b)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Support and Procurement Organization” for “North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Support Organization” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s1279/b/1/B">Pub. L. 115–232, § 1279(b)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “support or procurement partnership agreement” for “support partnership agreement”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3)(C)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/s1279/b/2">Pub. L. 115–232, § 1279(b)(2)</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted “ ‘support or procurement partnership agreement’ ” for “ ‘weapon system partnership agreement’ ” and “North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Support and Procurement Organization” for “North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Support Organization”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/113/276/s208/a/1">Pub. L. 113–276, § 208(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and” for “the Speaker of the House of Representatives and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/113/276/s208/a/2">Pub. L. 113–276, § 208(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “, the Committees on Foreign Affairs and Armed Services of the House of Representatives,” after “the Speaker of the House of Representatives” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (e)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s1250/b/1">Pub. L. 113–66, § 1250(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Support Organization and its executive agencies” for “Maintenance and Supply Agency of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s1250/b/2">Pub. L. 113–66, § 1250(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “support partnership agreement” for “weapon system partnership agreement”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3)(C)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s1250/b/1">Pub. L. 113–66, § 1250(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Support Organization and its executive agencies” for “Maintenance and Supply Agency of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3)(C)(i)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/113/66/s1250/b/3">Pub. L. 113–66, § 1250(b)(3)</ref>, substituted “activities” for “a specific weapon system”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (e)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/266">Pub. L. 111–266</ref> inserted “Israel,” before “or New Zealand”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (e)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/110/429/s203/b/1">Pub. L. 110–429, § 203(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “the Republic of Korea,” before “or New Zealand”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/110/429/s203/b/3">Pub. L. 110–429, § 203(b)(3)</ref>, inserted “the Republic of Korea,” before “or Israel”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/110/429/s203/b/4">Pub. L. 110–429, § 203(b)(4)</ref>, substituted “, to any member government of that Organization, or to the Governments of the Republic of Korea, Australia, New Zealand, Japan, or Israel if that Organization, member government, or the Governments of the Republic of Korea, Australia, New Zealand, Japan, or Israel” for “or to any member government of that Organization if that Organization or member government”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (h)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/102/s534">Pub. L. 109–102, § 534</ref>(<i>l</i>)(1), inserted “or the Governments of Australia, New Zealand, Japan, or Israel” after “North Atlantic Treaty Organization”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/109/102/s534">Pub. L. 109–102, § 534</ref>(<i>l</i>)(2), which directed the substitution of “, to any member of that Organization, or to the Governments of Australia, New Zealand, Japan, or Israel if that Organization, member government, or the Governments of Australia, New Zealand, Japan, or Israel” for “or to any member government that Organization if that Organization or member government”, could not be executed because the phrase “or to any member government that Organization if that Organization or member government” does not appear in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref> inserted “and the Coast Guard” after “Department of Defense” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/104/164/s112/c/2">Pub. L. 104–164, § 112(c)(2)</ref>, inserted “or to any high-income foreign country (as described in that chapter)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s4303/a">Pub. L. 104–106, § 4303(a)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A) and added subpars. (B) and (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/104/164/s147/a/3/A">Pub. L. 104–164, § 147(a)(3)(A)</ref>, (b), substituted “similar agreements with countries” for “similar agreements with Japan, Australia, and New Zealand, and with other countries” in first sentence and struck out at end “As used in this subsection, the term ‘major non-NATO allies’ means those countries designated as major non-NATO allies for purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2350a/i/3">section 2350a(i)(3) of title 10</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/104/201">Pub. L. 104–201</ref> substituted “Security Investment program” for “Infrastructure Program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/s112">Pub. L. 104–106, § 112</ref>, struck out heading and text of subsec. (j). Text read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(1) Funds received from the sale of tanks under this section shall be available for the upgrading of tanks for fielding to the Army.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2) Funds received from the sale of infantry fighting vehicles or armored personnel carriers under this section shall be available for the upgrading of infantry fighting vehicles or armored personnel carriers for fielding to the Army.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(3) Paragraphs (1) and (2) apply only to the extent provided in advance in appropriations Acts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(4) This subsection applies with respect to funds received from sales occurring after <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/104/164/s104/b/1">Pub. L. 104–164, § 104(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “the President shall determine that the sale of such articles will not have an adverse impact on the national technology and industrial base and, particularly, will not reduce the opportunities of entities in the national technology and industrial base to sell new or used equipment to the countries to which such articles are transferred.” for “the President shall first consider the effects of the sale of the articles on the national technology and industrial base, particularly the extent, if any, to which the sale reduces the opportunities of entities in the national technology and industrial base to sell new equipment to the country or countries to which the excess defense articles are sold.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/104/164/s152/a">Pub. L. 104–164, § 152(a)</ref>, added subsec. (<i>l</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/104/164/s152/b">Pub. L. 104–164, § 152(b)</ref>, added subsec. (m).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref> added subsec. (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/102/484">Pub. L. 102–484</ref> added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/102/25">Pub. L. 102–25</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t10/s2350a/i/3">section 2350a(i)(3) of title 10</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2767a">section 2767a of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (e)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/101/165/s9104/c/1">Pub. L. 101–165, § 9104(c)(1)</ref>, inserted reference to section 2792(b) and (c) of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/101/165/s9104/c/2">Pub. L. 101–165, § 9104(c)(2)</ref>, (3), redesignated subpar. (C) as (B) and inserted exception for equipment wholly paid for from funds transferred under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 or from funds made available under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2763">section 2763 of this title</ref>. Former subpar. (B), which included charges for any use of plant and production equipment in connection with defense articles, was struck out.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1)(C), (D). <ref href="/us/pl/101/165/s9104/c/3">Pub. L. 101–165, § 9104(c)(3)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (D) as (C). Former subpar. (C) redesignated (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/165/s9104/c/4">Pub. L. 101–165, § 9104(c)(4)</ref>, substituted reference to par. (1)(B) for reference to pars. (1)(B) and (1)(C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/456">Pub. L. 100–456</ref> added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/100/202">Pub. L. 100–202</ref> inserted “and with other countries which are major non-NATO allies,” after “New Zealand,” and inserted last sentence defining “major non-NATO allies”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/83/s107/a/1">Pub. L. 99–83, § 107(a)(1)</ref>, (2), designated existing provisions as par. (1), and substituted “(A)”, “(B)”, and “(C)” for “(1)”, “(2)”, and “(3)”, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/99/83/s108/a">Pub. L. 99–83, § 108(a)</ref>, inserted provisions relating to training sold to a purchaser receiving assistance under chapter 5 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/83/s107/a/3">Pub. L. 99–83, § 107(a)(3)</ref>, added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/99/83/s109">Pub. L. 99–83, § 109</ref>, inserted provisions excluding pro rata share of fixed base operation costs.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/99/83/s108/b">Pub. L. 99–83, § 108(b)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/83">Pub. L. 99–83</ref>, §§ 110, 111(1), (2), designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted applicability to contract administrative services, and substituted “(A)” and “(B)” for “(1)” and “(2)”, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/83/s111/3">Pub. L. 99–83, § 111(3)</ref>, added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/98/473">Pub. L. 98–473</ref> struck out “sold to a purchaser who is concurrently receiving assistance under chapter 5 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961” after “in the case of training”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/98/473">Pub. L. 98–473</ref> struck out subsec. (g) which related to NATO standardization agreements and similar agreements with Japan, Australia, and New Zealand.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (i)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/97/392">Pub. L. 97–392</ref> inserted reference to proposals to sell under the authority of subchapter II–B.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/97/113/s103">Pub. L. 97–113, § 103</ref>, substituted provision for a report within forty-eight hours of existence of or change in status of significant hostilities or terrorist acts or series of such acts, which may endanger American lives or property for provision for a report within 48 hours after outbreak of significant hostilities and omitted provision for statement of relation between the defense services and hostilities in the country, the location and precise nature of personnel activities, and likelihood of personnel engagement in the hostilities.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/97/113/s104">Pub. L. 97–113, § 104</ref>, authorized reduction or waiver of charges for use and nonrecurring research, development, and production costs respecting sales significantly advancing United States interests in standardization with Armed Forces of Japan, Australia, or New Zealand in furtherance of the mutual defense treaties between the United States and those countries.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/96/533/s115/b/2">Pub. L. 96–533, § 115(b)(2)</ref>, included payment, in case of training sold to a purchaser currently receiving international military education and training assistance, of additional costs incurred by the United States Government in furnishing the training.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/533/s102">Pub. L. 96–533, § 102</ref>, designated existing provision as par. (1), substituted “training and advising that may engage United States personnel in combat activities” for “training, advising, or otherwise providing assistance regarding combat activities”, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/96/533/s103">Pub. L. 96–533, § 103</ref>, authorized the President to enter into standardization agreements with Japan, Australia, and New Zealand.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/96/533/s105/b/1">Pub. L. 96–533, § 105(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “defense articles, defense services, or design and construction services” for “defense articles or defense services” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsecs. (h), (i). <ref href="/us/pl/96/92">Pub. L. 96–92</ref> added subsec. (h) and redesignated former subsec. (h) as (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (e)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/95/384">Pub. L. 95–384</ref> added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/329/s205">Pub. L. 94–329, § 205</ref>, designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and substituted provisions authorizing President to sell defense articles and defense services from Department of Defense stocks to eligible countries and international organizations who agree to pay specified values for such articles and services in United States dollars, for provisions requiring that payment for defense articles and defense services from stocks be made in advance, or if in the best interest of the United States as determined by the President, within a reasonable period not to exceed 120 days after delivery of the articles or rendering of the services.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b) to (h). <ref href="/us/pl/94/329">Pub. L. 94–329</ref>, §§ 205, 206, added subsecs. (b) to (h).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id900f5a02-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id900f5a03-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dD/tXLIII/s4303/b">Pub. L. 104–106, div. D, title XLIII, § 4303(b)</ref>–(d), <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/659">110 Stat. 659</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/106/dD/tXLIII/s4303/b">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Conditions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Subsection (a) [amending this section] shall be effective only if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the President, in the budget of the President for fiscal year 1997, proposes legislation that if enacted would be qualifying offsetting legislation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> there is enacted qualifying offsetting legislation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Effective Date</inline>.—</heading><content>If the conditions in subsection (b) are met, then the amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date of the enactment of qualifying offsetting legislation [<date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> The term ‘qualifying offsetting legislation’ means legislation that includes provisions that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> offset fully the estimated revenues lost as a result of the amendments made by subsection (a) for each of the fiscal years 1997 through 2005;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> expressly state that they are enacted for the purpose of the offset described in subparagraph (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> are included in full on the PayGo scorecard.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘PayGo scorecard’ means the estimates that are made by the Director of the Congressional Budget Office and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget under section 252(d) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 [<ref href="/us/usc/t2/s902/d">2 U.S.C. 902(d)</ref>].”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Qualifying offsetting legislation was enacted by <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/s3303">Pub. L. 104–201, § 3303</ref>, listed in a Materials in the National Defense Stockpile table under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s98d">section 98d of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id900f5a04-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1985 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/83">Pub. L. 99–83</ref> effective <date date="1985-10-01">Oct. 1, 1985</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/83/s1301">section 1301 of Pub. L. 99–83</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151–1">section 2151–1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id900f5a05-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1968-07-01">July 1, 1968</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/629/s41">section 41 of Pub. L. 90–629</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id900f5a06-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/164/tI/s152/c">Pub. L. 104–164, title I, § 152(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-07-21">July 21, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1439">110 Stat. 1439</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/164/tI/s152/c">“Under the direction of the President, the Secretary of Defense shall promulgate regulations to implement subsections (<i>l</i>) and (m) of section 21 of the Arms Export Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2761">22 U.S.C. 2761</ref>(<i>l</i>), (m)], as added by this section.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id900f5a07-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id900f5a08-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Improvements to Security Cooperation Workforce and Defense Acquisition Workforce</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXII/s1211">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title XII, § 1211</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1082">139 Stat. 1082</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXII/s1211">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Responsibilities of Secretary of Defense</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall, consistent with the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s384">section 384 of title 10</ref>, United States Code, seek to ensure that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> members of the defense acquisition workforce engaged in foreign military sales planning and execution—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> are aware of evolving United States regional- and country-level foreign partner defense capability-building priorities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> coordinate with the security cooperation workforce to enhance responsiveness to foreign partner requests and defense capability-building priorities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> evaluations of members of the defense acquisition workforce measure—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> adherence to meeting the foreign partner defense capability-building requirements identified in Department of Defense strategy documents;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> responsiveness to foreign partner defense capability-building requests;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> ability to meet foreign partner defense capability-building delivery schedule requirements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> advancement of foreign partner defense capability-building priorities identified in the guidance described in subsection (b).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guidance.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall update, as necessary, Department of Defense guidance governing the execution of foreign military sales by the Department to ensure that such guidance—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> incorporates priorities of the national security strategy report (submitted pursuant to section 108 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3043">50 U.S.C. 3043</ref>)) and the national defense strategy (required under <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s113/g">section 113(g) of title 10</ref>, United States Code);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> is informed by the theater campaign plans and theater security cooperation strategies of the combatant commands;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> is disseminated to the security cooperation workforce and the defense acquisition workforce.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The updated guidance required by paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> identify regional and country-level foreign partner defense capability-building priorities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> identify levels of urgency and desired timelines for achieving foreign partner defense capability-building priorities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> provide guidance to the defense acquisition workforce and the security cooperation workforce on levels of resourcing, innovation, and risk tolerance that should be considered in meeting urgent needs through the execution of foreign military sales.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Foreign Military Sales Continuous Process Improvement Board</inline>.—</heading><note topic="miscellaneous" id="id900f5a09-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<p> [Amended <ref href="/us/pl/118/159/s1210/b/2">section 1210(b)(2) of Pub. L. 118–159</ref>, set out as a note below.]</p></note>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The term ‘defense acquisition workforce’ means the Department of Defense acquisition workforce described in chapter 87 of title 10, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘security cooperation workforce’ has the meaning given the term in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s384">section 384 of title 10</ref>, United States Code.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id900f5a0a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Modifications to Foreign Military Sales Processes</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXII/s1212">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title XII, § 1212</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1084">139 Stat. 1084</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXII/s1212">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Acquisition Strategies</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall, with respect to the foreign military sales process—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> establish a requirement that, in developing letters of offer and acceptance for a foreign military sale, the acquisition program manager, or other official responsible for the program, shall develop an acquisition strategy that is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> informed by input from the purchaser of such foreign military sale; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> executed in a manner that effectively addresses urgency of need and associated risk tolerance of such purchaser; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> in establishing such requirement, ensure that such purchaser is provided an opportunity to provide input on urgency of need and associated risk tolerance, alternative acquisition approaches that may be taken to accelerate program delivery, and the schedule, cost, and capability trade-offs associated with such alternate approaches.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Agreements With Manufacturers.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>A United States prime contractor may enter into a covered agreement with a manufacturer to begin the process of acquiring long-lead Government-furnished equipment based on forecasted requirements prior to the execution of a contract for a commercial sale or issuance of a letter of offer and acceptance for a foreign military sale.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Department of defense policy.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense and each Secretary of a military department shall implement policies that allow United States prime contractors to enter into covered agreements described in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The policies required by subparagraph (A) shall require—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><chapeau> United States prime contractors to be responsible for—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> negotiating directly with the manufacturer of Government-furnished equipment, including with respect to the terms and conditions described in subsection (c)(1)(B); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> providing any payment to such manufacturer; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> transfer of Government-furnished equipment from such manufacturer to the prime contractor shall not occur until the date on which a contract for a commercial sale or letter of offer and acceptance is executed with respect to the foreign military sale that is the subject of the covered agreement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as authorizing, requiring, or providing for the United States Government to assume any liability or other financial responsibility with respect to a covered agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> The term ‘covered agreement’ means an agreement between a United States prime contractor and a manufacturer pursuant to which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the prime contractor, in anticipation of a foreign military sale, enters into a contract with the manufacturer for the production of one or more defense articles (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s301">section 301 of title 10</ref>, United States Code) that will be supplied to the prime contractor as Government-furnished equipment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the parties agree to the allocation of risks, obligations, profits, and costs in the event the anticipated foreign military sale does not occur, including whether the defense articles manufactured under the agreement are retained by the manufacturer; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the United States Government assumes no liability with respect to either party in the event the anticipated foreign military sale does not occur.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘foreign military sales process’ means the processes for foreign military sales authorized under chapter 2 of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2761">22 U.S.C. 2761</ref> et seq.).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id900f5a0b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Improvements to Defense Acquisition Workforce for Foreign Military Sales</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/159/dA/tXII/s1210/b">Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XII, § 1210(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2098">138 Stat. 2098</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXII/s1211/c">Pub. L. 119–60, div. A, title XII, § 1211(c)</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1083">139 Stat. 1083</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/60/dA/tXII/s1211/c">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Foreign Military Sales Continuous Process Improvement Board.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a Foreign Military Sales Continuous Process Improvement Board (in this section referred to as the ‘Board’) to serve as an enduring governance structure within the Department of Defense that reports to the Secretary on matters relating to the foreign military sales process so as to enhance accountability and continuous improvement within the Department, including the objectives of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> improving the understanding, among officials of the Department, of ally and partner requirements;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> enabling efficient reviews for release of technology;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> providing ally and partner countries with relevant priority equipment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> accelerating acquisition and contracting support;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> expanding the capacity of the defense industrial base;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> working with other departments and agencies to promote broad United States Government support; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> any other matters determined by the Secretary to be relevant to the Board.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Membership.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Board shall be composed of not fewer than seven members, each of whom shall have expertise in security cooperation, security assistance, defense acquisition, business process reform, or any disciplines the Secretary determines to be important to the functioning of the Board.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certain members.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Up to three of the members of the Board may be selected from among individuals who are not any of the following:</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> Officers or employees of the Department of Defense.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> Members of the Armed Forces.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="III">     “(III)</num><content> A registered lobbyist.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Clearance</inline>.—</heading><content>Each member of the Board described in this subparagraph shall be individuals who are determined to be eligible for access to classified information necessary to participate on the Board.”</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(3) <inline class="small-caps">Sunset</inline>.—This subsection shall terminate on <date date="2030-12-31">December 31, 2030</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(c) <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—In this section:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) The term ‘defense acquisition workforce’ means the Department of Defense acquisition workforce described in chapter 87 of title 10, United States Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) The term ‘nonprofit organization’ means an organization described in section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [<ref href="/us/usc/t26/s501/c/3">26 U.S.C. 501(c)(3)</ref>] and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such Code[.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(3) The term ‘security cooperation workforce’ has the meaning given the term in <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s384">section 384 of title 10</ref>, United States Code.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id900f5a0c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Notional Milestones and Standard Timelines for Contracts for Foreign Military Sales</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tVIII/s887">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VIII, § 887</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1506">131 Stat. 1506</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tVIII/s887">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VIII, § 887</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3791">134 Stat. 3791</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tVIII/s887">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense shall establish specific notional milestones and standard timelines for the Department of Defense to achieve such milestones in its processing of a foreign military sale (as authorized under chapter 2 of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2761">22 U.S.C. 2761</ref> et seq.)). Such milestones and timelines—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> may vary depending on the complexity of the foreign military sale; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> shall cover the period beginning on the date of receipt of a complete letter of request (as described in chapter 5 of the Security Assistance Management Manual of the Defense Security Cooperation Agency) from a foreign country and ending on the date of the final delivery of a defense article or defense service sold through the foreign military sale.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>], the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report describing the milestones and timelines developed pursuant to paragraph (1) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submissions to Congress.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Quarterly notification</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>During the period beginning 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and ending on <date date="2022-12-31">December 31, 2022</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress, on a quarterly basis, a report that includes a list of each foreign military sale with a value greater than or equal to the dollar threshold for congressional notification under section 36 of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2776">22 U.S.C. 2776</ref>)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> for which the final delivery of a defense article or defense service has not been completed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> that has not met a standard timeline to achieve a notional milestone as established under subsection (a).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than <date date="2019-11-01">November 1, 2019</date>, and annually thereafter until <date date="2022-12-31">December 31, 2022</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that summarizes—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the number, set forth separately by dollar value and notional milestone, of foreign military sales that met the standard timeline to achieve a notional milestone established under subsection (a) during the preceding fiscal year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the number, set forth separately by dollar value and notional milestone, of each foreign military sale that did not meet the standard timeline to achieve a notional milestone established under subsection (a), and a description of any extenuating factors explaining why such a sale did not achieve such milestone.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicability</inline>.—</heading><content>The requirements of this subsection apply only to foreign military sales processes within the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the terms ‘defense article’ and ‘defense service’ have the meanings given those terms, respectively, in section 47 of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2794">22 U.S.C. 2794</ref>); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> the term ‘appropriate committees of Congress’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id900f5a0d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">International Sales Process Improvements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tXII/s1297">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1297</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2563">130 Stat. 2563</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tXII/s1297">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Plan Required</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>], the Secretary of Defense shall develop a plan to improve the management and use of fees collected on transfer of defense articles and services via sale, lease, or grant to international customers under programs over which the Defense Security Cooperation Agency has administration responsibilities. The plan shall include options to use fees more effectively—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to improve the staffing and processes of the licensing review cycle at the Defense Technology Security Administration and other reviewing authorities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to maintain a cadre of contracting officers and acquisition officials who specialize in foreign military sales contracting.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Process for Gathering Input</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a process for contractors to provide input, feedback, and adjudication of any differences regarding the appropriateness of governmental pricing and availability estimates prior to the delivery to potential foreign customers of formal responses to Letters of Request for Pricing and Availability.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id900f5a0e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id900f5a0f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of certain functions of the President under this section, see section 1(c) of Ex. Ord. No. 13637, <date date="2013-03-08">Mar. 8, 2013</date>, 78 F.R. 16129, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of this title</ref>. Functions were previously delegated by Ex. Ord. No. 11958, which was formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of this title</ref> and was revoked, subject to a savings provision, by section 4 of Ex. Ord. No. 13637.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
