<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id900f5a10-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2762"><num value="2762">§ 2762.</num><heading> Procurement for cash sales</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id900f5a11-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2762/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of President; dependable undertaking by foreign country or international organization; interest rates</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the President may, without requirement for charge to any appropriation or contract authorization otherwise provided, enter into contracts for the procurement of defense articles or defense services for sale for United States dollars to any foreign country or international organization if such country or international organization provides the United States Government with a dependable undertaking (1) to pay the full amount of such contract which will assure the United States Government against any loss on the contract, and (2) to make funds available in such amounts and at such times as may be required to meet the payments required by the contract, and any damages and costs that may accrue from the cancellation of such contract, in advance of the time such payments, damages, or costs are due. Interest shall be charged on any net amount by which any such country or international organization is in arrears under all of its outstanding unliquidated dependable undertakings, considered collectively. The rate of interest charged shall be a rate not less than a rate determined by the Secretary of the Treasury taking into consideration the current average market yield on outstanding short-term obligations of the United States as of the last day of the month preceding the net arrearage and shall be computed from the date of net arrearage.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id900f5a12-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2762/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Issuance of letters of offer under emergency determination; availability of appropriations for payment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President may, if he determines it to be in the national interest, issue letters of offer under this section which provide for billing upon delivery of the defense article or rendering of the defense service and for payment within one hundred and twenty days after the date of billing. This authority may be exercised, however, only if the President also determines that the emergency requirements of the purchaser for acquisition of such defense articles and services exceed the ready availability to the purchaser of funds sufficient to make payments on a dependable undertaking basis and submits both determinations to the Congress together with a special emergency request for authorization and appropriation of additional funds to finance such purchases under this chapter. Appropriations available to the Department of Defense may be used to meet the payments required by the contracts for the procurement of defense articles and defense services and shall be reimbursed by the amounts subsequently received from the country or international organization to whom articles or services are sold.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id900f5a13-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2762/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability of Renegotiation Act of 1951</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of the Renegotiation Act of 1951 do not apply to procurement contracts heretofore or hereafter entered into under this section, <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2769">section 2769 of this title</ref>, or predecessor provisions of law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id900f5a14-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2762/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Competitive pricing</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900f5a15-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2762/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Procurement contracts made in implementation of sales under this section for defense articles and defense services wholly paid for from funds made available on a nonrepayable basis shall be priced on the same costing basis with regard to profit, overhead, independent research and development, bid and proposal, and other costing elements, as is applicable to procurements of like items purchased by the Department of Defense for its own use.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id900f5a16-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2762/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Direct costs associated with meeting additional or unique requirements of the purchaser shall be allowable under contracts described in paragraph (1). Loadings applicable to such direct costs shall be permitted at the same rates applicable to procurement of like items purchased by the Department of Defense for its own use.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id900f5a17-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/629">Pub. L. 90–629</ref>, ch. 2, § 22, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1323">82 Stat. 1323</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/189/s25/3">Pub. L. 93–189, § 25(3)</ref>, <date date="1973-12-17">Dec. 17, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/730">87 Stat. 730</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/329/tII/s207">Pub. L. 94–329, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="1976-06-30">June 30, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/738">90 Stat. 738</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/384/s17">Pub. L. 95–384, § 17</ref>, <date date="1978-09-26">Sept. 26, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/740">92 Stat. 740</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/533/tI/s105/b/2">Pub. L. 96–533, title I, § 105(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-16">Dec. 16, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/3134">94 Stat. 3134</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/107/tV/s531A/a">Pub. L. 104–107, title V, § 531A(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-12">Feb. 12, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/731">110 Stat. 731</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/7/dB/tXII/s1223">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(7) [div. B, title XII, § 1223]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–498.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id900f5a18-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id900f5a19-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id900f5a1a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (b), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/90/629">Pub. L. 90–629</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1321">82 Stat. 1321</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Renegotiation Act of 1951, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/act/1951-03-23/ch15">act Mar. 23, 1951, ch. 15</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/65/7">65 Stat. 7</ref>, which was classified principally to section 1211 et seq. of the former Appendix to Title 50, War and National Defense, prior to its omission from the Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id900f5a1b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/104/107">Pub. L. 104–107</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/533">Pub. L. 96–533</ref> substituted “procurement contracts” for “contracts for the procurement of defense articles and defense services” and inserted reference to contracts entered into under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2769">section 2769 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/384">Pub. L. 95–384</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/329/s207/a">Pub. L. 94–329, § 207(a)</ref>, inserted provisions requiring interest to be charged on any net amount a country or international organization is in arrears and the rate of interest to be determined by the Secretary of Treasury considering current average market yield of short-term obligations of United States on a particular day.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/94/329/s207/b">Pub. L. 94–329, § 207(b)</ref>, substituted provisions authorizing President to issue letters of offer with provisions for billing on delivery of article or rendering of service and payment within 120 days after billing date where President determines that emergency conditions exist, for provisions authorizing President to accept a dependable undertaking of a foreign country or international organization with respect to sales of defense articles and services and to make payment within 120 days of delivery of article or rendering of service.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—<ref href="/us/pl/93/189">Pub. L. 93–189</ref> designated text preceding first proviso as subsec. (a) and inserted “Except as otherwise provided in this section,” before “the President”, designated first proviso as subsec. (b) and inserted reference to acceptance of a dependable undertaking of a foreign country or international organization, and struck out further provisions setting forth Presidential powers with respect to sales agreements with and payments by purchasing countries or international organizations.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id900f5a1c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id900f5a1d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment; Implementing Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/107/tV/s531A/b">Pub. L. 104–107, title V, § 531A(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-12">Feb. 12, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/731">110 Stat. 731</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/107/tV/s531A/b">
<inline>“Section 22(d) of the Arms Export Control Act [subsec. (d) of this section], as added by subsection (a)—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> shall take effect on the 60th day following the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-02-12">Feb. 12, 1996</date>];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> shall be applicable only to contracts made in implementation of sales made after such effective date; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> shall be implemented by revised procurement regulations, which shall be issued prior to such effective date.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id900f5a1e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1968-07-01">July 1, 1968</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/629/s41">section 41 of Pub. L. 90–629</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="similarProvisions" id="id900f5a1f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Similar Provisions</heading><p>Provisions similar to those comprising subsec. (d)(2) of this section were contained in the following appropriation acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/2/tV/s556">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(2) [title V, § 556]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1535">113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–100.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dA/s101/d/tV/s536">Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(d) [title V, § 536]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-150">112 Stat. 2681–150</ref>, 2681–181.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/118/tV/s535">Pub. L. 105–118, title V, § 535</ref>, <date date="1997-11-26">Nov. 26, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2416">111 Stat. 2416</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/208/dA/tI/s101/c/tV/s533A">Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(c) [title V, § 533A]</ref>, <date date="1996-09-30">Sept. 30, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3009-121">110 Stat. 3009–121</ref>, 3009–153.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/107/tV/s531A/c">Pub. L. 104–107, title V, § 531A(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-12">Feb. 12, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/731">110 Stat. 731</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id900f5a20-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Requirement To Use Firm Fixed-Price Contracts for Foreign Military Sales</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tVIII/s807/c">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1486">133 Stat. 1486</ref>, provided that the regulations prescribed pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tVIII/s830/a">section 830(a) of title VIII of div. A of Pub. L. 114–328</ref>, formerly set out as a note below, would not take effect until <date date="2020-12-31">Dec. 31, 2020</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tVIII/s830">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title VIII, § 830</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2282">130 Stat. 2282</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tVIII/s812">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VIII, § 812</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1461">131 Stat. 1461</ref>, which directed the Secretary of Defense to prescribe regulations to require firm fixed-price contracts for foreign military sales not later than 180 days after <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, and to establish a pilot program for acceleration of foreign military sales, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tVIII/s888">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title VIII, § 888</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3791">134 Stat. 3791</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id900f5a21-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id900f5a22-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of functions of the President under subsec. (a) of this section, see section 1(d) of Ex. Ord. No. 13637, <date date="2013-03-08">Mar. 8, 2013</date>, 78 F.R. 16129, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of this title</ref>. Functions were previously delegated by Ex. Ord. No. 11958, which was formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of this title</ref> and was revoked, subject to a savings provision, by section 4 of Ex. Ord. No. 13637.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
