<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9011ca42-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2764"><num value="2764">§ 2764.</num><heading> Guaranties</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9011ca43-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2764/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Guaranty against political and credit risks of nonpayment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President may guarantee any individual, corporation, partnership, or other juridical entity doing business in the United States (excluding United States Government agencies other than the Federal Financing Bank) against political and credit risks of nonpayment arising out of their financing of credit sales of defense articles, defense services, and design and construction services to friendly countries and international organizations. Fees shall be charged for such guaranties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9011ca44-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2764/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Sale of promissory notes of friendly countries and international organizations; guaranty of payment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President may sell to any individual, corporation, partnership, or other juridical entity (excluding United States Government agencies other than the Federal Financing Bank) promissory notes issued by friendly countries and international organizations as evidence of their obligations to make repayments to the United States on account of credit sales financed under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2763">section 2763 of this title</ref>, and may guarantee payment thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9011ca45-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2764/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Guaranty Reserve Fund; payment of guaranties; guaranty reserve below prescribed amount</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Funds obligated under this section before <date date="1980-12-16">December 16, 1980</date>, which constitute a single reserve for the payment of claims under guaranties issued under this section shall remain available for expenditure for the purposes of this section on and after that date. That single reserve may, on and after <date date="1985-08-08">August 8, 1985</date>, be referred to as the “Guaranty Reserve Fund”. Funds provided for necessary expenses to carry out the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2763">section 2763 of this title</ref> and of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2311">section 2311 of this title</ref> may be used to pay claims on the Guaranty Reserve Fund to the extent that funds in the Guaranty Reserve Fund are inadequate for that purpose. For purposes of any provision in this chapter or any other Act relating to a prohibition or limitation on the availability of funds under this chapter, whenever a guaranty is issued under this section, the principal amount of the loan so guaranteed shall be deemed to be funds made available for use under this chapter. Any guaranties issued hereunder shall be backed by the full faith and credit of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9011ca46-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/629">Pub. L. 90–629</ref>, ch. 2, § 24, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1324">82 Stat. 1324</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/189/s25/4">Pub. L. 93–189, § 25(4)</ref>, <date date="1973-12-17">Dec. 17, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/730">87 Stat. 730</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/559/s45/a/3">Pub. L. 93–559, § 45(a)(3)</ref>, (4), <date date="1974-12-30">Dec. 30, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1814">88 Stat. 1814</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/533/tI">Pub. L. 96–533, title I</ref>, §§ 104(a), 105(b)(3), <date date="1980-12-16">Dec. 16, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/3132">94 Stat. 3132</ref>, 3134; <ref href="/us/pl/99/83/tI/s106/b">Pub. L. 99–83, title I, § 106(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="1985-08-08">Aug. 8, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/196">99 Stat. 196</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/71/tI">Pub. L. 100–71, title I</ref>, <date date="1987-07-11">July 11, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/409">101 Stat. 409</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9011ca47-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9011ca48-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id9011ca49-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (c), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/90/629">Pub. L. 90–629</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1321">82 Stat. 1321</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9011ca4a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/100/71">Pub. L. 100–71</ref>, which directed that the second par. be struck out and a new one-sentence par. be inserted, was executed to reflect the probable intent of Congress by substituting the new sentence for the third sentence which read as follows: “Funds authorized to be appropriated by <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2771/a">section 2771(a) of this title</ref> to carry out this chapter which are allocated for credits at market rates of interest may be used to pay claims under such guarantees to the extent funds in the Guaranty Reserve Fund are inadequate for that purpose.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/83">Pub. L. 99–83</ref> inserted provisions authorizing the single reserve to be termed the “Guaranty Reserve Fund”, and substituted provisions relating to payment of claims under guarantees, for provisions relating to report to Congress respecting any payment of claims reducing the single reserve.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/96/533/s105/b/3">Pub. L. 96–533, § 105(b)(3)</ref>, substituted “defense articles, defense services, and design and construction services” for “defense articles and defense services”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/533/s104/a">Pub. L. 96–533, § 104(a)</ref>, substituted provisions making funds obligated before <date date="1980-12-16">Dec. 16, 1980</date> available for expenditure after such date for payment of guaranteed claims, requiring the President to report to Congress the reduction of the single reserve below $750,000,000 with recommendation for an appropriations authorization of additional funds and deeming the principal amount of a guaranteed loan to be funds made available for use under this chapter for purposes of any limitation on availability of funds for prior provisions for obligation of available funds in an amount equal to 10 per centum of principal amount of contractual liability related to a guaranty under this section, making such funds a single reserve for payment of guaranteed claims, and providing for transfer of any funds deobligated during any current fiscal year to the general fund of the Treasury.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Subsecs. (a), (b). <ref href="/us/pl/93/559/s45/a/3">Pub. L. 93–559, § 45(a)(3)</ref>, inserted “other than the Federal Financing Bank” in parenthetical text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/93/559/s45/a/4">Pub. L. 93–559, § 45(a)(4)</ref>, substituted “10” for “25” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/93/189">Pub. L. 93–189</ref> substituted “to carry out this chapter” for “pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2771">section 2771 of this title</ref>” and inserted “principal amount of” before “contractual liability” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9011ca4b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9011ca4c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1985 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/83">Pub. L. 99–83</ref> effective <date date="1985-10-01">Oct. 1, 1985</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/83/s1301">section 1301 of Pub. L. 99–83</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151–1">section 2151–1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9011ca4d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1974 Amendment; Adjustment of Obligations Charged Against Appropriations; Credit for Fiscal Year 1975 Appropriations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/93/559/s45/b">Pub. L. 93–559, § 45(b)</ref>, <date date="1974-12-30">Dec. 30, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1815">88 Stat. 1815</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/93/559/s45/b">“The amendment made by paragraph (4) of subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect on <date date="1974-07-01">July 1, 1974</date>. Obligations initially charged against appropriations made available for purposes authorized by section 31(a) of the Foreign Military Sales Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2771/a">section 2771(a) of this title</ref>] after <date date="1974-06-30">June 30, 1974</date>, and prior to the enactment of this section [<date date="1974-12-30">Dec. 30, 1974</date>] in an amount equal to 25 per centum of the principal amount of contractual liability related to guaranties issued pursuant to section 24(a) of that Act [subsec. (a) of this section] shall be adjusted to reflect such amendment with proper credit to the appropriations made available in the fiscal year 1975 to carry out that Act [this chapter].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id9011ca4e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1968-07-01">July 1, 1968</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/629/s41">section 41 of Pub. L. 90–629</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9011ca4f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Foreign Military Sales Debt Reform</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/145/s118">Pub. L. 102–145, § 118</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/102/266/s102">Pub. L. 102–266, § 102</ref>, <date date="1992-04-01">Apr. 1, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/93">106 Stat. 93</ref>, provided that the authority and conditions provided under the heading “Foreign Military Sales Debt Reform” in H.R. 2621, One Hundred Second Congress, 1st session, as passed by the House of Representatives on <date date="1991-06-19">June 19, 1991</date>, shall be applicable to funds appropriated by <ref href="/us/pl/102/145">Pub. L. 102–145</ref> (and are hereby enacted) in lieu of the authority and conditions provided under the heading “Foreign Military Sales Debt Reform” in <ref href="/us/pl/101/513">Pub. L. 101–513</ref> [set out below]. Provisions under the heading “Foreign Military Sales Debt Reform” in H.R. 2621, as referred to above, provided that: <quotedContent>“Subsection (b) under the heading ‘Foreign Military Sales Debt Reform’ in the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1988 [<ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101/e/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(e) [title III, § 301]</ref>, set out below], is hereby repealed.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/101/513/tIII">Pub. L. 101–513, title III</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1999">104 Stat. 1999</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/513/tIII">“Funds made available by the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1988 [<ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101/e/tIII">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(e) [title III]</ref>, set out below], for obligation and expenditure after <date date="1988-10-01">October 1, 1988</date>, subject to a Presidential budget request, under the heading ‘Foreign Military Sales Debt Reform’, subsection (b) ‘Interest Rate Reduction’ shall be available, subject to the same conditions and provisos, only after <date date="1991-10-01">October 1, 1991</date>.”</quotedContent>
 Similar provisions were contained in the following prior appropriation acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/167/tIII">Pub. L. 101–167, title III</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1214">103 Stat. 1214</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/461/tIII">Pub. L. 100–461, title III</ref>, <date date="1988-10-01">Oct. 1, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2268-18">102 Stat. 2268–18</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101/e/tIII">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(e) [title III]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1329-131">101 Stat. 1329–131</ref>, 1329–148, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/101/167/tIII">Pub. L. 101–167, title III</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1214">103 Stat. 1214</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/145/s118">Pub. L. 102–145, § 118</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/102/266/s102">Pub. L. 102–266, § 102</ref>, <date date="1992-04-01">Apr. 1, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/93">106 Stat. 93</ref>, provided in part that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/266/s102">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Refinancing</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President is authorized during fiscal years 1988 through 1991 to transfer existing United States guaranties of outstanding Foreign Military Sales (FMS) credit debt, or to issue new guaranties, either of which would be applied to loans, bonds, notes or other obligations made or issued (as the case may be) by private United States financial institutions (the private lender) to finance the prepayment at par of the principal amounts maturing after <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date> of existing FMS loans bearing interest rates of eight percent or higher, and arrearages thereon. The loans, bonds, notes or other obligations are hereinafter referred to as the ‘private loan’: <i>Provided</i>, That such guaranties which are transferred or are made pursuant to paragraph (a) shall cover no more and no less than ninety percent of the private loan or any portion or derivative thereof plus unpaid accrued interest and arrearages, if any, outstanding at the time of guaranty transfer or extension: <i>Provided further</i>, That the total amount of the guaranty of the private loan cannot exceed ninety percent of the outstanding principal, unpaid accrued interest and arrearages, if any, at any time: <i>Provided further</i>, That of the total amount of the private loan, the ninety percent guaranteed portion of the private loan cannot be separated from the private loan at any time: <i>Provided further</i>, That no sums in addition to the payment of the outstanding principal amounts maturing after <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date> of the loan (or advance), plus unpaid accrued interest thereon, and arrearages, if any, shall be charged by the private lender or the Federal Financing Bank as a result of such prepayment against the borrower, the guarantor, or the Guaranty Reserve Fund (GRF), except that the private lender may include, in the interest rate charged, a standard fee to cover costs, such fee which will be set at prevailing market rates, and no guaranty fee shall be charged on guarantees transferred or issued pursuant to this provision: <i>Provided further</i>, That the terms of guaranties transferred or issued under this paragraph shall be exactly the same as the existing loans or guarantees, except as modified by this paragraph and including but not limited to the final maturity and principal and interest payment structure of the existing loans which shall not be altered, except that the repayments of the private loan issued debt may be consolidated into two payments per year: <i>Provided further</i>, That the private loan or guarantees transferred or issued pursuant to this paragraph shall be fully and freely transferable, except that any guaranty transferred or extended shall cease to be effective if the private loan or any derivative thereof is to be used to provide significant support for any non-registered obligation: <i>Provided further</i>, That for purposes of sections 23 and 24 of the Arms Export Control Act (AECA) [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2763">22 U.S.C. 2763</ref>, 2764], the term ‘defense services’ shall be deemed to include the refinancing of FMS debt outstanding at the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>]: <i>Provided further</i>, That not later than ninety days after the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury (Secretary) shall issue regulations to carry out the purposes of this heading and that in issuing such regulations, the Secretary shall (1) facilitate the prepayment of loans and loan advances hereunder, (2) provide for full processing of each application within thirty days of its submission to the Secretary, and (3) except as provided in section 24(a) of the AECA, impose no restriction that increases the cost to borrowers of obtaining private financing for prepayment hereunder or that inhibits the ability of the borrower to enter into prepayment arrangements hereunder: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Secretary of State shall transmit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, and the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate, a copy of the text of any agreement entered into pursuant to this section not more than thirty days after its entry into force, together with a description of the transaction.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0" status="repealed"><num value="b">“[(b)</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/102/145/s118">Pub. L. 102–145, § 118</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/102/266/s102">Pub. L. 102–266, § 102</ref>, <date date="1992-04-01">Apr. 1, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/93">106 Stat. 93</ref>.]</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Arrearages</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> None of the funds provided pursuant to the Arms Export Control Act (relating to Foreign Military Sales credits) [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.] or pursuant to chapter 2 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act (relating to the Military Assistance program) [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2311">22 U.S.C. 2311</ref> et seq.] shall be made available to any country for which one or more loans is refinanced pursuant to paragraph (a) of this heading and which is in default for a period in excess of ninety days in payment of principal or interest on (A) any loan made to such country guaranteed by the United States pursuant to paragraph (a) of this heading, and (B) any other loan issued pursuant to the Arms Export Control Act outstanding on the date of enactment of this provision [<date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> In conjunction with any interest rate reduction pursuant to the authority provided in paragraph (b) of this heading, the President shall require the country to commit in writing that within two years of the effective date of the interest rate reduction it will be no more than ninety days in arrears on the repayment of principal and interest on all loans for which the interest rate is thus reduced and will remain no more than ninety days in arrears for the remaining life of all such loans. None of the funds provided pursuant to the Arms Export Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.] or chapter 2 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2311">22 U.S.C. 2311</ref> et seq.] shall be made available to any country during any period in which it fails to comply with such commitment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purposes and Reports</inline>.—</heading><content>The authorities of paragraphs (a) and (b) of this heading may be utilized by the President in efforts to negotiate base rights and base access agreements, and for other bilateral foreign policy matters: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Secretaries of Defense, State, and Treasury shall transmit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, and the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate a joint report detailing the United States financial and foreign policy purposes served by implementation of this authority on a country by country basis not later than <date date="1989-03-01">March 1, 1989</date>, and a second joint report not later than <date date="1989-08-01">August 1, 1989</date>.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id9011ca50-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id9011ca51-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of functions of the President under this section, with certain conditions, see section 1(f) of Ex. Ord. No. 13637, <date date="2013-03-08">Mar. 8, 2013</date>, 78 F.R. 16129, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of this title</ref>. Functions were previously delegated by Ex. Ord. No. 11958, which was formerly set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of this title</ref> and was revoked, subject to a savings provision, by section 4 of Ex. Ord. No. 13637.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
