<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8eae6a47-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s276ee"><num value="276ee">§ 276ee.</num><heading> Powers of board; personal liability of members; compensation; decisions reviewable by Secretary of the Army; annual report; jurisdiction of court</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The board shall have all the usual powers of a trustee in respect to all property administered by it, but the members of the board shall not be personally liable, except for misfeasance, on account of any acts performed in their trust capacity. The members of the board shall not be required to furnish bond, and no additional compensation shall accrue to any of them on account of their duties as trustees. Within the limits prescribed by sections 276bb to 276dd of this title, the administration, control, and expenditure of this fund and its application to the purposes intended shall be according to the sole discretion of the board, and the exercise of its discretion and authority in regard thereto and its decisions thereon, including any payments made or authorized by it to be made from the Kermit Roosevelt fund, shall not be subject to review except by the Secretary of the Army, to whom the board shall, on the 1st day of January, each year, render a full report of its activities during the preceding twelve months. The actions of the board shall not be subject to judicial review except in an action brought in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, which is given jurisdiction of such suits, for the purpose of enforcing the provisions of any trust accepted by the board.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8eae6a48-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1945-07-02/ch228/s5">July 2, 1945, ch. 228, § 5</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/59/317">59 Stat. 317</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343">July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, § 205(a), <ref href="/us/stat/61/501">61 Stat. 501</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8eae6a49-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8eae6a4a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8eae6a4b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s228">section 228 of Title 5</ref> prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s1">Pub. L. 89–554, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/378">80 Stat. 378</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8eae6a4c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id8eae6a4d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Department of War designated Department of the Army and title of Secretary of War changed to Secretary of the Army by section 205(a) of <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343/tII">act July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/501">61 Stat. 501</ref>. Section 205(a) of act <date date="1947-07-26">July 26, 1947</date>, was repealed by section 53 of <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041">act Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/641">70A Stat. 641</ref>. Section 1 of act <date date="1956-08-10">Aug. 10, 1956</date>, enacted “Title 10, Armed Forces” which in sections 3010 to 3013 continued Department of the Army under administrative supervision of Secretary of the Army.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
