<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8eac200d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s276m"><num value="276m">§ 276m.</num><heading> United States Delegation to Parliamentary Assembly of Conference on Security and Cooperation in Europe (CSCE)</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8eac200e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s276m/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In accordance with the allocation of seats to the United States in the Parliamentary Assembly of the Conference on Security and Cooperation in Europe (hereinafter referred to as the “CSCE Assembly”) not to exceed 17 Members of Congress shall be appointed to meet jointly and annually with representative parliamentary groups from other Conference on Security and Cooperation in Europe (CSCE) member-nations for the purposes of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8eac200f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s276m/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> assessing the implementation of the objectives of the CSCE;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8eac2010-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s276m/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> discussing subjects addressed during the meetings of the Council of Ministers for Foreign Affairs and the biennial Summit of Heads of State or Government;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8eac2011-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s276m/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> initiating and promoting such national and multilateral measures as may further cooperation and security in Europe.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8eac2012-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s276m/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment of Delegation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For each meeting of the CSCE Assembly, there shall be appointed a United States Delegation, as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8eac2013-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s276m/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In 1992 and every even-numbered year thereafter, 9 Members shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House from Members of the House (not less than 4 of whom, including the Chairman of the United States Delegation, shall be from the Committee on Foreign Affairs); and 8 Members shall, upon recommendations of the Majority and Minority leaders of the Senate, be appointed by the President Pro Tempore of the Senate from Members of the Senate (not less than 4 of whom, including the Vice Chairman of the United States Delegation, shall be from the Committee on Foreign Relations, unless the President Pro Tempore of the Senate, upon recommendations of the Majority and Minority leaders of the Senate, determines otherwise).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8eac2014-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s276m/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In every odd-numbered year beginning in 1993, 9 Members shall, upon recommendation of the Majority and Minority Leaders <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002022">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002022"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should not be capitalized.</note> of the Senate, be appointed by the President Pro Tempore of the Senate from Members of the Senate (not less than 4 of whom, including the Chairman of the United States Delegation, shall be from the Committee on Foreign Relations, unless the President Pro Tempore of the Senate, upon recommendations of the Majority and Minority leaders of the Senate, determines otherwise); and 8 Members shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House from Members of the House (not less than 4 of whom, including the Vice Chairman, shall be from the Committee on Foreign Affairs).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8eac2015-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s276m/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrative support</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of providing general staff support and continuity between successive delegations, each United States Delegation shall have 2 secretaries (one of whom shall be appointed by the Chairman of the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and one of whom shall be appointed by the Chairman of the Delegation of the Senate).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8eac2016-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s276m/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Funding</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id8eac2017-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s276m/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> United States participation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated for each fiscal year $80,000 to assist in meeting the expenses of the United States delegation.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002023">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002023"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be capitalized.</note> For each fiscal year for which an appropriation is made under this subsection, half of such appropriation may be disbursed on voucher to be approved by the Chairman and half of such appropriation may be disbursed on voucher to be approved by the Vice Chairman.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id8eac2018-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s276m/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Amounts appropriated pursuant to this subsection are authorized to be available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8eac2019-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s276m/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The United States Delegation shall, for each fiscal year for which an appropriation is made, submit to the Congress a report including its expenditures under such appropriation. The certificate of the Chairman and Vice Chairman of the United States Delegation shall be final and conclusive upon the accounting officers in the auditing of the accounts of the United States Delegation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8eac201a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/138/tI/s169">Pub. L. 102–138, title I, § 169</ref>, <date date="1991-10-28">Oct. 28, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/677">105 Stat. 677</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8eac201b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id8eac201c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id8eac201d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 13029. Change of Name of Conference on Security and Cooperation in Europe</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 13029, <date date="1996-12-03">Dec. 3, 1996</date>, 61 F.R. 64591, provided in part that effective <date date="1995-01-01">Jan. 1, 1995</date>, the Conference on Security and Cooperation in Europe would be called the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
