<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8eae6a59-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s277a"><num value="277a">§ 277a.</num><heading> Investigations of commission; construction of works or projects</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of State, acting through the American Commissioner, International Boundary Commission, United States and Mexico, is further authorized to conduct technical and other investigations relating to the defining, demarcation, fencing, or monumentation of the land and water boundary between the United States and Mexico, to flood control, water resources, conservation, and utilization of water, sanitation and prevention of pollution, channel rectification, stabilization, drainage of transboundary storm waters, and other related matters upon the international boundary between the United States and Mexico; and to construct and maintain fences, monuments and other demarcations of the boundary line between the United States and Mexico, and sewer systems, water systems, and electric light, power and gas systems crossing the international border, and to continue such work and operations through the American Commissioner as are now in progress and are authorized by law.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President is authorized and empowered to construct, operate, and maintain on the Rio Grande River below Fort Quitman, Texas, any and all works or projects which are recommended to the President as the result of such investigations and by the President are deemed necessary and proper.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8eae6a5a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1924-05-13/ch153/s2">May 13, 1924, ch. 153, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/43/118">43 Stat. 118</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1927-03-03/ch381/s2">Mar. 3, 1927, ch. 381, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/1403">44 Stat. 1403</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-19/ch561">Aug. 19, 1935, ch. 561</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/660">49 Stat. 660</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/246/tIV/s412/b/2">Pub. L. 101–246, title IV, § 412(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-02-16">Feb. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/70">104 Stat. 70</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8eae6a5b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8eae6a5c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8eae6a5d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—<ref href="/us/pl/101/246">Pub. L. 101–246</ref> inserted reference to drainage of transboundary storm waters.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1935—Act <date date="1935-08-19">Aug. 19, 1935</date>, amended section generally.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1927—Act <date date="1927-03-03">Mar. 3, 1927</date>, increased appropriation from $20,000 to $50,000.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8eae6a5e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id8eae6a5f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">International Boundary Commission, United States and Mexico, American section, to which powers, duties, and functions of International Water Commission, United States and Mexico, American section, were transferred by <ref href="/us/act/1932-06-30/ch314">act June 30, 1932, ch. 314</ref>, pt. II, title V, § 510, <ref href="/us/stat/47/417">47 Stat. 417</ref>, reconstituted as International Boundary and Water Commission by Water Treaty of 1944.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="repeals" id="id8eae6a60-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Repeals</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act <date date="1927-03-03">Mar. 3, 1927</date>, cited as a credit to this section, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s8/a">Pub. L. 89–554, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/647">80 Stat. 647</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8eae6a61-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Water Resources Planning</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Jurisdiction, powers, or prerogatives of the International Boundary and Water Commission, United States and Mexico, unaffected by Water Resources Planning Act, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1962–1">section 1962–1 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
