<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8eae6a62-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s277b"><num value="277b">§ 277b.</num><heading> Works or projects under treaty</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8eae6a63-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s277b/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Construction, operation, maintenance, and supervision; sewage interceptor system</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President is further authorized (1) to construct any project or works which may be provided for in a treaty entered into with Mexico and to repair, protect, maintain, or complete works now existing or now under construction or those that may be constructed under the treaty provisions aforesaid; and to construct any project or works designed to facilitate compliance with the provisions of treaties between the United States and Mexico; (2) to operate and maintain any project or works so constructed or, subject to such rules and regulations for continuing supervision by the said American Commissioner or any Federal agency as the President may cause to be promulgated, to turn over the operation and maintenance of such project or works to any Federal agency, or any State, county, municipality, district, or other political subdivision within which such project or works may be in whole or in part situated, upon such terms, conditions, and requirements as the President may deem appropriate; and (3) to carry out preliminary surveys, operations, and maintenance of the interceptor system constructed to intercept sewage flows from Tijuana from selected canyon areas.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8eae6a64-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s277b/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Rio Grande bank protection project</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Expenditures for the Rio Grande bank protection project shall be subject to the provisions and conditions made with respect to that project in the first undesignated paragraph under the heading “<inline class="small-caps">International Obligations</inline>” contained in the Act of <date date="1945-04-25">April 25, 1945</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/59/89">59 Stat. 89</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8eae6a65-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s277b/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Anzalduas diversion dam</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Anzalduas diversion dam shall not be operated for irrigation or water supply purposes in the United States unless suitable arrangements have been made with the prospective water users for repayment to the Government of the United States for such portions of the dam as shall have been allocated to such purposes by the Secretary of State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8eae6a66-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s277b/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Improvements to Rio Grande Canalization Project</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Pursuant to the authority of subsection (a) and in order to facilitate further compliance with the terms of the Convention for Equitable Distribution of the Waters of the Rio Grande, <date date="1906-05-21">May 21, 1906</date>, United States-Mexico, the Secretary of State, acting through the United States Commissioner of the International Boundary and Water Commission, may make improvements to the Rio Grande Canalization Project, originally authorized by the Act of <date date="1935-08-29">August 29, 1935</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/49/961">49 Stat. 961</ref>). Such improvements may include all such works as may be needed to stabilize the Rio Grande in the reach between the Percha Diversion Dam in New Mexico and the American Diversion Dam in El Paso.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8eae6a67-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1924-05-13/ch153/s3">May 13, 1924, ch. 153, § 3</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-19/ch561">Aug. 19, 1935, ch. 561</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/660">49 Stat. 660</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/246/tIV/s412/b/1">Pub. L. 101–246, title IV, § 412(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-02-16">Feb. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/70">104 Stat. 70</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/319/tI/s104">Pub. L. 104–319, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3866">110 Stat. 3866</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8eae6a68-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8eae6a69-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8eae6a6a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The first undesignated paragraph under the heading “<inline class="small-caps">International Obligations</inline>” contained in the Act of <date date="1945-04-25">April 25, 1945</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/59/89">59 Stat. 89</ref>), referred to in subsec. (b), is not classified to the Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8eae6a6b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/104/319">Pub. L. 104–319</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—<ref href="/us/pl/101/246">Pub. L. 101–246</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), redesignated cls. (a) and (b) as (1) and (2), respectively, added cl. (3), and added subsecs. (b) and (c).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
