<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8eb0da9e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s277d–12"><num value="277d–12">§ 277d–12.</num><heading> Expenditures for flood fighting, rescue operations, repairs or restoration of flood control or sanitation works threatened or destroyed by floodwaters of Rio Grande, Colorado, or Tijuana Rivers</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">On and after <date date="1956-06-20">June 20, 1956</date>, in addition to the funds available under the appropriation “Rio Grande emergency flood protection”, the United States Commissioner is authorized to expend from any appropriation available to the International Boundary and Water Commission, United States and Mexico, American Section, such sums as may be necessary for prosecution of emergency flood fighting and rescue operations, repairs or restoration of any flood control or sanitation works threatened or destroyed by floodwaters of the Rio Grande, the Colorado or Tijuana Rivers, or other streams running across or near the boundary, and for taking emergency actions, consistent with the emergency provisions of the Safe Drinking Water Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300f">42 U.S.C. 300f</ref> et seq.], to protect against health threatening surface and ground water pollution problems along the United States-Mexico boundary.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8eb0da9f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1956-06-20/ch414">June 20, 1956, ch. 414</ref>, title I, <ref href="/us/stat/70/302">70 Stat. 302</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/246/tIV/s412/a">Pub. L. 101–246, title IV, § 412(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-02-16">Feb. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/69">104 Stat. 69</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/tIV/s423/b">Pub. L. 103–236, title IV, § 423(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/457">108 Stat. 457</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8eb0daa0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8eb0daa1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8eb0daa2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Safe Drinking Water Act, referred to in text, is title XIV of act <date date="1944-07-01">July 1, 1944</date>, as added <date date="1974-12-16">Dec. 16, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/93/523/s2/a">Pub. L. 93–523, § 2(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1660">88 Stat. 1660</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter XII (§ 300f et seq.) of chapter 6A of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">section 201 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8eb0daa3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref> substituted “Tijuana Rivers, or other streams running across or near the boundary, and for taking emergency actions, consistent with the emergency provisions of the Safe Drinking Water Act, to protect against health threatening surface and ground water pollution problems along the United States-Mexico boundary” for “Tijuana Rivers, and for taking emergency actions to protect against health threatening sanitation problems by repairing or replacing existing capital infrastructure along the United States-Mexico Boundary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—<ref href="/us/pl/101/246">Pub. L. 101–246</ref> inserted “or sanitation” after “flood control” and inserted before period at end “, the Colorado or Tijuana Rivers, and for taking emergency actions to protect against health threatening sanitation problems by repairing or replacing existing capital infrastructure along the United States-Mexico Boundary”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
