<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8eb0dae3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s277d–30"><num value="277d–30">§ 277d–30.</num><heading> Lower Rio Grande drainage conveyance canal projects; agreements with Mexico for construction, operation, and maintenance; division of costs; non-Federal assurances of one-half of Federal costs</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of State, acting through the United States Commissioner, International Boundary and Water Commission, United States and Mexico, is authorized, notwithstanding any other provision of law and subject to the conditions provided in this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s277d–31">section 277d–31 of this title</ref> to conclude an agreement or agreements with the appropriate official or officials of the Government of the United Mexican States for the construction, operation, and maintenance by the United Mexican States under the supervision of the International Boundary and Water Commission, United States and Mexico, of a drainage conveyance canal through Mexican territory for the discharge of waters of El Morillo and other drains in the United Mexican States into the Gulf of Mexico in the manner, and having substantially the characteristics, described in said Commission’s minute numbered 223, dated <date date="1965-11-30">November 30, 1965</date>. The agreement or agreements shall provide that the cost of construction including costs of design and right-of-way and the costs of operation and maintenance, shall be equally divided between the United Mexican States and the United States. Before concluding the agreement or agreements, the Secretary of State shall receive satisfactory assurances from private citizens or a responsible local group that they or it will pay to the United States Treasury one-half of the actual United States costs of such construction, including costs of design and right-of-way, and one-half of the actual costs of operation and maintenance allocated under such agreement or agreements to the United States. Payments to the United States Treasury under this section shall be covered into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8eb0dae4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/584/s1">Pub. L. 89–584, § 1</ref>, <date date="1966-09-19">Sept. 19, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/808">80 Stat. 808</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
