<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8eb0daf0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s277d–33"><num value="277d–33">§ 277d–33.</num><heading> Authorization; construction, operation, and maintenance, appropriations, and acquisition of land</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Pursuant to the agreement concluded under the authority of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s277d–32">section 277d–32 of this title</ref>, the United States Commissioner is authorized to construct, operate, and maintain the portion of the “International Flood Control Project, Tijuana River Basin,” assigned to the United States, and there is hereby authorized to be appropriated to the Department of State for use of the United States section the sum of $10,800,000 for construction costs of such project, as modified, based on estimated June 1976 prices, plus or minus such amounts as may be justified by reason of price index fluctuations in costs involved therein, and such sums as may be necessary for its maintenance and operation, except that no funds may be appropriated under sections 277d–32 and 277d–33 of this title for the fiscal year ending on <date date="1977-09-30">September 30, 1977</date>. Contingent upon the furnishing by the city of San Diego of its appropriate share of the funds for the acquisition of the land and interests therein needed to carry out the agreement between the United States and Mexico to construct such project, the Secretary of State, acting through the United States Commissioner, is further authorized to participate financially with non-Federal interests in the acquisition of said lands and interest therein, to the extent that funds provided by the city of San Diego are insufficient for this purpose.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8eb0daf1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/640/s2">Pub. L. 89–640, § 2</ref>, <date date="1966-10-10">Oct. 10, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/884">80 Stat. 884</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/425">Pub. L. 94–425</ref>, <date date="1976-09-28">Sept. 28, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1333">90 Stat. 1333</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8eb0daf2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8eb0daf3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8eb0daf4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—<ref href="/us/pl/94/425">Pub. L. 94–425</ref> substituted provisions authorizing appropriations of $10,800,000 for construction costs for project based on June 1976 prices, with exception that no funds may be appropriated for fiscal year ending <date date="1977-09-30">Sept. 30, 1977</date> for provisions authorizing appropriations not to exceed $12,600,000 for construction costs for project, eliminated provision requiring approval of title by Attorney General, and inserted provision authorizing financial participation of Secretary of State through Commissioner to acquire land for construction of project contingent upon city of San Diego furnishing its appropriate share of funds.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
