<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8eb34c98-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s277h"><num value="277h">§ 277h.</num><heading> Authority of the International Boundary and Water Commission to assist State and local governments</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8eb34c99-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s277h/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commissioner of the United States section of the International Boundary and Water Commission may provide technical tests, evaluations, information, surveys, or others <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002026">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002026"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “other”.</note> similar services to State or local governments upon the request of such State or local government on a reimbursable basis.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8eb34c9a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s277h/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Reimbursements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Reimbursements shall be paid in advance of the goods or services ordered and shall be for the estimated or actual cost as determined by the United States section of the International Boundary and Water Commission. Proper adjustment of amounts paid in advance shall be made as determined by the United States section of the International Boundary and Water Commission on the basis of the actual cost of goods or services provided. Reimbursements received by the United States section of the International Boundary and Water Commission for providing services under this section shall be credited to the appropriation from which the cost of providing the services is charged.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8eb34c9b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/7/dA/tVII/s702">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(7) [div. A, title VII, § 702]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–459.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
