<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90272788-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1"><num value="2799aa–1">§ 2799aa–1.</num><heading> Nuclear reprocessing transfers, illegal exports for nuclear explosive devices, transfers of nuclear explosive devices, and nuclear detonations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90272789-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibitions on assistance to countries involved in transfer of nuclear reprocessing equipment, materials, or technology; exceptions; procedures applicable</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9027278a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, no funds made available to carry out the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.] or this chapter may be used for the purpose of providing economic assistance (including assistance under chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2346">22 U.S.C. 2346</ref> et seq.]), providing military assistance or grant military education and training, providing assistance under chapter 6 of part II of that Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2348">22 U.S.C. 2348</ref> et seq.], or extending military credits or making guarantees, to any country which the President determines—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9027278b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> delivers nuclear reprocessing equipment, materials, or technology to any other country on or after <date date="1977-08-04">August 4, 1977</date>, or receives such equipment, materials, or technology from any other country on or after <date date="1977-08-04">August 4, 1977</date> (except for the transfer of reprocessing technology associated with the investigation, under international evaluation programs in which the United States participates, of technologies which are alternatives to pure plutonium reprocessing), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9027278c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is a non-nuclear-weapon state which, on or after <date date="1985-08-08">August 8, 1985</date>, exports illegally (or attempts to export illegally) from the United States any material, equipment, or technology which would contribute significantly to the ability of such country to manufacture a nuclear explosive device, if the President determines that the material, equipment, or technology was to be used by such country in the manufacture of a nuclear explosive device.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">For purposes of clause (B), an export (or attempted export) by a person who is an agent of, or is otherwise acting on behalf of or in the interests of, a country shall be considered to be an export (or attempted export) by that country.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9027278d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, the President in any fiscal year may furnish assistance which would otherwise be prohibited under that paragraph if he determines and certifies in writing during that fiscal year to the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate that the termination of such assistance would be seriously prejudicial to the achievement of United States nonproliferation objectives or otherwise jeopardize the common defense and security. The President shall transmit with such certification a statement setting forth the specific reasons therefor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9027278e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9027278f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A certification under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall take effect on the date on which the certification is received by the Congress. However, if, within 30 calendar days after receiving this certification, the Congress enacts a joint resolution stating in substance that the Congress disapproves the furnishing of assistance pursuant to the certification, then upon the enactment of that resolution the certification shall cease to be effective and all deliveries of assistance furnished under the authority of that certification shall be suspended immediately.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id90272790-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any joint resolution under this paragraph shall be considered in the Senate in accordance with the provisions of section 601(b) of the International Security Assistance and Arms Export Control Act of 1976.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90272791-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibitions on assistance to countries involved in transfer or use of nuclear explosive devices; exceptions; procedures applicable</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id90272792-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in paragraphs (4), (5), and (6), in the event that the President determines that any country, after the effective date of part B of the Nuclear Proliferation Prevention Act of 1994—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90272793-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> transfers to a non-nuclear-weapon state a nuclear explosive device,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90272794-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> is a non-nuclear-weapon state and either—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90272795-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> receives a nuclear explosive device, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90272796-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> detonates a nuclear explosive device,</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90272797-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> transfers to a non-nuclear-weapon state any design information or component which is determined by the President to be important to, and known by the transferring country to be intended by the recipient state for use in, the development or manufacture of any nuclear explosive device, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90272798-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> is a non-nuclear-weapon state and seeks and receives any design information or component which is determined by the President to be important to, and intended by the recipient state for use in, the development or manufacture of any nuclear explosive device,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">then the President shall forthwith report in writing his determination to the Congress and shall forthwith impose the sanctions described in paragraph (2) against that country.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id90272799-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The sanctions referred to in paragraph (1) are as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9027279a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The United States Government shall terminate assistance to that country under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">22 U.S.C. 2151</ref> et seq.], except for humanitarian assistance or food or other agricultural commodities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9027279b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> The United States Government shall terminate—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9027279c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> sales to that country under this chapter of any defense articles, defense services, or design and construction services, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9027279d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> licenses for the export to that country of any item on the United States Munitions List.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9027279e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The United States Government shall terminate all foreign military financing for that country under this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9027279f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> The United States Government shall deny to that country any credit, credit guarantees, or other financial assistance by any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government, except that the sanction of this subparagraph shall not apply—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id902727a0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/2/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to any transaction subject to the reporting requirements of title V of the National Security Act of 1947 [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3091">50 U.S.C. 3091</ref> et seq.] (relating to congressional oversight of intelligence activities),</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id902727a1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/2/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to medicines, medical equipment, and humanitarian assistance, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id902727a2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/2/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> to any credit, credit guarantee, or financial assistance provided by the Department of Agriculture to support the purchase of food or other agricultural commodity.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902727a3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> The United States Government shall oppose, in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s262d">section 262d of this title</ref>, the extension of any loan or financial or technical assistance to that country by any international financial institution.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902727a4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> The United States Government shall prohibit any United States bank from making any loan or providing any credit to the government of that country, except for loans or credits for the purpose of purchasing food or other agricultural commodities, which includes fertilizer.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902727a5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> The authorities of section 4605 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002237">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002237"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of title 50 shall be used to prohibit exports to that country of specific goods and technology (excluding food and other agricultural commodities), except that such prohibition shall not apply to any transaction subject to the reporting requirements of title V of the National Security Act of 1947 [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3091">50 U.S.C. 3091</ref> et seq.] (relating to congressional oversight of intelligence activities).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id902727a6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> As used in this subsection—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902727a7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the term “design information” means specific information that relates to the design of a nuclear explosive device and that is not available to the public; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902727a8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the term “component” means a specific component of a nuclear explosive device.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id902727a9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id902727aa-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, the President may, for a period of not more than 30 days of continuous session, delay the imposition of sanctions which would otherwise be required under paragraph (1)(A) or (1)(B) of this subsection if the President first transmits to the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and to the chairman of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, a certification that he has determined that an immediate imposition of sanctions on that country would be detrimental to the national security of the United States. Not more than one such certification may be transmitted for a country with respect to the same detonation, transfer, or receipt of a nuclear explosive device.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id902727ab-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> If the President transmits a certification to the Congress under subparagraph (A), a joint resolution which would permit the President to exercise the waiver authority of paragraph (5) of this subsection shall, if introduced in either House within thirty days of continuous session after the Congress receives this certification, be considered in the Senate in accordance with subparagraph (C) of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id902727ac-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Any joint resolution under this paragraph shall be considered in the Senate in accordance with the provisions of section 601(b) of the International Security Assistance and Arms Export Control Act of 1976.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id902727ad-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> For purposes of this paragraph, the term “joint resolution” means a joint resolution the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: “That the Congress having received on __ a certification by the President under section 102(b)(4) of the Arms Export Control Act with respect to __, the Congress hereby authorizes the President to exercise the waiver authority contained in section 102(b)(5) of that Act.”, with the date of receipt of the certification inserted in the first blank and the name of the country inserted in the second blank.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id902727ae-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, if the Congress enacts a joint resolution under paragraph (4) of this subsection, the President may waive any sanction which would otherwise be required under paragraph (1)(A) or (1)(B) if he determines and certifies in writing to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate that the imposition of such sanction would be seriously prejudicial to the achievement of United States nonproliferation objectives or otherwise jeopardize the common defense and security. The President shall transmit with such certification a statement setting forth the specific reasons therefor.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id902727af-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id902727b0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In the event the President is required to impose sanctions against a country under paragraph (1)(C) or (1)(D), the President shall forthwith so inform such country and shall impose the required sanctions beginning 30 days after submitting to the Congress the report required by paragraph (1) unless, and to the extent that, there is enacted during the 30-day period a law prohibiting the imposition of such sanctions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id902727b1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the sanctions which are required to be imposed against a country under paragraph (1)(C) or (1)(D) shall not apply if the President determines and certifies in writing to the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives that the application of such sanctions against such country would have a serious adverse effect on vital United States interests. The President shall transmit with such certification a statement setting forth the specific reasons therefor.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id902727b2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> For purposes of this subsection, continuity of session is broken only by an adjournment of Congress sine die and the days on which either House is not in session because of an adjournment of more than three days to a day certain are excluded in the computation of any period of time in which Congress is in continuous session.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id902727b3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> The President may not delegate or transfer his power, authority, or discretion to make or modify determinations under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id902727b4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> “Non-nuclear-weapon state” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this section, the term “non-­nuclear-weapon state” means any country which is not a nuclear-weapon state, as defined in Article IX(3) of the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id902727b5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/90/629">Pub. L. 90–629</ref>, ch. 10, § 102, as added <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/tVIII/s826/a">Pub. L. 103–236, title VIII, § 826(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/516">108 Stat. 516</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/105/194/s2/a">Pub. L. 105–194, § 2(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="1998-07-14">July 14, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/627">112 Stat. 627</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/276/tII/s208/a/1">Pub. L. 113–276, title II, § 208(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-18">Dec. 18, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2992">128 Stat. 2992</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id902727b6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id902727b7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id902727b8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1) and (b)(2)(A), is <ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, <date date="1961-09-04">Sept. 4, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/424">75 Stat. 424</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 32 (§ 2151 et seq.) of this title. Chapters 4 and 6 of part II of the Act are classified generally to parts IV (§ 2346 et seq.) and VI (§ 2348 et seq.), respectively, of subchapter II of chapter 32 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">section 2151 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1) and (b)(2)(B)(i), (C), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/90/629">Pub. L. 90–629</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1321">82 Stat. 1321</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 601(b) of the International Security Assistance and Arms Export Control Act of 1976, referred to in subsecs. (a)(3)(B) and (b)(4)(C), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/329/s601/b">section 601(b) of Pub. L. 94–329</ref>, title VI, <date date="1976-06-30">June 30, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/765">90 Stat. 765</ref>, which is not classified to the Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of part B of the Nuclear Proliferation Prevention Act of 1994 [part B of title VIII of <ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref>], referred to in subsec. (b)(1), as 60 days after <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s831">section 831 of Pub. L. 103–236</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6301">section 6301 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Security Act of 1947, referred to in subsec. (b)(2)(D)(i), (G), is <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343">act July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/495">61 Stat. 495</ref>, which was formerly classified principally to chapter 15 (§ 401 et seq.) of Title 50, War and National Defense, prior to editorial reclassification in chapter 44 (§ 3001 et seq.) of Title 50. Title V of the Act is now classified generally to subchapter III (§ 3091 et seq.) of chapter 44 of Title 50. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4605">Section 4605 of title 50</ref>, referred to in subsec. (b)(2)(G), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/115/232/dA/tXVII/s1766/a">Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XVII, § 1766(a)</ref>, <date date="2018-08-13">Aug. 13, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/2232">132 Stat. 2232</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 102 of the Arms Export Control Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(4)(D), is classified to this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id902727b9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/113/276">Pub. L. 113–276</ref> substituted “the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and” for “the Speaker of the House of Representatives and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (b)(2)(D)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/105/194/s2/c">Pub. L. 105–194, § 2(c)</ref>, inserted “medicines, medical equipment, and” after “to”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(D)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/105/194/s2/a">Pub. L. 105–194, § 2(a)</ref>, added cl. (iii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/105/194/s2/b">Pub. L. 105–194, § 2(b)</ref>, inserted “, which includes fertilizer” before period at end.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id902727ba-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id902727bb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Governmental Affairs of Senate changed to Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of Senate, effective <date date="2005-01-04">Jan. 4, 2005</date>, by Senate Resolution No. 445, One Hundred Eighth Congress, Oct. 9. 2004.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id902727bc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/194/s2/d">Pub. L. 105–194, § 2(d)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-14">July 14, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/627">112 Stat. 627</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/194/s2/d">“The amendment made by subsection (a)(3) [amending this section] shall apply to any credit, credit guarantee, or other financial assistance provided by the Department of Agriculture before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-07-14">July 14, 1998</date>] through <date date="1999-09-30">September 30, 1999</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id902727bd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 60 days after <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s831">section 831 of Pub. L. 103–236</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6301">section 6301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id902727be-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Waiver of Certain Sanctions Against North Korea</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/252/tI/s1405">Pub. L. 110–252, title I, § 1405</ref>, <date date="2008-06-30">June 30, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/2337">122 Stat. 2337</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/113/188/tVIII/s801">Pub. L. 113–188, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="2014-11-26">Nov. 26, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2020">128 Stat. 2020</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/235/dJ/tVII/s7034/i">Pub. L. 113–235, div. J, title VII, § 7034(i)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-16">Dec. 16, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2624">128 Stat. 2624</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/235/dJ/tVII/s7034/i">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Waiver Authority.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Except as provided in subsection (b), the President may waive in whole or in part, with respect to North Korea, the application of any sanction contained in subparagraph (A), (B), (D) or (G) under section 102(b)(2) of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b">22 U.S.C. 2799aa–1(b)</ref>[(2)(A), (B), (D), (G)]), for the purpose of providing assistance related to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the implementation and verification of the compliance by North Korea with its commitment, undertaken in the Joint Statement of <date date="2005-09-19">September 19, 2005</date>, to abandon all nuclear weapons and existing nuclear programs as part of the verifiable denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the elimination of the capability of North Korea to develop, deploy, transfer, or maintain weapons of mass destruction and their delivery systems.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority under paragraph (1) shall expire 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2008-06-30">June 30, 2008</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limited exception related to certain sanctions and prohibitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The authority under subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to a sanction or prohibition under subparagraph (B) or (G) of section 102(b)(2) of the Arms Export Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b">22 U.S.C. 2799aa–1(b)</ref> [(2)(B), (G)], unless the President determines and certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> all reasonable steps will be taken to assure that the articles or services exported or otherwise provided will not be used to improve the military capabilities of the armed forces of North Korea; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> such waiver is in the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limited exception related to certain activities</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Unless the President determines and certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that using the authority under subsection (a) is vital to the national security interests of the United States, such authority shall not apply with respect to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> an activity described in subparagraph (A) of section 102(b)(1) of the Arms Export Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/1/A">22 U.S.C. 2799aa–1(b)(1)(A)</ref>] that occurs after <date date="2005-09-19">September 19, 2005</date>, and before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2008-06-30">June 30, 2008</date>];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> an activity described in subparagraph (C) of such section that occurs after <date date="2005-09-19">September 19, 2005</date>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> an activity described in subparagraph (D) of such section that occurs after the date of enactment of this Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception related to certain activities occurring after date of enactment</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority under subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to an activity described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 102(b)(1) of the Arms Export Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/1/A">22 U.S.C. 2799aa–1(b)(1)(A)</ref>, (B)] that occurs after the date of the enactment of this Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limited exception related to lethal weapons</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority under subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to any export of lethal defense articles that would be prevented by the application of section 102(b)(2) of the Arms Export Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/2">22 U.S.C. 2799aa–1(b)(2)</ref>].”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(c) <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate Congressional Committees Defined</inline>.—In this section, the term ‘appropriate congressional committees’ means—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) the Committees on Appropriations, Armed Services, and Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) the Committees on Appropriations, Armed Services, and Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Amendment of <ref href="/us/pl/110/252/s1405">section 1405 of Pub. L. 110–252</ref>, set out above, by <ref href="/us/pl/113/235/dJ/s7034/i">section 7034(i) of div. J of Pub. L. 113–235</ref>, which directed that subsec. (c) of section 1405 be repealed, was not executed to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the prior amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/113/188/s801">section 801 of Pub. L. 113–188</ref>, which struck out subsec. (c) and redesignated subsec. (d) as (c).]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id902727bf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Exemption for Rhinoceros, Tiger, Asian Elephant, and Great Ape Conservation Programs</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/63/tI">Pub. L. 107–63, title I</ref>, <date date="2001-11-05">Nov. 5, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/421">115 Stat. 421</ref>, provided in part: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/63/tI">“That funds made available under this Act [see Tables for classification], <ref href="/us/pl/106/291">Public Law 106–291</ref> [see Tables for classification], and <ref href="/us/pl/106/554">Public Law 106–554</ref> [see Tables for classification] and hereafter in annual appropriations Acts for rhinoceros, tiger, Asian elephant, and great ape conservation programs are exempt from any sanctions imposed against any country under section 102 of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1">22 U.S.C. 2799aa–1</ref>).”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>Similar provisions were contained in the following prior appropriation acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/291/tI">Pub. L. 106–291, title I</ref>, <date date="2000-10-11">Oct. 11, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/927">114 Stat. 927</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/3/tI">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(3) [title I]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1535">113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–141.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id902727c0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Waiver of Certain Sanctions Against India and Pakistan</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/79/tIX/s9001">Pub. L. 106–79, title IX, § 9001</ref>, <date date="1999-10-25">Oct. 25, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1283">113 Stat. 1283</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/107/228/dB/tXIV/s1405/b">Pub. L. 107–228, div. B, title XIV, § 1405(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1458">116 Stat. 1458</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/228/dB/tXIV/s1405/b">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Waiver Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, the President may waive, with respect to India and Pakistan, the application of any sanction contained in section 101 or 102 of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa">22 U.S.C. 2799aa</ref> or <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1">22 U.S.C. 2799aa–1</ref>), section 2(b)(4) of the Export Import Bank Act of 1945 (<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635/b/4">12 U.S.C. 635(b)(4)</ref>), or section 620E(e) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended, (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2375/e">22 U.S.C. 2375(e)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception</inline>.—</heading><content>The authority to waive the application of a sanction or prohibition (or portion thereof) under subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to a sanction or prohibition contained in subparagraph (B), (C), or (G) of section 102(b)(2) of the Arms Export Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/2/B">22 U.S.C. 2799aa–1(b)(2)(B)</ref>, (C), (G)], unless the President determines, and so certifies to the Congress, that the application of the restriction would not be in the national security interests of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination of Waiver</inline>.—</heading><content>The President may not exercise the authority of subsection (a), and any waiver previously issued under subsection (a) shall cease to apply, with respect to India or Pakistan, if that country detonates a nuclear explosive device after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1999-10-25">Oct. 25, 1999</date>] or otherwise takes such action which would cause the President to report pursuant to section 102(b)(1) of the Arms Export Control Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2799aa–1/b/1">22 U.S.C. 2799aa–1(b)(1)</ref>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Targeted Sanctions.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sense of the congress.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> it is the sense of the Congress that the broad application of export controls to nearly 300 Indian and Pakistani entities is inconsistent with the specific national security interests of the United States and that this control list requires refinement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> export controls should be applied only to those Indian and Pakistani entities that make direct and material contributions to weapons of mass destruction and missile programs and only to those items that can contribute to such programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reporting requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1999-10-25">Oct. 25, 1999</date>], the President shall submit both a classified and unclassified report to the appropriate congressional committees listing those Indian and Pakistani entities whose activities contribute to missile programs or weapons of mass destruction programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Congressional Notification</inline>.—</heading><content>The issuance of a license for export of a defense article, defense service, or technology under the authority of this section shall be subject to the same requirements as are applicable to the export of items described in section 36(c) of the Arms Export Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2776/c">22 U.S.C. 2776(c)</ref>), including the transmittal of information and the application of congressional review procedures. The application of these requirements shall be subject to the dollar amount thresholds specified in that section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Repeal</inline>.—</heading><note topic="miscellaneous" id="id902727c1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<p>[Repealed section 101(a) [title IX] of div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref>, formerly set out below.]”</p></note>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id902727c2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">India-Pakistan Relief</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dA/s101/a/tIX">Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(a) [title IX]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681">112 Stat. 2681</ref>, 2681–40, known as the India-Pakistan Relief Act, provided for a one-year waiver of certain sanctions against India and Pakistan under the Arms Export Control Act, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/106/79/tIX/s9001/f">Pub. L. 106–79, title IX, § 9001(f)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-25">Oct. 25, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1284">113 Stat. 1284</ref>, effective <date date="1999-10-21">Oct. 21, 1999</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id902727c3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effect on Existing Sanctions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/194/s2/e">Pub. L. 105–194, § 2(e)</ref>, <date date="1998-07-14">July 14, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/627">112 Stat. 627</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/194/s2/e">“Any sanction imposed under section 102(b)(1) of the Arms Export Control Act [subsec. (b)(1) of this section] before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-07-14">July 14, 1998</date>] shall cease to apply upon that date with respect to the items described in the amendments made by subsections (b) and (c) [amending this section]. In the case of the amendment made by subsection (a)(3) [amending this section], any sanction imposed under section 102(b)(1) of the Arms Export Control Act before the date of the enactment of this Act shall not be in effect during the period beginning on that date and ending on <date date="1999-09-30">September 30, 1999</date>, with respect to the activities and items described in the amendment.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id902998c4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id902998c5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of President under subsec. (a)(2) of this section delegated to Secretary of State by section 1(a)(iii) of Ex. Ord. No. 13346, <date date="2004-07-08">July 8, 2004</date>, 69 F.R. 41905, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of Title 3</ref>, The President.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id902998c6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Sanctions Against India for Detonation of a Nuclear Explosive Device</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Determination of President of the United States, No. 98–22, <date date="1998-05-13">May 13, 1998</date>, 63 F.R. 27665, provided a determination that India, a non-nuclear-weapon state, detonated a nuclear explosive device on <date date="1998-05-11">May 11, 1998</date>, and imposed sanctions described in subsec. (b)(2) of this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id902998c7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Sanctions Against Pakistan for Detonation of a Nuclear Explosive Device</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Determination of President of the United States, No. 98–25, <date date="1998-05-30">May 30, 1998</date>, 63 F.R. 31881, provided a determination that Pakistan, a non-nuclear-weapon state, detonated a nuclear explosive device on <date date="1998-05-28">May 28, 1998</date>, and imposed sanctions described in subsec. (b)(2) of this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id902998c8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Waiver of Certain Sanctions Against India and Pakistan</heading>
<p>Provisions relating to waiver of sanctions against India and Pakistan consistent with <ref href="/us/pl/106/79/s9001">section 9001 of Pub. L. 106–79</ref>, set out as a note above, or section 101(a) [title IX, § 902] of <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref>, formerly set out in a note above, were contained in the following:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Determination of President of the United States, No. 2001–28, <date date="2001-09-22">Sept. 22, 2001</date>, 66 F.R. 50095.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Determination of President of the United States, No. 2001–23, <date date="2001-08-09">Aug. 9, 2001</date>, 66 F.R. 44521.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Determination of President of the United States, No. 2001–11, <date date="2001-01-19">Jan. 19, 2001</date>, 66 F.R. 8503.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Determination of President of the United States, No. 2000–18, <date date="2000-03-16">Mar. 16, 2000</date>, 65 F.R. 16297.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Determination of President of the United States, No. 2000–4, <date date="1999-10-27">Oct. 27, 1999</date>, 64 F.R. 60649.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Determination of President of the United States, No. 99–7, <date date="1998-12-01">Dec. 1, 1998</date>, 34 Weekly Compilation of Presidential Documents 2402, <date date="1998-12-07">Dec. 7, 1998</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
