<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id902998d0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2801"><num value="2801">§ 2801.</num><heading> Congressional findings</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902998d1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2801/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> international expositions, when properly organized, financed, and executed, have a significant impact on the economic growth of the region surrounding the exposition and, under appropriate international sanction, are important instruments of national policy, particularly in the exchange of ideas and the demonstration of cultural achievements between peoples;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902998d2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2801/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> in view of the widely varying circumstances under which international expositions have developed in the United States, the different degrees to which the Federal Government has assisted and participated in such expositions, and the increasing number of proposals for future expositions, the national interest requires that Federal action concerning such expositions be given orderly consideration; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902998d3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2801/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> such orderly consideration is best achieved by the development of uniform standards, criteria, and procedures to establish the conditions under which the Government hereafter will (A) recognize international expositions proposed to be held in the United States, and (B) take part in such expositions.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id902998d4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/269/s1">Pub. L. 91–269, § 1</ref>, <date date="1970-05-27">May 27, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/271">84 Stat. 271</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
