<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id902998d5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2802"><num value="2802">§ 2802.</num><heading> Federal recognition</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id902998d6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2802/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any international exposition proposed to be held in the United States shall be eligible on application from its sponsors to receive the recognition of the Federal Government upon a finding of the President that recognition will be in the national interest. In making such a finding the President shall consider—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902998d7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2802/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a report by the Secretary of Commerce which shall include (A) an evaluation of purposes and reasons for the exposition, and (B) a determination that guaranteed financial and other support has been secured by the exposition from affected State and local governments and from business and civic leadership of the region and others in amounts sufficient in his judgment to assure the successful development and progress of the exposition;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902998d8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2802/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a report by the Secretary of State that the proposed exposition qualifies for consideration of registration by the Bureau of International Expositions (hereafter referred to as BIE); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902998d9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2802/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> such other evidence as the President may consider to be appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id902998da-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2802/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Recognition and registration procedure; compliance with international convention; participation by States and foreign governments</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon a finding by the President that an international exposition is eligible for Federal recognition, the President may take such measures recognizing the exposition as he deems proper, including, but not limited to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902998db-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2802/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> presenting of an official request by the United States for registration of the exposition by the BIE;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902998dc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2802/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> providing for fulfillment of the requirements of the Convention of <date date="1928-11-22">November 22, 1928</date>, as amended, relating to international expositions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902998dd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2802/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> extending invitations, by proclamation or by such other manner he deems proper, to the several States of the Union and to foreign governments to take part in the exposition, provided that he shall not extend such an invitation until he has been notified officially of BIE registration for the exposition.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id902998de-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2802/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall report his actions under this section promptly to the Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id902998df-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/269/s2">Pub. L. 91–269, § 2</ref>, <date date="1970-05-27">May 27, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/271">84 Stat. 271</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
