<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id902998e0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2803"><num value="2803">§ 2803.</num><heading> Federal participation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id902998e1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2803/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Congressional authorization; proposals</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Federal Government may participate in an international exposition proposed to be held in the United States only upon the authorization of the Congress. If the President finds that Federal participation is in the national interest, he shall transmit to the Congress his proposal for such participation, which proposal shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902998e2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2803/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> evidence that the international exposition has met the criteria for Federal recognition and, pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2802">section 2802 of this title</ref>, it has been so recognized;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902998e3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2803/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a statement that the international exposition has been registered by the BIE; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902998e4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2803/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a plan prepared by the Secretary of Commerce in cooperation with other interested departments and agencies of the Federal Government for Federal participation in the exposition. The Secretary of Commerce shall include in such plan any documentation described in subsection (b)(1)(A) of this section, a rendering of any design described in subsection (b)(1)(B) of this section, and any recommendation based on the determination under subsection (b)(1)(C) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id902998e5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2803/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Construction of Federal pavilion</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id902998e6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2803/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In developing a plan under subsection (a)(3) of this section the Secretary of Commerce shall consider whether the plan should include the construction of a Federal pavilion. If the Secretary of Commerce determines that a Federal pavilion should be constructed, he shall request the Administrator of General Services (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Administrator”) to determine, in consultation with such Secretary, whether there is a federally endorsed need for a permanent structure in the area of the exposition. If the Administrator determines that any such need exists—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902998e7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2803/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Administrator shall fully document such determination, including the identification of the need, and shall transmit such documentation to the Secretary of Commerce;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902998e8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2803/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Administrator, shall design a pavilion which satisfies the federally endorsed needs for—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id902998e9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2803/b/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> participation in the exposition; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id902998ea-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2803/b/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> permanent use of such pavilion after the termination of participation in the exposition; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902998eb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2803/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the Secretary of Commerce shall determine whether the Federal Government should be deeded a satisfactory site for the Federal pavilion in fee simple, free of all liens and encumbrances, as a condition of participation in the exposition.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id902998ec-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2803/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Notwithstanding paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection, if the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Administrator determines that no design of a Federal pavilion will satisfy both needs described in paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection, the Secretary shall design a temporary Federal pavilion.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id902998ed-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2803/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations for Federal pavilion</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The enactment of a specific authorization of appropriations shall be required—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902998ee-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2803/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to construct a Federal pavilion in accordance with the plan prepared pursuant to subsection (a)(3) of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902998ef-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2803/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> if the Federal pavilion is not temporary, to modify such Federal pavilion after termination of participation in the exposition if modification is necessary to adapt such pavilion for use by the Federal Government to satisfy a need described in subsection (b)(1)(B)(ii) of this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902998f0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2803/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> if the Federal pavilion is temporary, to dismantle, demolish, or otherwise dispose of such Federal pavilion after termination of Federal participation in the exposition.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id902998f1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2803/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Requisites and temporary nature of Federal pavilion</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902998f2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2803/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a Federal pavilion shall be considered to satisfy both needs described in subsection (b)(1)(B) of this section if the Federal pavilion which satisfies the needs described in paragraph (1)(B)(i) of such subsection can be modified after completion of the exposition to satisfy the needs described in paragraph (1)(B)(ii) of such subsection, provided that such modification shall cost no more than the expense of demolition, dismantling, or other disposal, or if the cost is higher, it shall be no more than 50 per centum of the original cost of the construction of the pavilion; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902998f3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2803/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a Federal pavilion is temporary if the Federal pavilion is designed to satisfy the minimum needs of the Federal Government described in subsection (b)(1)(B)(i) of this section and is intended for disposal by the Federal Government after the termination of participation in the exposition.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id902998f4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/269/s3">Pub. L. 91–269, § 3</ref>, <date date="1970-05-27">May 27, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/272">84 Stat. 272</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/254/s16/a">Pub. L. 97–254, § 16(a)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-08">Sept. 8, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/812">96 Stat. 812</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id902998f5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id902998f6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id902998f7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/254/s16/a/1">Pub. L. 97–254, § 16(a)(1)</ref>–(3), designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), redesignated cls. (a) to (c) thereof as cls. (1) to (3) respectively, and in cl. (3) as so redesignated, substituted provisions requiring the Secretary of Commerce to include in a plan under this section any documentation, designs, or recommendations described in subsec. (b) of this section for provisions that the Secretary in developing a plan should consider whether there was a need for the construction of a Federal pavilion, and if so, that there could be included in the plan a recommendation that Government participation in the exposition be conditioned on its being deeded a satisfactory site for the pavilion and that the Secretary would seek the advice of the Administrator of the General Services Administration in carrying out the provisions of former subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b) to (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/254/s16/a/4">Pub. L. 97–254, § 16(a)(4)</ref>, added subsecs. (b) to (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id902998f8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id902998f9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/254">Pub. L. 97–254</ref> effective <date date="1982-09-08">Sept. 8, 1982</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/254/s15">Pub. L. 97–254, § 15</ref>, <date date="1982-09-18">Sept. 18, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/812">96 Stat. 812</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
