<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8eb595e7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s280c"><num value="280c">§ 280c.</num><heading> Employment of personnel with specialized skills</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized, when the Commission is desirous of obtaining the services of a person having special scientific or other technical or professional qualifications, from time to time to detail, or authorize the detail of, for temporary service to or in cooperation with the Commission, any person in the employ or service of the Government of the United States who has such qualifications, with the approval of the Government agency in which such person is employed or serving, under the same conditions as those governing the detail of officers and employees of the United States Government to the government of another country in accordance with the provisions of the Act of <date date="1938-05-25">May 25, 1938</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/52/442">52 Stat. 442</ref>), as amended, except that the authority vested in the President under that Act shall be vested in the Secretary for the purpose of carrying out this section.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8eb595e8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1948-01-28/ch38/s4">Jan. 28, 1948, ch. 38, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/16">62 Stat. 16</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8eb595e9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8eb595ea-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8eb595eb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1938-05-25">May 25, 1938</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/52/442">52 Stat. 442</ref>), as amended, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1938-05-25/ch277">act May 25, 1938, ch. 277</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/442">52 Stat. 442</ref>, which was classified to section 118e of former title 5, Executive Departments and Government Officers and Employees, and was repealed by <ref href="/us/act/1948-01-26/ch36/s1004/a">act Jan. 26, 1948, ch. 36, § 1004(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/13">62 Stat. 13</ref>. Section 1004(c) of act <date date="1948-01-26">Jan. 26, 1948</date>, provided that any reference to provisions of act <date date="1938-05-25">May 25, 1938</date> shall be construed to be applicable to the appropriate provisions of titles III and IX of act <date date="1948-01-26">Jan. 26, 1948</date> [see sections 1451 et seq., 1478 and 1479 of this title].</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
