<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8eba519b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s283gg"><num value="283gg">§ 283gg.</num><heading> Jurisdiction of United States courts</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of any civil action which may be brought within the United States, its territories or possessions, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, by or against the Corporation in accordance with the agreement, the Corporation shall be deemed to be an inhabitant of the Federal judicial district in which its principal office within the United States or its agent appointed for the purpose of accepting service or notice of service is located, and any such action to which the Corporation shall be a party shall be deemed to arise under the laws of the United States, and the district courts of the United States, including the courts enumerated in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s460">section 460 of title 28</ref>, shall have original jurisdiction of any such action. When the Corporation is a defendant in any action in a State court, it may at any time before the trial thereof remove the action into the appropriate district court of the United States by following the procedure for removal provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1446">section 1446 of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8eba519c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/473/tI/s101/1/tI">Pub. L. 98–473, title I, § 101(1) [title I]</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1884">98 Stat. 1884</ref>, 1885.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8eba519d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8eba519e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8eba519f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is based on section 208 of title II of S. 2416, Ninety-eighth Congress, as introduced <date date="1984-03-13">Mar. 13, 1984</date>, and enacted into law by <ref href="/us/pl/98/473">Pub. L. 98–473</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
