<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8eba5142-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s283z–7"><num value="283z–7">§ 283z–7.</num><heading> Limitations on policy based lending</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8eba5143-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s283z–7/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> take all necessary steps to encourage the Bank to limit the aggregate value of the policy based loans made by the Bank (other than policy based loans made to any country which the Bank has determined is economically less developed or has a limited market economy, which are used to purchase sovereign debt of such country or to reduce the debt or debt service burden of such country) during the 4-year period beginning on <date date="1990-01-01">January 1, 1990</date>, to 25 percent of the aggregate value of all loans made by the Bank during such 4-year period;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8eba5144-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s283z–7/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> take all necessary steps to encourage the Bank to limit the aggregate value of the policy based loans made by the Bank to the government of a particular country during such 4-year period, to 50 percent of the aggregate value of all loans made by the Bank to such government during such 4-year period;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8eba5145-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s283z–7/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> instruct the United States Executive Director of the Bank to explore with the other Executive Directors of the Bank ways to use a portion of the resources made available to the Bank by reason of the subscription and contribution described in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s283z–5/a/2">section 283z–5(a)(2) of this title</ref> for debt reduction and debt service reduction for countries described in paragraph (1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8eba5146-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s283z–7/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> before the end of the 12-month period beginning on <date date="1989-12-19">December 19, 1989</date>, report to the Congress on the matters described in paragraph (3).</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id8eba5147-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/86/147/s35">Pub. L. 86–147, § 35</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/101/240/tII/s203">Pub. L. 101–240, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2498">103 Stat. 2498</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
