<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8ebcc261-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s285c"><num value="285c">§ 285c.</num><heading> Congressional authorization needed for certain actions</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Unless the Congress by law authorizes such action, neither the President nor any person or agency shall, on behalf of the United States, (a) subscribe to additional shares of stock of the Bank; (b) vote for or agree to any amendment of the agreement which increases the obligations of the United States, or which would change the purpose or functions of the Bank; or (c) make a loan or provide other financing to the Bank, except that funds for technical assistance note to exceed $1,000,000 in any one year may be provided to the Bank by a United States agency created pursuant to an Act of Congress which is authorized by law to provide funds to international organizations.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8ebcc262-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/369/s5">Pub. L. 89–369, § 5</ref>, <date date="1966-03-16">Mar. 16, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/72">80 Stat. 72</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8ebcc263-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8ebcc264-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8ebcc265-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Subsequent Replenishments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/118/tV/s560/a">Pub. L. 105–118, title V, § 560(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-26">Nov. 26, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2425">111 Stat. 2425</ref>, provided in part that the Secretary of the Treasury may contribute on behalf of the United States to the sixth replenishment of the resources of the Asian Development Fund, subject to obtaining the necessary appropriations, and authorized $400,000,000 to be appropriated without fiscal year limitation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/87/tV/s526">Pub. L. 103–87, title V, § 526</ref>, <date date="1993-09-30">Sept. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/952">107 Stat. 952</ref>, provided in part that the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to agree on behalf of the United States to participate in the fifth replenishment of the Asian Development Fund, subject to obtaining the necessary appropriations.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
