<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8ebf331d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286a"><num value="286a">§ 286a.</num><heading> Appointments</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ebf331e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Governors and executive directors; term of office</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall appoint a governor of the Fund who shall also serve as a governor of the Bank, and an executive director of the Fund and an executive director of the Bank. The executive directors so appointed shall also serve as provisional executive directors of the Fund and the Bank for the purposes of the respective Articles of Agreement. The term of office for the governor of the Fund and of the Bank shall be five years. The term of office for the executive directors shall be two years, but the executive directors shall remain in office until their successors have been appointed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ebf331f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Alternates; term of office</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall appoint an alternate for the governor of the Fund and an alternate for the governor of the Bank. The President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall appoint an alternate for each of the executive directors. The alternate for each executive director shall be appointed from among individuals recommended to the President by the executive director. The terms of office for alternates for the governor and the executive directors shall be the same as the terms specified in subsection (a) for the governor and executive directors.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ebf3320-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Governor to serve as councillor; alternates and associates</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Should the provisions of Schedule D of the Articles of Agreement of the Fund apply, the Governor of the Fund shall also serve as councillor, shall designate an alternate for the councillor, and may designate associates.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ebf3321-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation for services</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8ebf3322-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286a/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> No person shall be entitled to receive any salary or other compensation from the United States for services as a Governor, executive director, councillor, alternate, or associate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8ebf3323-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286a/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The United States executive director of the Fund shall not be compensated by the Fund at a rate in excess of the rate provided for an individual occupying a position at level IV of the Executive Schedule under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5315">section 5315 of title 5</ref>. The United States alternate executive director of the Fund shall not be compensated by the Fund at a rate in excess of the rate provided for an individual occupying a position at level V of the Executive Schedule under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5316">section 5316 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8ebf3324-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286a/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States executive director of the Fund to present to the Fund’s Executive Board a comprehensive set of proposals, consistent with maintaining high levels of competence of Fund personnel and consistent with the Articles of Agreement, with the objective of assuring that salaries and other compensation accorded Fund employees do not exceed those received by persons filling similar levels of responsibility within national government service or private industry. The Secretary shall report these proposals together with any measures adopted by the Fund’s Executive Board to the Congress prior to <date date="1979-02-01">February 1, 1979</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8ebf3325-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1945-07-31/ch339/s3">July 31, 1945, ch. 339, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/59/512">59 Stat. 512</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/94">Pub. L. 93–94</ref>, <date date="1973-08-15">Aug. 15, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/314">87 Stat. 314</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/564/s2">Pub. L. 94–564, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-10-19">Oct. 19, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2660">90 Stat. 2660</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/435/s2">Pub. L. 95–435, § 2</ref>, <date date="1978-10-10">Oct. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1051">92 Stat. 1051</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8ebf3326-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8ebf3327-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8ebf3328-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/435">Pub. L. 95–435</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added pars. (2) and (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/94/564/s2/1">Pub. L. 94–564, § 2(1)</ref>, amended subsec. (c) generally to provide that the Governor serve as councillor and designate an alternate and associates. Former provisions relating to compensation were included in subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/94/564/s2/2">Pub. L. 94–564, § 2(2)</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/93/94">Pub. L. 93–94</ref> substituted “and an alternate for the governor of the Bank” for “who shall also serve as alternate for the governor of the Bank”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8ebf3329-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id8ebf332a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/94/564/s9">Pub. L. 94–564, § 9</ref>, <date date="1976-10-19">Oct. 19, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2661">90 Stat. 2661</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/94/564/s9">“The amendments made by sections 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, and 7 of this Act [amending this section, sections 286c, 286e–2, 286<i>o</i>, 286q, and 286r of this title, and section 822a of former Title 31, Money and Finance] shall become effective upon the entry into force of the amendments to the Articles of Agreement of the International Monetary Fund approved in Resolution Numbered 31–4 of the Board of Governors of the Fund.”</quotedContent>
 Such amendments entered into force <date date="1978-04-01">Apr. 1, 1978</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8ebf332b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Levels of Fund Salaries and Minimization of Travel Costs</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/389/s9">Pub. L. 96–389, § 9</ref>, <date date="1980-10-07">Oct. 7, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1554">94 Stat. 1554</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/389/s9">“The United States Executive Director to the Fund shall seek to insure (a) that Fund salaries do not exceed those levels endorsed by the Fund Bank Joint Committee on Staff Compensation Issues; and (b) that travel costs are minimized by limiting first class and supersonic travel to instances where no reasonable alternative exists.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
