<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8ebf332c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286b"><num value="286b">§ 286b.</num><heading> National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Problems</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ebf332d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286b/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment and composition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to coordinate the policies and operations of the representatives of the United States on the Fund and the Bank and of all agencies of the Government which make or participate in making foreign loans or which engage in foreign financial, exchange or monetary transactions, there is hereby established the National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Problems (hereinafter referred to as the “Council”), consisting of the Secretary of the Treasury, as Chairman, the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Commerce, the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the President of the Export-Import Bank of the United States, and during such period as the Foreign Operations Administration shall continue to exist, the Director of the Foreign Operations Administration.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ebf332e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286b/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties and functions; reports by Council</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8ebf332f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286b/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Council, after consultation with the representatives of the United States on the Fund and the Bank, shall recommend to the President general policy directives for the guidance of the representatives of the United States on the Fund and the Bank.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8ebf3330-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286b/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Council shall advise and consult with the President and the representatives of the United States on the Fund and the Bank on major problems arising in the administration of the Fund and the Bank.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8ebf3331-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286b/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Council shall coordinate, by consultation or otherwise, so far as is practicable, the policies and operations of the representatives of the United States on the Fund and the Bank, the Export-Import Bank of the United States and all other agencies of the Government to the extent that they make or participate in the making of foreign loans or engage in foreign financial, exchange or monetary transactions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8ebf3332-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286b/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Whenever, under the Articles of Agreement of the Fund or the Articles of Agreement of the Bank, the approval, consent or agreement of the United States is required before an act may be done by the respective institutions, the decision as to whether such approval, consent, or agreement, shall be given or refused shall (to the extent such decision is not prohibited by <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s286c">section 286c of this title</ref>) be made by the Council, under the general direction of the President. No governor, executive director, or alternate representing the United States shall vote in favor of any waiver of condition under article V, section 4, or in favor of any declaration of the United States dollar as a scarce currency under article VII, section 3, of the Articles of Agreement of the Fund, without prior approval of the Council.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8ebf3333-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286b/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The Council shall make such reports and recommendations to the President as he may from time to time request, or as the Council may consider necessary to more effectively or efficiently accomplish the purposes of this subchapter or the purposes for which the Council is created.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8ebf3334-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286b/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> The general policy objectives for the guidance of the United States Executive Director of the Bank shall take into account the effect that development assistance loans have upon individual industry sectors and international commodity markets—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ebf3335-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286b/b/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to minimize projected adverse impacts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ebf3336-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286b/b/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to avoid, wherever possible, government subsidization of production and exports of international commodities without regard to economic conditions in the markets for such commodities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ebf3337-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286b/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports to Council</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The representatives of the United States on the Fund and the Bank, and the Export-Import Bank of the United States (and all other agencies of the Government to the extent that they make or participate in the making of foreign loans or engage in foreign financial, exchange or monetary transactions) shall keep the Council fully informed of their activities and shall provide the Council with such further information or data in their possession as the Council may deem necessary to the appropriate discharge of its responsibilities under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8ebf3338-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1945-07-31/ch339/s4">July 31, 1945, ch. 339, § 4</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/59/512">59 Stat. 512</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1948-04-03/ch169">Apr. 3, 1948, ch. 169</ref>, title I, § 106, <ref href="/us/stat/62/141">62 Stat. 141</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1951-10-10/ch479">Oct. 10, 1951, ch. 479</ref>, title V, § 501(e)(2), <ref href="/us/stat/65/378">65 Stat. 378</ref>; 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 5, eff. <date date="1953-06-30">June 30, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 3741, <ref href="/us/stat/67/637">67 Stat. 637</ref>; 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 7, eff. <date date="1953-08-01">Aug. 1, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 4541, <ref href="/us/stat/67/639">67 Stat. 639</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-09/ch660/s2">Aug. 9, 1954, ch. 660, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/678">68 Stat. 678</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/126/s1/1">Pub. L. 89–126, § 1(1)</ref>, <date date="1965-08-14">Aug. 14, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/519">79 Stat. 519</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/267/s1/a">Pub. L. 90–267, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1968-03-13">Mar. 13, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/47">82 Stat. 47</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/tI">Pub. L. 98–181, title I</ref> [title VIII, § 808(a)], <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1273">97 Stat. 1273</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/240/tV/s541/d/1">Pub. L. 101–240, title V, § 541(d)(1)</ref>, (f)(1), <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2518">103 Stat. 2518</ref>, 2519.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8ebf3339-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8ebf333a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8ebf333b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/101/240">Pub. L. 101–240</ref> redesignated pars. (7) and (8) as (5) and (6), respectively, and struck out former pars. (5) and (6) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(5) The Council shall transmit to the President and to the Congress an annual report with respect to the participation of the United States in the Fund and Bank.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(6) Each such report shall contain such data concerning the operations and policies of the Fund and Bank, such recommendations concerning the Fund and Bank, and such other data and material as the Council may deem appropriate.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/98/181">Pub. L. 98–181</ref> added par. (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/89/126">Pub. L. 89–126</ref> substituted provisions requiring an annual report, for provisions which required the Council to report from time to time, but not less frequently than every six months.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/89/126">Pub. L. 89–126</ref> struck out provisions which required special reports on operations and policies of the Fund and Bank and prescribed contents of such reports, and inserted provisions requiring the annual report to contain such data concerning the operations and policies of the Fund and Bank, such recommendations concerning the Fund and the Bank, and such other data and material as deemed appropriate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1954—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1954-08-09">Aug. 9, 1954</date>, provided membership on Council for President of the Export-Import Bank of Washington.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1951—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1951-10-10">Oct. 10, 1951</date>, substituted “Mutual Security Agency” for “Economic Cooperation Administration”, and “Director for Mutual Security” for “Administrator for Economic Cooperation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1948—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/act/1948-04-03/ch169/tI/s106">Act Apr. 3, 1948, ch. 169, title I, § 106</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/141">62 Stat. 141</ref>, added Administrator for Economic Cooperation, during existence of the Administration, to membership of National Advisory Council.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8ec17d2c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id8ec17d2d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Export-Import Bank of Washington” changed in text to “Export-Import Bank of the United States” to conform to such change in name in the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945, section 635 et seq. of Title 12, Banks and Banking, provided for in <ref href="/us/pl/90/267/s1/a">section 1(a) of Pub. L. 90–267</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id8ec17d2e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1954 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by act <date date="1954-08-09">Aug. 9, 1954</date>, effective upon initial appointment of President, First Vice President, and one member of the Board of Directors of the Export-Import Bank of Washington, see section 4 of act <date date="1954-08-09">Aug. 9, 1954</date>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s635a">section 635a of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="repeals" id="id8ec17d2f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Repeals</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act <date date="1948-04-03">Apr. 3, 1948</date>, cited as a credit to this section, was repealed by <ref href="/us/act/1952-06-20/ch449/s7/c">act June 20, 1952, ch. 449, § 7(c)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/144">66 Stat. 144</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id8ec17d30-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id8ec17d31-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Problems abolished and its functions, together with functions of its chairman and other officers, transferred to President by sections 1(b) and 3(a) of Reorg. Plan No. 4 of 1965, eff. <date date="1965-07-27">July 27, 1965</date>, 30 F.R. 9353, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1321">79 Stat. 1321</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Function of Chairman of Board of Directors of Export-Import Bank of Washington of being a member of National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Problems abolished by Reorg. Plan No. 5 of 1953, eff. <date date="1953-06-30">June 30, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 3741, <ref href="/us/stat/67/637">67 Stat. 637</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Foreign Operations Administration abolished by Ex. Ord. No. 10610, <date date="1955-05-09">May 9, 1955</date>, 20 F.R. 3179, and its functions and offices transferred to Department of State to be administered by International Cooperation Administration. For later transfer, see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2381">section 2381 of this title</ref>, and notes set out under that section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Office of Director for Mutual Security abolished and functions of Director transferred to Director of Foreign Operations Administration by Reorg. Plan No. 7 of 1953, eff. <date date="1953-08-01">Aug. 1, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 4541. Section 4 of said Reorg. Plan No. 7 of 1953, specifically provided that Director of Foreign Operations Administration shall be a member of National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Problems.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id8ec17d32-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 11269. National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Policies</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 11269, <date date="1966-02-14">Feb. 14, 1966</date>, 31 F.R. 2813, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 11334, <date date="1967-03-07">Mar. 7, 1967</date>, 32 F.R. 3933; Ex. Ord. No. 11808, <date date="1974-09-30">Sept. 30, 1974</date>, 39 F.R. 35563; Ex. Ord. No. 11977, <date date="1977-03-14">Mar. 14, 1977</date>, 42 F.R. 14671; Ex. Ord. No. 12164, <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 56681; Ex. Ord. No. 12188, <date date="1980-01-02">Jan. 2, 1980</date>, 45 F.R. 989; Ex. Ord. No. 12403, <date date="1983-02-08">Feb. 8, 1983</date>, 48 F.R. 6087; Ex. Ord. No. 12567, <date date="1986-10-02">Oct. 2, 1986</date>, 51 F.R. 35495; Ex. Ord. No. 12647, <date date="1988-08-02">Aug. 2, 1988</date>, 53 F.R. 29323; Ex. Ord. No. 12766, <date date="1991-06-18">June 18, 1991</date>, 56 F.R. 28463; Ex. Ord. No. 13118, § 10(9), <date date="1999-03-31">Mar. 31, 1999</date>, 64 F.R. 16598, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By virtue of the authority vested in me by Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1965 (30 F.R. 9353) [set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees], and as President of the United States, it is ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Establishment of Council</i>. (a) There is hereby established the National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Policies, hereinafter referred to as the Council.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Council shall be composed of the following members: the Secretary of the Treasury, who shall be the chairman of the Council, the Assistant to the President for Economic Affairs, who shall be Deputy Chairman of the Council, the Secretary of State, the United States Trade Representative, the Secretary of Commerce, the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, and the President of the Export-Import Bank of Washington [now the Export-Import Bank of the United States].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) Whenever matters within the jurisdiction of the Council may be of interest to Federal agencies not represented on the Council under Section 1(b) of this order, the Chairman of the Council may consult with such agencies and may invite them to designate representatives to participate in meetings and deliberations of the Council.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. <i>Functions of the Council</i>. (a) Exclusive of the functions delegated by the provisions of Section 3, below, and subject to the limitations contained in subsection (b) of this Section, all of the functions which are now vested in the President in consequence of their transfer to him effected by the provisions of Section 1(b) of Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1965 are hereby delegated to the Council.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The functions under Sections 4(a) and 4(b)(3) of the Bretton Woods Agreements Act, including those made applicable to the International Finance Corporation, the Inter-American Development Bank, and the International Development Association (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s286b/a">22 U.S.C. 286b(a)</ref> and (b)(3); 282b; 283b; 284b), to the extent that such functions consist of coordination of policies, are hereby delegated to the Council. The functions so delegated shall be deemed to include the authority to review proposed individual loan, financial, exchange, or monetary transactions to the extent necessary or desirable to effectuate the coordination of policies.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The Council shall perform with respect to the Asian Development Bank, African Development Fund,, [sic] African Development Bank, Inter-American Investment Corporation, Multilateral Investment Guarantee Agency, and European Bank for Reconstruction and Development, the same functions as those delegated to it by subsections (a) and (b) of this section with respect to other international financial institutions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. <i>Functions of the Secretary of the Treasury</i>. (a) Functions which are now vested in the President in consequence of their transfer to him effected by the provisions of Section 1(b) of Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1965 are hereby delegated to the Secretary of the Treasury to the extent of the following:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(1) Authority, subject to the provisions of Section 7 of this Order, to instruct representatives of the United States to international financial organizations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(2) Authority provided for in Section 4(b)(4) of the Bretton Woods Agreements Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s286b/b/4">22 U.S.C. 286b(b)(4)</ref>). Such authority, insofar as it relates to the development aspects of the policies, programs, or projects of the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development shall be exercised subject to the provisions of Section 7 of this Order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) In carrying out the functions delegated to him by subsection (a) of this Section the Secretary shall consult with the Council.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) Nothing in this order shall be deemed to derogate from the responsibilities of the Secretary of State with respect to the foreign policy of the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The Secretary of the Treasury shall perform, with respect to the Asian Development Bank, African Development Fund,, [sic] African Development Bank, Inter-American Investment Corporation, Multilateral Investment Guarantee Agency, and European Bank for Reconstruction and Development, the same functions as those delegated to him by subsections (a) and (b) of this section with respect to other international financial institutions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) The Secretary of the Treasury is hereby delegated the functions conferred upon the President by Section 203(b) and <ref href="/us/act/1976-05-31/s207">Section 207 of the Act of May 31, 1976</ref> (<ref href="/us/stat/90/593">90 Stat. 593</ref> and 594, <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s290g–1">22 U.S.C. 290g–1</ref> and 290g–5), subject to the provisions of Section 7 of this Order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 4. <i>Information</i>. (a) All agencies and officers of the Government, including representatives of the United States to international financial organizations, (1) shall keep the Council or the Secretary of the Treasury, as the case may be, fully informed concerning the foreign loan, financial, exchange, and monetary transactions in which they engage or may engage or with respect to which they have other responsibility, and (2) shall provide the Council, the Secretary of State, and the Secretary with such further information or data in their possession as the Council, the Secretary of State, or the Secretary, as the case may be, may deem necessary to the appropriate discharge of the responsibilities of the Council, the Secretary of State, and Secretary under Sections 2 and 3 of this order, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Council shall from time to time transmit to all appropriate agencies and officers of the Government statements of the policies of the Council under this order and such other information relating to the above-mentioned transactions or to the functions of the Council hereunder as the Council shall deem desirable.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 5. <i>Executive Order No. 10033</i>. Section 2(a) of Executive Order No. 10033 of <date date="1949-02-08">February 8, 1949</date> [set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s286f">section 286f of this title</ref>], is hereby amended by substituting for the name “National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Problems” the following: “National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Policies.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 6. <i>Effective date</i>. The provisions of this order shall be effective as of <date date="1966-01-01">January 1, 1966</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 7. <i>Functions of the Secretary of State</i>. The Secretary of State shall advise both the Secretary of the Treasury and the appropriate United States representatives to the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, the International Development Association, the International Finance Corporation, the Inter-American Development Bank, the Asian Development Bank, the African Development Fund,, [sic] African Development Bank, Inter-American Investment Corporation, Multilateral Investment Guarantee Agency, and European Bank for Reconstruction and Development on the development aspects of matters relating to those institutions and their activities.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
