<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8ec17d37-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286c"><num value="286c">§ 286c.</num><heading> Congressional authorization needed for certain actions</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Unless Congress by law authorizes such action, neither the President nor any person or agency shall on behalf of the United States (a) request or consent to any change in the quota of the United States under article III, section 2(a), of the Articles of Agreement of the Fund; (b) propose a par value for the United States dollar under paragraph 2, paragraph 4, or paragraph 10 of schedule C of the Articles of Agreement of the Fund; (c) propose any change in the par value of the United States dollar under paragraph 6 of schedule C of the Articles of Agreement of the Fund, or approve any general change in par values under paragraph 11 of schedule C; (d) subscribe to additional shares of stock under article II, section 3, of the Articles of Agreement of the Bank; (e) accept any amendment under article XXVIII of the Articles of Agreement of the Fund or Article VIII of the Articles of Agreement of the Bank; (f) make any loan to the Fund or the Bank; or (g) approve any disposition of Fund gold, unless the Secretary certifies to the Congress that such disposition is necessary for the Fund to restitute gold to its members, or for the Fund to provide liquidity that will enable the Fund to meet member country claims on the Fund or to meet threats to the systemic stability of the international financial system. Unless Congress by law authorizes such action, no governor or alternate appointed to represent the United States shall vote for an increase of capital stock of the Bank under article II, section 2, of the Articles of Agreement of the Bank, if such increase involves an increased subscription on the part of the United States. Neither the President nor any person or agency shall, on behalf of the United States, consent to any borrowing (other than borrowing from a foreign government or other official public source) by the Fund of funds denominated in United States dollars, unless the Secretary of the Treasury transmits a notice of such proposed borrowing to both Houses of the Congress at least 60 days prior to the date on which such borrowing is scheduled to occur.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8ec17d38-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1945-07-31/ch339/s5">July 31, 1945, ch. 339, § 5</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/59/514">59 Stat. 514</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/126/s1/2">Pub. L. 89–126, § 1(2)</ref>, <date date="1965-08-14">Aug. 14, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/519">79 Stat. 519</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/564/s3">Pub. L. 94–564, § 3</ref>, <date date="1976-10-19">Oct. 19, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2660">90 Stat. 2660</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/147/s4/a/1">Pub. L. 95–147, § 4(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1977-10-28">Oct. 28, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1228">91 Stat. 1228</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/tI">Pub. L. 98–181, title I</ref> [title VIII, § 811], <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1274">97 Stat. 1274</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/5/tV/s504/d/1">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(5) [title V, § 504(d)(1)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–317.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8ec17d39-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8ec17d3a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8ec17d3b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—<ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref>, which directed substitution of “approve any disposition of Fund gold, unless the Secretary certifies to the Congress that such disposition is necessary for the Fund to restitute gold to its members, or for the Fund to provide liquidity that will enable the Fund to meet member country claims on the Fund or to meet threats to the systemic stability of the international financial system.” for “approve either the disposition of more than 25 million ounces of Fund gold for the benefit of the Trust Fund established by the Fund on <date date="1976-05-06">May 6, 1976</date>, or the establishment of any additional trust fund whereby resources of the International Monetary Fund would be used for the special benefit of a single member, or of a particular segment of the membership, of the Fund.” in cl. (g) of first sentence, was executed by making the substitution for text which ended with “the fund.” rather than “the Fund.”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—<ref href="/us/pl/98/181">Pub. L. 98–181</ref> inserted provision prohibiting the President or any person or agency from consenting to a borrowing of funds denominated in dollars unless notice of such borrowing is transmitted to Congress at least 60 days prior to such borrowing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—<ref href="/us/pl/95/147">Pub. L. 95–147</ref> added to cl. (g) provisions relating to disposition of more than 25 million ounces of Fund gold for the benefit of the Trust Fund.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—<ref href="/us/pl/94/564">Pub. L. 94–564</ref> amended cls. (a) to (g) generally.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—<ref href="/us/pl/89/126">Pub. L. 89–126</ref> inserted “if such increase involves an increased subscription on the part of the United States”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8ec17d3c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id8ec17d3d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment effective <date date="1978-04-01">Apr. 1, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/564/s9">section 9 of Pub. L. 94–564</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s286a">section 286a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
