<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8ec3ee09-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286j"><num value="286j">§ 286j.</num><heading> Use of Fund resources</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ec3ee0a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286j/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Official interpretation of authority of Fund</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The governor and executive director of the Fund appointed by the United States are directed to obtain promptly an official interpretation by the Fund as to whether its authority to use its resources extends beyond current monetary stabilization operations to afford temporary assistance to members in connection with seasonal, cyclical, and emergency fluctuations in the balance of payment of any member for current transactions, and whether it has authority to use its resources to provide facilities for relief, reconstruction, or armaments, or to meet a large or sustained outflow of capital on the part of any member.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ec3ee0b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286j/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Proposal of amendment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the interpretation by the Fund answers in the affirmative any of the questions stated in subsection (a), the governor of the Fund representing the United States is directed to propose promptly and support an amendment to the Articles of Agreement for the purpose of expressly negativing such interpretation. The President is authorized and directed to accept an amendment to that effect on behalf of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8ec3ee0c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1945-07-31/ch339/s13">July 31, 1945, ch. 339, § 13</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/59/517">59 Stat. 517</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
