<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8ec65f2e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286m"><num value="286m">§ 286m.</num><heading> Amount of loan; public-debt transaction; disposition of interest payments</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of carrying out the agreement dated <date date="1945-12-06">December 6, 1945</date>, between the United States and the United Kingdom, the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to use as a public-debt transaction not to exceed $3,750,000,000 of the proceeds of any securities issued after <date date="1946-07-15">July 15, 1946</date>, under chapter 31 of title 31, and the purposes for which securities may be issued under that chapter are extended to include such purpose. Payments to the United Kingdom under this section and section 286<i>l</i> of this title and pursuant to the agreement and repayments thereof shall be treated as public-debt transactions of the United States. Payments of interest to the United States under the agreement shall be covered into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8ec65f2f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-07-15/ch577/s2">July 15, 1946, ch. 577, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/535">60 Stat. 535</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8ec65f30-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8ec65f31-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8ec65f32-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Agreement dated <date date="1945-12-06">December 6, 1945</date>, between the United States and the United Kingdom, referred to in text, is set out as a note under section 286<i>l</i> of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8ec65f33-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Chapter 31 of title 31” and “that chapter” substituted in text for “the Second Liberty Bond Act, as amended” and “that Act”, respectively, on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s4/b">Pub. L. 97–258, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1067">96 Stat. 1067</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 31, Money and Finance.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was not enacted as a part of <ref href="/us/act/1945-07-31/ch339">act July 31, 1945, ch. 339</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/59/512">59 Stat. 512</ref>, known as the Bretton Woods Agreement Act, which comprises this subchapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
