<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8ecb1a68-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286rr"><num value="286rr">§ 286rr.</num><heading> Approval to sell a limited amount of the Fund’s gold</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8ecb1a69-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286rr/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to instruct the United States Executive Director of the Fund to vote to approve the sale of up to 12,965,649 ounces of the Fund’s gold acquired since the second Amendment to the Fund’s Articles of Agreement, only if such sales are consistent with the guidelines agreed to by the Executive Board of the Fund described in the Report of the Managing Director to the International Monetary and Financial Committee on a New Income and Expenditure Framework for the International Monetary Fund (<date date="2008-04-09">April 9, 2008</date>) to prevent disruption to the world gold market: <i>Provided</i>, That at least 30 days prior to any such vote, the Secretary shall consult with the appropriate congressional committees regarding the use of proceeds from the sale of such gold: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Secretary of the Treasury shall seek to ensure that:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ecb1a6a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286rr/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Fund will provide support to low-income countries that are eligible for the Poverty Reduction and Growth Facility or other low-income lending from the Fund by making available Fund resources of not less than $4,000,000,000;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ecb1a6b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286rr/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> such Fund resources referenced above will be used to leverage additional support by a significant multiple to provide loans with substantial concessionality and debt service payment relief and/or grants, as appropriate to a country’s circumstances: <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002031">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002031"><num>1</num> So in original. The colon probably should be a semicolon.</note></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ecb1a6c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286rr/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> support provided through forgiveness of interest on concessional loans will be provided for not less than two years; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ecb1a6d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286rr/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the support provided to low-income countries occurs within six years, a substantial amount of which shall occur within the initial two years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id8ecb1a6e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286rr/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> In addition to agreeing to and accepting the amendments referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s286pp">section 286pp of this title</ref> relating to the use of proceeds from the sale of such gold, the United States Governor is authorized, consistent with subsection (a), to take such actions as may be necessary, including those referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s286c/e">section 286c(e) of this title</ref>, to also use such proceeds for the purpose of assisting low-income countries.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8ecb1a6f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1945-07-31/ch339/s66">July 31, 1945, ch. 339, § 66</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/111/32/tXIV/s1402">Pub. L. 111–32, title XIV, § 1402</ref>, <date date="2009-06-24">June 24, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1918">123 Stat. 1918</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
