<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8ec8a897-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286z"><num value="286z">§ 286z.</num><heading> Collection and exchange of information on monetary and financial problems</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ec8a898-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286z/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ec8a899-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286z/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the lack of sufficient information currently available to allow members of the Fund to make sound and prudent decisions concerning their public and private sector international borrowing, and to allow lenders to make sound and prudent decisions concerning their international lending, threatens the stability of the international monetary system; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ec8a89a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286z/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> in recognition of the Fund’s duties, as provided particularly by article VIII of the Articles of Agreement of the Fund, to act as a center for the collection and exchange of information on monetary and financial problems, the Fund should adopt necessary and appropriate measures to ensure that more complete and timely financial information will be available.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ec8a89b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286z/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Initiation by United States Executive Director of discussions with other Directors; adoption of procedures</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To this end, the Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Director of the Fund to initiate discussions with other directors of the Fund and with Fund management, and to propose and vote for, the adoption of procedures, within the Fund—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ec8a89c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286z/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> to collect and disseminate information, on a quarterly basis, from and to Fund members, and to such other persons as the Fund deems appropriate, concerning—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8ec8a89d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286z/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the extension of credit by banks or nonbanks to private and public entities, including all government entities, instrumentalities, and central banks of member countries; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id8ec8a89e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286z/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the receipt of such credit by those private and public entities of member countries, where such banks or nonbanks are not principally established within the borders of the member country to which the credits are extended; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ec8a89f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286z/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to disseminate publicly information which is developed in the course of the Fund’s collection, and to review and comment on efforts which the Fund determines would serve to enhance the informational base upon which international borrowing and lending decisions are taken.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ec8a8a0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286z/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> “Credit” defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “credit” includes—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ec8a8a1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286z/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> outstanding loans to private and public entities, including government entities, instrumentalities, and central banks of any member, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id8ec8a8a2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286z/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> unused lines of credit which have been made available to those private and public entities of any member,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">where such loans or lines of credit are repayable in freely convertible currency.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ec8a8a3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s286z/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Providing necessary information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President is authorized to use the authority provided under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s286f">section 286f of this title</ref> to require any person (as defined in such section) subject to the jurisdiction of the United States to provide such information as the Fund determines to be necessary in order to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8ec8a8a4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1945-07-31/ch339/s42">July 31, 1945, ch. 339, § 42</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/98/181/tI">Pub. L. 98–181, title I</ref> [title VIII, § 802(a)(4)], <date date="1983-11-30">Nov. 30, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1269">97 Stat. 1269</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
