<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8ed70147-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s287q"><num value="287q">§ 287q.</num><heading> General and special conferences; expenses; acceptance of services and gifts or bequests of money or materials</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The National Commission shall call general conferences for the discussion of matters relating to the activities of the Organization, to which conferences organized bodies actively interested in such matters shall be invited to send representatives: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the travel and maintenance of such representation shall be without expense to the Government. Such general conferences shall be held annually or biennially, as the National Commission may determine, and in such places as it may designate. They shall be attended so far as possible by the members of the National Commission and by the delegates of the United States to the General Conference of the Organization. The National Commission is further authorized to call special conferences of experts for the consideration of specific matters relating to the Organization by persons of specialized competences. The Department of State may pay their transportation and other expenses as authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5703">section 5703 of title 5</ref>, for the period of actual attendance and of necessary travel. The National Commission is further authorized to receive and accept services and gifts or bequests of money or materials to carry out any of the educational, scientific, or cultural purposes of the National Commission as set forth in this subchapter and in the constitution of the Organization. Any money so received shall be held by the Secretary of State and shall be subject to disbursement through the disbursement facilities of the Treasury Department as the terms of the gift or bequest may require and shall remain available for expenditure by grant or otherwise until expended: <i>Provided</i>, That no such gift or bequest may be accepted or disbursed if the terms thereof are inconsistent with the purposes of the National Commission as set forth in this subchapter and in the constitution of the Organization. Gifts or bequests provided for herein shall, for the purposes of Federal income, estate, and gift taxes, be deemed to be a gift to or for the United States. The National Commission and Secretary of State shall submit to Congress annual reports of receipts and expenditures of funds and bequests received and disbursed pursuant to the provisions of this section.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002035">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002035"><num>1</num> See Termination of Reporting Requirements note below.</note></p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8ed97148-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-07-30/ch700/s5">July 30, 1946, ch. 700, § 5</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/713">60 Stat. 713</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/477">Pub. L. 85–477</ref>, ch. V, § 502(e), <date date="1958-06-30">June 30, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/273">72 Stat. 273</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/139/s10">Pub. L. 87–139, § 10</ref>, <date date="1961-08-14">Aug. 14, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/341">75 Stat. 341</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/164/tI/s106/a">Pub. L. 98–164, title I, § 106(a)</ref>, <date date="1983-11-22">Nov. 22, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1018">97 Stat. 1018</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8ed97149-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8ed9714a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id8ed9714b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The constitution of the Organization, referred to in text, is the Constitution of the United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s287m">section 287m of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8ed9714c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5703">Section 5703 of title 5</ref>” substituted in text for “section 5 of the Administrative Expenses Act of 1946, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s73b–2">5 U.S.C. 73b–2</ref>)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s7/b">Pub. L. 89–554, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/631">80 Stat. 631</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8ed9714d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—<ref href="/us/pl/98/164">Pub. L. 98–164</ref> struck out provision prohibiting acceptance of gifts or bequests aggregating more than $200,000 in any year.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1961—<ref href="/us/pl/87/139">Pub. L. 87–139</ref> substituted provisions authorizing payment of transportation and other expenses of attending experts as authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5703">section 5703 of title 5</ref>, for provisions which allowed the experts $10 per diem plus actual transportation expenses.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—<ref href="/us/pl/85/477">Pub. L. 85–477</ref> authorized the National Commission to receive and accept services and gifts or bequests of money or materials.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8ed9714e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8ed9714f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Reporting Requirements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/89/348/s1/21">Pub. L. 89–348, § 1(21)</ref>, <date date="1965-11-08">Nov. 8, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1311">79 Stat. 1311</ref>, repealed the following reporting requirement: <quotedContent>“The annual report to Congress by the National Commission on Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Cooperation and the Secretary of State of the receipts and expenditures of funds and bequests received and disbursed in connection with the United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization (<ref href="/us/stat/72/273">72 Stat. 273</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s287q">22 U.S.C. 287q</ref>).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
