<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8edbbbb7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s288g"><num value="288g">§ 288g.</num><heading> Organization of American States; extension of privileges and immunities to members</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Under such terms and conditions as he shall determine, the President is hereby authorized to extend, or to enter into an agreement extending, to the representatives of member states (other than the United States) to the Organization of American States and to permanent observers to the Organization of American States, and to members of the staffs of said representatives and permanent observers, the same privileges and immunities, subject to corresponding conditions and obligations, as are enjoyed by diplomatic envoys accredited to the United States.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8edbbbb8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1952-07-10/ch628">July 10, 1952, ch. 628</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/516">66 Stat. 516</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/149/s1/b">Pub. L. 93–149, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1973-11-07">Nov. 7, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/560">87 Stat. 560</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8edbbbb9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8edbbbba-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8edbbbbb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was not enacted as part of the International Organizations Immunities Act which comprises this subchapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8edbbbbc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—<ref href="/us/pl/93/149">Pub. L. 93–149</ref> substituted provisions extending diplomatic privileges and immunities to representatives of member states to the Organization of American States, to permanent observers to the Organization of American States, and to member of staff of such representatives and permanent observers, for provisions extending such privileges and immunities to representatives of member states on the Council of the Organization of American State and members of their staff.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id8edbbbbd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id8edbbbbe-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 11931. Extension of Diplomatic Privileges and Immunities to Permanent Observers to Organization of American States</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 11931, <date date="1976-08-03">Aug. 3, 1976</date>, 41 F.R. 32689, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By virtue of the authority vested in me by the Act of <date date="1973-11-07">November 7, 1973</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/87/560">87 Stat. 560</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s288g">22 U.S.C. 288g</ref>), and as President of the United States of America, I extend to Permanent Observers to the Organization of American States, and to the members of the diplomatic staffs of such Permanent Observers, the same privileges and immunities, subject to corresponding conditions and obligations, as are enjoyed by diplomatic envoys accredited to the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Executive order shall be effective as of <date date="1973-11-07">November 7, 1973</date>. The enjoyment of privileges and immunities extended hereunder shall be subject to any Agreements entered into between the Government of the United States and the Organization of American States after that date.</p>
<signature>
<name>Gerald R. Ford.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
