<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8edbbbe0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s288l"><num value="288l">§ 288l.</num><heading> The Holy See</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Under such terms and conditions as the President shall determine, the President is authorized to extend, or to enter into an agreement to extend, to the Permanent Observer Mission of the Holy See to the United Nations in New York, and to its members, the privileges and immunities enjoyed by the diplomatic missions of member states to the United Nations, and their members, subject to corresponding conditions and obligations.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8edbbbe1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/109/472/s7/b">Pub. L. 109–472, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="2007-01-11">Jan. 11, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3556">120 Stat. 3556</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8edbbbe2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8edbbbe3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8edbbbe4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Department of State Authorities Act of 2006, and not as part of the International Organizations Immunities Act which comprises this subchapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id8edbbbe5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id8edbbbe6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 13427. Extending Privileges and Immunities to the Permanent Observer Mission of the Holy See to the United Nations</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 13427, <date date="2007-03-07">Mar. 7, 2007</date>, 72 F.R. 10879, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 7(b) of the Department of State Authorities Act of 2006 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s288">22 U.S.C. 288</ref><i>l</i>), I hereby extend to the Permanent Observer Mission of the Holy See to the United Nations in New York, and to its members, the privileges and immunities enjoyed by the diplomatic missions of member states to the United Nations, and members of such missions, subject to corresponding conditions and obligations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This extension of privileges and immunities is not intended to abridge in any respect privileges or immunities that the Permanent Observer Mission of the Holy See to the United Nations in New York and its members otherwise may have acquired or may acquire by law.</p>
<signature>
<name>George W. Bush.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
