<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90299973-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2906"><num value="2906">§ 2906.</num><heading> Management of the Friendship Trust Fund</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90299974-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2906/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Constituent amounts</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Fund shall consist of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90299975-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2906/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> amounts appropriated under sections 2902(d) and (e)(1) of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90299976-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2906/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> any other amounts received by the Fund by way of gifts and donations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90299977-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2906/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> interest and proceeds credited to it under subsection (b) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90299978-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2906/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Investments by Secretary of Treasury in authorized obligations; issuance of obligations and special obligations; conditions of acquisition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be the duty of the Secretary of the Treasury (hereafter referred to as the “Secretary”) to invest such portion of the Fund as is not, in the judgment of the Commission, required to meet current withdrawals. Such investment may be made only in interest-bearing obligations of the United States, in obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by the United States, in interest-bearing obligations of Japan, or in obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by Japan. For such purposes, the obligations may be acquired (1) on original issue at the issue price, or (2) by purchase of outstanding obligations at the market price. The purposes for which obligations of the United States may be issued under chapter 31 of title 31, are hereby extended to authorize the issuance at par of special obligations exclusively to the Fund. Such special obligations shall bear interest at a rate equal to the average rate of interest, computed as to the end of the calendar month next preceding the date of such issue, borne by all marketable interest-bearing obligations of the United States issued during the preceding two years then forming part of the public debt; except that where such average rate is not a multiple of one-eight of 1 per centum, the rate of interest of such special obligations shall be the multiple of one-eighth of 1 per centum next lower than such average rate. Such special obligations shall be issued only if the Secretary determines that the purchase of other interest-bearing obligations of the United States, or of obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by the United States on original issue or at the market price, is not in the public interest.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90299979-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2906/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Sale of obligations; redemption of special obligations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any obligation acquired by the Fund (except special obligations issued exclusively to the Fund) may be sold by the Secretary at the market price, and such special obligations may be redeemed at par plus accrued interest.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9029997a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2906/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Credit to Fund of interest on, and proceeds from sale or redemption of, any obligations held in Fund</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in the Fund shall be credited to and form a part of the Fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9029997b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s2906/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Payments for implementation of programs and necessary expenses of Commission; appropriation of amounts; exceptions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2905/4">section 2905(4) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall pay out of the Fund such amounts, including expenses of the Commission, as the Commission considers necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter; except that amounts in the Fund, other than amounts which have been appropriated and amounts received (including amounts earned as interest on, and proceeds from the sale or redemption of, obligations purchased with amounts received) by the Commission pursuant to sections 2905(2) and (3) of this title, shall be subject to the appropriation process.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9029997c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/118/s7">Pub. L. 94–118, § 7</ref>, <date date="1975-10-20">Oct. 20, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/606">89 Stat. 606</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/350/tIV/s401/3/B">Pub. L. 94–350, title IV, § 401(3)(B)</ref>, <date date="1976-07-12">July 12, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/833">90 Stat. 833</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/241/tV/s503/b">Pub. L. 97–241, title V, § 503(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/298">96 Stat. 298</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dA/s101/b/tIV/s404/b">Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(b) [title IV, § 404(b)]</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-50">112 Stat. 2681–50</ref>, 2681–101.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9029997d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9029997e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id9029997f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (b), “chapter 31 of title 31” substituted for “the Second Liberty Bond Act, as amended” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s4/b">Pub. L. 97–258, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1067">96 Stat. 1067</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 31, Money and Finance.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id90299980-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref> amended second sentence generally. Prior to amendment, second sentence read as follows: “Such investment of amounts authorized to be appropriated under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2902/d">section 2902(d) of this title</ref> may be made only in interest-bearing obligations of the United States or in obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by the United States.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/97/241">Pub. L. 97–241</ref> inserted “(including amounts earned as interest on, and proceeds from the sale or redemption of, obligations purchased with amounts received)” after “amounts received”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/94/350">Pub. L. 94–350</ref> substituted “investment of amounts authorized to be appropriated under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2902/d">section 2902(d) of this title</ref> may be made” for “investment may be made” in second sentence.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
