<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8ee2e80b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s290k–9"><num value="290k–9">§ 290k–9.</num><heading> Jurisdiction of United States courts and enforcement of arbitral awards</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of any civil action which may be brought within the United States, its territories or possessions, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, by or against the Agency in accordance with the Convention, including an action brought to enforce an arbitral award against the Agency, the Agency shall be deemed to be an inhabitant of the Federal judicial district in which its principal office within the United States or its agent appointed for the purpose of accepting service or notice of service is located, and any such action to which the Agency shall be a party shall be deemed to arise under the laws of the United States, and the district courts of the United States, including the courts enumerated in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s460">section 460 of title 28</ref>, shall have original jurisdiction of any such action. When the Agency is a defendant in any action in a State court, it may at any time before the trial thereof remove the action into the appropriate district court of the United States by following the procedure for removal provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1446">section 1446 of title 28</ref>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id8ee2e80c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101/e/tI">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(e) [title I]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1329-131">101 Stat. 1329–131</ref>, 1329–134.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8ee2e80d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8ee2e80e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id8ee2e80f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is based on section 412 of title IV of H.R. 3750, One Hundredth Congress, as introduced <date date="1987-12-11">Dec. 11, 1987</date>, and enacted into law by <ref href="/us/pl/100/202">Pub. L. 100–202</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
