<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8ee7a278-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s292"><num value="292">§ 292.</num><heading> Acquisition of sites and buildings for diplomatic and consular establishments; allotment of space; credit of payments without regard to limitations of amounts</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ee7a279-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s292/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of Secretary of State</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of State is empowered to acquire by purchase or construction in the manner hereinafter provided, within the limits of appropriations made to carry out this chapter, by exchange, in whole or in part, of any building or grounds of the United States in foreign countries and under the jurisdiction and control of the Secretary of State, sites and buildings in foreign capitals and in other foreign cities, and to alter, repair, and furnish such buildings for the use of the diplomatic and consular establishments of the United States, or for the purpose of consolidating within one or more buildings, the embassies, legation, consulates, and other agencies of the United States Government there maintained. The space in such buildings shall be allotted by the Secretary of State among the several agencies of the United States Government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ee7a27a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s292/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Payments from other than appropriated funds for acquisition of property</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Payments made for rent or otherwise by the United States from funds other than appropriations made to carry out this chapter may be credited toward the acquisition of property under this chapter without regard to limitations of amounts imposed by this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8ee7a27b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s292/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization for improvements and construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of State may improve or construct facilities overseas for other Federal departments and agencies on an advance-of-funds or reimbursable basis if such advances or reimbursements are credited to the Embassy Security, Construction, and Maintenance account and remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8ee7a27c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1926-05-07/ch250/s1">May 7, 1926, ch. 250, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/403">44 Stat. 403</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1928-05-29/ch876/s1">May 29, 1928, ch. 876, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/45/971">45 Stat. 971</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/94/s2/b">Pub. L. 88–94, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1963-08-12">Aug. 12, 1963</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/77/122">77 Stat. 122</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/636/s2">Pub. L. 89–636, § 2</ref>, <date date="1966-10-10">Oct. 10, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/881">80 Stat. 881</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/105/tI/s106/a">Pub. L. 95–105, title I, § 106(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-17">Aug. 17, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/845">91 Stat. 845</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/323/tI/s119">Pub. L. 114–323, title I, § 119</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1912">130 Stat. 1912</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id8ee7a27d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id8ee7a27e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id8ee7a27f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/114/323">Pub. L. 114–323</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/105/s106/a/1">Pub. L. 95–105, § 106(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “to carry out” for “pursuant to”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/105/s106/a/2">Pub. L. 95–105, § 106(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “to carry out” for “under authority of”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—<ref href="/us/pl/89/636">Pub. L. 89–636</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1963—<ref href="/us/pl/88/94">Pub. L. 88–94</ref> struck out “, subject to the direction of the commission hereinafter established,” after “is empowered”, “under such terms and conditions as in the judgment of the commission may best protect the interests of the United States,” after “in part,” and “, to the extent deemed advisable by the commission,” after “consolidating” and substituted “. The space in such buildings shall be allotted by the Secretary of State” for “, which buildings shall be appropriately designated by the commission, and the space in which shall be allotted by the Secretary of State under the direction of the commission.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1928—Act <date date="1928-05-29">May 29, 1928</date>, inserted “or by exchange, in whole or in part, under such terms and conditions as in the judgment of the commission may best protect the interest of the United States, of any building or grounds of the United States in foreign countries and under the jurisdiction and control of the Secretary of State”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id8ee7a280-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8ee7a281-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Standard Design in Capital Construction</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dE/tLII/s5202">Pub. L. 117–81, div. E, title LII, § 5202</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/2353">135 Stat. 2353</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/81/dE/tLII/s5202">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sense of Congress</inline>.—</heading><content>It is the sense of Congress that the Department’s Bureau of Overseas Building Operations (OBO) or successor office should give appropriate consideration to standardization in construction, in which each new United States embassy and consulate starts with a standard design and keeps customization to a minimum.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall carry out any new United States embassy compound or new consulate compound project that utilizes a non-standard design, including those projects that are in the design or pre-design phase as of the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>], only in consultation with the appropriate congressional committees and the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives. The Secretary shall provide the appropriate congressional committees and the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives, for each such project, the following documentation:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> A comparison of the estimated full lifecycle costs of the project to the estimated full lifecycle costs of such project if it were to use a standard design.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> A comparison of the estimated completion date of such project to the estimated completion date of such project if it were to use a standard design.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> A comparison of the security of the completed project to the security of such completed project if it were to use a standard design.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> A justification for the Secretary’s selection of a non-standard design over a standard design for such project.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> A written explanation if any of the documentation necessary to support the comparisons and justification, as the case may be, described in paragraphs (1) through (4) cannot be provided.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sunset</inline>.—</heading><content>The consultation requirement under subsection (b) shall expire on the date that is 4 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “Department”, “Secretary”, and “appropriate congressional committees” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s5202">section 5202 of Pub. L. 117–81</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s5002">section 5002 of Pub. L. 117–81</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s263c">section 263c of this title</ref>.]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definition of “non-standard design” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s5202">section 5202 of Pub. L. 117–81</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s5214">section 5214 of Pub. L. 117–81</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s306">section 306 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8ee7a282-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Value Engineering and Risk Assessment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dE/tLII/s5207">Pub. L. 117–81, div. E, title LII, § 5207</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/2357">135 Stat. 2357</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/81/dE/tLII/s5207">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Federal departments and agencies are required to use value engineering (VE) as a management tool, where appropriate, to reduce program and acquisition costs pursuant to OMB Circular A–131, Value Engineering, dated <date date="2013-12-31">December 31, 2013</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> OBO has a Policy Directive and Standard Operation Procedure, dated <date date="2017-05-24">May 24, 2017</date>, on conducting risk management studies on all international construction projects.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notification Requirements.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Submission to authorizing committees</inline>.—</heading><content>Any notification that includes the allocation of capital construction and maintenance funds shall be submitted to the appropriate congressional committees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement to confirm completion of value engineering and risk assessment studies</inline>.—</heading><content>The notifications required under paragraph (1) shall include confirmation that the Department has completed the requisite VE and risk management process described in subsection (a), or applicable successor process.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reporting and Briefing Requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees upon request—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> a description of each risk management study referred to in subsection (a)(2) and a table detailing which recommendations related to each such study were accepted and which were rejected; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> a report or briefing detailing the rationale for not implementing any such recommendations that may otherwise yield significant cost savings to the Department if implemented.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of “Department”, “Secretary”, and “appropriate congressional committees” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s5207">section 5207 of Pub. L. 117–81</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s5002">section 5002 of Pub. L. 117–81</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s263c">section 263c of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8ee7a283-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Statement of Policy</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dE/tLII/s5213">Pub. L. 117–81, div. E, title LII, § 5213</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/2358">135 Stat. 2358</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/81/dE/tLII/s5213">“It is the policy of the United States that the Bureau of Overseas Building Operations of the Department or its successor office shall continue to balance functionality and security with accessibility, as defined by guidelines established by the United States Access Board in constructing embassies and consulates, and shall ensure compliance with the Architectural Barriers Act of 1968 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4151">42 U.S.C. 4151</ref> et seq.) to the fullest extent possible.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definition of “Department” as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s5213">section 5213 of Pub. L. 117–81</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/s5002">section 5002 of Pub. L. 117–81</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s263c">section 263c of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id8ee7a284-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Property Agreements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/236/tI/s134">Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 134</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/396">108 Stat. 396</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/103/415/s1/z">Pub. L. 103–415, § 1(z)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4302">108 Stat. 4302</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/415/s1/z">“Whenever the Department of State enters into lease-purchase agreements involving property in foreign countries pursuant to section 1 of the Foreign Service Buildings Act, 1926 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s292">22 U.S.C. 292</ref>), the Department shall account for such transactions in accordance with fiscal year obligations.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
