<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id902c09e8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3102"><num value="3102">§ 3102.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this chapter, the term—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902c09e9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3102/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> “United States”, when used in a geographic sense, means the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Canal Zone, and all territories and possessions of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902c09ea-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3102/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> “foreign”, when used in a geographic sense, means that which is situated outside the United States or which belongs to or is characteristic of a country other than the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902c09eb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3102/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> “person” means any individual, branch, partnership, associated group, association, estate, trust, corporation, or other organization (whether or not organized under the laws of any State), and any government (including a foreign government, the United States Government, a State or local government, and any agency, corporation, financial institution, or other entity or instrumentality thereof, including a government-sponsored agency);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902c09ec-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3102/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> “United States person” means any person resident in the United States or subject to the jurisdiction of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902c09ed-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3102/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> “foreign person” means any person resident outside the United States or subject to the jurisdiction of a country other than the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902c09ee-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3102/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> “business enterprise” means any organization, association, branch, or venture which exists for profitmaking purposes or to otherwise secure economic advantage, and any ownership of any real estate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902c09ef-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3102/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> “parent” means a person of one country who, directly or indirectly, owns or controls 10 per centum or more of the voting stock of an incorporated business enterprise, or an equivalent ownership interest in an unincorporated business enterprise, which is located outside that country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902c09f0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3102/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> “affiliate” means a business enterprise located in one country which is directly or indirectly owned or controlled by a person of another country to the extent of 10 per centum or more of its voting stock for an incorporated business or an equivalent interest for an unincorporated business, including a branch;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902c09f1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3102/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> “international investment” means (A) the ownership or control, directly or indirectly, by contractual commitment or otherwise, by foreign persons of any interest in property in the United States, or of stock, other securities, or short- and long-term debt obligations of a United States person, and (B) the ownership or control, directly or indirectly, by contractual commitment or otherwise, by United States persons of any interest in property outside the United States, or of stock, other securities, or short-and long-term debt obligations of a foreign person;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902c09f2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3102/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> “direct investment” means the ownership or control, directly or indirectly, by one person of 10 per centum or more of the voting securities of an incorporated business enterprise or an equivalent interest in an unincorporated business enterprise; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902c09f3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3102/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> “portfolio investment” means any international investment which is not direct investment.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id902c09f4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/472/s3">Pub. L. 94–472, § 3</ref>, <date date="1976-10-11">Oct. 11, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2060">90 Stat. 2060</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id902c09f5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id902c09f6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id902c09f7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definition of Canal Zone, referred to in par. (1), see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3602/b">section 3602(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
