<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id902c0a24-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3105"><num value="3105">§ 3105.</num><heading> Enforcement</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id902c0a25-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3105/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil penalty for failure to furnish information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whoever fails to furnish any information required under this chapter, whether required to be furnished in the form of a report or otherwise, or to comply with any rule, regulation, order, or instruction promulgated under this chapter, shall be subject to a civil penalty of not less than $2,500, and not more than $25,000, in a proceeding brought under subsection (b) of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id902c0a26-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3105/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil action for failure to furnish information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever it appears that any person has failed to furnish any information required under this chapter, whether required to be furnished in the form of a report or otherwise, or has failed to comply with any rule, regulation, order, or instruction promulgated under this chapter, a civil action may be brought in an appropriate district court of the United States, or the appropriate United States court of any territory or other place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, and such court may enter a restraining order or a permanent or temporary injunction commanding such person to furnish such information or to comply with such rule, regulation, order, or instruction, as the case may be, or impose the civil penalty provided in subsection (a) of this section, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id902c0a27-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3105/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Criminal penalty for failure to submit information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whoever willfully fails to submit any information required under this chapter, whether required to be furnished in the form of a report or otherwise, or willfully violates any rule, regulation, order, or instruction promulgated under this chapter, upon conviction, shall be fined not more than $10,000 and, if an individual, may be imprisoned for not more than one year, or both, and any officer, director, employee, or agent of any corporation who knowingly participates in such violation, upon conviction, may be punished by a like fine, imprisonment, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id902c0a28-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/94/472/s6">Pub. L. 94–472, § 6</ref>, <date date="1976-10-11">Oct. 11, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2063">90 Stat. 2063</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/533/s7/b">Pub. L. 101–533, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-07">Nov. 7, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2349">104 Stat. 2349</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id902c0a29-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id902c0a2a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id902c0a2b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/533">Pub. L. 101–533</ref> substituted “shall be subject to a civil penalty of not less than $2,500, and not more than $25,000,” for “may be subject to a civil penalty not exceeding $10,000”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
