<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id902e5359-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3143"><num value="3143">§ 3143.</num><heading> Reports by Government Accountability Office</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id902e535a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3143/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Comptroller General, to the extent permitted by law, including <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3144">section 3144 of this title</ref>, is authorized to review the information described in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3142/b">section 3142(b) of this title</ref> for purposes of preparing the reports referred to in subsection (b) of this section. Nothing in this section authorizes disclosure of any individually identifiable data or information in any form that can be associated with or otherwise identify, directly or indirectly, any person, including any enterprise or establishment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id902e535b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3143/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Consistent with the provisions of this section, the Comptroller General may submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, the Committee on Ways and Means, and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and to the Joint Economic Committee of the Congress reports—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902e535c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3143/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> analyzing reports issued by the Secretary of Commerce under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3142">section 3142 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902e535d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3143/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> making recommendations for changes in the analysis done in the report due the following year under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3142">section 3142 of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902e535e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3143/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> making recommendations for improving the collection by respective Federal agencies of data on foreign direct investment in the United States, including use of private sector data, and improving survey questionnaires to obtain useful and consistent information that avoids unnecessary redundancy among Federal agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902e535f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3143/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> reviewing the status and processes for reconciliation of data exchanged as required by this Act and the amendments made by this Act, and making any recommendations for improving and augmenting international financial data;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902e5360-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3143/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> making recommendations for possible additional policy coordination within the executive branch affecting foreign direct investment in the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902e5361-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3143/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> making recommendations for improvement of the coverage, industry classification, and consistency among Federal agencies of their respective surveys.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id902e5362-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3143/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Other reviews and reports</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id902e5363-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3143/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Comptroller General may, to the extent permitted by law, including <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3104/c">section 3104(c) of this title</ref> and <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3144">section 3144 of this title</ref>, also review data and information at the Bureau of the Census, the Bureau of Labor Statistics, and the Bureau of Economic Analysis and from time to time report to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, the Committee on Ways and Means, and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and to the Joint Economic Committee of the Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id902e5364-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3143/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Comptroller General shall, in carrying out paragraph (1), comply with procedures relating to access to and disclosure of data and information established within the Federal statistical agencies referred to in paragraph (1), and maintain any and all individually identifiable data and information at the statistical agency where the information is reviewed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id902e5365-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3143/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Confidentiality; review by other agencies</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In preparing any report under this section, the Comptroller General shall not—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902e5366-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3143/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> disclose any confidential business information or present any information in a way in which any person, including a business enterprise or establishment, can be identified; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id902e5367-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3143/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> combine, match, or use in any other way individually identifiable data or information maintained by any of the Federal statistical agencies referred to in subsection (c) with any other individually identifiable confidential data or information that is not collected by such statistical agencies.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Before issuing any such report, the Comptroller General shall in each instance submit the report to the head or heads of the agency or agencies from which confidential or identifiable information described in the preceding sentence was obtained. The agency or agencies concerned shall promptly review the report for the purpose of assuring that the confidentiality of such information and identity is maintained, and for any other purpose, and shall provide the Comptroller General with appropriate comments or other suggestions within 10 working days after receiving the report.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id902e5368-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3143/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Right of access</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The access by the Comptroller General to information under this Act shall be in conformity with <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s716">section 716 of title 31</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id902e5369-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/533/s4">Pub. L. 101–533, § 4</ref>, <date date="1990-11-07">Nov. 7, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2346">104 Stat. 2346</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/316/tI/s111/c">Pub. L. 104–316, title I, § 111(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-19">Oct. 19, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3833">110 Stat. 3833</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/271/s8/b">Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="2004-07-07">July 7, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/814">118 Stat. 814</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id902e536a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id902e536b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id902e536c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act and the amendments made by this Act, referred to in subsecs. (b)(4) and (e), is <ref href="/us/pl/101/533">Pub. L. 101–533</ref>, <date date="1990-11-07">Nov. 7, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2344">104 Stat. 2344</ref>, known as the Foreign Direct Investment and International Financial Data Improvements Act of 1990, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3141">section 3141 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id902e536d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—<ref href="/us/pl/108/271">Pub. L. 108–271</ref> substituted “Government Accountability Office” for “General Accounting Office” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/316/s111/c/1">Pub. L. 104–316, § 111(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “reports referred to in” for “report required under”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/104/316/s111/c/2/A">Pub. L. 104–316, § 111(c)(2)(A)</ref>, (D), substituted “Reports” for “Report” in heading, in introductory provisions substituted “Consistent with the provisions of this section, the Comptroller General may submit” for “Not later than 5 months after each report issued by the Secretary of Commerce under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3142">section 3142 of this title</ref>, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit”, and struck out closing provisions which read as follows: “Reports under this subsection shall be issued only with respect to the first 3 reports issued by the Secretary of Commerce under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3142">section 3142 of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/316/s111/c/2/B">Pub. L. 104–316, § 111(c)(2)(B)</ref>, which directed that subsec. (b) be amended by substituting “Congress reports” for “Congress, a report”, was executed in the introductory provisions by making the substitution for “Congress a report”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/316/s111/c/2/C">Pub. L. 104–316, § 111(c)(2)(C)</ref>, substituted “reports issued by the Secretary of Commerce under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3142">section 3142 of this title</ref>” for “the report of the Secretary of Commerce”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id902e536e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id902e536f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Commerce of House of Representatives by <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/a">section 1(a) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress. Committee on Commerce of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives, and jurisdiction over matters relating to securities and exchanges and insurance generally transferred to Committee on Financial Services of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Seventh Congress, <date date="2001-01-03">Jan. 3, 2001</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
