<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90330ee6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3310"><num value="3310">§ 3310.</num><heading> Employment of United States Government agency personnel</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90330ee7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3310/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Separation from Government service; reemployment or reinstatement upon termination of Institute employment; benefits</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id90330ee8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3310/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Under such terms and conditions as the President may direct, any agency of the United States Government may separate from Government service for a specified period any officer or employee of that agency who accepts employment with the Institute.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id90330ee9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3310/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> An officer or employee separated by an agency under paragraph (1) of this subsection for employment with the Institute shall be entitled upon termination of such employment to reemployment or reinstatement with such agency (or a successor agency) in an appropriate position with the attendant rights, privileges, and benefits with <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002252">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002252"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “which”.</note> the officer or employee would have had or acquired had he or she not been so separated, subject to such time period and other conditions as the President may prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id90330eea-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3310/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> An officer or employee entitled to reemployment or reinstatement rights under paragraph (2) of this subsection shall, while continuously employed by the Institute with no break in continuity of service, continue to participate in any benefit program in which such officer or employee was participating prior to employment by the Institute, including programs for compensation for job-related death, injury, or illness; programs for health and life insurance; programs for annual, sick, and other statutory leave; and programs for retirement under any system established by the laws of the United States; except that employment with the Institute shall be the basis for participation in such programs only to the extent that employee deductions and employer contributions, as required, in payment for such participation for the period of employment with the Institute, are currently deposited in the program’s or system’s fund or depository. Death or retirement of any such officer or employee during approved service with the Institute and prior to reemployment or reinstatement shall be considered a death in or retirement from Government service for purposes of any employee or survivor benefits acquired by reason of service with an agency of the United States Government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id90330eeb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3310/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Any officer or employee of an agency of the United States Government who entered into service with the Institute on approved leave of absence without pay prior to <date date="1979-04-10">April 10, 1979</date>, shall receive the benefits of this section for the period of such service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90357eec-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3310/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Employment of aliens on Taiwan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any agency of the United States Government employing alien personnel on Taiwan may transfer such personnel, with accrued allowances, benefits, and rights, to the Institute without a break in service for purposes of retirement and other benefits, including continued participation in any system established by the laws of the United States for the retirement of employees in which the alien was participating prior to the transfer to the Institute, except that employment with the Institute shall be creditable for retirement purposes only to the extent that employee deductions and employer contributions, as required, in payment for such participation for the period of employment with the Institute, are currently deposited in the system’s fund or depository.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90357eed-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3310/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Institute employees not deemed United States employees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Employees of the Institute shall not be employees of the United States and, in representing the Institute, shall be exempt from <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s207">section 207 of title 18</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90357eee-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3310/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Tax treatment of amounts paid Institute employees</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id90357eef-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3310/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> For purposes of sections 911 and 913 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002253">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002253"><num>2</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of title 26, amounts paid by the Institute to its employees shall not be treated as earned income. Amounts received by employees of the Institute shall not be included in gross income, and shall be exempt from taxation, to the extent that they are equivalent to amounts received by civilian officers and employees of the Government of the United States as allowances and benefits which are exempt from taxation under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s912">section 912 of title 26</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id90357ef0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3310/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Except to the extent required by subsection (a)(3) of this section, service performed in the employ of the Institute shall not constitute employment for purposes of chapter 21 of title 26 and title II of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">42 U.S.C. 401</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id90357ef1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/8/s11">Pub. L. 96–8, § 11</ref>, <date date="1979-04-10">Apr. 10, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/18">93 Stat. 18</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id90357ef2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id90357ef3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id90357ef4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t26/s913">Section 913 of title 26</ref>, referred to in subsec. (d)(1), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/97/34/tI/s112/a">Pub. L. 97–34, title I, § 112(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/194">95 Stat. 194</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Chapter 21 (§ 3101 et seq.) of title 26, referred to in subsec. (d)(2), is known as the Federal Insurance Contributions Act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Social Security Act, referred to in subsec. (d)(2), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/620">49 Stat. 620</ref>. Title II of the Social Security Act is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 401 et seq.) of chapter 7 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1305">section 1305 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id90357ef5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> substituted “Internal Revenue Code of 1986” for “Internal Revenue Code of 1954”, which for purposes of codification was translated as “title 26” thus requiring no change in text.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id90357ef6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id90357ef7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective as of <date date="1979-01-01">January 1, 1979</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/8/s18">section 18 of Pub. L. 96–8</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3301">section 3301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id90357ef8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id90357ef9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 13054. Eligibility of Certain Overseas Employees for Noncompetitive Appointments</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 13054, <date date="1997-07-07">July 7, 1997</date>, 62 F.R. 36965, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 13062, § 6, <date date="1997-09-29">Sept. 29, 1997</date>, 62 F.R. 51756, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including sections 3301 and 3302 of title 5 and <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref> of the United States Code, and in order to permit certain overseas employees to acquire competitive status upon returning to the United States, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. A United States citizen who is a family member of a Federal civilian employee who has separated from Federal service to accept employment with the American Institute in Taiwan pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/96/8/s11">section 11 of Public Law 96–8</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3310/a">22 U.S.C. 3310(a)</ref>) may be appointed noncompetitively in a manner similar to noncompetitive appointments under Executive Order 12721 [<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3301">5 U.S.C. 3301</ref> note] and implementing regulations of the Office of Personnel Management to a competitive service position in the executive branch, provided such family member meets the qualifications and other requirements established by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, including an appropriate period of satisfactory overseas employment with the American Institute in Taiwan.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. The Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to implement this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. This order shall be effective upon publication in the Federal Register.</p>
<signature>
<name>William J. Clinton.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
