<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9043d7eb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3713"><num value="3713">§ 3713.</num><heading> Panama Canal emergency authority</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If authorizing legislation described in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3712/b/1">section 3712(b)(1) of this title</ref> has not been enacted for a fiscal year, then the Commission may withdraw funds from the Panama Canal Revolving Fund in order to defray emergency expenses and to ensure the continuous, efficient, and safe operation of the Panama Canal, including expenses for capital projects. The authority of this section may be exercised only until authorizing legislation described in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3712/b/1">section 3712(b)(1) of this title</ref> is enacted, or for a period of 24 months after the end of the fiscal year for which such authorizing legislation was last enacted, whichever occurs first. Within 60 days after the end of any calendar quarter in which expenditures are made under this section, the Commission shall report such expenditures to the appropriate committees of the Congress.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id9043d7ec-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/70/tI/s1303">Pub. L. 96–70, title I, § 1303</ref>, <date date="1979-09-27">Sept. 27, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/478">93 Stat. 478</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tV/s5423/a">Pub. L. 100–203, title V, § 5423(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-273">101 Stat. 1330–273</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dC/tXXXV/s3529/2">Pub. L. 104–106, div. C, title XXXV, § 3529(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/642">110 Stat. 642</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dC/tXXXV/s3548/b/2">Pub. L. 104–201, div. C, title XXXV, § 3548(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2869">110 Stat. 2869</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9043d7ed-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9043d7ee-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9043d7ef-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—<ref href="/us/pl/104/201">Pub. L. 104–201</ref> substituted “section 3712(b)(1)” for “section 3712(c)(1)” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/106">Pub. L. 104–106</ref> struck out “The authority of this section may not be used for administrative expenses.” after “capital projects.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—<ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref> substituted “authority” for “Fund” in section catchline and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(a) On <date date="1979-10-01">October 1, 1979</date>, the Secretary of the Treasury shall establish and thereafter shall maintain in the Treasury a fund to be known as the ‘Panama Canal Emergency Fund’. There are authorized to be appropriated for deposit in such Fund (1) for the fiscal year beginning on <date date="1979-10-01">October 1, 1979</date>, $40,000,000, and (2) for any fiscal year beginning on or after <date date="1980-10-01">October 1, 1980</date>, such additional sums as may be specifically authorized by law for such fiscal year.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(b) The Commission may make withdrawals from the Panama Canal Emergency Fund by check in order to defray emergency expenses and to insure the continuous, efficient, and safe operation of the Panama Canal, if funds appropriated for the operation and maintenance of the Canal are insufficient for such purposes. Any withdrawal from such Fund to cover increased costs attributable to unprogrammed increases in traffic may not be made in amounts greater than the revenues from such increased traffic. Such Fund shall not be available for payments to Panama under Article XIII of the Panama Canal Treaty of 1977. Any withdrawal from such fund or expenditure made under this subsection shall be reported forthwith by the Commission to the Congress and to the Office of Management and Budget.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9043d7f0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9043d7f1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1987 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref> effective <date date="1988-01-01">Jan. 1, 1988</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/s5429">section 5429 of Pub. L. 100–203</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3712">section 3712 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
