<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id904d4d54-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3922a"><num value="3922a">§ 3922a.</num><heading> Representation of minorities and women in Foreign Service</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id904d4d55-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3922a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Development of program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The head of each agency utilizing the Foreign Service personnel system shall develop, consistent with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7201">section 7201 of title 5</ref>, a plan designed to increase significantly the number of members of minority groups and women in the Foreign Service in that agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id904d4d56-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3922a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Emphasis on mid-levels</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each plan developed pursuant to this section shall, consistent with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7201">section 7201 of title 5</ref>, place particular emphasis on achieving significant increases in the numbers of minority group members and women who are in the mid-levels of the Foreign Service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id904d4d57-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/93/tI/s152">Pub. L. 99–93, title I, § 152</ref>, <date date="1985-08-16">Aug. 16, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/428">99 Stat. 428</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/204/tI/s185/c/3">Pub. L. 100–204, title I, § 185(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1366">101 Stat. 1366</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id904d4d58-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id904d4d59-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id904d4d5a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1986 and 1987, and not as part of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id904d4d5b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/100/204">Pub. L. 100–204</ref> struck out subsec. (c) which read as follows: “The head of each agency utilizing the Foreign Service personnel system shall report annually to the Congress on the plan developed pursuant to this section as part of the report required to be submitted pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3905/d/2">section 3905(d)(2) of this title</ref>. Subsequent reports pursuant to that section shall include reports on the implementation of these plans, giving particular attention to the progress being made in increasing, through advancement and promotion, the numbers of members of minority groups and women in the mid-levels of the Foreign Service.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id904d4d5c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id904d4d5d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report Concerning Minorities and the Foreign Service</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dG">Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. B, title XXIII, § 2318, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-829">112 Stat. 2681–829</ref>, required the Secretary of State to submit, in calendar years 1998 and 1999, a report to Congress concerning minorities and the Foreign Service officer corps, with relevant information and specified data.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id904d4d5e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Mid-Level Women and Minority Placement Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/236/tI/s178">Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 178</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/414">108 Stat. 414</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/236/tI/s178">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading><content>It is the purpose of this section to promote the acquisition and retention of highly qualified, trained, and experienced women and minority personnel within the Foreign Service, to provide the maximum opportunity for the Foreign Service to meet staffing needs and to acquire the services of experienced and talented women and minority personnel, and to help alleviate the impact of downsizing, reduction-in-force, and budget restrictions occurring in the defense and national security-related agencies of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><content>For each of the fiscal years 1994 and 1995, the Secretary of State shall to the maximum extent practicable appoint to the Foreign Service qualified women and minority applicants who are participants in the priority placement program of the Department of Defense, the Department of Defense out-placement referral program, the Office of Personnel Management Automated Applicant Referral System, or the Office of Personnel Management Interagency Placement Program. The Secretary shall make such appointments through the mid-level entry program of the Department of State under section 306 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3946">22 U.S.C. 3946</ref>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>], the Secretary of State shall prepare and submit a report concerning the implementation of subsection (a) to the Chairman of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives. Such report shall include recommendations on methods to improve implementation of the purpose of this section.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id904d4d5f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Women and Minorities in Foreign Service</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/204/tI/s183">Pub. L. 100–204, title I, § 183</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1364">101 Stat. 1364</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/204/tI/s183">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Congress finds that the Department of State and other Foreign Service agencies have not been successful in their efforts—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to recruit and retain members of minority groups in order to increase significantly the number of members of minority groups in the Foreign Service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to provide adequate career advancement for women and members of minority groups in order to increase significantly the numbers of women and members of minority groups in the senior levels of the Foreign Service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">A More Representative Foreign Service</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of State and the head of each of the other agencies utilizing the Foreign Service personnel system—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> shall substantially increase their efforts to implement effectively the plans required by section 152(a) of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1986 and 1987 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3922a/a">22 U.S.C. 3922a(a)</ref>], so that the Foreign Service becomes truly representative of the American people throughout all levels of the Foreign Service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> shall ensure that those plans effectively address the need to promote increased numbers of qualified women and members of minority groups into the senior levels of the Foreign Service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Department of State Hiring Practices of Minorities and Women</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of State shall include annually as part of the report required to be submitted pursuant to section 105(d)(2) of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 [former <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3905/d/2">22 U.S.C. 3905(d)(2)</ref>]—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> a report on the progress made at the Assistant Secretary and Bureau level of the Department of State in increasing the presence of minorities and women at all levels in the Foreign Service and Civil Service workforces of the Department of State, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the specific actions taken to address the lack of Hispanic Americans, Asian Americans, and Native Americans in the Senior Executive Service and Senior Foreign Service of the Department of State.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
