<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id904d4d88-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3925"><num value="3925">§ 3925.</num><heading> Compatibility between Foreign Service and other Government personnel systems</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Service shall be administered to the extent practicable in conformity with general policies and regulations of the Government. The Secretary shall consult with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and the heads of such other agencies as the President shall determine, in order to assure compatibility of the Foreign Service personnel system with other Government personnel systems to the extent practicable.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id904d4d89-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/465/tI/s205">Pub. L. 96–465, title I, § 205</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2079">94 Stat. 2079</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id904d4d8a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id904d4d8b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id904d4d8c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of President under this section delegated to Secretary of State, see section 1 of Ex. Ord. No. 12293, <date date="1981-02-23">Feb. 23, 1981</date>, 46 F.R. 13969, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3901">section 3901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id904d4d8d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Consultation With Other Federal Departments and Agencies</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For authority for the Secretary of State to consult with the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Commerce, the Director of the United States Information Agency, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to ensure compatibility between the Foreign Service personnel system and other government personnel systems, see section 2 of Ex. Ord. No. 12293, <date date="1981-02-23">Feb. 23, 1981</date>, 46 F.R. 13969, as amended, set out as note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3901">section 3901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
