<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id904d4d8e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3926"><num value="3926">§ 3926.</num><heading> Regulations; delegation of functions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id904d4d8f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3926/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Secretary may prescribe such regulations as the Secretary deems appropriate to carry out functions under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id904d4d90-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3926/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The Secretary may delegate functions under this chapter which are vested in the Secretary to any employee of the Department or any member of the Service.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id904d4d91-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/465/tI/s206">Pub. L. 96–465, title I, § 206</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2079">94 Stat. 2079</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id904d4d92-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id904d4d93-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id904d4d94-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations Regarding Foreign Language Competence Within Foreign Service</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/236/tI/s191/a">Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 191(a)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/418">108 Stat. 418</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/103/415/s1/u">Pub. L. 103–415, § 1(u)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4302">108 Stat. 4302</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/415/s1/u">
<inline>“Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>], the Secretary of State shall promulgate regulations—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> establishing hiring preferences for Foreign Service Officer candidates competent in languages, with priority preference given to those languages in which the Department of State has a deficit;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> establishing a standard that employees will not receive long-term training in more than 3 languages, and requiring that employees achieve full professional proficiency (S4/R4) in 1 language as a condition for training in a third, with exceptions for priority needs of the service at the discretion of the Director General;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> requiring that employees receiving long-term training in a language, or hired with a hiring preference for a language, serve at least 2 tours in jobs requiring that language, with exceptions for certain limited-use languages and priority needs of the service at the discretion of the Director General;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> requiring that significant consideration be given to foreign language competence and use in the evaluation, assignment, and promotion of all Foreign Service Officers of the Department of State, the Agency for International Development, and the United States Information Agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> requiring the identification of appropriate Washington, D.C. metropolitan area positions as language-designated; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> requiring remedial training and suspension of language differential payments for employees receiving such payments who have failed to maintain required levels of proficiency.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For abolition of United States Information Agency (other than Broadcasting Board of Governors and International Broadcasting Bureau), transfer of functions, and treatment of references thereto, see sections 6531, 6532, and 6551 of this title.]</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
