<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id904fbea6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s3950"><num value="3950">§ 3950.</num><heading> Reemployment rights following limited appointment</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any employee of an agency who accepts a limited appointment in the Service with the consent of the head of the agency in which the employee is employed shall be entitled, upon the termination of such limited appointment, to be reemployed in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3597">section 3597 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id904fbea7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/465/tI/s310">Pub. L. 96–465, title I, § 310</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2087">94 Stat. 2087</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id904fbea8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id904fbea9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id904fbeaa-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Entitlement to Benefits for Services Performed Outside United States; Service Exceeding Thirty Months</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Persons appointed, employed, or assigned after <date date="1959-05-19">May 19, 1959</date>, under former <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1787/c">section 1787(c) of this title</ref> or <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2385/d">section 2385(d) of this title</ref> for the purpose of performing functions under the Mutual Security Act of 1954 (see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1754">section 1754 of this title</ref>) and the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (section 2151 et seq. of this title) outside the United States shall not, unless otherwise agreed by the agency in which such benefits may be exercised, be entitled to the benefits provided for by this section in cases in which their service under the appointment, employment, or assignment exceeds thirty months. See Ex. Ord. No. 12163, § 1–602(b), <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 56677, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2381">section 2381 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
