<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90595b10-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028"><num value="4028">§ 4028.</num><heading> Training for Foreign Service officers</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90595b11-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Human rights, religious freedom, and human trafficking training</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90595b12-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary of State, with the assistance of other relevant officials, such as the Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom appointed under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6411/b">section 6411(b) of this title</ref>, the Director of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking, and the director of the George P. Shultz National Foreign Affairs Training Center, shall establish as part of the standard training provided after <date date="1999-01-01">January 1, 1999</date>, for officers of the Service, including chiefs of mission, instruction in the field of internationally recognized human rights. Such training shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90595b13-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> instruction on international documents and United States policy in human rights, which shall be mandatory for all members of the Service having reporting responsibilities relating to human rights and for chiefs of mission;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90595b14-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> instruction on the internationally recognized right to freedom of religion, the nature, activities, and beliefs of different religions, and the various aspects and manifestations of violations of religious freedom;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90595b15-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> instruction on international documents and United States policy on trafficking in persons, including provisions of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (division A of <ref href="/us/pl/106/386">Public Law 106–386</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7101">22 U.S.C. 7101</ref> et seq.) which may affect the United States bilateral relationships; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90595b16-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> for Foreign Service Officers who will be assigned to a country experiencing or at risk of mass atrocities, as determined by the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence and relevant civil society organizations, instruction on recognizing patterns of escalation and early warning signs of potential atrocities, and methods of preventing and responding to atrocities, including conflict assessment methods, peacebuilding, mediation for prevention, early action and response, and appropriate transitional justice measures to address atrocities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90595b17-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Religious freedom training</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90595b18-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/a/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In carrying out the training required under paragraph (1)(B), the Director of the George P. Shultz National Foreign Affairs Training Center shall, not later than the one year after <date date="2016-12-16">December 16, 2016</date>, conduct training on religious freedom for all Foreign Service officers, including all entry level officers, all officers prior to departure for posting outside the United States, and all outgoing deputy chiefs of mission and ambassadors. Such training shall be included in—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90595b19-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/a/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the A–100 course attended by all Foreign Service officers;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90595b1a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/a/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the courses required of every Foreign Service officer prior to a posting outside the United States, with segments tailored to the particular religious demography, religious freedom conditions, and United States strategies for advancing religious freedom, in each receiving country; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90595b1b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/a/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the courses required of all outgoing deputy chiefs of mission and ambassadors.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90595b1c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/a/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Development of curriculum</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In carrying out the training required under paragraph (1)(B), the Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom, in coordination with the Director of the George P. Shultz National Foreign Affairs Training Center and other Federal officials, as appropriate, and in consultation with the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom established under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6431/a">section 6431(a) of this title</ref>, shall make recommendations to the Secretary of State regarding a curriculum for the training of United States Foreign Service officers under paragraph (1)(B) on the scope and strategic value of international religious freedom, how violations of international religious freedom harm fundamental United States interests, how the advancement of international religious freedom can advance such interests, how United States international religious freedom policy should be carried out in practice by United States diplomats and other Foreign Service officers, and the relevance and relationship of international religious freedom to United States defense, diplomacy, development, and public affairs efforts. The Secretary of State should ensure the availability of sufficient resources to develop and implement such curriculum.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90595b1d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/a/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Information sharing</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The curriculum and training materials developed under this paragraph shall be shared with the United States Armed Forces and other Federal departments and agencies with personnel who are stationed overseas, as appropriate, to provide training on—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90595b1e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/a/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> United States religious freedom policies;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90595b1f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/a/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> religious traditions;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90595b20-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/a/2/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> religious engagement strategies;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90595b21-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/a/2/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> religious and cultural issues; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90595b22-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/a/2/C/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> efforts to counter violent religious extremism.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90595b23-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Refugees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall provide sessions on refugee law and adjudications and on religious persecution to each individual seeking a commission as a United States consular officer. The Secretary shall also ensure that any member of the Service who is assigned to a position that may be called upon to assess requests for consideration for refugee admissions, including any consular officer, has completed training on refugee law and refugee adjudications in addition to the training required in this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90595b24-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Child soldiers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of State, with the assistance of other relevant officials, shall establish as part of the standard training provided for chiefs of mission, deputy chiefs of mission, and other officers of the Service who are or will be involved in the assessment of child soldier use or the drafting of the annual Human Rights Report instruction on matters related to child soldiers, and the substance of the Child Soldiers Prevention Act of 2008.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90595b25-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Economic and commercial diplomacy</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of State, with the assistance of other relevant officials and the private sector, shall establish as part of the standard training provided for economic and commercial officers of the Foreign Service, chiefs of mission, and deputy chiefs of mission, training on matters related to economic and commercial diplomacy, with particular attention to market access and other elements of an enabling framework for United States businesses, commercial advocacy, and United States foreign economic policy, in addition to awareness about the support of the United States Government available to United States businesses, including support provided by the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Commerce, the Export-Import Bank of the United States, the Millennium Challenge Corporation, the Trade and Development Agency, the Department of the Treasury, the United States Agency for International Development, and the United States International Development Finance Corporation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90595b26-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Training in multilateral diplomacy</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90595b27-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary, in consultation with other senior officials as appropriate, shall establish training courses on—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90595b28-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the conduct of diplomacy at international organizations and other multilateral institutions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90595b29-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> broad-based multilateral negotiations of international instruments.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90595b2a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4028/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Required training</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Members of the Service, including appropriate chiefs of mission and other officers who are assigned to United States missions representing the United States to international organizations and other multilateral institutions or who are assigned in other positions that have as their primary responsibility formulation of policy related to such organizations and institutions, or participation in negotiations of international instruments, shall receive specialized training in the areas described in paragraph (1) prior to the beginning of service for such assignment or, if receiving such training at that time is not practical, within the first year of beginning such assignment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id90595b2b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/465/tI/s708">Pub. L. 96–465, title I, § 708</ref>, as added and amended <ref href="/us/pl/105/292/tI/s104">Pub. L. 105–292, title I, § 104</ref>, title VI, § 602(b), <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2795">112 Stat. 2795</ref>, 2812; <ref href="/us/pl/107/132/s2/b">Pub. L. 107–132, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-16">Jan. 16, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/2412">115 Stat. 2412</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/164/tI/s104/d">Pub. L. 109–164, title I, § 104(d)</ref>, <date date="2006-01-10">Jan. 10, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3565">119 Stat. 3565</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/457/tIV/s406">Pub. L. 110–457, title IV, § 406</ref>, <date date="2008-12-23">Dec. 23, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/5091">122 Stat. 5091</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/281/tI/s103/a">Pub. L. 114–281, title I, § 103(a)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1430">130 Stat. 1430</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/441/s4">Pub. L. 115–441, § 4</ref>, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5587">132 Stat. 5587</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dJ/tVII/s705">Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title VII, § 705</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3071">133 Stat. 3071</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dF/tLXVII/s6702/a">Pub. L. 118–31, div. F, title LXVII, § 6702(a)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/1015">137 Stat. 1015</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id90595b2c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id90595b2d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id90595b2e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000, referred to in subsec. (a)(1)(C), is div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/106/386">Pub. L. 106–386</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1466">114 Stat. 1466</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 78 (§ 7101 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7101">section 7101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Child Soldiers Prevention Act of 2008, referred to in subsec. (c), is title IV of <ref href="/us/pl/110/457">Pub. L. 110–457</ref>, <date date="2008-12-23">Dec. 23, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/5087">122 Stat. 5087</ref>, which is classified principally to sections 2370c to 2370c–2 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 2008 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">section 2151 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id90595b2f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2023—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/118/31">Pub. L. 118–31</ref> added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (a)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/115/441">Pub. L. 115–441</ref> added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94">Pub. L. 116–94</ref> added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/114/281/s103/a/1">Pub. L. 114–281, § 103(a)(1)</ref>, inserted subsec. heading, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and inserted par. heading, redesignated former pars. (1) to (3) as subpars. (A) to (C), respectively, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/114/281/s103/a/2">Pub. L. 114–281, § 103(a)(2)</ref>, (3), inserted headings.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/110/457">Pub. L. 110–457</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/109/164">Pub. L. 109–164</ref> inserted “, the Director of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking,” after “<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6411/b">section 6411(b) of this title</ref>” in introductory provisions and added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/107/132">Pub. L. 107–132</ref> inserted “George P. Shultz” after “director of the” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—<ref href="/us/pl/105/292/s602/b">Pub. L. 105–292, § 602(b)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id90595b30-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id90595b31-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/110/457">Pub. L. 110–457</ref> effective 180 days after <date date="2008-12-23">Dec. 23, 2008</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/457/s407">section 407 of Pub. L. 110–457</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2370c">section 2370c of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90595b32-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Economic and Commercial Diplomacy Training</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/47/dF/tVII/s7028/b">Pub. L. 118–47, div. F, title VII, § 7028(b)</ref>, <date date="2024-03-23">Mar. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/778">138 Stat. 778</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/47/dF/tVII/s7028/b">“In carrying out section 705 of title VII of division J of <ref href="/us/pl/116/94">Public Law 116–94</ref> [amending this section], the Secretary of State shall annually assess training needs across the economic and commercial diplomacy issue areas and ensure, after a review of course offerings, course attendance records, and course evaluation results, that current offerings meet training needs.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90595b33-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Training for Department Employees</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/31/dF/tLXVII/s6702/b">Pub. L. 118–31, div. F, title LXVII, § 6702(b)</ref>, <date date="2023-12-22">Dec. 22, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/137/1015">137 Stat. 1015</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/31/dF/tLXVII/s6702/b">“The Secretary of State shall ensure that employees of the Department of State who are assigned to positions described in paragraph (2) of subsection (e) of section 708 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4028/e/2">22 U.S.C. 4028(e)(2)</ref>] (as added by subsection (a) of this section), including members of the civil service or general service, or who are seconded to international organizations for a period of at least one year, receive training described in such subsection and participate in other such courses as the Secretary may recommend to build or augment identifiable skills that would be useful for such Department officials representing United States interests at these institutions and organizations.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
