<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90605f99-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4053"><num value="4053">§ 4053.</num><heading> Reassignment and retirement of former Presidential appointees</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90605f9a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4053/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Reassignment or retirement of participants not eligible for retirement</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A participant, who completes an assignment under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3942/b">section 3942(b) of this title</ref> in a position to which the participant was appointed by the President, and is not otherwise eligible for retirement—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90605f9b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4053/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> shall be reassigned within 90 days after the termination of such assignment and any period of authorized leave, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90605f9c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4053/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> if the Secretary of State determines that reassignment is not in the interest of the Foreign Service, shall be retired from the Service and receive retirement benefits in accordance with section 4046 or 4071d of this title, as appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90605f9d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4053/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Retirement of participants eligible for retirement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A participant who completes an assignment under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3942/b">section 3942(b) of this title</ref> in a position to which the participant was appointed by the President and is eligible for retirement and is not reassigned within 90 days after the termination of such assignment and any period of authorized leave, shall be retired from the Service and receive retirement benefits in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4046">section 4046 of this title</ref> or <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4071d">section 4071d of this title</ref>, as appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90605f9e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4053/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Retirement of reemployed participants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A participant who is retired under subsection (a)(2) and is subsequently employed by the United States Government, thereafter, shall be eligible to retire only under the terms of the applicable retirement system.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id90605f9f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/465/tI/s813">Pub. L. 96–465, title I, § 813</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2113">94 Stat. 2113</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/138/tI/s149">Pub. L. 102–138, title I, § 149</ref>, <date date="1991-10-28">Oct. 28, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/670">105 Stat. 670</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/tI/s174">Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 174</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/413">108 Stat. 413</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id90605fa0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id90605fa1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id90605fa2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref> added subsecs. (a) to (c) and struck out former subsecs. (a) to (c) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(a) Except as provided under subsection (b) of this section, a participant, who completes an assignment under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3942/b">section 3942(b) of this title</ref> in a position to which he or she was appointed by the President, shall be offered reassignment within 90 days after the termination of such assignment and any period of authorized leave.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(b) Subsection (a) of this section shall not apply with respect to a participant, if the Secretary of State determines that reassignment of the participant is not in the interest of the United States and the Foreign Service.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(c) A participant who is not reassigned under subsection (a) of this section shall be retired from the Service and receive retirement benefits in accordance with section 4046 or 4071d of this title, as appropriate.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—<ref href="/us/pl/102/138">Pub. L. 102–138</ref> inserted “Reassignment and” in section catchline and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “If a participant completes an assignment under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3942/b">section 3942(b) of this title</ref> in a position to which he or she was appointed by the President and has not been reassigned within 3 months after the termination of such assignment (plus any period of authorized leave), the participant shall be retired from the Service and receive retirement benefits in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4046">section 4046 of this title</ref>.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
