<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90605ffc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056"><num value="4056">§ 4056.</num><heading> Creditable service</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90605ffd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability of civil service provisions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id90605ffe-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002286">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002286"><num>1</num> See Amendment of Section note below.</note> Except as otherwise specified by law, all periods of civilian and military and naval service, and all other periods through the date of final separation of a participant from the Service that the Secretary of State determines would be creditable toward retirement under the Civil Service Retirement and Disability System (as determined in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8332">section 8332 of title 5</ref>), shall be creditable for purposes of this part. Conversely, any such service performed after <date date="1976-12-31">December 31, 1976</date>, that would not be creditable under specified conditions under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8332">section 8332 of title 5</ref>, shall be excluded under this part under the same conditions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id90605fff-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The service of an individual who first becomes a participant on or after <date date="1983-10-17">October 17, 1983</date>, without any credit under this section for civilian service performed prior to <date date="1982-10-01">October 1, 1982</date>, shall include credit for:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90606000-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> each period of military or naval service performed before <date date="1957-01-01">January 1, 1957</date>, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90606001-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> each period of military or naval service performed after <date date="1956-12-31">December 31, 1956</date>, and before the separation on which the entitlement to annuity under this part is based, only if a deposit (with interest if any is required) is made with respect to that period, as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4045/e">section 4045(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id90606002-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The service of an individual who first became a participant on or after <date date="1983-10-17">October 17, 1983</date>, with credit under this section for civilian service performed prior to October 1982, shall include credit for each period of military or naval service performed before the date of the separation on which the entitlement to an annuity under this part is based, subject, in the case of military or naval service performed after December 1956, to subsection (j).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id90606003-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The service of an individual who first became a participant before <date date="1983-10-17">October 17, 1983</date>, shall include credit for each period of military or naval service performed before the date of the separation on which the entitlement to an annuity under this part is based, subject, in the case of military or naval service performed after December 1976, to subsection (j).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90606004-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Unused sick leave credit</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In computing any annuity under this part, the total service of a participant who retires on an immediate annuity or who dies leaving a survivor or survivors entitled to annuity includes (without regard to the 35-year limitation imposed by <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4046/a">section 4046(a) of this title</ref>) the days of unused sick leave to the credit of the participant, except that these days shall not be counted in determining average basic salary or annuity eligibility under this part. A contribution to the Fund shall not be required from a participant for this service credit.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90606005-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Service with other Government agency when on approved leave without pay; arrangement for payment of retirement deductions and agency contributions; special contribution</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id90606006-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A participant who enters on approved leave without pay to serve as a full-time officer or employee of an organization composed primarily of Government employees may, within 60 days after entering on that leave without pay, file with the employing agency an election to receive full retirement credit for such periods of leave without pay and arrange to pay concurrently into the Fund through the employing agency, amounts equal to the retirement deductions and agency contributions on the Foreign Service salary rate that would be applicable if the participant were in a pay status. If the election and all payments provided by this subsection are not made for the periods of such leave without pay occurring after <date date="1976-11-07">November 7, 1976</date>, the participant may not receive any credit for such periods of leave without pay occurring after such date.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id90606007-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A participant may make a special contribution for any period or periods of approved leave without pay while serving before <date date="1976-11-07">November 7, 1976</date>, as a full-time officer or employee of an organization composed primarily of Government employees. Any such contribution shall be based upon the suspended Foreign Service salary rate and shall be computed in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4045">section 4045 of this title</ref>. A participant who makes such contributions shall be allowed full retirement credit for the period or periods of leave without pay. If this contribution is not made, up to 6 months’ retirement credit shall be allowed for such periods of leave without pay each calendar year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90606008-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Special contribution in repayment of refund of retirement contributions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0"><sup>1</sup> A participant who has received a refund of retirement contributions (which has not been repaid) under this or any other retirement system for Government employees covering service which may be creditable may make a special contribution for such service under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4045">section 4045 of this title</ref>. Credit may not be allowed for service covered by the refund unless the special contribution is made.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90606009-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Civilian service under other Government retirement system</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No credit in annuity computation shall be allowed for any period of civilian service for which a participant made retirement contributions to another retirement system for Government employees unless—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9060600a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the right to any annuity under the other system which is based on such service is waived, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9060600b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a special contribution is made under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4045">section 4045 of this title</ref> covering such service.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9060600c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Service in military during period of war or national emergency</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A participant who during a period of war, or national emergency proclaimed by the President or declared by the Congress, leaves the Service to enter the military service is deemed, for the purpose of this part, as not separated from the Service unless the participant applies for and receives a lump-sum payment under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4055">section 4055 of this title</ref>. However, the participant is deemed to be separated from the Service after the expiration of 5 years of such military service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9060600d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Recomputation of annuity for participants of Japanese ancestry interned during World War II</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9060600e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An annuity or survivor annuity based on the service of a participant of Japanese ancestry who would be eligible under section 8332(<i>l</i>) of title 5, for credit for civilian service for periods of internment during World War II shall, upon application to the Secretary of State, be recomputed to give credit for that service. Any such recomputation of an annuity shall apply with respect to months beginning more than 30 days after the date on which application for such recomputation is received by the Secretary of State.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9060600f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary of State shall take such action as may be necessary and appropriate to inform individuals entitled to have any service credited or annuity recomputed under this subsection of their entitlement to such credit or recomputation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id90606010-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary of State shall, on request, assist any individual referred to in paragraph (1) in obtaining from any agency or other Government establishment information necessary to verify the entitlement of the individual to have any service credited or any annuity recomputed under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id90606011-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Any agency or other Government establishment shall, upon request, furnish to the Secretary of State any information it possesses with respect to the internment or other detention, as described in section 8332(<i>l</i>) of title 5, of any participant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90606012-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Service as employees of Member or office of Congress while on approved leave without pay</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A participant who, while on approved leave without pay, serves as a full-time paid employee of a Member or office of the Congress shall continue to make contributions to the Fund based upon the Foreign Service salary rate that would be in effect if the participant were in a pay status. The participant’s employing office in the Congress shall make a matching contribution (from the appropriation or fund which is used for payment of the salary of the participant) to the Treasury of the United States to the credit of the Fund. All periods of service for which full contributions to the Fund are made under this subsection shall be counted as creditable service for purposes of this part and shall not, unless all retirement credit is transferred, be counted as creditable service under any other Government retirement system.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90606013-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Former spouses</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id90606014-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Service of a participant shall be considered creditable service for purposes of applying provisions of this part relating to former spouses if such service would be creditable—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90606015-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/i/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> under subsection (c)(1) or (2) but for the fact an election was not made under subsection (c)(1) or a special contribution was not made under subsection (c)(2), and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90606016-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/i/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> under subsection (d) but for the fact that a refund of contributions has not been repaid unless the former spouse received under this part a portion of the lump sum (or a spousal agreement or court order provided otherwise).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id90606017-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A former spouse shall not be considered as married to a participant for periods assumed to be creditable service under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4048/a">section 4048(a) of this title</ref> or <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4049/e">section 4049(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90606018-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Redetermination of credit for military and naval service</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id90606019-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as otherwise provided by statute or Executive Order, <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8332/j">section 8332(j) of title 5</ref>, relating to redetermination of credit for military and naval service, shall be applied to annuities payable under this part. The Secretary of State shall redetermine service, and may request and obtain information from the Secretary of Health and Human Services, as the Office of Personnel Management is directed or authorized to do in section 8332(j).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9060601a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8332/j">Section 8332(j) of title 5</ref> shall not apply with respect to:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9060601b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/j/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the service of any individual who first became a participant on or after <date date="1983-10-17">October 17, 1983</date>, without any credit under this section for civilian service performed prior to October 1982; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9060601c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/j/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any military or naval service performed prior to 1957 by an individual who first became a participant on or after <date date="1983-10-17">October 17, 1983</date>, with credit under this section for civilian service performed prior to October 1982, or any period of military or naval service performed after 1956 with respect to which the participant has made a contribution (with interest if any is required) under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4045/e">section 4045(e) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9060601d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4056/j/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> any military or naval service performed prior to 1977 by any individual who first became a participant before <date date="1983-10-17">October 17, 1983</date>, or any period of military or naval service performed after 1976 with respect to which the participant has made a contribution (with interest if any is required) under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4045/e">section 4045(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9060601e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/465/tI/s816">Pub. L. 96–465, title I, § 816</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2118">94 Stat. 2118</ref>; Ex. Ord. No. 12446, § 4(b), (c), <date date="1983-10-17">Oct. 17, 1983</date>, 48 F.R. 48444, 48445; <ref href="/us/pl/99/335/tIV/s402/a/2">Pub. L. 99–335, title IV, § 402(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-06">June 6, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/609">100 Stat. 609</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/246/tI/s145/a">Pub. L. 101–246, title I, § 145(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-02-16">Feb. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/36">104 Stat. 36</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9060601f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I84" topic="prospectiveAmendment" id="id90606020-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered fontsize8 smallCaps">Amendment of Section</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">Ex. Ord. No. 12446, § 5, <date date="1983-10-17">Oct. 17, 1983</date>, 48 F.R. 48445, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4067">section 4067 of this title</ref>, provided that:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I42" class="indent0 fontsize8 italic">“(a) Section 816(a) of the Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4056/a">22 U.S.C. 4056(a)</ref>) is deemed to be further amended so that the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8332/j">section 8332(j) of Title 5</ref> of the United States Code, relating to credit for military service, shall not apply with respect to any individual who is entitled to an annuity under such Act [this chapter] on or before the date of approval of this Order [<date date="1983-10-17">Oct. 17, 1983</date>], or who is entitled to an annuity based on a separation from service occurring on or before such date.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I42" class="indent0 fontsize8 italic">“(b) Subject to subsection (c), in any case in which an individual described in subsection (a) is also entitled to old-age or survivors insurance benefits under section 202 of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s402">42 U.S.C. 402</ref>] (or would be entitled to such benefits upon filing application therefor), the amount of the annuity to which such individual is entitled under chapter 8 of the Act [this subchapter] (after taking into account subsection (a)) which is payable for any month shall be reduced by an amount determined by multiplying the amount of such old-age or survivors insurance benefit for the determination month by a fraction—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I57" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">“(1) the numerator of which is the total of the wages (within the meaning of section 209 of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s409">42 U.S.C. 409</ref>]) for service referred to in section 210(1) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s410">42 U.S.C. 410</ref>] (relating to service in the uniformed services) and deemed additional wages (within the meaning of section 229 of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s429">42 U.S.C. 429</ref>]) of such individual credited for years after 1956 and before the calendar year in which the determination month occurs, up to the contribution and benefit base determined under section 230 of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s430">42 U.S.C. 430</ref>] (or other applicable maximum annual amount referred to in section 215(e)(1) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s415/e/1">42 U.S.C. 415(e)(1)</ref>]) for each such year, and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I57" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">“(2) the denominator of which is the total of all wages deemed additional wages described in paragraph (1) of this subsection plus all other wages (within the meaning of section 209 of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s409">42 U.S.C. 409</ref>]) and all self-employment income (within the meaning of section 211(b) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s411/b">42 U.S.C. 411(b)</ref>]) of such individual credited for years after 1936 and before the calendar year in which the determination month occurs, up to the contribution and benefit base (or such other amount referred to in such section 215(e)(1) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s415/e/1">42 U.S.C. 415(e)(1)</ref>]) for each such year.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I42" class="indent0 fontsize8 italic">“(c) Subsection (b) shall not reduce the annuity of any individual below the amount of the annuity which would be payable under chapter 8 of the Act [this subchapter] to the individual for the determination month if <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8332/j">section 8332(j) of Title 5</ref> of the United States Code applied to the individual for such month.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I42" class="indent0 fontsize8 italic">“(d) For purposes of this section, the term ‘determination month’ means—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I57" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">“(1) the first month the individual described in subsection (a) is entitled to old-age or survivors insurance benefits under section 202 of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s402">42 U.S.C. 402</ref>] (or would be entitled to such benefits upon filing application therefor); or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I57" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">“(2) the first day of the month following the month in which this Order is issued [Oct. 1983] in the case of any individual so entitled to such benefits for such month.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I42" class="indent0 fontsize8 italic">“(e) The preceding provisions of this section shall take effect with respect to any annuity payment payable under chapter 8 of the Act [this subchapter] for calendar months beginning after the date of this Order [<date date="1983-10-17">Oct. 17, 1983</date>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I42" class="indent0 fontsize8 italic">“(f) The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall furnish such information to the Secretary of State as may be necessary to carry out the preceding provisions of this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">Ex. Ord. No. 12446, § 1(b), (c), provided that subsection (d) of this section, applicable (i) to contributions for civilian service performed on or after the first day of Nov. 1983, (ii) to contributions for prior refunds to participants for which application is received by the employing agency on and after such first day of Nov. 1983, and (iii) to excess contributions under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4055/h">section 4055(h) of this title</ref> and voluntary contributions under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4065/a">section 4065(a) of this title</ref> from the first day of Nov. 1983, is deemed to be amended to exclude from the computation of creditable civilian service under subsec. (a) of this section any period of civilian service for which retirement deductions or contributions have not been made under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4045/d">section 4045(d) of this title</ref> unless—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(1) the participant makes a contribution for such period as provided in such <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4045/d">section 4045(d) of this title</ref>; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">(2) no contribution is required for such service as provided under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4045/f">section 4045(f) of this title</ref> as deemed to be amended by this Order, or under any other statute.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9062d121-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9062d122-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (i)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/246">Pub. L. 101–246</ref> amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “A former spouse shall not be considered as married to a participant—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) for periods assumed to be creditable service under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4048/a">section 4048(a) of this title</ref> or <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4049/e">section 4049(e) of this title</ref>, or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) for any extra period of creditable service provided under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4057">section 4057 of this title</ref> for service of a participant at an unhealthful post unless the former spouse resided with the participant at that post during that period.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsecs. (a), (b), (f), (h), (i)(1), (j)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/335">Pub. L. 99–335</ref> substituted “part” for “subchapter” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (a). Ex. Ord. No. 12446, § 4(b), designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added pars. (2) to (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). Ex. Ord. No. 12446, § 4(c), added subsec. (j).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9062d123-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9062d124-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/335">Pub. L. 99–335</ref> effective <date date="1987-01-01">Jan. 1, 1987</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/335/s702/a">section 702(a) of Pub. L. 99–335</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8401">section 8401 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9062d125-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1983 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 4 of Ex. Ord. No. 12446 effective <date date="1983-10-17">Oct. 17, 1983</date>, see section 4(e) of Ex. Ord. No. 12446, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4067">section 4067 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
