<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9062d1a6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4066"><num value="4066">§ 4066.</num><heading> Cost-of-living adjustment of annuities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9062d1a7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4066/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A cost-of-living annuity increase shall become effective under this section on the effective date of each such increase under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8340/b">section 8340(b) of title 5</ref>. Each such increase shall be applied to each annuity payable from the Fund under this part which has a commencing date not later than the effective date of the increase.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9062d1a8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4066/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability of increases under other provisions of law</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each annuity increase under this section shall be identical to the corresponding percentage increase under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8340/b">section 8340(b) of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9062d1a9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4066/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility for increases</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Eligibility for an annuity increase under this section shall be governed by the commencing date of each annuity payable from the Fund under this part as of the effective date of an increase except as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9062d1aa-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4066/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The first increase (if any) made under this section to an annuity which is payable from the Fund to a participant or to the surviving spouse or former spouse of a deceased participant who died in service or a deceased annuitant whose annuity was not increased under this section, shall be equal to the product (adjusted to the nearest ⅒ of 1 percent) of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9062d1ab-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4066/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> <sup>1</sup>⁄<sub>12</sub> of the applicable percent change computed under subsection (b) of this section, multiplied by</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9062d1ac-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4066/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> the number of months (counting any portion of a month as a month)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9062d1ad-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4066/c/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> for which the annuity was payable from the Fund before the effective date of the increase, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9062d1ae-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4066/c/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in the case of a surviving spouse or former spouse of a deceased annuitant whose annuity has not been so increased, since the annuity was first payable to the deceased annuitant.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9062d1af-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4066/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Effective from its commencing date, an annuity payable from the Fund under this part to the survivor of an annuitant, except a child entitled to an annuity under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4046/c">section 4046(c) of this title</ref> or section 4049(c) or (d) of this title, shall be increased by the total percentage increase the annuitant was receiving under this section at death.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9062d1b0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4066/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> For purposes of computing or recomputing an annuity to a child under section 4046(c) or (d) of this title or section 4049(c) or (d) of this title, the items $900, $1,080, $2,700, and $3,240 appearing in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4046/c">section 4046(c) of this title</ref> shall be increased by the total percentage increases by which corresponding amounts are being increased under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8340">section 8340 of title 5</ref> on the date the annuity of the child becomes effective.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9062d1b1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4066/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Exclusion of additional annuity purchased after retirement by voluntary contribution</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No increase in annuity provided by this section shall be computed on any additional annuity purchased at retirement by voluntary contributions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9062d1b2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4066/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Rounding off of amount; minimum increases</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The monthly installment of annuity after adjustment under this section shall be rounded to the next lowest dollar, except such installment shall after adjustment reflect an increase of at least $1.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9062d1b3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4066/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Rate of increase for surviving spouses of annuitants electing reduced annuity</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Effective from its commencing date, there shall be an increase of 10 percent in the annuity of each surviving spouse whose entitlement to annuity resulted from the death of an annuitant who, prior to <date date="1976-10-01">October 1, 1976</date>, elected a reduced annuity in order to provide a spouse’s survivor annuity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9062d1b4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4066/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Maximum annuity</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9062d1b5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4066/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> An annuity shall not be increased by reason of any adjustment under this section to an amount which exceeds the greater of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9062d1b6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4066/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the maximum pay rate payable for class FS–1 under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3963">section 3963 of this title</ref>, 30 days before the effective date of the adjustment under this section; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9062d1b7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4066/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> the final pay (or average pay, if higher) of the former participant with respect to whom the annuity is paid, increased by the overall annual average percentage adjustments (compounded) in rates of pay of the Foreign Service Schedule under such <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3963">section 3963 of this title</ref> during the period—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9062d1b8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4066/g/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> beginning on the date the annuity commenced (or, in the case of a survivor of the retired participant, the date the participant’s annuity commenced), and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9062d1b9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4066/g/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> ending on the effective date of the adjustment under this section.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9062d1ba-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4066/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> For the purposes of paragraph (1) of this subsection, “pay” means the rate of salary or basic pay as payable under any provision of law, including any provision of law limiting the expenditure of appropriated funds.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9062d1bb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/465/tI/s826">Pub. L. 96–465, title I, § 826</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2123">94 Stat. 2123</ref>; Ex. Ord. No. 12289, § 1, <date date="1981-02-14">Feb. 14, 1981</date>, 46 F.R. 12693; Ex. Ord. No. 12446, §§ 2(a), 6(a), <date date="1983-10-17">Oct. 17, 1983</date>, 48 F.R. 48443, 48446; <ref href="/us/pl/99/335/tIV/s402/a/3">Pub. L. 99–335, title IV, § 402(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1986-06-06">June 6, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/609">100 Stat. 609</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/238/tII/s219">Pub. L. 100–238, title II, § 219</ref>, <date date="1988-01-08">Jan. 8, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1775">101 Stat. 1775</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9062d1bc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9062d1bd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9062d1be-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/238">Pub. L. 100–238</ref> amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “The first increase (if any) made under this section to an annuity which is payable from the Fund under this part to a participant or to the surviving spouse of a deceased participant who dies in service shall be equal to the product (adjusted to the nearest ⅒ of 1 percent) of—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(a) ⅙ of the applicable percent change determined under subsection (b) of this section, multiplied by</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(b) the number of full months for which the annuity was payable from the Fund under this part before the effective date of the increase (counting any portion of a month as a full month).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">In the administration of this paragraph, the number of days of unused sick leave to the credit of a participant or deceased participant on the effective date of the then last preceding general annuity increase under this section shall be deemed to be equal to the number of days of unused sick leave to his or her credit on the day of separation from the Service.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsecs. (a), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/335">Pub. L. 99–335</ref> inserted “under this part” after “payable from the Fund” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (e). Ex. Ord. No. 12446, § 2(a), substituted “rounded to the next lowest” for “fixed at the nearest”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). Ex. Ord. No. 12446, § 6(a), added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (c)(1). Ex. Ord. No. 12289 amended first sentence of par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, first sentence read as follows: “An annuity (except a deferred annuity) payable from the Fund to a participant who retires and receives an immediate annuity, or to a surviving spouse or former spouse of a deceased participant who dies in service or who dies after being separated with benefits under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4009/b/2">section 4009(b)(2) of this title</ref>, which has a commencing date after the effective date of the then last preceding general annuity increase under this section shall not be less than the annuity which would have been payable if the commencing date of such annuity had been the effective date of such last preceding increase.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9062d1bf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9062d1c0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/238">Pub. L. 100–238</ref> effective 90 days after <date date="1988-01-08">Jan. 8, 1988</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/238/s261/a">section 261(a) of Pub. L. 100–238</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4054">section 4054 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9062d1c1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/335">Pub. L. 99–335</ref> effective <date date="1987-01-01">Jan. 1, 1987</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/335/s702/a">section 702(a) of Pub. L. 99–335</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8401">section 8401 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9062d1c2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1983 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 2(a) Ex. Ord. No. 12446 effective with respect to any adjustment or redetermination of any annuity made on or after <date date="1983-10-17">Oct. 17, 1983</date>, see section 2(b) of Ex. Ord. No. 12446, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4067">section 4067 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 6 of Ex. Ord. No. 12446 applicable to any adjustment occurring on or after <date date="1983-04-01">Apr. 1, 1983</date> under this section to any annuity payable from the Foreign Service Retirement and Disability Fund, whether such annuity has a commencing date before, on, or after <date date="1983-10-17">Oct. 17, 1983</date>, but shall not cause any annuity to be reduced below the rate that is payable on <date date="1983-10-17">Oct. 17, 1983</date>, see section 6(b) of Ex. Ord. No. 12446, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4067">section 4067 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9062d1c3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by Ex. Ord. No. 12289 effective <date date="1981-02-15">Feb. 15, 1981</date>, see section 3 of Ex. Ord. No. 12289, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4067">section 4067 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9062d1c4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Delay in Cost-of-Living Adjustments During Fiscal Years 1994, 1995, and 1996</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Any cost-of-living increase scheduled to take effect during fiscal year 1994, 1995, or 1996 under this section delayed until first day of third calendar month after date such increase would otherwise take effect, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/66/s11001">section 11001 of Pub. L. 103–66</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s8340">section 8340 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
