<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9069fd20-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4101"><num value="4101">§ 4101.</num><heading> Congressional findings and policy</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9069fd21-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4101/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> experience in both private and public employment indicates that the statutory protection of the right of workers to organize, bargain collectively, and participate through labor organizations of their own choosing in decisions which affect them—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9069fd22-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4101/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> safeguards the public interest,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9069fd23-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4101/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> contributes to the effective conduct of public business, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9069fd24-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4101/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> facilitates and encourages the amicable settlement of disputes between workers and their employers involving conditions of employment;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9069fd25-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4101/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the public interest demands the highest standards of performance by members of the Service and the continuous development and implementation of modern and progressive work practices to facilitate improved performance and efficiency; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9069fd26-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4101/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the unique conditions of Foreign Service employment require a distinct framework for the development and implementation of modern, constructive, and cooperative relationships between management officials and organizations representing members of the Service.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Therefore, labor organizations and collective bargaining in the Service are in the public interest and are consistent with the requirement of an effective and efficient Government. The provisions of this subchapter should be interpreted in a manner consistent with the requirement of an effective and efficient Government.</continuation>
<sourceCredit id="id9069fd27-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/465/tI/s1001">Pub. L. 96–465, title I, § 1001</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2128">94 Stat. 2128</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
