<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id906eb7ec-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4140"><num value="4140">§ 4140.</num><heading> Judicial review</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id906eb7ed-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4140/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Any aggrieved party may obtain judicial review of a final action of the Secretary or the Board on any grievance in the district courts of the United States in accordance with the standards set forth in chapter 7 of title 5, if the request for judicial review is filed not later than 180 days after the final action of the Secretary or the Board (or in the case of an aggrieved party who is posted abroad at the time of the final action of the Secretary or the Board, if the request for judicial review is filed not later than 180 days after the aggrieved party’s return to the United States). <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s706">Section 706 of title 5</ref> shall apply without limitation or exception. This subsection shall not apply to any grievance with respect to which subsection (b) applies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id906eb7ee-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4140/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id906eb7ef-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4140/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> For purposes of this subsection, the term “aggrieved party” means a grievant.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id906eb7f0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4140/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> With respect to a grievance based on an alleged violation of a law, rule, regulation, or policy directive referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4131/a/1/H">section 4131(a)(1)(H) of this title</ref>, judicial review of whether the act, omission, or condition that is the basis of the grievance violates such law, rule, regulation, or policy directive may be obtained by an aggrieved party only if such party commences a civil action, not later than 90 days after such party receives notice of the final action of the Secretary or the Board, in an appropriate district court of the United States for de novo review.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id906eb7f1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/465/tI/s1110">Pub. L. 96–465, title I, § 1110</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2148">94 Stat. 2148</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/138/tI/s153/e">Pub. L. 102–138, title I, § 153(e)</ref>, <date date="1991-10-28">Oct. 28, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/674">105 Stat. 674</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/tI/s177/b">Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 177(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/414">108 Stat. 414</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id906eb7f2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id906eb7f3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id906eb7f4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref> inserted before period at end of first sentence “, if the request for judicial review is filed not later than 180 days after the final action of the Secretary or the Board (or in the case of an aggrieved party who is posted abroad at the time of the final action of the Secretary or the Board, if the request for judicial review is filed not later than 180 days after the aggrieved party’s return to the United States)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—<ref href="/us/pl/102/138">Pub. L. 102–138</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), inserted provision that subsec. (a) not apply to any grievance with respect to which subsec. (b) applies, and added subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id906eb7f5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id906eb7f6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1991 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/138">Pub. L. 102–138</ref> not applicable with respect to any grievance, within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4131">section 4131 of this title</ref>, arising before <date date="1991-10-28">Oct. 28, 1991</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/138/s153/f">section 153(f) of Pub. L. 102–138</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4115">section 4115 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id906eb7f7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Judicial Review of Certain Foreign Service Grievances</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/246/tI/s152">Pub. L. 101–246, title I, § 152</ref>, <date date="1990-02-16">Feb. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/42">104 Stat. 42</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/246/tI/s152">“For the purposes of judicial review under section 1110 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4140">22 U.S.C. 4140</ref>], any recommendation made by the Foreign Service Grievance Board with respect to the tenure of a grievant which was reviewed by the Secretary of State before the date of enactment of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989 [<date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>], shall be considered to be a final action of the Department of State, and any such recommendation shall be considered to have been made within the authority of the Foreign Service Grievance Board.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
