<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90712985-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4171"><num value="4171">§ 4171.</num><heading> Model foreign language competence posts</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90712986-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4171/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Designation of posts; time of designation and implementation; determination of competency standards</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to carry out the purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4022">section 4022 of this title</ref> and to help ascertain the relationship between foreign language competence and the effectiveness of representation of the United States abroad, the Secretary of State shall designate as model foreign language competence posts at least two Foreign Service posts in countries where English is not the common language. Such designation shall be made no later than <date date="1981-10-01">October 1, 1981</date>, and shall be implemented so that no later than <date date="1983-10-01">October 1, 1983</date>, each Government employee permanently assigned to those posts shall possess an appropriate level of competence in the language common to the country where the post is located. The Secretary of State shall determine appropriate levels of language competence for employees assigned to those posts by reference to the nature of their functions and the standards employed by the George P. Shultz National Foreign Affairs Training Center.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90712987-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4171/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Continuation; report to Congress concerning operation of posts and advantages of meeting competency requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The posts designated under subsection (a) shall continue as model foreign language competence posts at least until <date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>. The Secretary of State shall submit no later than <date date="1986-01-31">January 31, 1986</date>, a report to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate describing the operation of such posts and the costs, advantages and disadvantages associated with meeting the foreign language competence requirements of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90712988-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4171/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Exceptions; report to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of State may authorize exceptions to the requirements of this section if he determines that unanticipated exigencies so require.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id90712989-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/465/tII/s2207">Pub. L. 96–465, title II, § 2207</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2163">94 Stat. 2163</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/tI/s139/7">Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 139(7)</ref>, (25), <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/398">108 Stat. 398</ref>, 399; <ref href="/us/pl/107/132/s1/b">Pub. L. 107–132, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-16">Jan. 16, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/2412">115 Stat. 2412</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9071298a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9071298b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9071298c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/107/132">Pub. L. 107–132</ref> substituted “George P. Shultz National Foreign Affairs Training Center” for “Foreign Service Institute”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s139/7">Pub. L. 103–236, § 139(7)</ref>, (25), amended subsec. (c) identically, striking out at end “Such exceptions shall be annually reported to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9071298d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id9071298e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Expansion of Model Foreign Language Competence Posts</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/246/tI/s161">Pub. L. 101–246, title I, § 161</ref>, <date date="1990-02-16">Feb. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/46">104 Stat. 46</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/101/302/tIII/s320/b/3">Pub. L. 101–302, title III, § 320(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1990-05-25">May 25, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/247">104 Stat. 247</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dG">Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XXII, § 2219(a)(1), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-817">112 Stat. 2681–817</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/132/s1/b">Pub. L. 107–132, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-01-16">Jan. 16, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/2412">115 Stat. 2412</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/132/s1/b">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Designation of Posts</inline>.—</heading><content>In order to carry out the purposes of section 702 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4022">22 U.S.C. 4022</ref>], and in light of the positive report issued on <date date="1986-03-28">March 28, 1986</date>, by the Department of State, as required by section 2207 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4171">22 U.S.C. 4171</ref>], the Secretary of State shall designate as model foreign language competence posts a minimum of six Foreign Service posts, representing the Department of State’s five geographic bureaus, in countries where English is not the common language. Such designation shall be made not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-02-16">Feb. 16, 1990</date>], and shall be implemented so that not later than <date date="1991-10-01">October 1, 1991</date>, in the case of non-hard language posts, and <date date="1992-10-01">October 1, 1992</date>, in the case of hard language posts, each Government employee permanently assigned to those posts shall possess an appropriate level of competence in the language common to the country where the post is located. The Secretary of State shall determine appropriate levels of language competence for employees assigned to those posts by reference to the nature of their functions and the standards employed by the George P. Shultz National Foreign Affairs Training Center.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">‘Hard Language Country’ Post To Be Designated</inline>.—</heading><content>At least one of the posts designated under subsection (a) shall be in a ‘hard language’ country, as identified in the report to the Under Secretary of State for Management of <date date="1986-05-12">May 12, 1986</date>, entitled ‘Hard Language Proficiency in the Foreign Service’. Such post shall be in one of the countries where the official or principal language is Arabic, Chinese, Japanese, or Russian.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination Date</inline>.—</heading><content>The posts designated under subsection (a) shall continue as model foreign language posts at least until <date date="1993-09-30">September 30, 1993</date>, in the case of non-hard language posts, and <date date="1994-09-30">September 30, 1994</date>, in the case of hard language posts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exemption Authority</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of State may authorize exceptions to the requirements of this section if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> he determines that unanticipated exigencies so require; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> he immediately reports such exceptions to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Excluded Posts</inline>.—</heading><content>The posts designated under subsection (a) may not include Dakar, Senegal, or Montevideo, Uruguay. The report required under subsection (c) shall include progress made in these posts in maintaining the high foreign language standards achieved under the initial pilot program.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
