<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9071298f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4172"><num value="4172">§ 4172.</num><heading> Savings provisions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90712990-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4172/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Determinations, authorizations, etc., under authority of Foreign Service Act of 1946 and grievances, claims, or appeals filed and pending on effective date of this chapter</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All determinations, authorizations, regulations, orders, agreements, exclusive recognition of an organization or other actions made, issued, undertaken, entered into, or taken under the authority of the Foreign Service Act of 1946 or any other law repealed, modified, or affected by this chapter shall continue in full force and effect until modified, revoked, or superseded by appropriate authority. Any grievances, claims, or appeals which were filed or made under any such law and are pending resolution on <date date="1981-02-15">February 15, 1981</date>, shall continue to be governed by the provisions repealed, modified, or affected by this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90712991-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4172/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Increase in annuity or other right to benefits</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This chapter shall not affect any increase in annuity or other right to benefits, which was provided by any provision amended or repealed by this chapter, with respect to any individual who became entitled to such benefit prior to <date date="1981-02-15">February 15, 1981</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90712992-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4172/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Cross references</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">References in law to provisions of the Foreign Service Act of 1946 or other law superseded by this chapter shall be deemed to include reference to the corresponding provisions of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id90712993-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/465/tII/s2401">Pub. L. 96–465, title II, § 2401</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2168">94 Stat. 2168</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id90712994-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id90712995-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id90712996-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Foreign Service Act of 1946, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (c), is <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-13/ch957">act Aug. 13, 1946, ch. 957</ref>, titles I to X, <ref href="/us/stat/60/999">60 Stat. 999</ref>, which was classified principally to chapter 14 (§ 801 et seq.) of this title, and was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/96/465/tII/s2205/1">Pub. L. 96–465, title II, § 2205(1)</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2159">94 Stat. 2159</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/96/465">Pub. L. 96–465</ref>, <date date="1980-10-17">Oct. 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2071">94 Stat. 2071</ref>, known as the Foreign Service Act of 1980, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3901">section 3901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id90712997-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsecs. (a) and (b), “<date date="1981-02-15">February 15, 1981</date>” substituted for “the effective date of this Act” pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/96/465/s2403">section 2403 of Pub. L. 96–465</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3901">section 3901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
