<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id907372bc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4197"><num value="4197">§ 4197.</num><heading> Following testamentary directions; assistance to testamentary appointee</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">When a citizen of the United States dies in a foreign country and leaves, by any lawful testamentary disposition, special directions for the custody and management, by the consular officer, or in his absence a diplomatic officer, within whose jurisdiction the death occurred, of the personal property in the foreign country which he possessed at the time of death, such officer shall, so far as the laws of the foreign country permit, strictly observe such directions if not contrary to the laws of the United States. If such citizen has named, by any lawful testamentary disposition, any other person than a consular officer or diplomatic officer to take charge of and manage such property, it shall be the duty of the officer, whenever required by the person so named, to give his official aid in whatever way may be practicable to facilitate the proceedings of such person in the lawful execution of his trust, and, so far as the laws of the country or treaty provisions permit, to protect the property of the deceased from any interference by the authorities of the country where such citizen died. To this end it shall be the duty of the consular officer, or if no consular officer is present a diplomatic officer, to safeguard the decedent’s property by placing thereon his official seal and to break and remove such seal only upon the request of the person designated by the deceased to take charge of and manage his property.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id907372bd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(R.S. § 1711; <ref href="/us/act/1940-07-12/ch618">July 12, 1940, ch. 618</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/54/760">54 Stat. 760</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id907372be-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id907372bf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id907372c0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">R.S. § 1711 derived from <ref href="/us/act/1856-08-18/ch127/s28">act Aug. 18, 1856, ch. 127, § 28</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/11/63">11 Stat. 63</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was not enacted as part of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 which comprises this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1177">section 1177 of this title</ref>, and prior thereto to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s77">section 77 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id907372c1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1940—Act <date date="1940-07-12">July 12, 1940</date>, amended section generally.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
