<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90737324-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4219"><num value="4219">§ 4219.</num><heading> Regulation of fees by President</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President is authorized to prescribe, from time to time, the rates or tariffs of fees to be charged for official services, and to designate what shall be regarded as official services, besides such as are expressly declared by law, in the business of the several embassies, legations, and consulates, and to adapt the same, by such differences as may be necessary or proper, to each embassy, legation, or consulate; and it shall be the duty of all officers and persons connected with such embassies, legations, and consulates to collect for such official services such and only such fees as may be prescribed for their respective embassies, legations, and consulates, and such rates or tariffs shall be reported annually to Congress.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id90737325-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(R.S. § 1745; <ref href="/us/act/1906-04-05/ch1366/s3">Apr. 5, 1906, ch. 1366, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/34/100">34 Stat. 100</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id90737326-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id90737327-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id90737328-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">R.S. § 1745 derived from <ref href="/us/act/1856-08-18/ch127/s16">act Aug. 18, 1856, ch. 127, § 16</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/11/57">11 Stat. 57</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References to “commercial agencies” and “commercial agency” were omitted in view of the abolition of the grade of commercial agent by act <date date="1906-04-05">Apr. 5, 1906</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was not enacted as part of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 which comprises this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1201">section 1201 of this title</ref>, and prior thereto to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s127">section 127 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id90737329-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id9073732a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 10718. Delegation of Authority to Secretary of State</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 10718, <date date="1957-06-27">June 27, 1957</date>, 22 F.R. 4632, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. There is hereby delegated to the Secretary of State the authority vested in the President by section 1745 of the Revised Statutes of the United States (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1201">22 U.S.C. 1201</ref>) [this section] to prescribe, from time to time, the rates or tariffs of fees to be charged for official services, and to designate what shall be regarded as official services, besides such as are expressly declared by law, in the business of the several embassies, legations, and consulates, and to adapt the same, by such differences as may be necessary or proper, to each embassy, legation, or consulate.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. This order shall not operate to amend, supersede, or terminate any rates or tariffs of fees, designations, or adaptations prescribed or made under authority of the said section 1745 [this section] and in force immediately prior to the issuance of this order; but authority to amend, supersede, or terminate the same, and to prescribe regulations necessary or desirable for the implementation of rates or tariffs of fees, designations, or adaptions heretofore or hereafter prescribed or made, shall be deemed to be included within the authority delegated by section 1 of this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. The rates or tariffs of fees and the regulations prescribed and any other actions taken by the Secretary of State under authority of this order shall be published in the Federal Register.</p>
<signature>
<name>Dwight D. Eisenhower.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
