<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9075e39c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4304"><num value="4304">§ 4304.</num><heading> Provision of benefits</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9075e39d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4304/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Request by foreign mission; terms and conditions as approved by Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon the request of a foreign mission, benefits may be provided to or for that foreign mission by or through the Secretary on such terms and conditions as the Secretary may approve.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9075e39e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4304/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Benefits through Secretary as mandatory; compliance with terms and conditions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Secretary determines that such action is reasonably necessary on the basis of reciprocity or otherwise—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9075e39f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4304/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to facilitate relations between the United States and a sending State,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9075e3a0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4304/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to protect the interests of the United States,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9075e3a1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4304/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to adjust for costs and procedures of obtaining benefits for missions of the United States abroad,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9075e3a2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4304/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to assist in resolving a dispute affecting United States interests and involving a foreign mission or sending State, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9075e3a3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4304/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> subject to subsection (f), to implement an exchange of property between the Government of the United States and the government of a foreign country, such property to be used by each government in the respective receiving state for, or in connection with, diplomatic or consular establishments,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">then the Secretary may require a foreign mission (A) to obtain benefits from or through the Secretary on such terms and conditions as the Secretary may approve, or (B) to forego the acceptance, use, or relation of any benefit or to comply with such terms and conditions as the Secretary may determine as a condition to the execution or performance in the United States of any contract or other agreement, the acquisition, retention, or use of any real property, or the application for or acceptance of any benefit (including any benefit from or authorized by any Federal, State, or municipal governmental authority, or any entity providing public services).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9075e3a4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4304/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Surcharge or fee; waiver of recourse</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Terms and conditions established by the Secretary under this section may include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9075e3a5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4304/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a requirement to pay to the Secretary a surcharge or fee, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9075e3a6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4304/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a waiver by a foreign mission (or any assignee of or person deriving rights from a foreign mission) of any recourse against any governmental authority, any entity providing public services, any employee or agent of such an authority or entity, or any other person, in connection with any action determined by the Secretary to be undertaken in furtherance of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9075e3a7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4304/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Agent for waiver of recourse</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of effectuating a waiver of recourse which is required under this section, the Secretary may designate any officer of the Department of State as the agent of a foreign mission (or of any assignee of or person deriving rights from a foreign mission). Any such waiver by an officer so designated shall for all purposes (including any court or administrative proceeding) be deemed to be a waiver by the foreign mission (or the assignee of or other person deriving rights from a foreign mission).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9075e3a8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4304/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Secret Service protection</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be deemed to preclude or limit in any way the authority of the United States Secret Service to provide protective services pursuant to section 3056 or 3056A of title 18 at a level commensurate with protective requirements as determined by the United States Secret Service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9075e3a9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4304/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> In-kind exchange of properties with foreign government; transfer of funds; reciprocal agreement; regulations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9075e3aa-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4304/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Upon a determination in each specific case by the Secretary of State or the Secretary’s designee that the purpose of the Foreign Service Buildings Act, 1926 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s292">22 U.S.C. 292</ref> et seq.], can best be met on the basis of an in-kind exchange of properties with a foreign country pursuant to subsection (b)(5), the Secretary of State may transfer funds made available under the heading “Acquisition and Maintenance of Buildings Abroad” (including funds held in the Foreign Service Buildings Fund) for such purpose to the Working Capital Fund, as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4308/h/1">section 4308(h)(1) of this title</ref>. Except for funds that may be provided by a foreign government for the purchase of property, only funds transferred under the preceding sentence may be used for the purposes of subsection (b)(5).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9075e3ab-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4304/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary of State may acquire property in the United States for the purposes of subsection (b)(5) only in the context of a specific reciprocal agreement with a specified foreign government. Property acquired by the United States in the foreign country through such an exchange shall benefit the United States at least to the same extent as the property acquired in the United States benefits the foreign government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9075e3ac-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4304/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary of State shall prescribe regulations for the implementation of any in-kind exchange of properties pursuant to subsection (b)(5).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9075e3ad-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4304/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> At least 15 days before entering into any reciprocal agreement for the exchange of property with another foreign government, the Secretary of State shall notify the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Public Works and Transportation of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9075e3ae-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4304/f/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9075e3af-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4304/f/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Proceeds from the disposition of properties acquired pursuant to this subsection shall be credited to the Foreign Service Buildings Fund (referred to in section 9 of the Foreign Service Buildings Act, 1926 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s300">22 U.S.C. 300</ref>]).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9075e3b0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4304/f/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The authority to spend proceeds received under subparagraph (A) may be exercised only to such extent or in such amounts as are provided in advance in an appropriation Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9075e3b1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1956-08-01/ch841">Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title II, § 204, as added <ref href="/us/pl/97/241/tII/s202/b">Pub. L. 97–241, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/284">96 Stat. 284</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/99/93/tI">Pub. L. 99–93, title I</ref>, §§ 126(b), 127(c), <date date="1985-08-16">Aug. 16, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/418">99 Stat. 418</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/246/tI/s116/b">Pub. L. 101–246, title I, § 116(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-02-16">Feb. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/24">104 Stat. 24</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/tI/s162">Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 162</ref>(<i>o</i>)(3), <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/410">108 Stat. 410</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/415/s1/cc">Pub. L. 103–415, § 1(cc)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4302">108 Stat. 4302</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/177/tVI/s605/d/2">Pub. L. 109–177, title VI, § 605(d)(2)</ref>, (e)(2)(B), <date date="2006-03-09">Mar. 9, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/255">120 Stat. 255</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9075e3b2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9075e3b3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id9075e3b4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Foreign Service Buildings Act, 1926, referred to in subsec. (f)(1), is <ref href="/us/act/1926-05-07/ch250">act May 7, 1926, ch. 250</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/44/403">44 Stat. 403</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 8 (§ 292 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s299">section 299 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9075e3b5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/109/177/s605/e/2/B">Pub. L. 109–177, § 605(e)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “section 3056 or 3056A of title 18” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t3/s202">section 202 of title 3</ref> or <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s3056">section 3056 of title 18</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/177/s605/d/2">Pub. L. 109–177, § 605(d)(2)</ref>, which directed amendment of section 204(e) of the State Department Basic Authorities Act by substituting “sections 3056 or 3056A” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t3/s202">section 202 of title 3</ref> or section 3056”, was not executed, because this section is section 204 of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 and because of the amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s605/e/2/B">Pub. L. 105–277, § 605(e)(2)(B)</ref>. See note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsecs. (a) to (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s162">Pub. L. 103–236, § 162</ref>(<i>o</i>)(3)(A), substituted “Secretary on such terms” for “Director on such terms” in subsecs. (a) and (b) and “Secretary” for “Director” in subsec. (c)(1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s162">Pub. L. 103–236, § 162</ref>(<i>o</i>)(3)(B), as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/103/415">Pub. L. 103–415</ref>, substituted “any officer” for “the Director or any other officer”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/101/246/s116/b/1">Pub. L. 101–246, § 116(b)(1)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/101/246/s116/b/2">Pub. L. 101–246, § 116(b)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/93/s127/c">Pub. L. 99–93, § 127(c)</ref>, inserted “to forego the acceptance, use, or relation of any benefit or” after “(B)” in provisions following par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/99/93/s126/b">Pub. L. 99–93, § 126(b)</ref>, substituted “chapter” for “section” and was executed by making the substitution to first reference to “section” as the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9075e3b6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id9075e3b7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Public Works and Transportation of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of House of Representatives by <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/a">section 1(a) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9075e3b8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref> applicable with respect to officials, offices, and bureaus of Department of State when executive orders, regulations, or departmental directives implementing the amendments by sections 161 and 162 of <ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref> become effective, or 90 days after <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, whichever comes earlier, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s161/b">section 161(b) of Pub. L. 103–236</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2651a">section 2651a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9075e3b9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1985 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/93/s126/b">section 126(b) of Pub. L. 99–93</ref> effective <date date="1985-10-01">Oct. 1, 1985</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/93/s126/e">section 126(e) of Pub. L. 99–93</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4314">section 4314 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id9075e3ba-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1982-10-01">Oct. 1, 1982</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/241/s204">section 204 of Pub. L. 97–241</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4301">section 4301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id9075e3bb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of the functions, personnel, assets, and obligations of the United States Secret Service, including the functions of the Secretary of the Treasury relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 381, 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
