<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9075e436-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4308"><num value="4308">§ 4308.</num><heading> General provisions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9075e437-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4308/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Issuance of regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may issue such regulations as the Secretary may determine necessary to carry out the policy of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9075e438-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4308/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Discharge of obligation; liability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Compliance with any regulation, instruction, or direction issued by the Secretary under this chapter shall to the extent thereof be a full acquittance and discharge for all purposes of the obligation of the person making the same. No person shall be held liable in any court or administrative proceeding for or with respect to anything done or omitted in good faith in connection with the administration of, or pursuant to and in reliance on, this chapter, or any regulation, instruction, or direction issued by the Secretary under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9075e439-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4308/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of employees from other Federal agencies; experts and consultants</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of administering this chapter—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9075e43a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4308/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Secretary may accept details and assignments of employees of Federal agencies to the Department of State on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis (with any such reimbursements to be credited to the appropriations made available for the salaries and expenses of officers and employees of the employing agency); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9075e43b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4308/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the Secretary may, to the extent necessary to obtain services without delay, exercise his authority to employ experts and consultants under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3109">section 3109 of title 5</ref> without requiring compliance with such otherwise applicable requirements for that employment as the Secretary may determine, except that such employment shall be terminated after 60 days if by that time those requirements are not complied with.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9075e43c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4308/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Contracts and subcontracts for supplies and services; advertisement; factors considered</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Contracts and subcontracts for supplies or services, including personal services, made by or on behalf of the Secretary shall be made after advertising, in such manner and at such times as the Secretary shall determine to be adequate to ensure notice and opportunity for competition, except that advertisement shall not be required when (1) the Secretary determines that it is impracticable or will not permit timely performance to obtain bids by advertising, or (2) the aggregate amount involved in a purchase of supplies or procurement of services does not exceed $10,000. Such contracts and subcontracts may be entered into without regard to laws and regulations otherwise applicable to solicitation, negotiation, administration, and performance of government contracts. In awarding contracts, the Secretary may consider such factors as relative quality and availability of supplies or services and the compatibility of the supplies or services with implementation of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9075e43d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4308/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer or loan of property to or from Department of State</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The head of any Federal agency may, for purposes of this chapter—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9075e43e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4308/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> transfer or loan any property to, and perform administrative and technical support functions and services for the operations of, the Department of State (with reimbursements to agencies under this paragraph to be credited to the current applicable appropriation of the agency concerned); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9075e43f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4308/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> acquire and accept services from the Department of State, including (whenever the Secretary determines it to be in furtherance of the purposes of this chapter) acquisitions without regard to laws normally applicable to the acquisition of services by such agency.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9075e440-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4308/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Attachment, execution, etc., of assets</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Assets of or under the control of the Department of State, wherever situated, which are used by or held for the use of a foreign mission shall not be subject to attachment, execution, injunction, or similar process, whether intermediate or final.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9075e441-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4308/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Discretion of Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided, any determination required under this chapter shall be committed to the discretion of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9075e442-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4308/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer and credit of funds</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9075e443-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4308/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In order to implement this chapter, the Secretary may transfer to the working capital fund established by <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2684">section 2684 of this title</ref> such amounts available to the Department of State as may be necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9075e444-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4308/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> All revenues, including proceeds from gifts and donations, received by the Secretary in carrying out this chapter may be credited to the working capital fund established by <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2684">section 2684 of this title</ref> and shall be available for purposes of this chapter in accordance with that section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id9075e445-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4308/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Only amounts transferred or credited to the working capital fund established by <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2684">section 2684 of this title</ref> may be used in carrying out the functions of the Secretary or the Director under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9075e446-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1956-08-01/ch841">Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title II, § 208, as added <ref href="/us/pl/97/241/tII/s202/b">Pub. L. 97–241, title II, § 202(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-08-24">Aug. 24, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/288">96 Stat. 288</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/tI/s162">Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 162</ref>(<i>o</i>)(6), <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/410">108 Stat. 410</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9075e447-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9075e448-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9075e449-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s162">Pub. L. 103–236, § 162</ref>(<i>o</i>)(6)(B), substituted “Department of State” for “Office of Foreign Missions”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s162">Pub. L. 103–236, § 162</ref>(<i>o</i>)(6)(A), substituted “behalf of the Secretary” for “behalf of the Director”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e), (f). <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s162">Pub. L. 103–236, § 162</ref>(<i>o</i>)(6)(B), substituted “Department of State” for “Office of Foreign Missions” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s162">Pub. L. 103–236, § 162</ref>(<i>o</i>)(6)(C), struck out “Director or the” after “received by the”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9075e44a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id9075e44b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref> applicable with respect to officials, offices, and bureaus of Department of State when executive orders, regulations, or departmental directives implementing the amendments by sections 161 and 162 of <ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref> become effective, or 90 days after <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, whichever comes earlier, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s161/b">section 161(b) of Pub. L. 103–236</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2651a">section 2651a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="id9075e44c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1982-10-01">Oct. 1, 1982</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/241/s204">section 204 of Pub. L. 97–241</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4301">section 4301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
