<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id907854e3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4351"><num value="4351">§ 4351.</num><heading> General authority and contents of publication</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id907854e4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4351/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Charter of publication</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Department of State shall continue to publish the “Foreign Relations of the United States historical series” (hereafter in this chapter referred to as the “FRUS series”), which shall be a thorough, accurate, and reliable documentary record of major United States foreign policy decisions and significant United States diplomatic activity. Volumes of this publication shall include all records needed to provide a comprehensive documentation of the major foreign policy decisions and actions of the United States Government, including the facts which contributed to the formulation of policies and records providing supporting and alternative views to the policy position ultimately adopted.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id907854e5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4351/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Editing principles</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The editing of records for preparation of the FRUS series shall be guided by the principles of historical objectivity and accuracy. Records shall not be altered and deletions shall not be made without indicating in the published text that a deletion has been made. The published record shall omit no facts which were of major importance in reaching a decision, and nothing shall be omitted for the purpose of concealing a defect of policy.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id907854e6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4351/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Deadline for publication of records</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall ensure that the FRUS series shall be published not more than 30 years after the events recorded.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id907854e7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1956-08-01/ch841">Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841</ref>, title IV, § 401, as added <ref href="/us/pl/102/138/tI/s198/a">Pub. L. 102–138, title I, § 198(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-10-28">Oct. 28, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/685">105 Stat. 685</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id907854e8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id907854e9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id907854ea-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Compliance With Deadline for Publication of FRUS Series; Notification to Congressional Committees on Failure To Comply; Final Deadline</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/138/tI/s198/c/2">Pub. L. 102–138, title I, § 198(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1991-10-28">Oct. 28, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/691">105 Stat. 691</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/138/tI/s198/c/2">
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> In order to come into compliance with section 401(c) of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4351/c">22 U.S.C. 4351(c)</ref>] (as amended by this section) the Secretary of State shall ensure that, by the end of the 3-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1991-10-28">Oct. 28, 1991</date>], all volumes of the Foreign Relations of the United States historical series (FRUS) for the years that are more than 30 years before the end of that 3-year period have been published.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> If the Secretary cannot reasonably meet the requirements of subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall notify the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and describe how the Department of State plans to meet the requirements of subparagraph (A). In no event shall volumes subject to subparagraph (A) be published later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
