<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id8eec84df-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s448"><num value="448">§ 448.</num><heading> Solicitation and collection of funds and contributions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8eec84e0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s448/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Unlawful acts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever the President shall have issued a proclamation under the authority of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s441/a">section 441(a) of this title</ref>, it shall thereafter be unlawful for any person within the United States to solicit or receive any contribution for or on behalf of the government of any state named in such proclamation or for or on behalf of any agent or instrumentality of any such state.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8eec84e1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s448/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Medical aid, food, and clothing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the solicitation or collection of funds and contributions to be used for medical aid and assistance, or for food and clothing to relieve human suffering, when such solicitation or collection of funds and contributions is made on behalf of and for use by any person or organization which is not acting for or on behalf of any such government, but all such solicitations and collections of funds and contributions shall be in accordance with and subject to such rules and regulations as may be prescribed.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id8eec84e2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s448/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Revocation of proclamation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever any proclamation issued under the authority of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s441/a">section 441(a) of this title</ref> shall have been revoked with respect to any state the provisions of this section shall thereupon cease to apply with respect to such state, except as to offenses committed prior to such revocation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id8eec84e3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/act/1939-11-04/ch2/s8">Nov. 4, 1939, ch. 2, § 8</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/54/8">54 Stat. 8</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
