<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id907a9ed5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4504"><num value="4504">§ 4504.</num><heading> Authority to make payments; purposes</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id907a9ed6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4504/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Secretary of State, after consultation with the Advisory Committee, shall make payments, in accordance with the provisions of this section, out of funds made available to carry out this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id907a9ed7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4504/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id907a9ed8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4504/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> One part of the payments made in each fiscal year shall be used to conduct a national research program at the postdoctoral or equivalent level, such program to include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id907a9ed9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4504/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the dissemination of information about the research program and the solicitation of proposals for research contracts from American institutions of higher education and not-for-profit corporations, such contracts to contain shared-cost provisions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id907a9eda-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4504/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the awarding of contracts for such research projects as the respective institution determines will best serve to carry out the purposes of this chapter after reviewing proposals submitted under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id907a9edb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4504/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> One part of the payments made in each fiscal year shall be used—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id907a9edc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4504/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> to establish and carry out a program of graduate, postdoctoral, and teaching fellowships for advanced training in studies on the countries of Eastern Europe and the independent states of the former Soviet Union and related studies, such program—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id907a9edd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4504/b/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to be coordinated with the research program described in paragraph (1);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id907a9ede-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4504/b/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to be conducted, on a shared-cost basis, at American institutions of higher education; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id907a9edf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4504/b/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><chapeau> to include—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id907a9ee0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4504/b/2/A/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the dissemination of information on the fellowship program and the solicitation of applications for fellowships from qualified institutions of higher education and qualified individuals; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id907a9ee1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4504/b/2/A/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the awarding of such fellowships as the respective institution determines will best serve to carry out the purposes of this chapter after reviewing applications submitted under subclause (I); and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id907a9ee2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4504/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to disseminate research, data, and findings on studies on the countries of Eastern Europe and the independent states of the former Soviet Union and related fields in such a manner and to such extent as the respective institution determines will best serve to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id907a9ee3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4504/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> One part of the payments made in each fiscal year shall be used—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id907a9ee4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4504/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to provide fellowship and research support for American specialists in the independent states of the former Soviet Union and the countries of Eastern Europe and related fields to conduct advanced research with particular emphasis upon the use of data on those states and countries; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id907a9ee5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4504/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to conduct seminars, conferences, and other similar workshops designed to facilitate research collaboration between Government and private specialists in the independent states of the former Soviet Union and the countries of Eastern Europe and related fields.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id907a9ee6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4504/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> One part of the payments made in each fiscal year shall be used to conduct specialized programs in advanced training and research on a reciprocal basis in the independent states of the former Soviet Union and the countries of Eastern Europe designed to facilitate access for American specialists to research institutes, personnel, archives, documentation, and other research and training resources located in those states and countries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id907a9ee7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4504/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> One part of the payments made in each fiscal year shall be used to support training in the languages of the independent states of the former Soviet Union and the countries of Eastern Europe. Such payments shall include grants to individuals to pursue such training and to summer language institutes operated by institutions of higher education. Preference shall be given for Russian language studies and, as appropriate, studies of other languages of the independent states of the former Soviet Union.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id907a9ee8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4504/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Payments may be made to carry out other research and training in studies on the countries of Eastern Europe and the independent states of the former Soviet Union not otherwise described in this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id907a9ee9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/164/tVIII/s805">Pub. L. 98–164, title VIII, § 805</ref>, <date date="1983-11-22">Nov. 22, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/1048">97 Stat. 1048</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/199/tIII/s302/6">Pub. L. 103–199, title III, § 302(6)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-17">Dec. 17, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2323">107 Stat. 2323</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id907a9eea-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id907a9eeb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id907a9eec-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (b)(2)(A), (B). <ref href="/us/pl/103/199/s302/6/A">Pub. L. 103–199, § 302(6)(A)</ref>, substituted “studies on the countries of Eastern Europe and the independent states of the former Soviet Union” for “Soviet and Eastern European studies”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/103/199/s302/6/B">Pub. L. 103–199, § 302(6)(B)</ref>, (C), substituted “independent states of the former Soviet Union and the countries of Eastern Europe and related fields” for “fields of Soviet and Eastern European studies and related studies” and “those states and countries” for “the Soviet Union and Eastern European countries”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/103/199/s302/6/B">Pub. L. 103–199, § 302(6)(B)</ref>, which directed the substitution of “independent states of the former Soviet Union and the countries of Eastern Europe and related fields” for “fields of Soviet and Eastern European studies and related studies”, was executed by making the substitution for “fields of Soviet and East European studies and related studies”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/103/199/s302/6/D">Pub. L. 103–199, § 302(6)(D)</ref>, substituted “independent states of the former Soviet Union” for “Union of Soviet Socialist Republics” and “those states and countries” for “the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics and Eastern European countries”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/103/199/s302/6/E">Pub. L. 103–199, § 302(6)(E)</ref>, substituted “training in the languages of the independent states of the former Soviet Union and the countries of Eastern Europe” for “language training in Russian and Eastern European languages” and inserted before period at end “and, as appropriate, studies of other languages of the independent states of the former Soviet Union”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/103/199/s302/6/A">Pub. L. 103–199, § 302(6)(A)</ref>, substituted “studies on the countries of Eastern Europe and the independent states of the former Soviet Union” for “Soviet and Eastern European studies”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id907a9eed-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="id907a9eee-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (b)(2)–(6), independent states of the former Soviet Union has the meaning given in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s5801">section 5801 of this title</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/199/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 103–199</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s5801">section 5801 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
