<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id907a9f06-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4601"><num value="4601">§ 4601.</num><heading> Congressional declaration of findings and purposes</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id907a9f07-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4601/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><chapeau> The Congress finds and declares that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id907a9f08-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4601/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a living institution embodying the heritage, ideals, and concerns of the American people for peace would be a significant response to the deep public need for the Nation to develop fully a range of effective options, in addition to armed capacity, that can leash international violence and manage international conflict;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id907a9f09-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4601/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> people throughout the world are fearful of nuclear war, are divided by war and threats of war, are experiencing social and cultural hostilities from rapid international change and real and perceived conflicts over interests, and are diverted from peace by the lack of problem-solving skills for dealing with such conflicts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id907a9f0a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4601/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> many potentially destructive conflicts among nations and peoples have been resolved constructively and with cost efficiency at the international, national, and community levels through proper use of such techniques as negotiation, conciliation, mediation, and arbitration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id907a9f0b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4601/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> there is a national need to examine the disciplines in the social, behavioral, and physical sciences and the arts and humanities with regard to the history, nature, elements, and future of peace processes, and to bring together and develop new and tested techniques to promote peaceful economic, political, social, and cultural relations in the world;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id907a9f0c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4601/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> existing institutions providing programs in international affairs, diplomacy, conflict resolution, and peace studies are essential to further development of techniques to promote peaceful resolution of international conflict, and the peacemaking activities of people in such institutions, government, private enterprise, and voluntary associations can be strengthened by a national institution devoted to international peace research, education and training, and information services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id907a9f0d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4601/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> there is a need for Federal leadership to expand and support the existing international peace and conflict resolution efforts of the Nation and to develop new comprehensive peace education and training programs, basic and applied research projects, and programs providing peace information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id907a9f0e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4601/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> the Commission on Proposals for the National Academy of Peace and Conflict Resolution, created by the Education Amendments of 1978, recommended establishing an academy as a highly desirable investment to further the Nation’s interest in promoting international peace;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id907a9f0f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4601/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> an institute strengthening and symbolizing the fruitful relation between the world of learning and the world of public affairs, would be the most efficient and immediate means for the Nation to enlarge its capacity to promote the peaceful resolution of international conflicts; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id907a9f10-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4601/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> the establishment of such an institute is an appropriate investment by the people of this Nation to advance the history, science, art, and practice of international peace and the resolution of conflicts among nations without the use of violence.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id907a9f11-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s4601/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> It is the purpose of this chapter to establish an independent, nonprofit, national institute to serve the people and the Government through the widest possible range of education and training, basic and applied research opportunities, and peace information services on the means to promote international peace and the resolution of conflicts among the nations and peoples of the world without recourse to violence.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id907a9f12-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/525/tXVII/s1702">Pub. L. 98–525, title XVII, § 1702</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2649">98 Stat. 2649</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id907a9f13-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id907a9f14-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id907a9f15-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Education Amendments of 1978, referred to in subsec. (a)(7), is <ref href="/us/pl/95/561">Pub. L. 95–561</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2143">92 Stat. 2143</ref>. Part B (§§ 1511–1519) of title XV of <ref href="/us/pl/95/561">Pub. L. 95–561</ref>, which provided for the Commission on Proposals for the National Academy of Peace and Conflict Resolution, was set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1123">section 1123 of Title 20</ref>, Education. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1978 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6301">section 6301 of Title 20</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id907a9f16-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="id907a9f17-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/525/tXVII/s1701">Pub. L. 98–525, title XVII, § 1701</ref>, <date date="1984-10-19">Oct. 19, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2649">98 Stat. 2649</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/525/tXVII/s1701">“This title [enacting this chapter] may be cited as the ‘United States Institute of Peace Act’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
