<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9088f78f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5331"><num value="5331">§ 5331.</num><heading> International initiative</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9088f790-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5331/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Directive</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9088f791-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5331/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Study</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary of the Treasury shall study the feasibility and advisability of establishing the International Debt Management Authority described in this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9088f792-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5331/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Explanation of determinations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Secretary of the Treasury determines that initiation of international discussions with regard to such authority would (A) result in material increase in the discount at which sovereign debt is sold, (B) materially increase the probability of default on such debt, or (C) materially enhance the likelihood of debt service failure or disruption, the Secretary shall include in his interim reports to the Congress an explanation in detail of the reasons for such determination.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9088f793-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5331/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Initiation of discussions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Unless such a determination is made, the Secretary of the Treasury shall initiate discussions with such industrialized and developing countries as the Secretary may determine to be appropriate with the intent to negotiate the establishment of the International Debt Management Authority, which would undertake to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9088f794-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5331/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> purchase sovereign debt of less developed countries from private creditors at an appropriate discount;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9088f795-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5331/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> enter into negotiations with the debtor countries for the purpose of restructuring the debt in order to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9088f796-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5331/a/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> ease the current debt service burden on the debtor countries; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9088f797-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5331/a/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> provide additional opportunities for economic growth in both debtor and industrialized countries; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9088f798-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5331/a/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> assist the creditor banks in the voluntary disposition of their Third World loan portfolio.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id908b6799-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5331/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Objectives</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In any discussions initiated under subsection (a), the Secretary should include the following specific proposals:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id908b679a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5331/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> That any loan restructuring assistance provided by such an authority to any debtor nation should involve substantial commitments by the debtor to (A) economic policies designed to improve resource utilization and minimize capital flight, and (B) preparation of an economic management plan calculated to provide sustained economic growth and to allow the debtor to meet its restructured debt obligations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id908b679b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5331/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> That support for such an authority should come from industrialized countries, and that greater support should be expected from countries with strong current account surpluses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id908b679c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5331/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> That such an authority should have a clearly defined close working relationship with the International Monetary Fund and the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development and the various regional development banks.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id908b679d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5331/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> That such an authority should be designed to operate as a self-supporting entity, requiring no routine appropriation of resources from any member government, and to function subject to the prohibitions contained in the first sentence of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s5332/a">section 5332(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id908b679e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5331/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> That such an authority should have a defined termination date and a clear proposal for the restoration of creditworthiness to debtor countries within this timeframe.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id908b679f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5331/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Interim reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">At the end of the 6-month period beginning on <date date="1988-08-23">August 23, 1988</date>, and at the end of the 12-month period beginning on <date date="1988-08-23">August 23, 1988</date>, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit a report on the progress being made on the study or in discussions described in subsection (a) to the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, and shall consult with such committees after submitting each such report.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id908b67a0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5331/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Final report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">On the conclusion of the study or of discussions described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall transmit a report containing a detailed description thereof to the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, together with such recommendations for legislation which the Secretary may determine to be necessary or appropriate for the establishment of the International Debt Management Authority.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id908b67a1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/418/tIII/s3111">Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3111</ref>, <date date="1988-08-23">Aug. 23, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1376">102 Stat. 1376</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id908b67a2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id908b67a3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id908b67a4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Banking and Financial Services of House of Representatives by <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/a">section 1(a) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress. Committee on Banking and Financial Services of House of Representatives abolished and replaced by Committee on Financial Services of House of Representatives, and jurisdiction over matters relating to securities and exchanges and insurance generally transferred from Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Seventh Congress, <date date="2001-01-03">Jan. 3, 2001</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
