<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id908db1dd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5441"><num value="5441">§ 5441.</num><heading> Educational and cultural exchanges and sister institutions programs with Poland and Hungary</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id908db1de-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5441/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Educational and cultural exchanges</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id908db1df-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5441/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Support for expanded U.S. participation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The United States should expand its participation in educational and cultural exchange activities with Poland and Hungary, using the full array of existing government-funded and privately-funded programs, with particular emphasis on the J. William Fulbright Educational Exchange Program, the International Visitors Program, the Samantha Smith Memorial Exchange Program, the exchange programs of the National Academy of Sciences, youth and student exchanges through such private organizations as The Experiment in International Living, The American Field Service Committee, and Youth for Understanding, and research exchanges sponsored by the International Research and Exchanges Board (IREX).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id908db1e0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5441/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Emphasis on skills in business and economics</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The United States should place particular emphasis on expanding its participation in educational exchange activities that will assist in developing the skills in business and economics that are necessary for the development of a free market economy in Poland and Hungary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id908db1e1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5441/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Binational Fulbright commissions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The United States should take all appropriate action to establish binational Fulbright commissions with Poland and Hungary in order to facilitate and enhance academic and scholarly exchanges with those countries.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id908db1e2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5441/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Reciprocal cultural centers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President should consider the establishment of reciprocal cultural centers in Poland and the United States and in Hungary and the United States to facilitate government-funded and privately-funded cultural exchanges.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id908db1e3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5441/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Sister institutions programs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall act to encourage the establishment of “sister institution” programs between American and Polish organizations and between American and Hungarian organizations, including such organizations as institutions of higher education, cities and towns, and organizations in such fields as medicine and health care, business management, environmental protection, and agricultural research and marketing.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id908db1e4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5441/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To enable the United States Information Agency to support the activities described in this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $12,000,000 for the 3-year period beginning <date date="1989-10-01">October 1, 1989</date>, in addition to amounts otherwise available for such purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id908db1e5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/179/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 101–179, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1989-11-28">Nov. 28, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1314">103 Stat. 1314</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id908db1e6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id908db1e7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id908db1e8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">United States Information Agency (other than Broadcasting Board of Governors and International Broadcasting Bureau) abolished and functions transferred to Secretary of State, see sections 6531 and 6532 of this title.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
