<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id909022d3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5506"><num value="5506">§ 5506.</num><heading> Department of State responsibilities and procedures at international disaster site</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id909022d4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5506/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Dispatch of senior State Department official to site</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after <date date="1990-11-16">November 16, 1990</date>, the Secretary of State shall issue such rules and guidelines as are necessary to provide that in the event of an international disaster, particularly an aviation tragedy, directly involving significant numbers of United States citizens abroad not less than one senior officer from the Bureau of Consular Affairs of the Department of State shall be dispatched to the site of such disaster.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id909022d5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5506/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Criteria for Department of State staffing at disaster site</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after <date date="1990-11-16">November 16, 1990</date>, the Secretary of State shall promulgate criteria for Department of State staffing of disaster sites abroad. Such criteria shall define responsibility for staffing decisions and shall consider the deployment of crisis teams under subsection (d). The Secretary of State shall promptly issue such rules and guidelines as are necessary to implement criteria developed pursuant to this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id909022d6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5506/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> State Department ombudsman</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after <date date="1990-11-16">November 16, 1990</date>, the Secretary of State shall issue such rules and guidelines as are necessary to provide that in the event of an international aviation disaster involving significant numbers of United States citizens abroad not less than one officer or employee of the Department of State shall be dispatched to the disaster site to provide on-site assistance to families who may visit the site and to act as an ombudsman in matters involving the foreign local government authorities and social service agencies.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id909022d7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5506/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Crisis teams</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after <date date="1990-11-16">November 16, 1990</date>, the Secretary of State shall promulgate procedures for the deployment of a “crisis team”, which may include public affairs, forensic, and bereavement experts, to the site of any international disaster involving United States citizens abroad to augment in-country Embassy and consulate staff. The Secretary of State shall promptly issue such rules and guidelines as are necessary to implement procedures developed pursuant to this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id909022d8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/604/tII/s207">Pub. L. 101–604, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3084">104 Stat. 3084</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id909022d9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id909022da-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="id909022db-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Authority of Secretary of State</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided, Secretary of State to have and exercise any authority vested by law in any official or office of Department of State and references to such officials or offices deemed to refer to Secretary of State or Department of State, as appropriate, see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2651a">section 2651a of this title</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s161/d">section 161(d) of Pub. L. 103–236</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2651a">section 2651a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
