<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90902305-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5601"><num value="5601">§ 5601.</num><heading> Purposes</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The purposes of this chapter are—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90902306-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5601/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to mandate United States sanctions, and to encourage international sanctions, against countries that use chemical or biological weapons in violation of international law or use lethal chemical or biological weapons against their own nationals, and to impose sanctions against companies that aid in the proliferation of chemical and biological weapons;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90902307-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5601/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to support multilaterally coordinated efforts to control the proliferation of chemical and biological weapons;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90902308-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5601/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to urge continued close cooperation with the Australia Group and cooperation with other supplier nations to devise ever more effective controls on the transfer of materials, equipment, and technology applicable to chemical or biological weapons production; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90902309-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5601/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to require Presidential reports on efforts that threaten United States interests or regional stability by Iran, Iraq, Syria, Libya, and others to acquire the materials and technology to develop, produce, stockpile, deliver, transfer, or use chemical or biological weapons.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id9090230a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/182/tIII/s302">Pub. L. 102–182, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="1991-12-04">Dec. 4, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1245">105 Stat. 1245</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9090230b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9090230c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id9090230d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this title”, meaning title III of <ref href="/us/pl/102/182">Pub. L. 102–182</ref>, <date date="1991-12-04">Dec. 4, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1245">105 Stat. 1245</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note below and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id9090230e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="id9090230f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/182/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 102–182, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1991-12-04">Dec. 4, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1245">105 Stat. 1245</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/182/tIII/s301">“This title [enacting this chapter, <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2798">section 2798 of this title</ref>, and <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4613">section 4613 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, amending sections 2798 and 5604 of this title and sections 4605 and 4613 of Title 50, and repealing provisions which enacted this chapter, <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2798">section 2798 of this title</ref>, and <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4613">section 4613 of Title 50</ref>, and which amended <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4605">section 4605 of Title 50</ref>] may be cited as the ‘Chemical and Biological Weapons Control and Warfare Elimination Act of 1991’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/138/tV/s501">Pub. L. 102–138, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1991-10-28">Oct. 28, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/722">105 Stat. 722</ref>, which provided that title V of <ref href="/us/pl/102/138">Pub. L. 102–138</ref>, which enacted this chapter, <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2798">section 2798 of this title</ref>, and <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4613">section 4613 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, and amended <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4605">section 4605 of Title 50</ref>, was to be cited as the “Chemical and Biological Weapons Control and Warfare Elimination Act of 1991”, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/102/182/tIII/s309/a">Pub. L. 102–182, title III, § 309(a)</ref>, <date date="1991-12-04">Dec. 4, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1258">105 Stat. 1258</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90902310-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Matters Relating to the Control of Biological Weapons</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/7/dB/tXI/s2">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(7) [div. B, title XI, chapter 2]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–490, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/7/dB/tXI/s2">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1121">“SEC. 1121.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This chapter may be cited as the ‘National Security and Corporate Fairness under the Biological Weapons Convention Act’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1122">“SEC. 1122.</num><heading> DEFINITIONS.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“In this chapter:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Biological weapons convention</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Biological Weapons Convention’ means the 1972 Convention on the Prohibition of the Development, Production and Stockpiling of Bacteriological (Biological) and Toxin Weapons and on their Destruction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Compliance protocol</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘compliance protocol’ means that segment of a bilateral or multilateral agreement that enables investigation of questions of compliance entailing written data or visits to facilities to monitor compliance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Industry</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘industry’ means any corporate or private sector entity engaged in the research, development, production, import, and export of peaceful pharmaceuticals and bio-technological and related products.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1123">“SEC. 1123.</num><heading> FINDINGS.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The threat of biological weapons and their proliferation is one of the greatest national security threats facing the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The threat of biological weapons and materials represents a serious and increasing danger to people around the world.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Biological weapons are relatively inexpensive to produce, can be made with readily available expertise and equipment, do not require much space to make and can therefore be readily concealed, do not require unusual raw materials or materials not readily available for legitimate purposes, do not require the maintenance of stockpiles, or can be delivered with low-technology mechanisms, and can effect widespread casualties even in small quantities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Unlike other weapons of mass destruction, biological materials capable of use as weapons can occur naturally in the environment and are also used for medicinal or other beneficial purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Biological weapons are morally reprehensible, prompting the United States Government to halt its offensive biological weapons program in 1969, subsequently destroy its entire biological weapons arsenal, and maintain henceforth only a robust defensive capacity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> The Senate gave its advice and consent to ratification of the Biological Weapons Convention in 1974.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> The Director of the Arms Control and Disarmament Agency explained, at the time of the Senate’s consideration of the Biological Weapons Convention, that the treaty contained no verification provisions because verification would be ‘difficult’.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> A compliance protocol has now been proposed to strengthen the 1972 Biological Weapons Convention.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> The resources needed to produce, stockpile, and store biological weapons are the same as those used in peaceful industry facilities to discover, develop, and produce medicines.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="10">“(10)</num><content> The raw materials of biological agents are difficult to use as an indicator of an offensive military program because the same materials occur in nature or can be used to produce a wide variety of products.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="11">“(11)</num><content> Some biological products are genetically manipulated to develop new commercial products, optimizing production and ensuring the integrity of the product, making it difficult to distinguish between legitimate commercial activities and offensive military activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="12">“(12)</num><content> Only a small culture of a biological agent and some growth medium are needed to produce a large amount of biological agents with the potential for offensive purposes.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="13">“(13)</num><content> The United States pharmaceutical and biotechnology industries are a national asset and resource that contribute to the health and well-being of the American public as well as citizens around the world.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="14">“(14)</num><content> One bacterium strain can represent a large proportion of a company’s investment in a pharmaceutical product and thus its potential loss during an arms control monitoring activity could conceivably be worth billions of dollars.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="15">“(15)</num><content> Biological products contain proprietary genetic information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="16">“(16)</num><content> The proposed compliance regime for the Biological Weapons Convention entails new data reporting and investigation requirements for industry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="17">“(17)</num><content> A compliance regime which contributes to the control of biological weapons and materials must have a reasonable chance of success in reducing the risk of production, stockpiling, or use of biological weapons while protecting the reputations, intellectual property, and confidential business information of legitimate companies.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1124">“SEC. 1124.</num><heading> TRIAL INVESTIGATIONS AND TRIAL VISITS.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">National Security Trial Investigations and Trial Visits</inline>.—</heading><content>The President shall conduct a series of national security trial investigations and trial visits, both during and following negotiations to develop a compliance protocol to the Biological Weapons Convention, with the objective of ensuring that the compliance procedures of the protocol are effective and adequately protect the national security of the United States. These trial investigations and trial visits shall be conducted at such sites as United States Government facilities, installations, and national laboratories.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">United States Industry Trial Investigations and Trial Visits</inline>.—</heading><content>The President shall take all appropriate steps to conduct or sponsor a series of United States industry trial investigations and trial visits, both during and following negotiations to develop a compliance protocol to the Biological Weapons Convention, with the objective of ensuring that the compliance procedures of the protocol are effective and adequately protect the national security and the concerns of affected United States industries and research institutions. These trial investigations and trial visits shall be conducted at such sites as academic institutions, vaccine production facilities, and pharmaceutical and biotechnology firms in the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Participation by Defense Department and Other Appropriate Personnel</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Defense and, as appropriate, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall make available specialized personnel to participate—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> in each trial investigation or trial visit conducted pursuant to subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> in each trial investigation or trial visit conducted pursuant to subsection (b), except for any investigation or visit in which the host facility requests that such personnel not participate,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">for the purpose of assessing the information security implications of such investigation or visit. The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, shall add to the report required by subsection (d)(2) a classified annex containing an assessment of the risk to proprietary and classified information posed by any investigation or visit procedures in the compliance protocol.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The President shall conduct a study on the need for investigations and visits under the compliance protocol to the Biological Weapons Convention, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> an assessment of risks to national security and United States industry and research institutions of such on-site activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> an assessment of the monitoring results that can be expected from such investigations and visits.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than the date on which a compliance protocol to the Biological Weapons Convention is submitted to the Senate for its advice and consent to ratification, the President shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report, in both unclassified and classified form, setting forth—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the findings of the study conducted pursuant to paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the results of trial investigations and trial visits conducted pursuant to subsections (a) and (b).”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
