<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90902311-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5602"><num value="5602">§ 5602.</num><heading> Multilateral efforts</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90902312-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5602/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Multilateral controls on proliferation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States to seek multilaterally coordinated efforts with other countries to control the proliferation of chemical and biological weapons. In furtherance of this policy, the United States shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90902313-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5602/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> promote agreements banning the transfer of missiles suitable for armament with chemical or biological warheads;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90902314-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5602/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> set as a top priority the early conclusion of a comprehensive global agreement banning the use, development, production, and stockpiling of chemical weapons;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90902315-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5602/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> seek and support effective international means of monitoring and reporting regularly on commerce in equipment, materials, and technology applicable to the attainment of a chemical or biological weapons capability; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90902316-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5602/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> pursue and give full support to multilateral sanctions pursuant to United Nations Security Council Resolution 620, which declared the intention of the Security Council to give immediate consideration to imposing “appropriate and effective” sanctions against any country which uses chemical weapons in violation of international law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90902317-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5602/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Multilateral controls on chemical agents, precursors, and equipment</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is also the policy of the United States to strengthen efforts to control chemical agents, precursors, and equipment by taking all appropriate multilateral diplomatic measures—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90902318-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5602/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to continue to seek a verifiable global ban on chemical weapons at the 40 nation Conference on Disarmament in Geneva;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90902319-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5602/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to support the Australia Group’s objective to support the norms and restraints against the spread and the use of chemical warfare, to advance the negotiation of a comprehensive ban on chemical warfare by taking appropriate measures, and to protect the Australia Group’s domestic industries against inadvertent association with supply of feedstock chemical equipment that could be misused to produce chemical weapons;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9090231a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5602/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> to implement paragraph (2) by proposing steps complementary to, and not mutually exclusive of, existing multilateral efforts seeking a verifiable ban on chemical weapons, such as the establishment of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9090231b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5602/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a harmonized list of export control rules and regulations to prevent relative commercial advantage and disadvantages accruing to Australia Group members,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9090231c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5602/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> liaison officers to the Australia Group’s coordinating entity from within the diplomatic missions,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9090231d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5602/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a close working relationship between the Australia Group and industry,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9090231e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5602/b/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> a public unclassified warning list of controlled chemical agents, precursors, and equipment,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9090231f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5602/b/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> information-exchange channels of suspected proliferants,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90902320-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5602/b/3/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> a “denial” list of firms and individuals who violate the Australia Group’s export control provisions, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90902321-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5602/b/3/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> broader cooperation between the Australia Group and other countries whose political commitment to stem the proliferation of chemical weapons is similar to that of the Australia Group; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90902322-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5602/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to adopt the imposition of stricter controls on the export of chemical agents, precursors, and equipment and to adopt tougher multilateral sanctions against firms and individuals who violate these controls or against countries that use chemical weapons.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id90902323-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/182/tIII/s303">Pub. L. 102–182, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1991-12-04">Dec. 4, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1245">105 Stat. 1245</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
