<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90974eaa-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5714"><num value="5714">§ 5714.</num><heading> Transportation</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the sense of the Congress that the following, which are based in part on the relevant provisions of the Joint Declaration, should be the policy of the United States after <date date="1997-06-30">June 30, 1997</date>, with respect to transportation from Hong Kong:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90974eab-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5714/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Recognizing Hong Kong’s position as an international transport center, the United States should continue to recognize ships and airplanes registered in Hong Kong and should negotiate air service agreements directly with Hong Kong.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90974eac-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5714/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The United States should continue to recognize ships registered by Hong Kong.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90974ead-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5714/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> United States commercial ships, in accordance with applicable United States and Hong Kong law, should remain free to port in Hong Kong.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90974eae-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5714/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The United States should continue to recognize airplanes registered by Hong Kong in accordance with applicable laws of the People’s Republic of China.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90974eaf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5714/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The United States should recognize licenses issued by the Hong Kong to Hong Kong airlines.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90974eb0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5714/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The United States should recognize certificates issued by the Hong Kong to United States air carriers for air service involving travel to, from, or through Hong Kong which does not involve travel to, from, or through other parts of the People’s Republic of China.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90974eb1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5714/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The United States should negotiate at the appropriate time directly with the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, acting under authorization from the Government of the People’s Republic of China, to renew or amend all air service agreements existing on <date date="1997-06-30">June 30, 1997</date>, and to conclude new air service agreements affecting all flights to, from, or through the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region which do not involve travel to, from, or through other parts of the People’s Republic of China.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90974eb2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5714/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> The United States should make every effort to ensure that the negotiations described in paragraph (7) lead to procompetitive air service agreements.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id90974eb3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/383/tI/s104">Pub. L. 102–383, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1992-10-05">Oct. 5, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1451">106 Stat. 1451</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
