<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id909e7a9e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841"><num value="5841">§ 5841.</num><heading> Authorization for establishment of Democracy Corps</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id909e7a9f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment; purpose</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President is authorized to provide for the establishment of the Democracy Corps as a private nonprofit organization, incorporated in the District of Columbia, whose purpose shall be to maintain a presence in the independent states of the former Soviet Union as described in subsection (c).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id909e7aa0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Board of Directors</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board of Directors of the Democracy Corps shall have not more than 10 members, appointed by the President. Individuals appointed to the Board—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id909e7aa1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> shall, individually or through the organizations they represent, have experience and expertise appropriate to carrying out the purpose of the Democracy Corps, including involvement either with activities of the type described in subsection (d) or in the independent states;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id909e7aa2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> shall be United States citizens; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id909e7aa3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> may not be officers or employees of the United States Government or Members of Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id909e7aa4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Grants to Democracy Corps; purpose</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator is authorized to make an annual grant to the Democracy Corps with the funds made available pursuant to this section. The purpose of such grants shall be to enable the Democracy Corps to maintain a presence in independent states of the former Soviet Union that will assist at the local level in the development of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id909e7aa5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> institutions of democratic governance (including judicial, electoral, legislative, and administrative processes), and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id909e7aa6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the nongovernmental organizations of a civil society (including charitable, educational, trade union, business, professional, voluntary, community, and other civic organizations),</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">by mobilizing the expertise of the American people to provide practical assistance through “on the ground” person-to-person advice, technical assistance, and small grants to indigenous individuals and indigenous entities, in accordance with subsection (d).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id909e7aa7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Activities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Democracy Corps shall be required to carry out its purpose through the placement within the independent states of teams of United States citizens with appropriate expertise and knowledge. Under guidelines developed by the Board, these teams shall assist indigenous individuals and entities in the independent states that are involved in the development of the institutions and organizations referred to in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (c) by—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id909e7aa8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> providing advice and technical assistance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id909e7aa9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> making small grants (which in most cases should not exceed $5,000) to such individuals and entities to assist the development of those institutions and organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id909e7aaa-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> identifying other sources of assistance; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id909e7aab-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> operating local centers to serve as information, logistical, and educational centers and otherwise encourage cooperation and effectiveness by those involved in the development of democratic institutions, a market-oriented economy, and a civil society in the independent states.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">These local centers may be designated as “Democracy Houses” or given another appropriate appellation.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id909e7aac-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Grant agreement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Grants under this section shall be made pursuant to a grant agreement requiring the Democracy Corps to comply with the requirements specified in this section and with such other terms and conditions as the Administrator may require, which shall include requirements regarding consultation with the coordinator designated pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s5812/a">section 5812(a) of this title</ref>, conflicts of interest, and accountability for funds, including a requirement for annual independent audits.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id909e7aad-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Democracy Corps shall be required to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id909e7aae-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> coordinate its activities pursuant to this section with the programs and activities of other entities operating in or providing assistance to the independent states of the former Soviet Union in support of the development of democratic institutions, a market-oriented economy, and a civil society; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id909e7aaf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> ensure that its activities pursuant to this section are designed to avoid duplication with activities carried out under other United States Government foreign assistance and international information, educational, cultural, and exchange programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id909e7ab0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition on campaign financing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Funds made available to the Democracy Corps under this section may not be expended by the Democracy Corps, or any recipient of a grant from the Democracy Corps, to finance the campaigns of candidates for public office.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id909e7ab1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Freedom of information</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id909e7ab2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding the fact that the Democracy Corps is not an agency or establishment of the United States Government, the Democracy Corps shall be required to comply fully with all of the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">section 552 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id909e7ab3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Publication in Federal Register</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of complying pursuant to paragraph (1) with <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552/a/1">section 552(a)(1) of title 5</ref>, the Democracy Corps shall make available to the Administrator such records and other information as the Administrator determines may be necessary for such purposes. The Administrator shall cause such records and other information to be published in the Federal Register.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id909e7ab4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/h/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> AID review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the event that the Democracy Corps determines not to comply with a request for records under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">section 552 of title 5</ref>, the Democracy Corps shall submit a report to the Administrator explaining the reasons for not complying with such request. If the Administrator approves such determination, the Agency for International Development shall assume full responsibility, including financial responsibility, for defending the Democracy Corps in any litigation relating to such request. If the Administrator disapproves such determination, the Democracy Corps shall be required to comply with such request.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id909e7ab5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board shall be required to submit to the Administrator and the Congress, not later than January 31 each year, a comprehensive report on the activities of the Democracy Corps. Each such report shall list each grant made by the Democracy Corps under subsection (d)(2) during the preceding fiscal year, specifying the grantee and the amount of the grant.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id909e7ab6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Of the amount authorized to be appropriated to carry out chapter 11 of part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2295">22 U.S.C. 2295</ref> et seq.], up to $15,000,000 for fiscal year 1993 are authorized to be appropriated for grants to the Democracy Corps under this section, in addition to amounts otherwise available for such purpose.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id909e7ab7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Sunset provision</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Grants may not be made to the Democracy Corps under this section after the end of fiscal year 1997.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id909e7ab8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id909e7ab9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/l/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Agency for International Development; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id909e7aba-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5841/l/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the term “Board” means the Board of Directors of the Democracy Corps.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id909e7abb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/511/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 102–511, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3335">106 Stat. 3335</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id909e7abc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id909e7abd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id909e7abe-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, referred to in subsec. (j), is <ref href="/us/pl/87/195">Pub. L. 87–195</ref>, <date date="1961-09-04">Sept. 4, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/424">75 Stat. 424</ref>. Chapter 11 of part I of the Act is classified generally to part XI (§ 2295 et seq.) of subchapter I of chapter 32 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2151">section 2151 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
