<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90a334c5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5951"><num value="5951">§ 5951.</num><heading> Findings on cooperative threat reduction</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress finds that it is in the national security interest of the United States for the United States to do the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90a334c6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5951/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Facilitate, on a priority basis, the transportation, storage, safeguarding, and elimination of nuclear and other weapons of the independent states of the former Soviet Union, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90a334c7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5951/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the safe and secure storage of fissile materials derived from the elimination of nuclear weapons;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90a334c8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5951/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the dismantlement of (i) intercontinental ballistic missiles and launchers for such missiles, (ii) submarine-launched ballistic missiles and launchers for such missiles, and (iii) heavy bombers; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90a334c9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5951/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the elimination of chemical, biological and other weapons capabilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90a334ca-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5951/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Facilitate, on a priority basis, the prevention of proliferation of weapons (and components of weapons) of mass destruction and destabilizing conventional weapons of the independent states of the former Soviet Union and the establishment of verifiable safeguards against the proliferation of such weapons and components.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90a334cb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5951/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Facilitate, on a priority basis, the prevention of diversion of weapons-related scientific expertise of the independent states of the former Soviet Union to terrorist groups or third world countries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90a334cc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5951/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Support (A) the demilitarization of the defense-related industry and equipment of the independent states of the former Soviet Union, and (B) the conversion of such industry and equipment to civilian purposes and uses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90a334cd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s5951/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Expand military-to-military and defense contacts between the United States and the independent states of the former Soviet Union.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id90a334ce-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tXII/s1202">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XII, § 1202</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1777">107 Stat. 1777</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id90a334cf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id90a334d0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="id90a334d1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 2003 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dC/tXXXVI/s3601">Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXVI, § 3601</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1822">117 Stat. 1822</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/136/dC/tXXXVI/s3601">“This title [enacting provisions set out as notes under this section and sections 1928, 5959, and 6321 of this title] may be cited as the ‘Nuclear Security Initiative Act of 2003’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="id90a334d2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tXII/s1201">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XII, § 1201</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1777">107 Stat. 1777</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tXII/s1201">“This title [enacting this chapter] may be cited as the ‘Cooperative Threat Reduction Act of 1993’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90a334d3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Congressional Notification</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tXII/s1246/c/3">Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title XII, § 1246(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/924">127 Stat. 924</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tXII/s1243/3">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title XII, § 1243(3)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3564">128 Stat. 3564</ref>, which required that the Secretary of Defense notify certain congressional committees of the Secretary’s intent to provide the Russian Federation with any sensitive missile defense information not less than 7 days prior to the provision of such information, including an explanation of the reasons for providing the information and the reasons why providing the information would not compromise United States national security, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/114/92/dA/tXVI/s1671/b/1">Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title XVI, § 1671(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/1130">129 Stat. 1130</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90a334d4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Briefings to Congressional Committees</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tXII/s1251/b">Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title XII, § 1251(b)</ref>, <date date="2013-12-26">Dec. 26, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/926">127 Stat. 926</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/66/dA/tXII/s1251/b">“Prior to signing an executive agreement with the Russian Federation relating to ballistic missile defense, the President, or the President’s designee, shall brief the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives on the objectives and contents of the executive agreement.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90a334d5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Sense of Congress on Agreements Between the United States and the Russian Federation on Nuclear Arms, Missile Defense Systems, and Long-Range Conventional Strike Systems</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dA/tXII/s1282">Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XII, § 1282</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2034">126 Stat. 2034</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/114/92/dA/tX/s1076/c">Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title X, § 1076(c)</ref>, <date date="2015-11-25">Nov. 25, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/998">129 Stat. 998</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/92/dA/tX/s1076/c">“It is the sense of Congress that any agreement between the United States and the Russian Federation related to nuclear arms, missile defense systems, or long-range conventional strike systems obligating the United States to reduce or limit the Armed Forces or armaments of the United States in any militarily significant manner may be made only pursuant to the treaty-making power of the President as set forth in Article II, section 2, clause 2 of the Constitution of the United States.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90a334d6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Sharing of Classified United States Ballistic Missile Defense Information With the Russian Federation</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/81/dA/tXII/s1244">Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title XII, § 1244</ref>, <date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1646">125 Stat. 1646</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/81/dA/tXII/s1244">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notification</inline>.—</heading><content>No classified United States ballistic missile defense information may be made available to the Russian Federation unless, 60 days prior to any instance in which the United States Government plans to provide such information to the Russian Federation, the President provides notification thereof to the appropriate congressional committees.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements of Notification</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each notification provided pursuant to subsection (a) shall include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> A detailed description of the classified United States ballistic missile defense information to be provided.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> An explanation of the national security interest in providing the information to the Russian Federation and any provisions for reciprocal sharing by the Russian Federation with the United States on its defensive systems.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> A certification that providing the information is consistent with United States national disclosure policy as of the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>] and that the decision to provide the information was made pursuant to a national disclosure policy review.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> If applicable, a detailed explanation of whether any exceptions to national disclosure policy were required in order to provide the information to the Russian Federation and why such exceptions were required.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> A certification that adequate measures are in place to protect the information from unauthorized disclosure. The certification shall include a description of the manner in which the information will be protected from unauthorized sharing or transfer to third parties as well as an analysis of the risks to the capabilities of the United States ballistic missile defense system if the information is shared or transferred to an unauthorized third party.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Form</inline>.—</heading><content>Each notification provided pursuant to subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate Congressional Committees Defined</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For the purposes of this section, the term ‘appropriate congressional committees’ means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Classified United States Ballistic Missile Defense Information Defined</inline>.—</heading><content>For the purposes of this section, the term ‘classified United States ballistic missile defense information’ means information related to United States ballistic missile defenses that is classified as of, or after, the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2011-12-31">Dec. 31, 2011</date>].”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90a334d7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Establishment of Interparliamentary Threat Reduction Working Group</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dC/tXXXVI/s3622">Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXVI, § 3622</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1824">117 Stat. 1824</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/136/dC/tXXXVI/s3622">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Working Group</inline>.—</heading><content>There is hereby established a working group to be known as the ‘Threat Reduction Working Group’ as an interparliamentary group of the Congress of the United States and the legislature of the Russian Federation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purpose of Working Group</inline>.—</heading><content>The purpose of the working group established by subsection (a) shall be to explore means to enhance cooperation between the United States and the Russian Federation with respect to nuclear nonproliferation and security and such other issues related to reducing the dangers of weapons of mass destruction as the members of the working group consider appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Membership</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The majority leader of the Senate, after consultation with the minority leader of the Senate, shall appoint not more than 10 Senators to the working group established by subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Speaker of the House of Representatives, after consultation with the minority leader of the House of Representatives, shall appoint not more than 30 Members of the House to the working group.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90a334d8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer to National Nuclear Security Administration of Department of Defense’s Cooperative Threat Reduction Program Relating to Elimination of Weapons Grade Plutonium Production in Russia</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dC/tXXXI/s3151">Pub. L. 107–314, div. C, title XXXI, § 3151</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2736">116 Stat. 2736</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/dC/tXXXI/s3135">Pub. L. 108–375, div. C, title XXXI, § 3135</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/2170">118 Stat. 2170</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/375/dC/tXXXI/s3135">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transfer of Program</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>There are hereby transferred to the Administrator for Nuclear Security the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The program, within the Cooperative Threat Reduction program of the Department of Defense, relating to the elimination of weapons grade plutonium production in Russia.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> All functions, powers, duties, and activities of that program performed before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>] by the Department of Defense.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transfer of Assets</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding any restriction or limitation in law on the availability of Cooperative Threat Reduction funds specified in paragraph (2), so much of the property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, and other funds employed, used, held, available, or to be made available in connection with the program transferred by subsection (a) are transferred to the Administrator for use in connection with the program transferred.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> The Cooperative Threat Reduction funds specified in this paragraph are the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Fiscal year 2002 Cooperative Threat Reduction funds, as specified in section 1301(b) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2002 (<ref href="/us/pl/107/107">Public Law 107–107</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/115/1254">115 Stat. 1254</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s5952">22 U.S.C. 5952</ref> note).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Fiscal year 2001 Cooperative Threat Reduction funds, as specified in section 1301(b) of the Floyd D. Spence National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2001 (as enacted into law by <ref href="/us/pl/106/398">Public Law 106–398</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>A–339; <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s5959">22 U.S.C. 5959</ref> note).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Fiscal year 2000 Cooperative Threat Reduction funds, as specified in section 1301(b) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2000 (<ref href="/us/pl/106/65">Public Law 106–65</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/113/792">113 Stat. 792</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s5952">22 U.S.C. 5952</ref> note).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Availability of Transferred Funds</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Notwithstanding any restriction or limitation in law on the availability of Cooperative Threat Reduction funds specified in subsection (b)(2), the Cooperative Threat Reduction funds transferred under subsection (b) for the program referred to in subsection (a) shall be available for activities as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> To design and construct, refurbish, or both, fossil fuel energy plants in Russia that provide alternative sources of energy to the energy plants in Russia that produce weapons grade plutonium.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> To carry out limited safety upgrades of not more than three energy plants in Russia that produce weapons grade plutonium, provided that such upgrades do not extend the life of those plants.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Amounts available under paragraph (1) for activities referred to in that paragraph shall remain available for obligation for three fiscal years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated by this title or any other Act for the program referred to in subsection (a), the Administrator for Nuclear Security may not obligate any funds for construction, or obligate or expend more than $100,000,000 for that program, until 30 days after the later of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the date on which the Administrator submits to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives], the Committee on International Relations [now Committee on Foreign Affairs] of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, a copy of an agreement or agreements entered into between the United States Government and the Government of the Russian Federation to shut down the three plutonium-producing reactors in Russia as specified under paragraph (2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the date on which the Administrator submits to the committees specified in subparagraph (A) a report on a plan to achieve international participation in the program referred to in subsection (a), including cost sharing.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> The agreement (or agreements) under paragraph (1)(A) shall contain—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a commitment to shut down the three plutonium-producing reactors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the date on which each such reactor will be shut down;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> a schedule and milestones for each such reactor to complete the shutdown of such reactor by the date specified under subparagraph (B);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> a schedule and milestones for refurbishment or construction of fossil fuel energy plants to be undertaken by the Government of the Russian Federation in support of the program;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> an arrangement for access to sites and facilities necessary to meet such schedules and milestones;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> an arrangement for audit and examination procedures in order to evaluate progress in meeting such schedules and milestones; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> any cost sharing arrangements between the United States Government and the Government of the Russian Federation in undertaking activities under such agreement (or agreements).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">International Participation in Program</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In order to achieve international participation in the program referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of Energy may, in consultation with the Secretary of State, enter into one or more agreements with any person, foreign government, or other international organization that the Secretary considers appropriate for the contribution of funds by such person, government, or organization for purposes of the program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3302">section 3302 of title 31</ref>, United States Code, and subject to paragraphs (3) and (4), the Secretary may retain and utilize any amounts contributed by a person, government, or organization under an agreement under paragraph (1) for purposes of the program without further appropriation and without fiscal year limitation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The Secretary may not utilize under paragraph (2) any amount contributed under an agreement under paragraph (1) until 30 days after the date on which the Secretary notifies the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] of the intent to utilize such amount, including the source of such amount and the proposed purpose for which such amount will be utilized.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> If any amount contributed under paragraph (1) has not been utilized within five years of receipt under that paragraph, the Secretary shall return such amount to the person, government, or organization contributing such amount under that paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Not later than 30 days after the receipt of any amount contributed under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a notice of the receipt of such amount.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="6">“(6)</num><chapeau> Not later than October 31 each year, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the receipt and utilization of amounts under this subsection during the preceding fiscal year. Each report for a fiscal year shall set forth—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a statement of any amounts received under this subsection, including the source of each such amount; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a statement of any amounts utilized under this subsection, including the purpose for which such amounts were utilized.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> The authority of the Secretary to accept and utilize amounts under this subsection shall expire on <date date="2011-12-31">December 31, 2011</date>.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90a334d9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Accelerated Disposition of Highly Enriched Uranium</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dC/tXXXI/s3157">Pub. L. 107–314, div. C, title XXXI, § 3157</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2740">116 Stat. 2740</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/314/dC/tXXXI/s3157">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program on Accelerated Disposition of HEU Authorized</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary of Energy may carry out a program to pursue with the Russian Federation options for blending highly enriched uranium so that the concentration of U–235 in such uranium is below 20 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> The options pursued under paragraph (1) shall include expansion of the Material Consolidation and Conversion program of the Department of Energy to include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> additional facilities for the blending of highly enriched uranium; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> additional centralized secure storage facilities for highly enriched uranium designated for blending.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Any site selected for the storage of uranium or blended material under paragraph (2)(B) shall undergo complete materials protection, control, and accounting upgrades before the commencement of the storage of uranium or blended material at such site under the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Construction With HEU Disposition Agreement</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this section may be construed as terminating, modifying, or otherwise affecting requirements for the disposition of highly enriched uranium under the Agreement Between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the Russian Federation Concerning the Disposition of Highly Enriched Uranium Extracted from Nuclear Weapons, signed at Washington on <date date="1993-02-18">February 18, 1993</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Release for Sale of Blended Uranium</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Uranium blended under this section may not be released for sale until the earlier of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> <date date="2014-01-01">January 1, 2014</date>; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the date on which the Secretary certifies that such uranium can be absorbed into the global market without undue disruption to the uranium mining, conversion, and enrichment industry in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Amount for Activities</inline>.—</heading><content>Of the amount to be appropriated by section 3101(a)(2) [<ref href="/us/stat/116/2729">116 Stat. 2729</ref>] for the Department of Energy for the National Nuclear Security Administration for defense nuclear nonproliferation, up to $10,000,000 may be available for carrying out this section.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90a334da-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plan for Accelerated Return of Weapons-Usable Nuclear Materials</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dC/tXXXI/s3160">Pub. L. 107–314, div. C, title XXXI, § 3160</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2742">116 Stat. 2742</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/314/dC/tXXXI/s3160">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Plan for Accelerated Return</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Energy shall work with the Russian Federation to develop a plan to accelerate the return to Russia of all weapons-usable nuclear materials located in research reactors and other facilities outside Russia that were supplied by the former Soviet Union.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Funding and Schedules</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>As part of the plan under subsection (a), the Secretary shall identify the funding and schedules required to assist the research reactors and facilities referred to in that subsection in—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> transferring highly enriched uranium to Russia; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> upgrading the materials protection, control, and accounting procedures at such research reactors and facilities until the weapons-usable nuclear materials in such reactors and facilities are returned in accordance with that subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coordination</inline>.—</heading><content>The provision of assistance under subsection (b) shall be closely coordinated with the International Atomic Energy Agency.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90a334db-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plan for Securing Nuclear Weapons, Material, and Expertise of the States of the Former Soviet Union</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dA/tXII/s1205">Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title XII, § 1205</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1247">115 Stat. 1247</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tXII/s1205">Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title XII, § 1205</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2664">116 Stat. 2664</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/314/dA/tXII/s1205">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Plan Required</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than <date date="2002-06-15">June 15, 2002</date>, the President shall submit to Congress a plan, that has been developed in coordination with all relevant Federal agencies—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> for cooperating with Russia on disposing, as soon as practicable, of nuclear weapons and weapons-usable nuclear material in Russia that Russia does not retain in its nuclear arsenals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> for assisting Russia in downsizing its nuclear weapons research and production complex;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> for cooperating with the other states of the former Soviet Union on disposing, as soon as practicable, of all nuclear weapons and weapons-usable nuclear material in such states; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> for preventing the outflow from the states of the former Soviet Union of scientific expertise that could be used for developing nuclear weapons, other weapons of mass destruction, and delivery systems for such weapons.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Content of Plan</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The plan required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Specific goals and measurable objectives for programs that are designed to carry out the objectives described in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Criteria for success for such programs, and a strategy for eventual termination of United States contributions to such programs and assumption of the ongoing support of those programs by others.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> A description of any administrative and organizational changes necessary to improve the coordination and effectiveness of such programs. In particular, the plan shall include consideration of the creation of an interagency committee that would have primary responsibilities within the executive branch for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> monitoring United States nonproliferation efforts in the states of the former Soviet Union;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> coordinating the implementation of United States policy with respect to such efforts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> recommending to the President integrated policies, budget options, and private sector and international contributions for such programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> An estimate of the cost of carrying out such programs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In developing the plan required by subsection (a), the President—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> is encouraged to consult with the relevant states of the former Soviet Union regarding the practicality of various options; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> shall consult with the majority and minority leadership of the appropriate committees of Congress.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Report on Implementation of Plan</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not later than <date date="2003-01-31">January 31, 2003</date>, and each year thereafter, the President shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation of the plan required by subsection (a) during the preceding year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> Each report under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a discussion of progress made during the year covered by such report in the matters of the plan required by subsection (a);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a discussion of consultations with foreign nations, and in particular the Russian Federation, during such year on joint programs to implement the plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> a discussion of cooperation, coordination, and integration during such year in the implementation of the plan among the various departments and agencies of the United States Government, as well as private entities that share objectives similar to the objectives of the plan; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> any recommendations that the President considers appropriate regarding modifications to law or regulations, or to the administration or organization of any Federal department or agency, in order to improve the effectiveness of any programs carried out during such year in the implementation of the plan.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Functions of President under <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/s1205/d">section 1205(d) of Pub. L. 107–107</ref>, set out above, delegated to Secretary of State by Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2005-11-02">Nov. 2, 2005</date>, 70 F.R. 72055.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90a334dc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Russian Nonstrategic Nuclear Arms</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tXIII/s1312">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title XIII, § 1312</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/796">113 Stat. 796</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title XIII, § 1308(g)(3)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–343, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">
<inline>“It is the sense of Congress that—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> it is in the interest of Russia to fully implement the Presidential Nuclear Initiatives announced in 1991 and 1992 by then-President of the Soviet Union Gorbachev and then-President of Russia Yeltsin;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the President of the United States should call on Russia to match the unilateral reductions in the United States inventory of tactical nuclear weapons, which have reduced the inventory by nearly 90 percent; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> if the re-certification under section 1310 [<ref href="/us/stat/113/795">113 Stat. 795</ref>] is made, the President should emphasize the continued interest of the United States in working cooperatively with Russia to reduce the dangers associated with Russia’s tactical nuclear arsenal.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90a334dd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Limitation on Use of Funds for Chemical Weapons Destruction Activities in Russia</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/261/dA/tXIII/s1304">Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title XIII, § 1304</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2163">112 Stat. 2163</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/261/dA/tXIII/s1304">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to the limitation in section 1405(b) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1998 (<ref href="/us/pl/105/85">Public Law 105–85</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/111/1961">111 Stat. 1961</ref>), no funds authorized to be appropriated for Cooperative Threat Reduction programs under this Act [see Tables for classification] or any other Act may be obligated or expended for chemical weapons destruction activities in Russia (including activities for the planning, design, or construction of a chemical weapons destruction facility or for the dismantlement of an existing chemical weapons production facility) until the President submits to Congress a written certification described in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Presidential Certification</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A certification under this subsection is either of the following certifications by the President:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> A certification that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Russia is making reasonable progress toward the implementation of the Bilateral Destruction Agreement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the United States and Russia have made substantial progress toward the resolution, to the satisfaction of the United States, of outstanding compliance issues under the Wyoming Memorandum of Understanding and the Bilateral Destruction Agreement; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Russia has fully and accurately declared all information regarding its unitary and binary chemical weapons, chemical weapons facilities, and other facilities associated with chemical weapons.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> A certification that the national security interests of the United States could be undermined by a policy of the United States not to carry out chemical weapons destruction activities under Cooperative Threat Reduction programs for which funds are authorized to be appropriated under this Act or any other Act for fiscal year 1999.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The term ‘Bilateral Destruction Agreement’ means the Agreement Between the United States of America and the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics on Destruction and Non-production of Chemical Weapons and on Measures to Facilitate the Multilateral Convention on Banning Chemical Weapons signed on <date date="1990-06-01">June 1, 1990</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The term ‘Wyoming Memorandum of Understanding’ means the Memorandum of Understanding Between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics Regarding a Bilateral Verification Experiment and Data Exchange Related to Prohibition on Chemical Weapons, signed at Jackson Hole, Wyoming, on <date date="1989-09-23">September 23, 1989</date>.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="1999-07-16">July 16, 1999</date>, 64 F.R. 40503, delegated to Secretary of Defense authority of President under <ref href="/us/pl/105/261/s1304/b/2">section 1304(b)(2) of Public Law 105–261</ref>, set out above.]</p>
<p>Similar provisions were contained in the following prior authorization acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dA/tXIV/s1406">Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title XIV, § 1406</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1961">111 Stat. 1961</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tXII/s1209">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XII, § 1209</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/472">110 Stat. 472</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90a334de-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Congressional Reports on Cooperative Threat Reduction Programs</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tXII">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XII</ref>, §§ 1201, 1205, 1206, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/469">110 Stat. 469</ref>, 470, 471, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dA/tXIV/s1431">Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1431</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2726">110 Stat. 2726</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tX/s1067/6">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(6)</ref>, title XIII, § 1311, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/774">113 Stat. 774</ref>, 796; <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title XIII, § 1308(g)(1)(C)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–343; <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tXIII/s1351/4">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title XIII, § 1351(4)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3607">128 Stat. 3607</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tXIII/s1351/4">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1201">“SEC. 1201.</num><heading> SPECIFICATION OF COOPERATIVE THREAT REDUCTION PROGRAMS.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of section 301 [<ref href="/us/stat/110/245">110 Stat. 245</ref>] and other provisions of this Act [see Tables for classification], Cooperative Threat Reduction programs are the programs specified in subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Specified Programs</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The programs referred to in subsection (a) are the following programs with respect to states of the former Soviet Union:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Programs to facilitate the elimination, and the safe and secure transportation and storage, of nuclear, chemical, and other weapons, fissile material suitable for use in nuclear weapons, and their delivery vehicles.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Programs to facilitate the safe and secure storage of fissile materials derived from the elimination of nuclear weapons.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Programs to prevent the proliferation of weapons, weapons components, and weapons-related technology and expertise.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Programs to expand military-to-military and defense contacts.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467" status="repealed"><num value="1205">“[SEC. 1205.</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/113/291/dA/tXIII/s1351/4">Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title XIII, § 1351(4)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3607">128 Stat. 3607</ref>.]</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467" status="repealed"><num value="1206">“[SEC. 1206.</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title XIII, § 1308(g)(1)(C)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–343.]”</content>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90a334df-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Condition on Assistance to Russia for Construction of Plutonium Storage Facility</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tXVI/s1612">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XVI, § 1612</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1850">107 Stat. 1850</ref>, provided:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tXVI/s1612">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading><content>Until a certification under subsection (b) is made, no funds may be obligated or expended by the United States for the purpose of assisting the Ministry of Atomic Energy of Russia to construct a storage facility for surplus plutonium from dismantled weapons.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certification of Russia’s Commitment to Halt Chemical Separation of Weapon-Grade Plutonium</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The prohibition in subsection (a) shall cease to apply upon a certification by the President to Congress that Russia—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> is committed to halting the chemical separation of weapon-grade plutonium from spent nuclear fuel; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> is taking all practical steps to halt such separation at the earliest possible date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sense of Congress on Plutonium Policy</inline>.—</heading><content>It is the sense of Congress that a key objective of the United States with respect to the nonproliferation of nuclear weapons should be to obtain a clear and unequivocal commitment from the Government of Russia that it will (1) cease all production and separation of weapon-grade plutonium, and (2) halt chemical separation of plutonium produced in civil nuclear power reactors.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="1994-06-01">June 1, 1994</date>, the President shall submit to Congress a report on the status of efforts by the United States to secure the commitments and achieve the objective described in subsections (b) and (c). The President shall include in the report a discussion of the status of joint efforts by the United States and Russia to replace any remaining Russian plutonium production reactors with alternative power sources or to convert such reactors to operation with alternative fuels that would permit their operation without generating weapon-grade plutonium.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="1994-03-10">Mar. 10, 1994</date>, 59 F.R. 14079, delegated to Secretary of State authority and duty of President under section 1612(b) and (d) of <ref href="/us/pl/103/160">Public Law 103–160</ref> set out above.]</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
