<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90aa61dd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6085"><num value="6085">§ 6085.</num><heading> Effective date</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90aa61de-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6085/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to subsections (b) and (c), this subchapter and the amendments made by this subchapter shall take effect on <date date="1996-08-01">August 1, 1996</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90aa61df-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6085/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Suspension authority</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90aa61e0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6085/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Suspension authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President may suspend the effective date under subsection (a) for a period of not more than 6 months if the President determines and reports in writing to the appropriate congressional committees at least 15 days before such effective date that the suspension is necessary to the national interests of the United States and will expedite a transition to democracy in Cuba.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90aa61e1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6085/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional suspensions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President may suspend the effective date under subsection (a) for additional periods of not more than 6 months each, each of which shall begin on the day after the last day of the period during which a suspension is in effect under this subsection, if the President determines and reports in writing to the appropriate congressional committees at least 15 days before the date on which the additional suspension is to begin that the suspension is necessary to the national interests of the United States and will expedite a transition to democracy in Cuba.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90aa61e2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6085/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Other authorities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90aa61e3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6085/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Suspension</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">After this subchapter and the amendments of this subchapter have taken effect—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90aa61e4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6085/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> no person shall acquire a property interest in any potential or pending action under this subchapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90aa61e5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6085/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the President may suspend the right to bring an action under this subchapter with respect to confiscated property for a period of not more than 6 months if the President determines and reports in writing to the appropriate congressional committees at least 15 days before the suspension takes effect that such suspension is necessary to the national interests of the United States and will expedite a transition to democracy in Cuba.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90aa61e6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6085/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional suspensions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President may suspend the right to bring an action under this subchapter for additional periods of not more than 6 months each, each of which shall begin on the day after the last day of the period during which a suspension is in effect under this subsection, if the President determines and reports in writing to the appropriate congressional committees at least 15 days before the date on which the additional suspension is to begin that the suspension is necessary to the national interests of the United States and will expedite a transition to democracy in Cuba.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90aa61e7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6085/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Pending suits</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The suspensions of actions under paragraph (1) shall not affect suits commenced before the date of such suspension, and in all such suits, proceedings shall be had, appeals taken, and judgments rendered in the same manner and with the same effect as if the suspension had not occurred.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90aa61e8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6085/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Rescission of suspension</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President may rescind any suspension made under subsection (b) or (c) upon reporting to the appropriate congressional committees that doing so will expedite a transition to democracy in Cuba.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id90aa61e9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/104/114/tIII/s306">Pub. L. 104–114, title III, § 306</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/821">110 Stat. 821</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id90aa61ea-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id90aa61eb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id90aa61ec-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subchapter, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (c)(1), was in the original “this title”, meaning title III of <ref href="/us/pl/104/114">Pub. L. 104–114</ref>, <date date="1996-03-12">Mar. 12, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/814">110 Stat. 814</ref>, which enacted this subchapter and sections 1643<i>l</i> and 1643m of this title and amended <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s1611">section 1611 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure. For complete classification of title III to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id90aa61ed-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90aa61ee-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Authority To Suspend the Provisions of Title III of the Cuban Liberty and Democratic Solidarity (LIBERTAD) Act of 1996</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2013-01-31">Jan. 31, 2013</date>, 78 F.R. 9573, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum for the Secretary of State</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref> of the United States Code, I hereby delegate to you the authority to suspend the provisions of title III of the Cuban Liberty and Democratic Solidarity (LIBERTAD) Act of 1996 (<ref href="/us/pl/104/114">Public Law 104–114</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6021–609">22 U.S.C. 6021–609</ref>1), as authorized by section 306(c)(2) of the Act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the Federal Register.</p>
<signature>
<name>Barack Obama.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
