<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90acab9a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204"><num value="6204">§ 6204.</num><heading> Authorities of Chief Executive Officer</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90acab9b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Chief Executive Officer shall have the following authorities:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acab9c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> To supervise all broadcasting activities conducted pursuant to this chapter, the Radio Broadcasting to Cuba Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1465">22 U.S.C. 1465</ref> et seq.],,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002332">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002332"><num>1</num> So in original.</note> the Television Broadcasting to Cuba Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1465aa">22 U.S.C. 1465aa</ref> et seq.], and Worldnet Television, except as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6205/b">section 6205(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acab9d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> To review and evaluate the mission and operation of, and to assess the quality, effectiveness, and professional integrity of, all such activities within the context of the broad foreign policy objectives of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acab9e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> To ensure that United States international broadcasting is conducted in accordance with the standards and principles contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6202">section 6202 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acab9f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> To review, evaluate, and determine, at least annually, after consultation with the Secretary of State, the addition or deletion of language services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acaba0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> To make and supervise grants and cooperative agreements for broadcasting and related activities in furtherance of the purposes of this chapter and on behalf of other agencies, accordingly.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acaba1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> To allocate funds appropriated for international broadcasting activities among the various elements of the Agency and grantees, subject to reprogramming notification requirements in law for the reallocation of funds.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acaba2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> To review engineering activities to ensure that all broadcasting elements receive the highest quality and cost-effective delivery services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acaba3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> To undertake such studies as may be necessary to identify areas in which broadcasting activities under its authority could be made more efficient and economical.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acaba4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> To submit to the President and the Congress an annual report which summarizes and evaluates activities under this chapter, the Radio Broadcasting to Cuba Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1465">22 U.S.C. 1465</ref> et seq.], and the Television Broadcasting to Cuba Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1465aa">22 U.S.C. 1465aa</ref> et seq.]. Each annual report shall place special emphasis on the assessment described in paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acaba5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> To the extent considered necessary to carry out the functions of the Chief Executive Officer, procure, rent, or lease supplies, services, and other property for journalism, media, production, and broadcasting, and related support services, notwithstanding any other provision of law relating to such acquisition, rental, or lease, and under the same terms and conditions as authorized under section 501(b) of the United States Information and Educational Exchange Act of 1948 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1461/b">22 U.S.C. 1461(b)</ref>), and for multiyear contracts and leases for periods of up to 20 years subject to the requirements of subsections (b) through (f) of <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s3903">section 3903 of title 41</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acaba6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> To appoint such personnel for the Chief Executive Officer as the Chief Executive Officer may determine to be necessary, which shall not be subject to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service, and to fix their compensation in accordance with the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acaba7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> To obligate and expend, for official reception and representation expenses, such amount as may be made available through appropriations (which for each of the fiscal years 1998 and 1999 may not exceed the amount made available to the Chief Executive Officer and the International Broadcasting Bureau for such purposes for fiscal year 1997).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acaba8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> To make available in the annual report required by paragraph (9) information on funds expended on administrative and managerial services by the Agency and by grantees and the steps the Chief Executive Officer has taken to reduce unnecessary overhead costs for each of the broadcasting services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acaba9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> The Chief Executive Officer may provide for the use of United States Government transmitter capacity for transmission or relay of Radio Free Asia or any other grantee authorized under this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acabaa-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acabab-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/15/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> To procure personal services at rates not to exceed the daily equivalent of the rate provided for positions classified above grade GS–15 of the General Schedule under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5108">section 5108 of title 5</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acabac-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/15/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> To allow those providing such services, while away from their homes or their regular places of business, travel expenses (including per diem in lieu of subsistence) as authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5703">section 5703 of title 5</ref> for persons in the Government service employed intermittently, while so employed.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acabad-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/16"><num value="16">(16)</num><content> To procure, pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1535">section 1535 of title 31</ref> (commonly known as the “Economy Act”), such goods and services from other departments or agencies for the Chief Executive Officer and the International Broadcasting Bureau as the Chief Executive Officer determines are appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acabae-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/17"><num value="17">(17)</num><content> To utilize the provisions of titles III, IV, V, VII, VIII, IX, and X of the United States Information and Educational Exchange Act of 1948 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1431">22 U.S.C. 1431</ref> et seq.], and section 6 of Reorganization Plan Number 2 of 1977, as in effect on the day before the effective date of title XIII of the Foreign Affairs Agencies Consolidation Act of 1998, to the extent the Chief Executive Officer considers necessary in carrying out the provisions and purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acabaf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/18"><num value="18">(18)</num><content> To utilize the authorities of any other statute, reorganization plan, Executive order, regulation, agreement, determination, or other official document or proceeding that had been available to the Director of the United States Information Agency, the Chief Executive Officer, or the Chief Executive Officer <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002333">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002333"><num>2</num> So in original. See 2016 Amendment note below.</note> before the effective date of title XIII of the Foreign Affairs Consolidation Act of 1998 for carrying out the broadcasting activities covered by this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acabb0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/19"><num value="19">(19)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acabb1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/19/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> To provide for the payment of primary and secondary school expenses for dependents of personnel stationed in the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands (CNMI) at a cost not to exceed expenses authorized by the Department of Defense for such schooling for dependents of members of the Armed Forces stationed in the Commonwealth, if the Chief Executive Officer determines that schools available in the Commonwealth are unable to provide adequately for the education of the dependents of such personnel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acabb2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/19/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> To provide transportation for dependents of such personnel between their places of residence and those schools for which expenses are provided under subparagraph (A), if the Chief Executive Officer determines that such schools are not accessible by public means of transportation.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acabb3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/20"><num value="20">(20)</num><content> To redirect or reprogram funds within the scope of any grant or cooperative agreement, or between grantees, as necessary (and not later than 15 days before any such redirection of funds between language services, to notify the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate regarding such redirection),.<sup>1</sup></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acabb4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/21"><num value="21">(21)</num><content> To change the name of the Agency pursuant to congressional notification 60 days prior to any such change.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90acabb5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/22"><num value="22">(22)</num><chapeau> To—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90acabb6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/22/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> require annual content reviews of each language service of Voice of America, The Office of Cuba Broadcasting, and each grantee network, consisting of a review of at least 10 percent of available unique weekly content from any selected week from the previous year, which shall be conducted, to the extent practicable, by fluent language speakers and experts without direct affiliation to the language service being reviewed, who are seeking any evidence of inappropriate or unprofessional content, which shall be submitted to the Office of Policy Research, the head and Board of the respective language service, and the Chief Executive Officer;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90acabb7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/22/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> submit to the appropriate congressional committees a list of anomalous reports, including status updates on anomalous services during the 3-year period commencing on the date of receipt of the first report of biased, unprofessional, or otherwise problematic content.”; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002334">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002334"><num>3</num> So in original. The period and quotation marks preceding the semicolon probably should not appear.</note> and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90acabb8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/a/22/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> launch a review, using external, native-language and regional experts, the results of which are to be reported to the appropriate congressional committees, if a widespread pattern of violations of the principles, standards, or journalistic code of ethics of a language service or grantee network has been identified.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90acabb9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Professional independence of broadcasters</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of State and the Chief Executive Officer, in carrying out their functions, shall respect the professional independence and integrity of the Agency, its broadcasting services, and the grantees of the Agency.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90acabba-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on corporate leadership of grantees</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90acabbb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Chief Executive Officer may not award any grant under subsection (a) to RFE/RL, Inc., Radio Free Asia, the Middle East Broadcasting Networks, the Open Technology Fund, or any other grantee authorized under this chapter (collectively referred to as “Agency Grantee Networks”) unless the incorporation documents of any such grantee require that the corporate leadership and Board of Directors of such grantee be selected in accordance with this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90acabbc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Conflicts of interest</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90acabbd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/c/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Chief Executive Officer</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Chief Executive Officer may not serve on any of the corporate boards of any grantee under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90acabbe-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/c/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal employees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A full-time employee of a Federal agency may not serve on a corporate board of any grantee under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90acabbf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6204/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Qualifications of grantee board members</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Individuals appointed under subsection (a) to the Board of Directors of any of the Agency Grantee Networks shall have requisite expertise in journalism, technology, broadcasting, or diplomacy, or appropriate language or cultural understanding relevant to the grantee’s mission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id90acabc0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/103/236/tIII/s305">Pub. L. 103–236, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/435">108 Stat. 435</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/415/s1/s/1">Pub. L. 103–415, § 1(s)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-25">Oct. 25, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4302">108 Stat. 4302</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dG">Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIII, § 1323(e)–(i), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-778">112 Stat. 2681–778</ref>, 2681–779; <ref href="/us/pl/107/228/dA/tV/s507/1">Pub. L. 107–228, div. A, title V, § 507(1)</ref>, <date date="2002-09-30">Sept. 30, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1394">116 Stat. 1394</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/140/s8">Pub. L. 109–140, § 8</ref>, <date date="2005-12-22">Dec. 22, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/2652">119 Stat. 2652</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/dA/tXII/s1288/2">Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1288(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-12-23">Dec. 23, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2549">130 Stat. 2549</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXII">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII</ref>, §§ 1299P(c)(2), 1299Q(c), (e)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4020">134 Stat. 4020</ref>, 4021, 4025; <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dI/tXCVII/s9706">Pub. L. 117–263, div. I, title XCVII, § 9706</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3915">136 Stat. 3915</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id90acabc1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id90acabc2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id90acabc3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1), (9), (17), (18) and (c)(1) the first place appearing, was in the original “this title”, meaning title III of <ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/432">108 Stat. 432</ref>, known as the United States International Broadcasting Act of 1994, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of title III to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6201">section 6201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Radio Broadcasting to Cuba Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), (9), is <ref href="/us/pl/98/111">Pub. L. 98–111</ref>, <date date="1983-10-04">Oct. 4, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/749">97 Stat. 749</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter V–A (§ 1465 et seq.) of chapter 18 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1465">section 1465 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Television Broadcasting to Cuba Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), (9), is part D of title II of <ref href="/us/pl/101/246">Pub. L. 101–246</ref>, <date date="1990-02-16">Feb. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/58">104 Stat. 58</ref>, which is classified principally to subchapter V–B (§ 1465aa et seq.) of chapter 18 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1465aa">section 1465aa of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a)(5), (14) and (c)(1) the second place appearing, was in the original “this Act”, and was translated, to reflect the probable intent of Congress, as reading “this title”, meaning title III of <ref href="/us/pl/103/236">Pub. L. 103–236</ref>, <date date="1994-04-30">Apr. 30, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/432">108 Stat. 432</ref>, known as the United States International Broadcasting Act of 1994, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of title III to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6201">section 6201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The United States Information and Educational Exchange Act of 1948, referred to in subsec. (a)(17), is <ref href="/us/act/1948-01-27/ch36">act Jan. 27, 1948, ch. 36</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/6">62 Stat. 6</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 18 (§ 1431 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1431">section 1431 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 6 of Reorganization Plan Number 2 of 1977, referred to in subsec. (a)(17), which was set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1461">section 1461 of this title</ref>, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dG">Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIII, § 1336(6), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-790">112 Stat. 2681–790</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For the effective date of title XIII of the Foreign Affairs Agencies Consolidation Act of 1998, referred to in subsec. (a)(17), (18), meaning the effective date of title XIII of subdiv. A of div. G of <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1301">section 1301 of Pub. L. 105–277</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6531">section 6531 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id90acabc4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Chief Executive Officer” was substituted for “Board” in section catchline to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1288/2/A/i">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1288(2)(A)(i)</ref>, which substituted “Chief Executive Officer” for “Board” wherever appearing in subsec. (a).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s305">section 305 of Pub. L. 103–236</ref>, which consists of subsecs. (a), (b), (e), and (c), in that order. Subsec. (e) of <ref href="/us/pl/103/236/s305">section 305 of Pub. L. 103–236</ref> amended sections 1465b and 1465c of this title and is omitted from the text of this section. There was no subsec. (c) or (d) after amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1288/2/B">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1288(2)(B)</ref>–(D). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1299Q/c/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1299Q(c)(2)</ref>, which added a new subsec. (c), directed that it be added at the end of this section, which technically places it after subsec. (e) but is shown here as following subsec. (b) due to the omission of subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXII/s1299Q/c">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1299Q(c)</ref>, (e)(2), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4021">134 Stat. 4021</ref>, 4025, which amended this section, was itself amended by <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dO/tXIII/s1301">Pub. L. 116–260, div. O, title XIII, § 1301</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2158">134 Stat. 2158</ref>, to make it effective 90 days after <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>. However, the amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/260">Pub. L. 116–260</ref> could not be executed because it was enacted before the provision from <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref> that it amended.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id90af1bc5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s9706/1">Pub. L. 117–263, § 9706(1)</ref>, struck out “direct and” before “supervise”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(20). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s9706/4">Pub. L. 117–263, § 9706(4)</ref>, which directed amendment of par. (22), “as redesignated”, of subsec. (a) by substituting a period for “and to condition grants” and all that followed, was executed by substituting a period for “and to condition grants or cooperative agreements, if appropriate, on such grants or cooperative agreements or any similar amendments as authorized under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6207/a">section 6207(a) of this title</ref>, including authority to name and replace the board of any grantee authorized under this chapter, to meet the purposes of this chapter in accordance with subsection (c).” in par. (20), as redesignated by <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s9706/3">Pub. L. 117–263, § 9706(3)</ref>, to reflect the probable intent of Congress. See Amendment note below. Par. (20), and not par. (22), contained the words “and to condition grants”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s9706/2">Pub. L. 117–263, § 9706(2)</ref>, (3), redesignated par. (21) as (20) and struck out former par. (20) which read as follows: “Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6207/a">section 6207(a) of this title</ref>, to condition, if appropriate, any grant or cooperative agreement to RFE/RL, Inc., Radio Free Asia, the Open Technology Fund, or the Middle East Broadcasting Networks, or any organization that is established through the consolidation of such entities, on authority to determine membership of their respective boards, and the consolidation of such grantee entities into a single grantee organization under terms and conditions established by the Agency in accordance with subsection (c).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(21), (22). <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/s9706/3">Pub. L. 117–263, § 9706(3)</ref>, redesignated pars. (22) and (23) as (21) and (22), respectively. Former par. (21) redesignated (20).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1299Q/e/2/A/i">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1299Q(e)(2)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “Agency” for “Board”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(13). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1299Q/e/2/A/ii">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1299Q(e)(2)(A)(ii)</ref>, substituted “Agency” for “Board”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(20). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1299Q/c/1/A">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1299Q(c)(1)(A)</ref>, (e)(2)(A)(iii), substituted “Agency” for “Board” and inserted “in accordance with subsection (c)” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1299P/c/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1299P(c)(2)</ref>, inserted “the Open Technology Fund,” before “or the Middle East Broadcasting Networks”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(21). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1299Q/c/1/B">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1299Q(c)(1)(B)</ref>, struck out “including with Federal officials,” before “to meet the purposes” and inserted “in accordance with subsection (c)” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(22). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1299Q/e/2/A/iv">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1299Q(e)(2)(A)(iv)</ref>, substituted “Agency” for “Board”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(23). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1299Q/c/1/C">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1299Q(c)(1)(C)</ref>, added par. (23).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1299Q/e/2/B">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1299Q(e)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “Agency” for “Board” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1299Q/c/2">Pub. L. 116–283, § 1299Q(c)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (c). See Codification note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1288/2/A/i">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1288(2)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “Chief Executive Officer” for “Board” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1288/2/A/ii">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1288(2)(A)(ii)</ref>, inserted “direct and” before “supervise”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1288/2/A/iii">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1288(2)(A)(iii)</ref>, inserted “and cooperative agreements” after “grants” and substituted “in furtherance of the purposes of this chapter and on behalf of other agencies, accordingly” for “in accordance with sections 6207 and 6208 of this title”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1288/2/A/iv">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1288(2)(A)(iv)</ref>, substituted “Board” for “International Broadcasting Bureau” and struck out “subject to the limitations in sections 6207 and 6208 of this title and” before “subject to reprogramming”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1288/2/A/i">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1288(2)(A)(i)</ref>, (v), substituted “Chief Executive Officer” for “Board”, inserted “, rent, or lease” after “procure”, and substituted “property for journalism, media, production, and broadcasting, and related support services, notwithstanding any other provision of law relating to such acquisition, rental, or lease, and under the same terms and conditions as authorized under section 501(b) of the United States Information and Educational Exchange Act of 1948 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1461/b">22 U.S.C. 1461(b)</ref>), and for multiyear contracts and leases for periods of up to 20 years subject to the requirements of subsections (b) through (f) of <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s3903">section 3903 of title 41</ref>” for “personal property”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(11). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1288/2/A/i">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1288(2)(A)(i)</ref>, (vi), struck out “staff” before “personnel” and substituted “for the Chief Executive Officer” for “for the Board”, “as the Chief Executive Officer” for “as the Board”, and “which shall not be subject” for “subject”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(12). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1288/2/A/i">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1288(2)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “Chief Executive Officer” for “Board”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(13). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1288/2/A/vii">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1288(2)(A)(vii)</ref>, substituted “Board” for “Bureau” and “Chief Executive Officer has taken” for “Board has taken”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(14). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1288/2/A/i">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1288(2)(A)(i)</ref>, (viii), substituted “Chief Executive Officer” for “Board” and inserted “transmission or” before “relay” and “or any other grantee authorized under this chapter” after “Radio Free Asia”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(15)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1288/2/A/ix">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1288(2)(A)(ix)</ref>, struck out “temporary and intermittent” after “To procure” and “to the same extent as is authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3109">section 3109 of title 5</ref>,” after “personal services”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(16). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1288/2/A/i">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1288(2)(A)(i)</ref>, (x), substituted “for the Chief Executive Officer” for “for the Board” and “Chief Executive Officer determines” for “Board determines”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(17). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1288/2/A/i">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1288(2)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “Chief Executive Officer” for “Board”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(18). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1288/2/A/i">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1288(2)(A)(i)</ref>, (xi), substituted “Agency, the Chief Executive Officer” for “Agency, the Bureau” and “or the Chief Executive Officer” for “or the Board”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(19). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1288/2/A/i">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1288(2)(A)(i)</ref>, substituted “Chief Executive Officer” for “Board” in subpars. (A) and (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(20) to (22). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1288/2/A/xii">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1288(2)(A)(xii)</ref>, added pars. (20) to (22).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b) to (d). <ref href="/us/pl/114/328/s1288/2/B">Pub. L. 114–328, § 1288(2)(B)</ref>–(D), redesignated subsec. (d) as (b), substituted “and the Chief Executive Officer” for “and the Board” and “Board” for “International Broadcasting Bureau”, and struck out former subsecs. (b) and (c) which related to delegation of authority and broadcasting budgets, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (a)(19). <ref href="/us/pl/109/140">Pub. L. 109–140</ref> added par. (19).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/107/228">Pub. L. 107–228</ref> substituted “annually,” for “annually,,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1323/e/1">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1323(e)(1)</ref>, struck out “direct and” after “To” and substituted “, the Television Broadcasting to Cuba Act, and Worldnet Television, except as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6205/b">section 6205(b) of this title</ref>” for “and the Television Broadcasting to Cuba Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1323/e/2">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1323(e)(2)</ref>, inserted “, after consultation with the Secretary of State,” after “annually,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1323/e/3">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1323(e)(3)</ref>, struck out “, through the Director of the United States Information Agency,” after “the Congress” and inserted at end “Each annual report shall place special emphasis on the assessment described in paragraph (2).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(12). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1323/e/4">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1323(e)(4)</ref>, substituted “1998 and 1999” for “1994 and 1995” and “to the Board and the International Broadcasting Bureau for such purposes for fiscal year 1997” for “to the Board for International Broadcasting for such purposes for fiscal year 1993”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(15) to (18). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1323/e/5">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1323(e)(5)</ref>, added pars. (15) to (18).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1323/f">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1323(f)</ref>, added subsec. (b). Former subsec. (b) redesignated (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1323/g">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1323(g)</ref>, (h), struck out “(1)” before “The Director”, struck out “the Director of the United States Information Agency for the consideration of the Director as a part of the Agency’s budget submission to” before “the Office of Management and Budget”, and struck out par. (2) which read as follows: “The Director of the United States Information Agency shall include in the Agency’s submission to the Office of Management and Budget the comments and recommendations of the Board concerning the proposed broadcasting budget.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1323/f/1">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1323(f)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (b) as (c). Former subsec. (c) redesignated (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1323/i">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1323(i)</ref>, amended heading and text of subsec. (d) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Director of the United States Information Agency and the Board, in carrying out their functions, shall respect the professional independence and integrity of the International Broadcasting Bureau, its broadcasting services, and grantees.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1323/f/1">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1323(f)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (c) as (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1323/f/1">Pub. L. 105–277, § 1323(f)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (d) as (e). See Codification note above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a)(14). <ref href="/us/pl/103/415">Pub. L. 103–415</ref> substituted “relay of Radio” for “relay to Radio”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id90af1bc6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id90af1bc7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2021 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1299P/c/2">section 1299P(c)(2) of Pub. L. 116–283</ref> effective and applicable beginning on <date date="2021-07-01">July 1, 2021</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/s1299P/e">section 1299P(e) of Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6203">section 6203 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="id90af1bc8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref> effective <date date="1999-10-01">Oct. 1, 1999</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1301">section 1301 of Pub. L. 105–277</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6531">section 6531 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90af1bc9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Expansion of Farsi Language Programming</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/84/dA/tXII/s1262">Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XII, § 1262</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2553">123 Stat. 2553</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/84/dA/tXII/s1262">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">International Broadcasting Operations Fund</inline>.—</heading><content>In addition to amounts otherwise authorized for the Broadcasting Board of Governors’ [now United States Agency for Global Media] International Broadcasting Operations Fund, there is authorized to be appropriated $15,000,000 to expand Farsi language programming and to provide for the dissemination of accurate and independent information to the Iranian people through radio, television, Internet, cellular telephone, short message service, and other communications.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Broadcasting Capital Improvements Fund</inline>.—</heading><content>In addition to amounts otherwise authorized for the Broadcasting Board of Governors’ Broadcasting Capital Improvements Fund, there is authorized to be appropriated $15,000,000 to expand transmissions of Farsi language programs to Iran.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Amounts</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In pursuit of the objectives described in subsections (a) and (b), amounts in the International Broadcasting Operations Fund and the Capital Improvements Fund may be used to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> develop additional transmission capability for Radio Farda and the Persian News Network to counter ongoing efforts to jam transmissions, including through additional shortwave and medium wave transmissions, satellite, and Internet mechanisms;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> develop additional proxy server capability and anti-censorship software to counter efforts to block Radio Farda and Persian News Network Web sites;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> develop technologies to counter efforts to block SMS text message exchange over cellular phone networks;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> expand program coverage and analysis by Radio Farda and the Persian News Network, including the development of broadcast platforms and programs, on the television, radio and Internet, for enhanced interactivity with and among the people of Iran;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> hire, on a permanent or short-term basis, additional staff for Radio Farda and the Persian News Network; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> develop additional Internet-based, Farsi-language television programming, including a Farsi-language, Internet-based news channel.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90af1bca-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Iranian Electronic Education, Exchange, and Media Fund</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/84/dA/tXII/s1263">Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XII, § 1263</ref>, <date date="2009-10-28">Oct. 28, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2553">123 Stat. 2553</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/84/dA/tXII/s1263">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><content>There is established in the Treasury of the United States the Iranian Electronic Education, Exchange, and Media Fund (referred to in this section as the ‘Fund’), consisting of amounts appropriated to the Fund pursuant to subsection (f).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Administration</inline>.—</heading><content>The Fund shall be administered by the Secretary of State.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Objective</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The objective of the Fund shall be to support the development of technologies, including Internet Web sites, that will aid the ability of the Iranian people to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> gain access to and share information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> exercise freedom of speech, freedom of expression, and freedom of assembly through the Internet and other electronic media;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> engage in Internet-based education programs and other exchanges between Americans and Iranians; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><chapeau> counter efforts—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> to block, censor, and monitor the Internet; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> to disrupt or monitor cellular phone networks or SMS text exchanges.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Amounts</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In pursuit of the objective described in subsection (c), amounts in the Fund may be used for grants to United States or foreign universities, nonprofit organizations, or companies for targeted projects that advance the purpose of the Fund, including projects that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> develop Farsi-language versions of existing social-networking Web sites;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> develop technologies, including Internet-based applications, to counter efforts—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> to block, censor, and monitor the Internet; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> to disrupt or monitor cellular phone networks or SMS text message exchanges;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> develop Internet-based, distance learning programs for Iranian students at United States universities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> promote Internet-based, people-to-people educational, professional, religious, or cultural exchanges and dialogues between United States citizens and Iranians.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transfers</inline>.—</heading><content>Amounts in the Fund may be transferred to the United States Agency for International Development, the Broadcasting Board of Governors [now United States Agency for Global Media], or any other agency of the Federal Government to the extent that such amounts are used to carry out activities that will further the objective described in subsection (c).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>There is authorized to be appropriated $20,000,000 to the Fund.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90af1bcb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Buying Power Maintenance Account</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/252/tI/s1408/c">Pub. L. 110–252, title I, § 1408(c)</ref>, <date date="2008-06-30">June 30, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/2342">122 Stat. 2342</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/252/tI/s1408/c">“The Broadcasting Board of Governors [now United States Agency for Global Media] may transfer funds into its Buying Power Maintenance Account, notwithstanding the requirement that such funds be provided in advance in appropriations Acts. The authority in this subsection may be exercised only with respect to funds appropriated or otherwise made available after fiscal year 2008.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90af1bcc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pilot Project for Transcription of Certain Programming Into English</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/53/tXX/s2032">Pub. L. 110–53, title XX, § 2032</ref>, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/516">121 Stat. 516</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/53/tXX/s2032">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transcription of Persian and Arabic Language Broadcasts</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>], the Broadcasting Board of Governors [now United States Agency for Global Media] shall initiate a pilot project to transcribe into the English language news and information programming broadcast by Radio Farda, Radio Sawa, the Persian Service of the Voice of America, and Alhurra.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Random Sampling; Public Availability</inline>.—</heading><content>The transcription required under subsection (a) shall consist of a random sampling of such programming. The transcripts shall be available to Congress and the public on the Internet site of the Board.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2008-05-01">May 1, 2008</date>, the Chairman of the Broadcasting Board of Governors shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report on the feasibility and utility of continuing the pilot project required under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>There is authorized to be appropriated to the ‘International Broadcasting Operations’ account of the Broadcasting Board of Governors $2,000,000 for fiscal year 2008 to carry out the pilot project required under subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
