<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90b8b8e8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432b"><num value="6432b">§ 6432b.</num><heading> Commission personnel matters</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8e9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432b/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission may, without regard to the civil service laws and regulations, appoint and terminate an Executive Director and such other additional personnel as may be necessary to enable the Commission to perform its duties. The decision to employ or terminate an Executive Director shall be made by an affirmative vote of at least six of the nine members of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8ea-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432b/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission may provide reasonable compensation to the Executive Director without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5 relating to classification of positions and General Schedule pay rates, except that the rate of pay for the Executive Director may not exceed the rate payable under level II of the Executive Schedule under section 5313 of such title. The rate of pay for other personnel of the Commission may not exceed the rate payable for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of such title. All employees of the Commission shall otherwise be treated as employees whose pay is disbursed by the Secretary of the Senate, including for purposes of applying the Standing Rules of the Senate. The Commission shall be treated as an employing office of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8eb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432b/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Professional staff</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission and the Executive Director shall hire Commission staff on the basis of professional and nonpartisan qualifications. Commissioners may not individually hire staff of the Commission. Staff shall serve the Commission as a whole and may not be assigned to the particular service of a single Commissioner or a specified group of Commissioners. This subsection does not prohibit staff personnel from assisting individual members of the Commission with particular needs related to their duties.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8ec-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432b/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Staff and services of other Federal agencies</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8ed-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432b/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Department of State</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary of State shall assist the Commission by providing on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis to the Commission such staff and administrative services as may be necessary and appropriate to perform its functions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8ee-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432b/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Other Federal agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon the request of the Commission, the head of any Federal department or agency may detail, on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis, any of the personnel of that department or agency to the Commission to assist it in carrying out its functions under this subchapter. The detail of any such personnel shall be without interruption or loss of civil service or Foreign Service status or privilege.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8ef-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432b/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Security clearances</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Executive Director shall be required to obtain a security clearance. The Executive Director may request, on a needs-only basis and in order to perform the duties of the Commission, that other personnel of the Commission be required to obtain a security clearance. The level of clearance shall be the lowest necessary to appropriately perform the duties of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8f0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432b/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Cost</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission shall reimburse all appropriate Government agencies for the cost of obtaining clearances for members of the Commission, for the Executive Director, and for any other personnel.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id90b8b8f1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/105/292/tII/s204">Pub. L. 105–292, title II, § 204</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/106/55/s1/b/3">Pub. L. 106–55, § 1(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/402">113 Stat. 402</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/112/75/s3/a">Pub. L. 112–75, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1273">125 Stat. 1273</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dJ/tVIII/s805/a">Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title VIII, § 805(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3077">133 Stat. 3077</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id90b8b8f2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id90b8b8f3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id90b8b8f4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/105/292/s204">section 204 of Pub. L. 105–292</ref> was renumbered section 206 and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6434">section 6434 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id90b8b8f5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s805/a/1">Pub. L. 116–94, § 805(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “provide reasonable compensation to the Executive Director” for “fix the compensation of the Executive Director and other personnel” and “may not exceed the rate payable under level II of the Executive Schedule under section 5313” for “and other personnel may not exceed the rate payable for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316” and inserted at end “The rate of pay for other personnel of the Commission may not exceed the rate payable for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of such title. All employees of the Commission shall otherwise be treated as employees whose pay is disbursed by the Secretary of the Senate, including for purposes of applying the Standing Rules of the Senate. The Commission shall be treated as an employing office of the Senate.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s805/a/2">Pub. L. 116–94, § 805(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “the Commission, for the Executive Director” for “the commission, for the executive director”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s805/a/3">Pub. L. 116–94, § 805(a)(3)</ref>, struck out subsec. (g) which related to application of antidiscrimination laws.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/112/75">Pub. L. 112–75</ref> added subsec. (g).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id90b8b8f6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90b8b8f7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Pending Claims</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/112/75/s3/b">Pub. L. 112–75, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/1273">125 Stat. 1273</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/112/75/s3/b">“Any administrative or judicial claim or action pending on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2011-12-23">Dec. 23, 2011</date>] may be maintained under [former] section 204(g) of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 [former <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6432b/g">22 U.S.C. 6432b(g)</ref>], as added by subsection (a).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
