<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90b8b8d5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432a"><num value="6432a">§ 6432a.</num><heading> Powers of the Commission</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8d6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Hearings and sessions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission may, for the purpose of carrying out its duties under this subchapter, hold hearings, sit and act at times and places in the United States, take testimony and receive evidence as the Commission considers advisable to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8d7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Information from Federal agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission may secure directly from any Federal department or agency such information as the Commission considers necessary to carry out the provisions of this section. Upon request of the Chairperson of the Commission, the head of such department or agency shall furnish such information to the Commission, subject to applicable law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8d8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Postal services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other departments and agencies of the Federal Government.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8d9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrative procedures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission may adopt such rules and regulations, relating to administrative procedure, as may be reasonably necessary to enable it to carry out the provisions of this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8da-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432a/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Views of the Commission</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Members of the Commission may speak in their capacity as private citizens. Statements on behalf of the Commission shall be issued in writing over the names of the Members. The Commission shall in its written statements clearly describe its statutory authority, distinguishing that authority from that of appointed or elected officials of the United States Government. Oral statements, where practicable, shall include a similar description. If a Member of the Commission is invited to speak at an event in his or her capacity as a Commissioner, the Member shall provide notice of the request to all Commissioners and the Executive Director as soon as the Commissioner becomes aware of such invitation. Speeches and responses to questions at official events shall reflect the views of the Commission. Official speeches and other prepared materials shall be made available to all Commissioners in advance of the event. If a Commissioner is speaking in his or her private capacity, he or she shall include qualifying language that the views they are representing are his or her own views and not the views of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8db-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432a/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Travel</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8dc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432a/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Members of the Commission may, with the approval of the Commission, conduct such travel as is necessary to carry out the purpose of this subchapter. Each trip must be approved by a majority of the Commission. This provision shall not apply to the Ambassador-at-Large, whose travel shall not require approval by the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8dd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432a/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition against payment of official travel by non-Federal sources</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Members of the Commission and Commission staff may not accept payment from a non-Federal source for expenses related to official travel on behalf of the Commission.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8de-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432a/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual disclosures</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than March 1 of each year, each Member of the Commission shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6433a/a">section 6433a(a) of this title</ref>) with respect to the most recently concluded 12-month period, that discloses any travel by the Member outside of the United States that was paid for or reimbursed by a person or entity other than the Member, a relative of the Member, or the Federal Government, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90b8b8df-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432a/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> who paid for or reimbursed the travel;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90b8b8e0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432a/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a good faith estimate of the cost of the travel, if the travel was funded by a person or entity that does not employ the Member; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90b8b8e1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432a/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> brief details of the travel and events related to such travel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id90b8b8e2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/105/292/tII/s203">Pub. L. 105–292, title II, § 203</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/106/55/s1/b/3">Pub. L. 106–55, § 1(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/401">113 Stat. 401</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dJ/tVIII">Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title VIII</ref>, §§ 804(b), 806(b), (c), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3077">133 Stat. 3077</ref>, 3078.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id90b8b8e3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id90b8b8e4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id90b8b8e5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/105/292">Pub. L. 105–292</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2787">112 Stat. 2787</ref>, known as the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6401">section 6401 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="id90b8b8e6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/105/292/s203">section 203 of Pub. L. 105–292</ref> was renumbered section 205 and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6433">section 6433 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id90b8b8e7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s804/b">Pub. L. 116–94, § 804(b)</ref>, inserted at end “If a Member of the Commission is invited to speak at an event in his or her capacity as a Commissioner, the Member shall provide notice of the request to all Commissioners and the Executive Director as soon as the Commissioner becomes aware of such invitation. Speeches and responses to questions at official events shall reflect the views of the Commission. Official speeches and other prepared materials shall be made available to all Commissioners in advance of the event. If a Commissioner is speaking in his or her private capacity, he or she shall include qualifying language that the views they are representing are his or her own views and not the views of the Commission.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s806/b">Pub. L. 116–94, § 806(b)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted heading, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s806/c">Pub. L. 116–94, § 806(c)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
