<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90b8b8c3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432"><num value="6432">§ 6432.</num><heading> Duties of Commission</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8c4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission shall have as its primary responsibility—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90b8b8c5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the annual and ongoing review of the facts and circumstances of violations of religious freedom presented in the Country Reports on Human Rights Practices, the Annual Report, and the Executive Summary, as well as information from other sources as appropriate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90b8b8c6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the making of policy recommendations to the President, the Secretary of State, and Congress with respect to matters involving international religious freedom.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8c7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Policy review and recommendations in response to violations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission, in evaluating United States Government policies in response to violations of religious freedom, shall consider and recommend options for policies of the United States Government with respect to each foreign country the government of which has engaged in or tolerated violations of religious freedom, including particularly severe violations of religious freedom, including diplomatic inquiries, diplomatic protest, official public protest demarche of protest, condemnation within multilateral fora, delay or cancellation of cultural or scientific exchanges, delay or cancellation of working, official, or state visits, reduction of certain assistance funds, termination of certain assistance funds, imposition of targeted trade sanctions, imposition of broad trade sanctions, and withdrawal of the chief of mission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8c8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Policy review and recommendations in response to progress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission, in evaluating the United States Government policies with respect to countries found to be taking deliberate steps and making significant improvement in respect for the right of religious freedom, shall consider and recommend policy options, including private commendation, diplomatic commendation, official public commendation, commendation within multilateral fora, an increase in cultural or scientific exchanges, or both, termination or reduction of existing Presidential actions, an increase in certain assistance funds, and invitations for working, official, or state visits.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8c9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Effects on religious communities and individuals</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Together with specific policy recommendations provided under subsections (b) and (c), the Commission shall also indicate its evaluation of the potential effects of such policies, if implemented, on the religious communities and individuals whose rights are found to be violated in the country in question.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8ca-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Monitoring</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8cb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commission shall, on an ongoing basis, monitor facts and circumstances of violations of religious freedom, in consultation with independent human rights groups and nongovernmental organizations, including churches and other religious communities, and make such recommendations as may be necessary to the appropriate officials and offices in the United States Government.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90b8b8cc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Tracking; review</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commission shall regularly—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90b8b8cd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> track the implementation by the United States Government of the recommendations it makes under paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90b8b8ce-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6432/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> review, to the extent practicable, the effectiveness of such implemented recommendations in advancing religious freedom internationally.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id90b8b8cf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/105/292/tII/s202">Pub. L. 105–292, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1998-10-27">Oct. 27, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2798">112 Stat. 2798</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/55/s1/b/1">Pub. L. 106–55, § 1(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1999-08-17">Aug. 17, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/401">113 Stat. 401</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dJ/tVIII/s804/a">Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title VIII, § 804(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3077">133 Stat. 3077</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id90b8b8d0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id90b8b8d1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id90b8b8d2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/116/94">Pub. L. 116–94</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted heading, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/106/55">Pub. L. 106–55</ref> struck out heading and text of subsec. (f). Text read as follows: “The Commission may, for the purpose of carrying out its duties under this subchapter, hold hearings, sit and act at times and places in the United States, take testimony, and receive evidence as the Commission considers advisable to carry out the purposes of this chapter.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id90b8b8d3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90b8b8d4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Sense of Congress</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/71/s2">Pub. L. 114–71, § 2</ref>, <date date="2015-10-16">Oct. 16, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/563">129 Stat. 563</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/71/s2">
<inline>“It is the sense of the Congress that the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> was created by Congress to independently assess and to accurately and unflinchingly describe threats to religious freedom around the world; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> in carrying out its prescribed duties, should use its authorized powers to ensure that efforts by the United States to advance religious freedom abroad are timely, appropriate to the circumstances, prudent, and effective.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
