<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90bd752e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6552"><num value="6552">§ 6552.</num><heading> Application of certain laws</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90bd752f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6552/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Application to functions of Department of State</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1461">Section 1461 of this title</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1461–1">section 1461–1 of this title</ref>, and <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1461–1a">section 1461–1a of this title</ref> shall not apply to public affairs and other information dissemination functions of the Secretary of State as carried out prior to any transfer of functions pursuant to this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90bd7530-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6552/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Application to functions transferred to Department of State</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1461">Section 1461 of this title</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1461–1">section 1461–1 of this title</ref>, and <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1461–1a">section 1461–1a of this title</ref> shall apply only to public diplomacy programs of the Director of the United States Information Agency as carried out prior to any transfer of functions pursuant to this chapter to the same extent that such programs were covered by these provisions prior to such transfer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90bd7531-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6552/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on use of funds</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id90bd7532-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6552/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1461">section 1461 of this title</ref> and <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s1461–1a">section 1461–1a of this title</ref>, funds specifically authorized to be appropriated for such public diplomacy programs, identified as public diplomacy funds in any Congressional Presentation Document described in subsection (e), or reprogrammed for public diplomacy purposes, shall not be used to influence public opinion in the United States, and no program material prepared using such funds shall be distributed or disseminated in the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="id90bd7533-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6552/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Construction</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in paragraph (1) may be construed (A) to interfere with the integration of administrative resources between public diplomacy and other functions of the Department of State or to prevent the occasional performance of functions other than public diplomacy by officials or employees of the Department of State who are primarily assigned to public diplomacy, provided there is no substantial resulting diminution in the amount of resources devoted to public diplomacy below the amounts described in paragraph (1), or (B) to supersede reprogramming procedures.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90bd7534-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6552/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Reporting requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The report submitted pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6601/f">section 6601(f) of this title</ref> shall include a detailed statement of the manner in which the special mission of public diplomacy carried out by USIA prior to the transfer of functions under this chapter shall be preserved within the Department of State, including the planned duties and responsibilities of any new bureaus that will perform such public diplomacy functions. Such report shall also include the best available estimates of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90bd7535-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6552/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the amounts expended by the Department of State for public affairs programs during fiscal year 1998, and on the personnel and support costs for such programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90bd7536-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6552/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the amounts expended by USIA for its public diplomacy programs during fiscal year 1998, and on the personnel and support costs for such programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90bd7537-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6552/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the amounts, including funds to be transferred from USIA and funds appropriated to the Department, that will be allocated for the programs described in paragraphs (1) and (2), respectively, during the fiscal year in which the transfer of functions from USIA to the Department occurs.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90bd7538-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6552/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Congressional Presentation Document</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Department of State’s Congressional Presentation Document for fiscal year 2000 and each fiscal year thereafter shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90bd7539-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6552/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the aggregated amounts that the Department will spend on such public diplomacy programs and on costs of personnel for such programs, and a detailed description of the goals and purposes for which such funds shall be expended; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90bd753a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6552/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the amount of funds allocated to and the positions authorized for such public diplomacy programs, including bureaus to be created upon the transfer of functions from USIA to the Department.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id90bd753b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dG">Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XIII, § 1333, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-785">112 Stat. 2681–785</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/7/dA/tIII/s304">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(7) [div. A, title III, § 304]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–434.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id90bd753c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id90bd753d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id90bd753e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a), (b), and (d), was in the original “this subdivision”, meaning subdiv. A of div. G of <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-765">112 Stat. 2681–765</ref>, known as the Foreign Affairs Agencies Consolidation Act of 1998. For complete classification of this subdivision to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6501">section 6501 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id90bd753f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted “, identified as public diplomacy funds in any Congressional Presentation Document described in subsection (e), or reprogrammed for public diplomacy purposes,” after “diplomacy programs”, and added par. (2).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
