<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90bfbedb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6613"><num value="6613">§ 6613.</num><heading> Transfer, appointment, and assignment of personnel</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90bfbedc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6613/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of personnel from ACDA and USIA</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in subchapter III—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90bfbedd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6613/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> not later than the date of abolition of ACDA, all personnel and positions of ACDA, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90bfbede-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6613/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> not later than the date of abolition of USIA, all personnel and positions of USIA,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">shall be transferred to the Department of State at the same grade or class and the same rate of basic pay or basic salary rate and with the same tenure held immediately preceding transfer.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90bfbedf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6613/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of personnel from AID</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in subchapter III, not later than the date of transfer of any function of AID to the Department of State under this chapter, all AID personnel performing such functions and all positions associated with such functions shall be transferred to the Department of State at the same grade or class and the same rate of basic pay or basic salary rate and with the same tenure held immediately preceding transfer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90bfbee0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6613/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Assignment authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, for a period of not more than 6 months commencing on the effective date of the transfer to the Department of State of personnel under subsections (a) and (b), is authorized to assign such personnel to any position or set of duties in the Department of State regardless of the position held or duties performed by such personnel prior to transfer, except that, by virtue of such assignment, such personnel shall not have their grade or class or their rate of basic pay or basic salary rate reduced, nor their tenure changed. In carrying out the reorganization under this Act, the Secretary shall ensure that the advances made in increasing the number and status of women and minorities within the foreign affairs agencies of the Federal Government, in terms of representation within the agencies as well as relative rank, are not undermined by discrimination within the newly reorganized Department of State. The Secretary shall consult with the relevant exclusive representatives (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4102">section 4102 of this title</ref> and in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s7103">section 7103 of title 5</ref>) with regard to the exercise of this authority. This subsection does not authorize the Secretary to assign any individual to any position that by law requires appointment by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90bfbee1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6613/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Superseding other provisions of law</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subsections (a) through (c) shall be exercised notwithstanding any other provision of law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id90bfbee2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dG">Pub. L. 105–277, div. G</ref>, subdiv. A, title XVI, § 1613, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-799">112 Stat. 2681–799</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/7/dA/tIII/s341">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(7) [div. A, title III, § 341]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–444.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id90bfbee3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id90bfbee4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id90bfbee5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subchapter III, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), was in the original “title XIII”, meaning title XIII of subdiv. A of div. G of <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-776">112 Stat. 2681–776</ref>. For complete classification of title XIII of div. G of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (b), was in the original “this subdivision”, meaning subdiv. A of div. G of <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-765">112 Stat. 2681–765</ref>, known as the Foreign Affairs Agencies Consolidation Act of 1998. For complete classification of this subdivision to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6501">section 6501 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (c), probably means division G of <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-761">112 Stat. 2681–761</ref>, known as the Foreign Affairs Reform and Restructuring Act of 1998. For complete classification of division G to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6501">section 6501 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4102">Section 4102 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (c), was in the original “section 1002 of the Foreign Service Act”, and was translated as meaning section 1002 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id90bfbee6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref> inserted after first sentence “In carrying out the reorganization under this Act, the Secretary shall ensure that the advances made in increasing the number and status of women and minorities within the foreign affairs agencies of the Federal Government, in terms of representation within the agencies as well as relative rank, are not undermined by discrimination within the newly reorganized Department of State.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
