<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90c4a097-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6761"><num value="6761">§ 6761.</num><heading> Penalties</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90c4a098-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6761/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90c4a099-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6761/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Penalty amounts</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90c4a09a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6761/a/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibited acts relating to inspections</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any person that is determined, in accordance with paragraph (2), to have violated <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6726">section 6726 of this title</ref> shall be required by order to pay a civil penalty in an amount not to exceed $25,000 for each such violation. For purposes of this paragraph, each day such a violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6726">section 6726 of this title</ref> continues shall constitute a separate violation of that section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90c4a09b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6761/a/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Recordkeeping violations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any person that is determined, in accordance with paragraph (2), to have violated <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6745">section 6745 of this title</ref> shall be required by order to pay a civil penalty in an amount not to exceed $5,000 for each such violation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90c4a09c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6761/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Hearing</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90c4a09d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6761/a/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Before imposing an order described in paragraph (1) against a person under this subsection for a violation of section 6726 or 6745 of this title, the Secretary of State shall provide the person or entity with notice and, upon request made within 15 days of the date of the notice, a hearing respecting the violation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90c4a09e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6761/a/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Conduct of hearing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any hearing so requested shall be conducted before an administrative law judge. The hearing shall be conducted in accordance with the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s554">section 554 of title 5</ref>. If no hearing is so requested, the Secretary of State’s imposition of the order shall constitute a final and unappealable order.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90c4a09f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6761/a/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Issuance of orders</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the administrative law judge determines, upon the preponderance of the evidence received, that a person or entity named in the complaint has violated section 6726 or 6745 of this title, the administrative law judge shall state his findings of fact and issue and cause to be served on such person or entity an order described in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90c4a0a0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6761/a/2/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Factors for determination of penalty amounts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In determining the amount of any civil penalty, the administrative law judge shall take into account the nature, circumstances, extent, and gravity of the violation or violations and, with respect to the violator, the ability to pay, effect on ability to continue to do business, any history of prior such violations, the degree of culpability, the existence of an internal compliance program, and such other matters as justice may require.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90c4a0a1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6761/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrative appellate review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The decision and order of an administrative law judge shall become the final agency decision and order of the head of the United States National Authority unless, within 30 days, the head of the United States National Authority modifies or vacates the decision and order, with or without conditions, in which case the decision and order of the head of the United States National Authority shall become a final order under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90c4a0a2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6761/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Offsets</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The amount of the civil penalty under a final order of the United States National Authority may be deducted from any sums owed by the United States to the person.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90c4a0a3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6761/a/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Judicial review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A person adversely affected by a final order respecting an assessment may, within 30 days after the date the final order is issued, file a petition in the Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit or for any other circuit in which the person resides or transacts business.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90c4a0a4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6761/a/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement of orders</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If a person fails to comply with a final order issued under this subsection against the person or entity—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90c4a0a5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6761/a/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> after the order making the assessment has become a final order and if such person does not file a petition for judicial review of the order in accordance with paragraph (5), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90c4a0a6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6761/a/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> after a court in an action brought under paragraph (5) has entered a final judgment in favor of the United States National Authority,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">the Secretary of State shall file a suit to seek compliance with the order in any appropriate district court of the United States, plus interest at currently prevailing rates calculated from the date of expiration of the 30-day period referred to in paragraph (5) or the date of such final judgment, as the case may be. In any such suit, the validity and appropriateness of the final order shall not be subject to review.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90c4a0a7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6761/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Criminal</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person who knowingly violates any provision of section 6726 or 6745 of this title, shall, in addition to or in lieu of any civil penalty which may be imposed under subsection (a) for such violation, be fined under title 18, imprisoned for not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id90c4a0a8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dI/tV/s501">Pub. L. 105–277, div. I, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-883">112 Stat. 2681–883</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id90c4a0a9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id90c4a0aa-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id90c4a0ab-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For authority of Secretary of Commerce to carry out certain functions with respect to proceedings under subsec. (a), and to issue regulations with respect thereto, see section 4 of Ex. Ord. No. 13128, <date date="1999-06-25">June 25, 1999</date>, 64 F.R. 34703, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6711">section 6711 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
