<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90cbcbed-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6941"><num value="6941">§ 6941.</num><heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress finds as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90cbcbee-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6941/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The opening of world markets through the elimination of tariff and nontariff barriers has contributed to a 56-percent increase in exports of United States goods and services since 1992.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90cbcbef-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6941/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Such export expansion, along with an increase in trade generally, has helped fuel the longest economic expansion in United States history.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90cbcbf0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6941/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The United States Government must continue to be vigilant in monitoring and enforcing the compliance by our trading partners with trade agreements in order for United States businesses, workers, and farmers to continue to benefit from the opportunities created by market-opening trade agreements.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90cbcbf1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6941/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The People’s Republic of China, as part of its accession to the World Trade Organization, has committed to eliminating significant trade barriers in the agricultural, services, and manufacturing sectors that, if realized, would provide considerable opportunities for United States farmers, businesses, and workers.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90cbcbf2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6941/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> For these opportunities to be fully realized, the United States Government must effectively monitor and enforce its rights under the agreements on the accession of the People’s Republic of China to the WTO.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id90cbcbf3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/106/286/dB/tIV/s411">Pub. L. 106–286, div. B, title IV, § 411</ref>, <date date="2000-10-10">Oct. 10, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/901">114 Stat. 901</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
