<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90cbcbf6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6943"><num value="6943">§ 6943.</num><heading> Authorization of appropriations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90cbcbf7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6943/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Department of Commerce</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Commerce, in addition to amounts otherwise available for such purposes, such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2001, and each fiscal year thereafter, for additional staff for—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90cbcbf8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6943/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> monitoring compliance by the People’s Republic of China with its commitments under the WTO, assisting United States negotiators with ongoing negotiations in the WTO, and defending United States antidumping and countervailing duty measures with respect to products of the People’s Republic of China;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90cbcbf9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6943/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> enforcement of United States trade laws with respect to products of the People’s Republic of China; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90cbcbfa-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6943/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a Trade Law Technical Assistance Center to assist small- and medium-sized businesses, workers, and unions in evaluating potential remedies available under the trade laws of the United States with respect to trade involving the People’s Republic of China.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90cbcbfb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6943/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Overseas Compliance Program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90cbcbfc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6943/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Commerce and the Department of State, in addition to amounts otherwise available, such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2001, and each fiscal year thereafter, to provide staff for monitoring in the People’s Republic of China that country’s compliance with its international trade obligations and to support the enforcement of the trade laws of the United States, as part of an Overseas Compliance Program which monitors abroad compliance with international trade obligations and supports the enforcement of United States trade laws.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90cbcbfd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6943/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Reporting</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The annual report on compliance by the People’s Republic of China submitted to the Congress under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6951">section 6951 of this title</ref> shall include the findings of the Overseas Compliance Program with respect to the People’s Republic of China.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90cbcbfe-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6943/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> United States Trade Representative</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Office of the United States Trade Representative, in addition to amounts otherwise available for such purposes, such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2001, and each fiscal year thereafter, for additional staff in—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90cbcbff-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6943/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Office of the General Counsel, the Monitoring and Enforcement Unit, and the Office of the Deputy United States Trade Representative in Geneva, Switzerland, to investigate, prosecute, and defend cases before the WTO, and to administer United States trade laws, including title III of the Trade Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2411">19 U.S.C. 2411</ref> et seq.) and other trade laws relating to intellectual property, government procurement, and telecommunications, with respect to the People’s Republic of China;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90cbcc00-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6943/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the Office of Economic Affairs, to analyze the impact on the economy of the United States, including United States exports, of acts of the Government of the People’s Republic of China affecting access to markets in the People’s Republic of China and to support the Office of the General Counsel in presenting cases to the WTO involving the People’s Republic of China;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90cbcc01-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6943/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the geographic office for the People’s Republic of China; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90cbcc02-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6943/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> offices relating to the WTO and to different sectors of the economy, including agriculture, industry, services, and intellectual property rights protection, to monitor and enforce the trade agreement obligations of the People’s Republic of China in those sectors.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90cbcc03-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6943/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Department of Agriculture</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Agriculture, in addition to amounts otherwise available for such purposes, such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2001, and each fiscal year thereafter, for additional staff to increase legal and technical expertise in areas covered by trade agreements and United States trade law, including food safety and biotechnology, for purposes of monitoring compliance by the People’s Republic of China with its trade agreement obligations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id90cbcc04-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/106/286/dB/tIV/s413">Pub. L. 106–286, div. B, title IV, § 413</ref>, <date date="2000-10-10">Oct. 10, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/901">114 Stat. 901</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id90cbcc05-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id90cbcc06-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id90cbcc07-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Trade Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (c)(1), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/618">Pub. L. 93–618</ref>, <date date="1975-01-03">Jan. 3, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1978">88 Stat. 1978</ref>. Title III of the Act is classified principally to subchapter III (§ 2411 et seq.) of chapter 12 of Title 19, Customs Duties. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s2101">section 2101 of Title 19</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
