<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90cbcc1c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s6963"><num value="6963">§ 6963.</num><heading> Composition of Task Force</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of State, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, and the heads of other executive branch agencies, as appropriate, acting through their respective designees at or above the level of Deputy Assistant Secretary, or in the case of the Customs Service, at or above the level of Assistant Commissioner, shall compose the Task Force. The designee of the Secretary of the Treasury shall chair the Task Force.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="id90cbcc1d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/106/286/dB/tV/s503">Pub. L. 106–286, div. B, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="2000-10-10">Oct. 10, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/904">114 Stat. 904</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/125/tVIII/s802/d/2">Pub. L. 114–125, title VIII, § 802(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="2016-02-24">Feb. 24, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/210">130 Stat. 210</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id90cbcc1e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id90cbcc1f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id90cbcc20-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection” substituted for “Commissioner of Customs” in text on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/114/125/s802/d/2">section 802(d)(2) of Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="id90cbcc21-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the United States Customs Service of the Department of the Treasury, including functions of the Secretary of the Treasury relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 203(1), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>. For establishment of U.S. Customs and Border Protection in the Department of Homeland Security, treated as if included in <ref href="/us/pl/107/296">Pub. L. 107–296</ref> as of <date date="2002-11-25">Nov. 25, 2002</date>, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>, as amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/114/125">Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/114/125/s802/b">section 802(b) of Pub. L. 114–125</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s211">section 211 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
