<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90ce1624-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103"><num value="7103">§ 7103.</num><heading> Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90ce1625-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall establish an Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90ce1626-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall appoint the members of the Task Force, which shall include the Secretary of State, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Director of National Intelligence, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Treasury, the United States Trade Representative, and such other officials as may be designated by the President.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90ce1627-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Chairman</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Task Force shall be chaired by the Secretary of State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90ce1628-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Activities of the Task Force</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Task Force shall carry out the following activities:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90ce1629-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Coordinate the implementation of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90ce162a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Measure and evaluate progress of the United States and other countries in the areas of trafficking prevention, protection, and assistance to victims of trafficking, and prosecution and enforcement against traffickers, including the role of public corruption in facilitating trafficking. The Task Force shall have primary responsibility for assisting the Secretary of State in the preparation of the reports described in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7107">section 7107 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90ce162b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Expand interagency procedures to collect and organize data, including significant research and resource information on domestic and international trafficking and providing an annual report on the case referrals received from the national human trafficking hotline by Federal departments and agencies. Any data collection procedures and reporting requirements established under this subsection shall respect the confidentiality of victims of trafficking.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90ce162c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Engage in efforts to facilitate cooperation among countries of origin, transit, and destination. Such efforts shall aim to strengthen local and regional capacities to prevent trafficking, prosecute traffickers and assist trafficking victims, and shall include initiatives to enhance cooperative efforts between destination countries and countries of origin and assist in the appropriate reintegration of stateless victims of trafficking.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90d0872d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Examine the role of the international “sex tourism” industry in the trafficking of persons and in the sexual exploitation of women and children around the world.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90d0872e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Engage in consultation and advocacy with governmental and nongovernmental organizations, among other entities, to advance the purposes of this chapter, and make reasonable efforts to distribute information to enable all relevant Federal Government agencies to publicize the National Human Trafficking Resource Center Hotline on their websites, in all headquarters offices, and in all field offices throughout the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90d0872f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><chapeau> Not later than <date date="2004-05-01">May 1, 2004</date>, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means, the Committee on Foreign Affairs <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002362">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002362"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma.</note> the Committee on Financial Services,, <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002363">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002363"><num>2</num> So in original.</note> and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, a report on Federal agencies that are implementing any provision of this chapter, or any amendment made by this chapter, which shall include, at a minimum, information on—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d08730-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the number of persons who received benefits or other services under subsections (b) and (f) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002364">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002364"><num>3</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7105">section 7105 of this title</ref> in connection with programs or activities funded or administered by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Labor, the Attorney General, the Board of Directors of the Legal Services Corporation, and other appropriate Federal agencies during the preceding fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d08731-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the number of persons who have been granted continued presence in the United States under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7105/c/3">section 7105(c)(3) of this title</ref> during the preceding fiscal year and the mean and median time taken to adjudicate applications submitted under such section, including the time from the receipt of an application by law enforcement to the issuance of continued presence, and a description of any efforts being taken to reduce the adjudication and processing time while ensuring the safe and competent processing of the applications;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d08732-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the number of persons who have applied for, been granted, or been denied a visa or otherwise provided status under subparagraph (T)(i) or (U)(i) of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101/a/15">section 1101(a)(15) of title 8</ref> during the preceding fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d08733-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the number of persons who have applied for, been granted, or been denied a visa or status under clause (ii) of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101/a/15/T">section 1101(a)(15)(T) of title 8</ref> during the preceding fiscal year, broken down by the number of such persons described in subclauses (I), (II), and (III) of such clause (ii);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d08734-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the amount of Federal funds expended in direct benefits paid to individuals described in subparagraph (D) in conjunction with T visa status;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d08735-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> the number of persons who have applied for, been granted, or been denied a visa or status under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101/a/15/U/i">section 1101(a)(15)(U)(i) of title 8</ref> during the preceding fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d08736-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> the mean and median time in which it takes to adjudicate applications submitted under the provisions of law set forth in subparagraph (C), including the time between the receipt of an application and the issuance of a visa and work authorization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d08737-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> any efforts being taken to reduce the adjudication and processing time, while ensuring the safe and competent processing of the applications;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d08738-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the number of persons who have been charged or convicted under one or more of sections 1581, 1583, 1584, 1589, 1590, 1591, 1592, or 1594 of title 18 during the preceding fiscal year and the sentences imposed against each such person;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d08739-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><content> the amount, recipient, and purpose of each grant issued by any Federal agency to carry out the purposes of sections 7104 and 7105 of this title, or <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2152d">section 2152d of this title</ref>, during the preceding fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d0873a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/K"><num value="K">(K)</num><content> the nature of training conducted pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7105/c/4">section 7105(c)(4) of this title</ref> during the preceding fiscal year;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d0873b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/L"><num value="L">(L)</num><content> the amount, recipient, and purpose of each grant under sections 20702 and 20705 of title 34; <sup>3</sup></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d0873c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/M"><num value="M">(M)</num><chapeau> activities by the Department of Defense to combat trafficking in persons, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90d0873d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/M/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> educational efforts for, and disciplinary actions taken against, members of the United States Armed Forces;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90d0873e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/M/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the development of materials used to train the armed forces of foreign countries;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90d0873f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/M/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> all known trafficking in persons cases reported to the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90d08740-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/M/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> efforts to ensure that United States Government contractors and their employees or United States Government subcontractors and their employees do not engage in trafficking in persons; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90d08741-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/M/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> all trafficking in persons activities of contractors reported to the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d08742-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/N"><num value="N">(N)</num><chapeau> activities or actions by Federal departments and agencies to enforce—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90d08743-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/N/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7104/g">section 7104(g) of this title</ref> and any similar law, regulation, or policy relating to United States Government contractors and their employees or United States Government subcontractors and their employees that engage in severe forms of trafficking in persons, the procurement of commercial sex acts, or the use of forced labor, including debt bondage;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90d08744-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/N/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1307">section 1307 of title 19</ref> (relating to prohibition on importation of convict-made goods), including any determinations by the Secretary of Homeland Security to waive the restrictions of such section; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90d08745-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/N/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> prohibitions on the procurement by the United States Government of items or services produced by slave labor, consistent with Executive Order 13107 (<date date="1998-12-10">December 10, 1998</date>);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d08746-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/O"><num value="O">(O)</num><content> the activities undertaken by the Senior Policy Operating Group to carry out its responsibilities under subsection (g); and <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002365">4</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002365"><num>4</num> So in original. The word “and” probably should not appear.</note></content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d08747-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/P"><num value="P">(P)</num><content> the activities undertaken by Federal agencies to train appropriate State, tribal, and local government and law enforcement officials to identify victims of severe forms of trafficking, including both sex and labor trafficking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d08748-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/Q"><num value="Q">(Q)</num><chapeau> the activities undertaken by Federal agencies in cooperation with State, tribal, and local law enforcement officials to identify, investigate, and prosecute offenses under sections 1581, 1583, 1584, 1589, 1590, 1591, 1592, 1594, 2251, 2251A, 2421, 2422, and 2423 of title 18, or equivalent State offenses, including, in each fiscal year—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90d08749-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/Q/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the number, age, gender, country of origin, and citizenship status of victims identified for each offense;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90d0874a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/Q/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the number of individuals charged, and the number of individuals convicted, under each offense;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90d0874b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/Q/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the number of individuals referred for prosecution for State offenses, including offenses relating to the purchasing of commercial sex acts;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90d0874c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/Q/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the number of victims granted continued presence in the United States under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7105/c/3">section 7105(c)(3) of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90d0874d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/Q/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> the number of victims granted a visa or otherwise provided status under subparagraph (T)(i) or (U)(i) of <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101/a/15">section 1101(a)(15) of title 8</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90d0874e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/Q/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> the number of individuals required by a court order to pay restitution in connection with a violation of each offense under title 18, the amount of restitution required to be paid under each such order, and the amount of restitution actually paid pursuant to each such order;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90d0874f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/Q/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> the age, gender, race, country of origin, country of citizenship, and description of the role in the offense of individuals convicted under each offense; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90d08750-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/Q/viii"><num value="viii">(viii)</num><content> the number of convictions obtained under chapter 77 of title 18, aggregated separately by the form of offense committed with respect to the victim, including recruiting, enticing, harboring, transporting, providing, obtaining, advertising, maintaining, patronizing, or soliciting a human trafficking victim;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d08751-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/R"><num value="R">(R)</num><content> the activities undertaken by the Department of Justice and the Department of Health and Human Services to meet the specific needs of minor victims of domestic trafficking, including actions taken pursuant to subsection (f) and section 20702(a) <sup>3</sup> of title 34, and the steps taken to increase cooperation among Federal agencies to ensure the effective and efficient use of programs for which the victims are eligible;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d08752-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/S"><num value="S">(S)</num><content> tactics and strategies employed by human trafficking task forces sponsored by the Department of Justice to reduce demand for trafficking victims;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d08753-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/T"><num value="T">(T)</num><content> the efforts of the United States to eliminate money laundering related to human trafficking and the number of investigations, arrests, indictments, and convictions in money laundering cases with a nexus to human trafficking;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d08754-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/U"><num value="U">(U)</num><content> with respect to applications described in subparagraph (B), (C), (D), or (F), when available, if the application was denied, the reason for the denial and the length of time it took for the denial to be issued; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d08755-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><chapeau> disaggregated data regarding—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90d08756-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/V/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the number of victims trafficked by third parties and by family members;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90d08757-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/V/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> victims trafficked by victim age; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90d08758-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/d/7/V/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> victims trafficked by the type of trafficking.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90d08759-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Office To Monitor and Combat Trafficking</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90d0875a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary of State shall establish within the Department of State an Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking, which shall provide assistance to the Task Force. Any such Office shall be headed by a Director, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, with the rank of Ambassador-at-Large. The Director shall have the primary responsibility for assisting the Secretary of State in carrying out the purposes of this chapter and may have additional responsibilities as determined by the Secretary. The Director shall consult with nongovernmental organizations and multilateral organizations, and with trafficking victims or other affected persons. The Director shall have the authority to take evidence in public hearings or by other means. The agencies represented on the Task Force are authorized to provide staff to the Office on a nonreimbursable basis.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90d0875b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> United States assistance</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director shall be responsible for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d0875c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> all policy, funding, and programming decisions regarding funds made available for trafficking in persons programs that are centrally controlled by the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90d0875d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> coordinating any trafficking in persons programs of the Department of State or the United States Agency for International Development that are not centrally controlled by the Director.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90d0875e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Regional strategies for combating trafficking in persons</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each regional bureau in the Department of State shall contribute to the realization of the anti-trafficking goals and objectives of the Secretary of State. Each year, in cooperation with the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons, each regional bureau shall submit a list of anti-trafficking goals and objectives to the Secretary of State for each country in the geographic area of responsibilities of the regional bureau. Host governments shall be informed of the goals and objectives for their particular country and, to the extent possible, host government officials should be consulted regarding the goals and objectives.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90d0875f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Senior Policy Operating Group</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90d08760-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There shall be established within the executive branch a Senior Policy Operating Group.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90d08761-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Membership; related matters</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90d08762-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/g/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Operating Group shall consist of the senior officials designated as representatives of the appointed members of the Task Force (pursuant to Executive Order No. 13257 of <date date="2002-02-13">February 13, 2002</date>).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90d08763-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/g/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Chairperson</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Operating Group shall be chaired by the Director of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking of the Department of State.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90d08764-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/g/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Operating Group shall meet on a regular basis at the call of the Chairperson.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90d08765-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/g/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Operating Group shall coordinate activities of Federal departments and agencies regarding policies (including grants and grant policies) involving the international trafficking in persons and the implementation of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90d08766-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/g/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability of information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each Federal department or agency represented on the Operating Group shall fully share all information with such Group regarding the department or agency’s plans, before and after final agency decisions are made, on all matters relating to grants, grant policies, and other significant actions regarding the international trafficking in persons and the implementation of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90d08767-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7103/g/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2003-12-19">December 19, 2003</date>, the President shall promulgate regulations to implement this section, including regulations to carry out paragraph (4).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id90d08768-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/106/386/dA/s105">Pub. L. 106–386, div. A, § 105</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1473">114 Stat. 1473</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/193/s6/a/1">Pub. L. 108–193, § 6(a)(1)</ref>, (b)(1), (c)(1), <date date="2003-12-19">Dec. 19, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2880">117 Stat. 2880</ref>, 2881; <ref href="/us/pl/109/164/tI/s104/a">Pub. L. 109–164, title I, § 104(a)</ref>, title II, § 205, <date date="2006-01-10">Jan. 10, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/3564">119 Stat. 3564</ref>, 3571; <ref href="/us/pl/110/457/tI">Pub. L. 110–457, title I</ref>, §§ 101, 102, title II, § 231, title III, § 304(a), <date date="2008-12-23">Dec. 23, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/5045">122 Stat. 5045</ref>, 5072, 5087; <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dA/tXVII/s1707">Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XVII, § 1707</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2098">126 Stat. 2098</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/4/tXII">Pub. L. 113–4, title XII</ref>, §§ 1201, 1203(a), 1231, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/136">127 Stat. 136</ref>, 138, 144; <ref href="/us/pl/114/22/tVI/s602">Pub. L. 114–22, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="2015-05-29">May 29, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/259">129 Stat. 259</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/392">Pub. L. 115–392</ref>, §§ 16, 18(a), <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5257">132 Stat. 5257</ref>, 5258; <ref href="/us/pl/115/425/tI/s121/a">Pub. L. 115–425, title I, § 121(a)</ref>, title II, § 201, <date date="2019-01-08">Jan. 8, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5478">132 Stat. 5478</ref>, 5482; <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dA/tIX/s902/85">Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title IX, § 902(85)</ref>, div. C, title XXXV, § 3562, div. F, title LXXI, § 7154(b), <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1553">133 Stat. 1553</ref>, 2009, 2260; <ref href="/us/pl/117/347/tIV/s404">Pub. L. 117–347, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="2023-01-05">Jan. 5, 2023</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/6208">136 Stat. 6208</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id90d08769-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id90d0876a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id90d0876b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (d)(1), (6), (7), (e)(1), and (g)(3), (4), was in the original “this division” meaning division A of <ref href="/us/pl/106/386">Pub. L. 106–386</ref>, <date date="2000-10-28">Oct. 28, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1466">114 Stat. 1466</ref>, known as the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of division A to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7101">section 7101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (f) of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7105">section 7105 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (d)(7)(A), probably means the first subsec. (f) of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7105">section 7105 of this title</ref>, relating to assistance for United States citizens and lawful permanent residents, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/110/457/tII/s213/a/1">Pub. L. 110–457, title II, § 213(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-12-23">Dec. 23, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/5064">122 Stat. 5064</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 20702 and 20705 of title 34, referred to in subsec. (d)(7)(L), was in the original “sections 202 and 204 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2005”, and was translated as reading “sections 202 and 204 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2005”, which enacted sections 20702 and 20705 of Title 34, Crime Control and Law Enforcement, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order 13107, referred to in subsec. (d)(7)(N)(iii), is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s601">section 601 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t34/s20702/a">Section 20702(a) of title 34</ref>, referred to in subsec. (d)(7)(R), was amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/113/4/tXII/s1241/a">Pub. L. 113–4, title XII, § 1241(a)</ref>, <date date="2013-03-07">Mar. 7, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/149">127 Stat. 149</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/115/393/tIII/s301/e/1/A">Pub. L. 115–393, title III, § 301(e)(1)(A)</ref>, <date date="2018-12-21">Dec. 21, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5272">132 Stat. 5272</ref>, and, as so amended, sets out definitions for that section. Prior to amendment, <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s20702/a">section 20702(a) of title 34</ref> related to grants made by the Secretary of Health and Human Services for assistance programs for victims of trafficking occurring within the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order No. 13257, referred to in subsec. (g)(2)(A), is set out as a note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id90d0876c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2023—Subsec. (d)(7)(Q)(vii). <ref href="/us/pl/117/347/s404/1/A">Pub. L. 117–347, § 404(1)(A)</ref>, inserted “and” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(7)(Q)(viii). <ref href="/us/pl/117/347/s404/1/B">Pub. L. 117–347, § 404(1)(B)</ref>, struck out “and” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(7)(R). <ref href="/us/pl/117/347/s404/2">Pub. L. 117–347, § 404(2)</ref>, struck out “and” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(7)(S). <ref href="/us/pl/117/347/s404/3">Pub. L. 117–347, § 404(3)</ref>, substituted semicolon for period in subpar. (S) relating to tactics and strategies employed by human trafficking task forces.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(7)(T). <ref href="/us/pl/117/347/s404/4">Pub. L. 117–347, § 404(4)</ref>, (5), redesignated subpar. (S) relating to efforts of the United States to eliminate money laundering as (T) and substituted semicolon for period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(7)(U), (V). <ref href="/us/pl/117/347/s404/6">Pub. L. 117–347, § 404(6)</ref>, added subpars. (U) and (V).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s3562">Pub. L. 116–92, § 3562</ref>, inserted “the Secretary of Commerce,” after “the Secretary of Education,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/115/425/s201">Pub. L. 115–425, § 201</ref>, inserted “the Secretary of the Treasury, the United States Trade Representative,” after “the Secretary of Education,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s7154/b/1">Pub. L. 116–92, § 7154(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “the Committee on Financial Services,” after “the Committee on Foreign Affairs” and “the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs,” after “the Committee on Foreign Relations,” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(7)(M)(v). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s902/85">Pub. L. 116–92, § 902(85)</ref>, substituted “Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment” for “Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(7)(Q)(vii), (R). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s7154/b/2">Pub. L. 116–92, § 7154(b)(2)</ref>, (3), which directed amendment of subpar. (Q)(vii) by substituting a semicolon for “; and” and subpar. (R) by substituting “; and” for the period at the end, could not be executed because of the intervening amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/115/425/s121/a/1">Pub. L. 115–425, § 121(a)(1)</ref>, (2), made in the course of adding the first subpar. (S). See below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(7)(S). <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s7154/b/4">Pub. L. 116–92, § 7154(b)(4)</ref>, added subpar. (S) relating to efforts of the United States to eliminate money laundering.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/115/425/s121/a">Pub. L. 115–425, § 121(a)</ref>, added subpar. (S) relating to tactics and strategies employed by human trafficking task forces.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/115/392/s18/a">Pub. L. 115–392, § 18(a)</ref>, inserted “and providing an annual report on the case referrals received from the national human trafficking hotline by Federal departments and agencies” after “international trafficking” and “and reporting requirements” after “Any data collection procedures”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(7)(Q)(viii). <ref href="/us/pl/115/392/s16">Pub. L. 115–392, § 16</ref>, added cl. (viii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (d)(7)(Q). <ref href="/us/pl/114/22">Pub. L. 114–22</ref> substituted “1590, 1591, 1592, 1594, 2251, 2251A, 2421, 2422, and 2423” for “1590, 1592, and 1594” in introductory provisions and added cls. (vi) and (vii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsec. (d)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/113/4/s1203/a">Pub. L. 113–4, § 1203(a)</ref>, inserted “, and make reasonable efforts to distribute information to enable all relevant Federal Government agencies to publicize the National Human Trafficking Resource Center Hotline on their websites, in all headquarters offices, and in all field offices throughout the United States” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(7)(B) to (H). <ref href="/us/pl/113/4/s1231/2">Pub. L. 113–4, § 1231(2)</ref>, added subpars. (B) to (H) and struck out former subpars. (B) and (C) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) the number of persons who have been granted continued presence in the United States under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7105/c/3">section 7105(c)(3) of this title</ref> during the preceding fiscal year;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(C) the number of persons who have applied for, been granted, or been denied a visa or otherwise provided status under <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101/a/15/T/i">section 1101(a)(15)(T)(i) of title 8</ref> during the preceding fiscal year;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Former subpars. (D) to (H) redesignated (I) to (M), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(7)(H)(iii) to (v). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239">Pub. L. 112–239</ref> added cls. (iii) and (v) redesignated former cl. (iii) as (iv).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(7)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/113/4/s1231/1">Pub. L. 113–4, § 1231(1)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (D) as (I). Former subpar. (I) redesignated (N).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(7)(J). <ref href="/us/pl/113/4/s1231/1">Pub. L. 113–4, § 1231(1)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (E) as (J). Former subpar. (J) redesignated (O).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/113/4/s1201/1">Pub. L. 113–4, § 1201(1)</ref>, substituted “subsection (g)” for “subsection (f) of this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(7)(K) to (O). <ref href="/us/pl/113/4/s1231/1">Pub. L. 113–4, § 1231(1)</ref>, redesignated subpars. (F) to (J) as (K) to (O), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(7)(P) to (R). <ref href="/us/pl/113/4/s1231/3">Pub. L. 113–4, § 1231(3)</ref>–(5), added subpars. (P) to (R).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/113/4/s1201/2">Pub. L. 113–4, § 1201(2)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (B) and cls. (i) and (ii) as par. (2) and subpars. (A) and (B), respectively, realigned margins, and struck out former par. (2) heading and subpar. (A) which related to coordination of certain activities against use of products or materials from victims of severe forms of trafficking and sexual exploitation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (f), (g). <ref href="/us/pl/113/4/s1201/3">Pub. L. 113–4, § 1201(3)</ref>, (4), added subsec. (f) and redesignated former subsec. (f) as (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/110/457/s101">Pub. L. 110–457, § 101</ref>, inserted “the Secretary of Education,” after “the Secretary of Homeland Security,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/110/457/s304/a">Pub. L. 110–457, § 304(a)</ref>, substituted “Committee on Foreign Affairs” for “Committee on International Relations” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(7)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/110/457/s231/1">Pub. L. 110–457, § 231(1)</ref>, substituted “subsections (b) and (f) of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7105">section 7105 of this title</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7105/b">section 7105(b) of this title</ref>” and inserted “the Attorney General,” after “the Secretary of Labor,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(7)(H) to (J). <ref href="/us/pl/110/457/s231/2">Pub. L. 110–457, § 231(2)</ref>–(4), added subpars. (H) and (I) and redesignated former subpar. (H) as (J).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/110/457/s102">Pub. L. 110–457, § 102</ref>, substituted “Office To Monitor and Combat Trafficking” for “Support for the Task Force” in subsec. heading, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and inserted par. heading, substituted “The Secretary of State shall” for “The Secretary of State is authorized to”, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/109/164/s104/a">Pub. L. 109–164, § 104(a)</ref>, substituted “the Director of National Intelligence, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security” for “the Director of Central Intelligence”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(7)(G), (H). <ref href="/us/pl/109/164/s205">Pub. L. 109–164, § 205</ref>, added subpar. (G) and redesignated former subpar. (G) as (H).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (d)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/108/193/s6/a/1">Pub. L. 108–193, § 6(a)(1)</ref>, added par. (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/108/193/s6/b/1">Pub. L. 108–193, § 6(b)(1)</ref>, inserted before period at end of second sentence “, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, with the rank of Ambassador-at-Large”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/108/193/s6/c/1">Pub. L. 108–193, § 6(c)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id90d0876d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="savings" id="id90d0876e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Savings Provision</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/193/s6/b/2">Pub. L. 108–193, § 6(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-19">Dec. 19, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2881">117 Stat. 2881</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/193/s6/b/2">“The individual who holds the position of Director of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking of the Department of State may continue to hold such position notwithstanding the amendment made by paragraph (1) [amending this section].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90d0876f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Senior Policy Operating Group</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/7/dB/tIV/s406">Pub. L. 108–7, div. B, title IV, § 406</ref>, <date date="2003-02-20">Feb. 20, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/92">117 Stat. 92</ref>, required the Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking to establish a Senior Policy Operating Group, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/108/193/s6/c/2">Pub. L. 108–193, § 6(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-19">Dec. 19, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2881">117 Stat. 2881</ref>. See subsec. (g) of this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id90d08770-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id90d08771-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 13257. President’s Interagency Task Force To Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 13257, <date date="2002-02-13">Feb. 13, 2002</date>, 67 F.R. 7259, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 13286, § 5, <date date="2003-02-28">Feb. 28, 2003</date>, 68 F.R. 10619; Ex. Ord. No. 13333, <date date="2004-03-18">Mar. 18, 2004</date>, 69 F.R. 13455, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000, (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7101">22 U.S.C. 7101</ref> <i>et seq</i>.) (the “Act”), and <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref>, United States Code, and in order to combat trafficking in persons, a contemporary manifestation of slavery whose victims are predominantly women and children, to ensure just and effective punishment of traffickers, and to protect their victims, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. (a) The President’s Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons is hereby established.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Task Force shall consist of:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(i) the Secretary of State;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(ii) the Attorney General;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(iii) the Secretary of Labor;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(iv) the Secretary of Health and Human Services;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(v) the Secretary of Homeland Security;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(vi) the Director of Central Intelligence;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(vii) the Director of the Office of Management and Budget;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(viii) the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(ix) any additional officers or employees of the United States as may be designated by the President.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The Task Force shall be chaired by the Secretary of State.</p>
<p><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 2. <i>Activities</i>. The Task Force shall, consistent with applicable law and the constitutional authorities and duties of the President, carry out the following activities:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) coordinate the implementation of the Act;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) measure and evaluate progress of the United States and other countries in the areas of trafficking in persons prevention, protection, and assistance to victims of trafficking in persons, and prosecutions and other enforcement efforts against traffickers, including the role of public corruption in facilitating trafficking in persons;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) assist the Secretary of State in the preparation of the annual reports described in section 110 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7107">22 U.S.C. 7107</ref>];</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) expand interagency procedures to collect and organize data, including significant research and resource information on domestic and international trafficking in persons, while ensuring that any data collection procedures involved, respect the confidentiality of victims of trafficking in persons;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) engage in efforts to facilitate cooperation among countries of origin, transit, and destination, and such efforts shall aim to strengthen local and regional capacities to prevent trafficking in persons, prosecute traffickers and assist trafficking victims; shall include initiatives to enhance cooperative efforts between destination countries, transit countries, and countries of origin; and shall assist in the appropriate reintegration of stateless victims of trafficking in persons;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(f) examine the role of the international “sex tourism” industry in the trafficking of persons and in the sexual exploitation of women and children around the world;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(g) engage in consultation and advocacy with governmental and nongovernmental organizations, among other entities, to advance the purposes of the Act; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(h) address such other matters related to the purposes of the Act as the President may determine.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 3. <i>Administration</i>. (a) The Department of State shall provide funding and administrative support for the Task Force, except as otherwise provided by the Act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) At the call of the Chair, the Task Force shall meet as necessary to accomplish its mission.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) Task Force members may designate representatives from their respective agencies to represent them at Task Force meetings.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) Whenever the work of the Task Force involves a matter committed by law or Presidential directive to the consideration of the National Security Council, or by Executive Order 13228 of <date date="2001-10-08">October 8, 2001</date> [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3021">50 U.S.C. 3021</ref> note], to the consideration of the Homeland Security Council, that work shall be undertaken, and any communication by the Secretary of State to the President shall be undertaken, in a manner consistent with such law, Presidential directive, or Executive Order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) The Task Force shall have no directive authority or other substantial independent authority.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(f) As necessary and appropriate, the Task Force shall report to the President, through the Secretary of State, the following:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(i) progress on the implementation of the Act; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">(ii) recommendations for United States policy to monitor and eliminate trafficking in persons and to protect the victims of trafficking in persons.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 4. <i>Guidelines, Policies, and Regulations</i>. (a) The Senior Policy Operating Group (SPOG), described in subsection 105(f) [now (g)] of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7103/g">22 U.S.C. 7103(g)</ref>], shall (i) establish guidelines and policies to coordinate the activities of executive branch departments and agencies regarding policies (including grants and grant policies) involving the international trafficking in persons and (ii) advise the Secretary of State what regulations may be necessary to implement section 105 of the Act, including such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the sharing of information on all matters relating to grants, grant policies, or other significant actions regarding the international trafficking in persons as set forth in subsection 105(f)(4) of the Act, to the extent permitted by law.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Secretary of State, in consultation with the members of the Task Force or their representatives, shall promulgate regulations to implement section 105 of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7103">22 U.S.C. 7103</ref>].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 5. <i>Enhanced Prevention of Trafficking in Persons</i>. (a) The Secretary of State, in consultation with the members of the Task Force or their representatives, shall carry out the functions under subsection 106(c) and subsection 106(d) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7104/c">22 U.S.C. 7104(c)</ref>, (d)].</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Secretary of State shall have the authority to determine, under section 106(e)(1) of the Act, foreign destinations where sex tourism is significant. The Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the members of the Task Force or their representatives and appropriate officials of the Departments of Commerce and Transportation, shall carry out all other functions under subsection 106(e) of the Act, including promulgation of any appropriate regulations relating to the distribution of the materials described in subsection 106(e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The head of each executive branch agency responsible for the establishment and conduct of initiatives and programs described in subsections 106(a) through (e) of the Act shall consult with appropriate nongovernmental organizations consistent with section 106(f) of the Act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The Secretary of State shall have responsibility to initiate appropriate regulatory implementation of the requirements set out in section 106(g) of the Act with respect to contracts, including proposing appropriate amendments to the Federal Acquisition Regulation. Each affected executive branch department or agency shall implement, within that department or agency, the requirements set out in section 106(g) of the Act with respect to grants and cooperative agreements.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 6. <i>Research on Trafficking in Persons</i>. The entities named in section 112A of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7109a">22 U.S.C. 7109a</ref>] shall carry out the research initiatives required by section 112A of the Act, and shall award grants according to such policies and guidelines as may be established by the SPOG described in section 105(f) of the Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7103/f">22 U.S.C. 7103(f)</ref>], as well as any applicable agency rules and regulations.</p>
<p><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 7. <i>Guidance for Exercising Authority and Performing Duties</i>. In exercising authority delegated by, or performing functions assigned in, this order, officers of the United States shall ensure that all actions taken by them are consistent with the President’s constitutional authority to:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) conduct the foreign affairs of the United States;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) withhold information the disclosure of which could impair the foreign relations, the national security, the deliberative processes of the Executive, or the performance of the Executive’s constitutional duties;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) recommend for congressional consideration such measures as the President may judge necessary or expedient; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) supervise the unitary Executive Branch.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec</inline>. 8. <i>Judicial Review</i>. This order does not create any rights or benefits, enforceable at law or equity, against the United States, its departments, its agencies, or other entities, its officers or employees, or any other person.</p>
<signature>
<name>George W. Bush.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
