<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90dede8d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7425"><num value="7425">§ 7425.</num><heading> Prohibition on direct or indirect transfer of classified national security information and law enforcement information to the International Criminal Court</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90dede8e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7425/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than the date on which the Rome Statute enters into force, the President shall ensure that appropriate procedures are in place to prevent the transfer of classified national security information and law enforcement information to the International Criminal Court for the purpose of facilitating an investigation, apprehension, or prosecution.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90dede8f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7425/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Indirect transfer</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The procedures adopted pursuant to subsection (a) shall be designed to prevent the transfer to the United Nations and to the government of any country that is party to the International Criminal Court of classified national security information and law enforcement information that specifically relates to matters known to be under investigation or prosecution by the International Criminal Court, except to the degree that satisfactory assurances are received from the United Nations or that government, as the case may be, that such information will not be made available to the International Criminal Court for the purpose of facilitating an investigation, apprehension, or prosecution.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90dede90-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7425/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of this section shall not be construed to prohibit any action permitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s7427">section 7427 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id90dede91-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/107/206/tII/s2006">Pub. L. 107–206, title II, § 2006</ref>, <date date="2002-08-02">Aug. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/904">116 Stat. 904</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
