<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90e399e4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601"><num value="7601">§ 7601.</num><heading> Findings</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399e5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> During the last 20 years, HIV/AIDS has assumed pandemic proportions, spreading from the most severely affected regions, sub-Saharan Africa and the Caribbean, to all corners of the world, and leaving an unprecedented path of death and devastation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399e6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> According to the Joint United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS (UNAIDS), more than 65,000,000 individuals worldwide have been infected with HIV since the epidemic began, more than 25,000,000 of these individuals have lost their lives to the disease, and more than 14,000,000 children have been orphaned by the disease. HIV/AIDS is the fourth-highest cause of death in the world.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399e7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399e8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> At the end of 2002, an estimated 42,000,000 individuals were infected with HIV or living with AIDS, of which more than 75 percent live in Africa or the Caribbean. Of these individuals, more than 3,200,000 were children under the age of 15 and more than 19,200,000 were women.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399e9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Women are four times more vulnerable to infection than are men and are becoming infected at increasingly high rates, in part because many societies do not provide poor women and young girls with the social, legal, and cultural protections against high risk activities that expose them to HIV/AIDS.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399ea-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Women and children who are refugees or are internally displaced persons are especially vulnerable to sexual exploitation and violence, thereby increasing the possibility of HIV infection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399eb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> As the leading cause of death in sub-Saharan Africa, AIDS has killed more than 19,400,000 individuals (more than 3 times the number of AIDS deaths in the rest of the world) and will claim the lives of one-quarter of the population, mostly adults, in the next decade.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399ec-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> An estimated 2,000,000 individuals in Latin America and the Caribbean and another 7,100,000 individuals in Asia and the Pacific region are infected with HIV or living with AIDS. Infection rates are rising alarmingly in Eastern Europe (especially in the Russian Federation), Central Asia, and China.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399ed-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> HIV/AIDS threatens personal security by affecting the health, lifespan, and productive capacity of the individual and the social cohesion and economic well-being of the family.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399ee-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> HIV/AIDS undermines the economic security of a country and individual businesses in that country by weakening the productivity and longevity of the labor force across a broad array of economic sectors and by reducing the potential for economic growth over the long term.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399ef-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> HIV/AIDS destabilizes communities by striking at the most mobile and educated members of society, many of whom are responsible for security at the local level and governance at the national and subnational levels as well as many teachers, health care personnel, and other community workers vital to community development and the effort to combat HIV/AIDS. In some countries the overwhelming challenges of the HIV/AIDS epidemic are accelerating the outward migration of critically important health care professionals.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399f0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> HIV/AIDS weakens the defenses of countries severely affected by the HIV/AIDS crisis through high infection rates among members of their military forces and voluntary peacekeeping personnel. According to UNAIDS, in sub-Saharan Africa, many military forces have infection rates as much as five times that of the civilian population.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399f1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><chapeau> HIV/AIDS poses a serious security issue for the international community by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e399f2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/10/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> increasing the potential for political instability and economic devastation, particularly in those countries and regions most severely affected by the disease;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e399f3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/10/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> decreasing the capacity to resolve conflicts through the introduction of peacekeeping forces because the environments into which these forces are introduced pose a high risk for the spread of HIV/AIDS; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e399f4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/10/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> increasing the vulnerability of local populations to HIV/AIDS in conflict zones from peacekeeping troops with HIV infection rates significantly higher than civilian populations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399f5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> The devastation wrought by the HIV/AIDS pandemic is compounded by the prevalence of tuberculosis and malaria, particularly in developing countries where the poorest and most vulnerable members of society, including women, children, and those individuals living with HIV/AIDS, become infected. According to the World Health Organization (WHO), HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria accounted for more than 5,700,000 deaths in 2001 and caused debilitating illnesses in millions more.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399f6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> Together, HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, malaria and related diseases are undermining agricultural production throughout Africa. According to the United Nations Food and Agricultural Organization, 7,000,000 agricultural workers throughout 25 African countries have died from AIDS since 1985. Countries with poorly developed agricultural systems, which already face chronic food shortages, are the hardest hit, particularly in sub-Saharan Africa, where high HIV prevalence rates are compounding the risk of starvation for an estimated 14,400,000 people.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399f7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> Tuberculosis is the cause of death for one out of every three people with AIDS worldwide and is a highly communicable disease. HIV infection is the leading threat to tuberculosis control. Because HIV infection so severely weakens the immune system, individuals with HIV and latent tuberculosis infection have a 100 times greater risk of developing active tuberculosis diseases thereby increasing the risk of spreading tuberculosis to others. Tuberculosis, in turn, accelerates the onset of AIDS in individuals infected with HIV.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399f8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> Malaria, the most deadly of all tropical parasitic diseases, has been undergoing a dramatic resurgence in recent years due to increasing resistance of the malaria parasite to inexpensive and effective drugs. At the same time, increasing resistance of mosquitoes to standard insecticides makes control of transmission difficult to achieve. The World Health Organization estimates that between 300,000,000 and 500,000,000 new cases of malaria occur each year, and annual deaths from the disease number between 2,000,000 and 3,000,000. Persons infected with HIV are particularly vulnerable to the malaria parasite. The spread of HIV infection contributes to the difficulties of controlling resurgence of the drug resistant malaria parasite.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399f9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content> HIV/AIDS is first and foremost a health problem. Successful strategies to stem the spread of the HIV/AIDS pandemic will require clinical medical interventions, the strengthening of health care delivery systems and infrastructure, and determined national leadership and increased budgetary allocations for the health sector in countries affected by the epidemic as well as measures to address the social and behavioral causes of the problem and its impact on families, communities, and societal sectors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399fa-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/16"><num value="16">(16)</num><content> Basic interventions to prevent new HIV infections and to bring care and treatment to people living with AIDS, such as voluntary counseling and testing and mother-to-child transmission programs, are achieving meaningful results and are cost-effective. The challenge is to expand these interventions from a pilot program basis to a national basis in a coherent and sustainable manner.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399fb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/17"><num value="17">(17)</num><content> Appropriate treatment of individuals with HIV/AIDS can prolong the lives of such individuals, preserve their families, prevent children from becoming orphans, and increase productivity of such individuals by allowing them to lead active lives and reduce the need for costly hospitalization for treatment of opportunistic infections caused by HIV.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399fc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/18"><num value="18">(18)</num><content> Nongovernmental organizations, including faith-based organizations, with experience in health care and HIV/AIDS counseling, have proven effective in combating the HIV/AIDS pandemic and can be a resource in assisting indigenous organizations in severely affected countries in their efforts to provide treatment and care for individuals infected with HIV/AIDS.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399fd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/19"><num value="19">(19)</num><content> Faith-based organizations are making an important contribution to HIV prevention and AIDS treatment programs around the world. Successful HIV prevention programs in Uganda, Jamaica, and elsewhere have included local churches and faith-based groups in efforts to promote behavior changes to prevent HIV, to reduce stigma associated with HIV infection, to treat those afflicted with the disease, and to care for orphans. The Catholic Church alone currently cares for one in four people being treated for AIDS worldwide. Faith-based organizations possess infrastructure, experience, and knowledge that will be needed to carry out these programs in the future and should be an integral part of United States efforts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399fe-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/20"><num value="20">(20)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e399ff-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/20/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Uganda has experienced the most significant decline in HIV rates of any country in Africa, including a decrease among pregnant women from 20.6 percent in 1991 to 7.9 percent in 2000.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a00-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/20/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Uganda made this remarkable turnaround because President Yoweri Museveni spoke out early, breaking long-standing cultural taboos, and changed widespread perceptions about the disease. His leadership stands as a model for ways political leaders in Africa and other developing countries can mobilize their nations, including civic organizations, professional associations, religious institutions, business and labor to combat HIV/AIDS.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a01-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/20/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Uganda’s successful AIDS treatment and prevention program is referred to as the ABC model: “Abstain, Be faithful, use Condoms”, in order of priority. Jamaica, Zambia, Ethiopia and Senegal have also successfully used the ABC model. Beginning in 1986, Uganda brought about a fundamental change in sexual behavior by developing a low-cost program with the message: “Stop having multiple partners. Be faithful. Teenagers, wait until you are married before you begin sex.”.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a02-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/20/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> By 1995, 95 percent of Ugandans were reporting either one or zero sexual partners in the past year, and the proportion of sexually active youth declined significantly from the late 1980s to the mid-1990s. The greatest percentage decline in HIV infections and the greatest degree of behavioral change occurred in those 15 to 19 years old. Uganda’s success shows that behavior change, through the use of the ABC model, is a very successful way to prevent the spread of HIV.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a03-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/21"><num value="21">(21)</num><chapeau> The magnitude and scope of the HIV/AIDS crisis demands a comprehensive, long-term, international response focused upon addressing the causes, reducing the spread, and ameliorating the consequences of the HIV/AIDS pandemic, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a04-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/21/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> prevention and education, care and treatment, basic and applied research, and training of health care workers, particularly at the community and provincial levels, and other community workers and leaders needed to cope with the range of consequences of the HIV/AIDS crisis;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a05-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/21/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> development of health care infrastructure and delivery systems through cooperative and coordinated public efforts and public and private partnerships;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a06-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/21/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> development and implementation of national and community-based multisector strategies that address the impact of HIV/AIDS on the individual, family, community, and nation and increase the participation of at-risk populations in programs designed to encourage behavioral and social change and reduce the stigma associated with HIV/AIDS; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a07-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/21/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> coordination of efforts between international organizations such as the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria, the Joint United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS (UNAIDS), the World Health Organization (WHO), national governments, and private sector organizations, including faith-based organizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a08-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/22"><num value="22">(22)</num><chapeau> The United States has the capacity to lead and enhance the effectiveness of the international community’s response by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a09-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/22/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> providing substantial financial resources, technical expertise, and training, particularly of health care personnel and community workers and leaders;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a0a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/22/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> promoting vaccine and microbicide research and the development of new treatment protocols in the public and commercial pharmaceutical research sectors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a0b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/22/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> making available pharmaceuticals and diagnostics for HIV/AIDS therapy;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a0c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/22/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> encouraging governments and faith-based and community-based organizations to adopt policies that treat HIV/AIDS as a multisectoral public health problem affecting not only health but other areas such as agriculture, education, the economy, the family and society, and assisting them to develop and implement programs corresponding to these needs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a0d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/22/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> promoting healthy lifestyles, including abstinence, delaying sexual debut, monogamy, marriage, faithfulness, use of condoms, and avoiding substance abuse; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a0e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/22/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> encouraging active involvement of the private sector, including businesses, pharmaceutical and biotechnology companies, the medical and scientific communities, charitable foundations, private and voluntary organizations and nongovernmental organizations, faith-based organizations, community-based organizations, and other nonprofit entities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a0f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/23"><num value="23">(23)</num><content> Prostitution and other sexual victimization are degrading to women and children and it should be the policy of the United States to eradicate such practices. The sex industry, the trafficking of individuals into such industry, and sexual violence are additional causes of and factors in the spread of the HIV/AIDS epidemic. One in nine South Africans is living with AIDS, and sexual assault is rampant, at a victimization rate of one in three women. Meanwhile in Cambodia, as many as 40 percent of prostitutes are infected with HIV and the country has the highest rate of increase of HIV infection in all of Southeast Asia. Victims of coercive sexual encounters do not get to make choices about their sexual activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a10-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/24"><num value="24">(24)</num><content> Strong coordination must exist among the various agencies of the United States to ensure effective and efficient use of financial and technical resources within the United States Government with respect to the provision of international HIV/AIDS assistance.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a11-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/25"><num value="25">(25)</num><content> In his address to Congress on <date date="2003-01-28">January 28, 2003</date>, the President announced the Administration’s intention to embark on a five-year emergency plan for AIDS relief, to confront HIV/AIDS with the goals of preventing 7,000,000 new HIV/AIDS infections, treating at least 2,000,000 people with life-extending drugs, and providing humane care for millions of people suffering from HIV/AIDS, and for children orphaned by HIV/AIDS.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a12-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/26"><num value="26">(26)</num><content> In this address to Congress, the President stated the following: “Today, on the continent of Africa, nearly 30,000,000 people have the AIDS virus—including 3,000,000 children under the age of 15. There are whole countries in Africa where more than one-third of the adult population carries the infection. More than 4,000,000 require immediate drug treatment. Yet across that continent, only 50,000 AIDS victims—only 50,000—are receiving the medicine they need.”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a13-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/27"><num value="27">(27)</num><content> Furthermore, the President focused on care and treatment of HIV/AIDS in his address to Congress, stating the following: “Because the AIDS diagnosis is considered a death sentence, many do not seek treatment. Almost all who do are turned away. A doctor in rural South Africa describes his frustration. He says, ‘We have no medicines. Many hospitals tell people, you’ve got AIDS, we can’t help you. Go home and die.’ In an age of miraculous medicines, no person should have to hear those words. AIDS can be prevented. Anti-retroviral drugs can extend life for many years * * * Ladies and gentlemen, seldom has history offered a greater opportunity to do so much for so many.”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a14-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/28"><num value="28">(28)</num><content> Finally, the President stated that “[w]e have confronted, and will continue to confront, HIV/AIDS in our own country”, proposing now that the United States should lead the world in sparing innocent people from a plague of nature, and asking Congress “to commit $15,000,000,000 over the next five years, including nearly $10,000,000,000 in new money, to turn the tide against AIDS in the most afflicted nations of Africa and the Caribbean”.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a15-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/29"><num value="29">(29)</num><content> On <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, the President signed this chapter into law, launching the largest international public health program of its kind ever created.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a16-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/30"><num value="30">(30)</num><chapeau> Between 2003 and 2008, the United States, through the President’s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief (PEPFAR) and in conjunction with other bilateral programs and the multilateral Global Fund has helped to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a17-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/30/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> provide antiretroviral therapy for over 1,900,000 people;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a18-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/30/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> ensure that over 150,000 infants, most of whom would have likely been infected with HIV during pregnancy or childbirth, were not infected; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a19-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/30/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> provide palliative care and HIV prevention assistance to millions of other people.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a1a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/31"><num value="31">(31)</num><content> While United States leadership in the battles against HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria has had an enormous impact, these diseases continue to take a terrible toll on the human race.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a1b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/32"><num value="32">(32)</num><chapeau> According to the 2007 AIDS Epidemic Update of the Joint United Nations Programme on HIV/AIDS (UNAIDS)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a1c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/32/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an estimated 2,100,000 people died of AIDS-related causes in 2007; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a1d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/32/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> an estimated 2,500,000 people were newly infected with HIV during that year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a1e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/33"><num value="33">(33)</num><content> According to the World Health Organization, malaria kills more than 1,000,000 people per year, 70 percent of whom are children under 5 years of age.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a1f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/34"><num value="34">(34)</num><content> According to the World Health Organization, ⅓ of the world’s population is infected with the tuberculosis bacterium, and tuberculosis is 1 of the greatest infectious causes of death of adults worldwide, killing 1,600,000 people per year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a20-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/35"><num value="35">(35)</num><content> Efforts to promote abstinence, fidelity, the correct and consistent use of condoms, the delay of sexual debut, and the reduction of concurrent sexual partners represent important elements of strategies to prevent the transmission of HIV/AIDS.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a21-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/36"><num value="36">(36)</num><chapeau> According to UNAIDS—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a22-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/36/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> women and girls make up nearly 60 percent of persons in sub-Saharan Africa who are HIV positive;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a23-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/36/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> women and girls are more biologically, economically, and socially vulnerable to HIV infection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a24-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/36/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> gender issues are critical components in the effort to prevent HIV/AIDS and to care for those affected by the disease.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a25-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/37"><num value="37">(37)</num><content> Children who have lost a parent to HIV/AIDS, who are otherwise directly affected by the disease, or who live in areas of high HIV prevalence may be vulnerable to the disease or its socioeconomic effects.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a26-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/38"><num value="38">(38)</num><content> Lack of health capacity, including insufficient personnel and inadequate infrastructure, in sub-Saharan Africa and other regions of the world is a critical barrier that limits the effectiveness of efforts to combat HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria, and to achieve other global health goals.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a27-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/39"><num value="39">(39)</num><chapeau> On <date date="2007-03-30">March 30, 2007</date>, the Institute of Medicine of the National Academies released a report entitled “PEPFAR Implementation: Progress and Promise”, which found that budget allocations setting percentage levels for spending on prevention, care, and treatment and for certain subsets of activities within the prevention category—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a28-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/39/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> have “adversely affected implementation of the U.S. Global AIDS Initiative”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a29-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/39/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> have inhibited comprehensive, integrated, evidence based approaches;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a2a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/39/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> “have been counterproductive”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a2b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/39/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> “may have been helpful initially in ensuring a balance of attention to activities within the 4 categories of prevention, treatment, care, and orphans and vulnerable children”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a2c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/39/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> “have also limited PEPFAR’s ability to tailor its activities in each country to the local epidemic and to coordinate with the level of activities in the countries’ national plans”; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a2d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/39/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><chapeau> should be removed by Congress and replaced with more appropriate mechanisms that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90e39a2e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/39/F/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> “ensure accountability for results from Country Teams to the U.S. Global AIDS Coordinator and to Congress”; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90e39a2f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/39/F/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> “ensure that spending is directly linked to and commensurate with necessary efforts to achieve both country and overall performance targets for prevention, treatment, care, and orphans and vulnerable children”.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a30-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/40"><num value="40">(40)</num><chapeau> The United States Government has endorsed the principles of harmonization in coordinating efforts to combat HIV/AIDS commonly referred to as the “Three Ones”, which includes—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a31-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/40/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> 1 agreed HIV/AIDS action framework that provides the basis for coordination of the work of all partners;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a32-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/40/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> 1 national HIV/AIDS coordinating authority, with a broadbased multisectoral mandate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a33-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/40/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> 1 agreed HIV/AIDS country-level monitoring and evaluating system.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90e39a34-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/41"><num value="41">(41)</num><chapeau> In the Abuja Declaration on HIV/AIDS, Tuberculosis and Other Related Infectious Diseases, of April 26–27, 2001 (referred to in this chapter as the “Abuja Declaration”), the Heads of State and Government of the Organization of African Unity (OAU)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a35-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/41/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> declared that they would “place the fight against HIV/AIDS at the forefront and as the highest priority issue in our respective national development plans”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a36-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/41/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> committed “TO TAKE PERSONAL RESPONSIBILITY AND PROVIDE LEADERSHIP for the activities of the National AIDS Commissions/Councils”;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a37-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/41/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> resolved “to lead from the front the battle against HIV/AIDS, Tuberculosis and Other Related Infectious Diseases by personally ensuring that such bodies were properly convened in mobilizing our societies as a whole and providing focus for unified national policymaking and programme implementation, ensuring coordination of all sectors at all levels with a gender perspective and respect for human rights, particularly to ensure equal rights for people living with HIV/AIDS”; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90e39a38-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s7601/41/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> pledged “to set a target of allocating at least 15% of our annual budget to the improvement of the health sector”.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id90e39a39-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/108/25/s2">Pub. L. 108–25, § 2</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/712">117 Stat. 712</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/293/s2">Pub. L. 110–293, § 2</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/2919">122 Stat. 2919</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id90e39a3a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id90e39a3b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id90e39a3c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in pars. (29) and (41), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/108/25">Pub. L. 108–25</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/711">117 Stat. 711</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out below and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id90e39a3d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Pars. (29) to (41). <ref href="/us/pl/110/293">Pub. L. 110–293</ref> added pars. (29) to (41).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id90e39a3e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="id90e39a3f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 2018 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/305/s1">Pub. L. 115–305, § 1</ref>, <date date="2018-12-11">Dec. 11, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4402">132 Stat. 4402</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/305/s1">“This Act [amending sections 7611, 7622, and 7673 of this title] may be cited as the ‘PEPFAR Extension Act of 2018’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="id90e39a40-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 2013 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/56/s1">Pub. L. 113–56, § 1</ref>, <date date="2013-12-02">Dec. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/127/648">127 Stat. 648</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/56/s1">“This Act [amending sections 2151b–2, 7611, 7622, and 7673 of this title] may be cited as the ‘PEPFAR Stewardship and Oversight Act of 2013’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitleOfAmendment" id="id90e39a41-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title of 2008 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/293/s1/a">Pub. L. 110–293, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="2008-07-30">July 30, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/2918">122 Stat. 2918</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/293/s1/a">“This Act [see Tables for classification] may be cited as the ‘Tom Lantos and Henry J. Hyde United States Global Leadership Against HIV/AIDS, Tuberculosis, and Malaria Reauthorization Act of 2008’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="id90e39a42-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/25/s1/a">Pub. L. 108–25, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-05-27">May 27, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/711">117 Stat. 711</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/25/s1/a">“This Act [enacting this chapter and sections 262p–8 and 2151b–2 to 2151b–4 of this title and amending sections 2151b, 2222, and 2651a of this title and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s242l">section 242l of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare] may be cited as the ‘United States Leadership Against HIV/AIDS, Tuberculosis, and Malaria Act of 2003’.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id90e39a43-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id90e39a44-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of functions of President under this chapter, except for functions set forth in section 7622(d)(4)(C)(i), (ii) of this title, to Secretary of State, see section 1–100(a)(16) of Ex. Ord. No. 12163, <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, 44 F.R. 56673, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2381">section 2381 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
