<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90f43b8b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002"><num value="8002">§ 8002.</num><heading> Statements of policy</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43b8c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The following shall be the policies of the United States:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43b8d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Oppose the development of a capability to produce nuclear weapons by any non-nuclear weapon state, within or outside of the NPT.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43b8e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Encourage States Party to the NPT to interpret the right to “develop research, production and use of nuclear energy for peaceful purposes”, as set forth in Article IV of the NPT, as being a right that applies only to the extent that it is consistent with the object and purpose of the NPT to prevent the spread of nuclear weapons and nuclear weapons capabilities, including by refraining from all nuclear cooperation with any State Party that the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) determines is not in full compliance with its NPT obligations, including its safeguards obligations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43b8f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Act in a manner fully consistent with the Guidelines for Nuclear Transfers and the Guidelines for Transfers of Nuclear-Related Dual-Use Equipment, Materials, Software and Related Technology developed by the NSG, and decisions related to the those <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002395">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002395"><num>1</num> So in original.</note> guidelines, and the rules and practices regarding NSG decisionmaking.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43b90-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Strengthen the NSG guidelines and decisions concerning consultation by members regarding violations of supplier and recipient understandings by instituting the practice of a timely and coordinated response by NSG members to all such violations, including termination of nuclear transfers to an involved recipient, that discourages individual NSG members from continuing cooperation with such recipient until such time as a consensus regarding a coordinated response has been achieved.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43b91-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Given the special sensitivity of equipment and technologies related to the enrichment of uranium, the reprocessing of spent nuclear fuel, and the production of heavy water, work with members of the NSG, individually and collectively, to further restrict the transfers of such equipment and technologies, including to India.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43b92-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Seek to prevent the transfer to a country of nuclear equipment, materials, or technology from other participating governments in the NSG or from any other source if nuclear transfers to that country are suspended or terminated pursuant to this chapter, the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2011">42 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et seq.), or any other United States law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43b93-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> With respect to South Asia</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The following shall be the policies of the United States with respect to South Asia:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43b94-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Achieve, at the earliest possible date, a moratorium on the production of fissile material for nuclear explosive purposes by India, Pakistan, and the People’s Republic of China.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43b95-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Achieve, at the earliest possible date, the conclusion and implementation of a treaty banning the production of fissile material for nuclear weapons to which both the United States and India become parties.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43b96-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Secure India’s—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43b97-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> full participation in the Proliferation Security Initiative;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43b98-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> formal commitment to the Statement of Interdiction Principles of such Initiative;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43b99-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> public announcement of its decision to conform its export control laws, regulations, and policies with the Australia Group and with the Guidelines, Procedures, Criteria, and Control Lists of the Wassenaar Arrangement;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43b9a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002/b/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> demonstration of satisfactory progress toward implementing the decision described in subparagraph (C); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43b9b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002/b/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> ratification of or accession to the Convention on Supplementary Compensation for Nuclear Damage, done at Vienna on <date date="1997-09-12">September 12, 1997</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43b9c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Secure India’s full and active participation in United States efforts to dissuade, isolate, and, if necessary, sanction and contain Iran for its efforts to acquire weapons of mass destruction, including a nuclear weapons capability and the capability to enrich uranium or reprocess nuclear fuel, and the means to deliver weapons of mass destruction.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43b9d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Seek to halt the increase of nuclear weapon arsenals in South Asia and to promote their reduction and eventual elimination.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43b9e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Ensure that spent fuel generated in India’s civilian nuclear power reactors is not transferred to the United States except pursuant to the Congressional review procedures required under section 131 f. of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2160/f">42 U.S.C. 2160(f)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43b9f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Pending implementation of the multilateral moratorium described in paragraph (1) or the treaty described in paragraph (2), encourage India not to increase its production of fissile material at unsafeguarded nuclear facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43ba0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> Ensure that any safeguards agreement or Additional Protocol to which India is a party with the IAEA can reliably safeguard any export or reexport to India of any nuclear materials and equipment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43ba1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> Ensure that the text and implementation of any agreement for cooperation with India arranged pursuant to section 123 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153">42 U.S.C. 2153</ref>) meet the requirements set forth in subsections a.(1) and a.(3) through a.(9) of such section [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153/a/1">42 U.S.C. 2153(a)(1)</ref>, (3)–(9)].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43ba2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8002/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> Any nuclear power reactor fuel reserve provided to the Government of India for use in safeguarded civilian nuclear facilities should be commensurate with reasonable reactor operating requirements.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id90f43ba3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/109/401/tI/s103">Pub. L. 109–401, title I, § 103</ref>, <date date="2006-12-18">Dec. 18, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2727">120 Stat. 2727</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id90f43ba4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id90f43ba5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id90f43ba6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (a)(6), was in the original “this title”, meaning title I of <ref href="/us/pl/109/401">Pub. L. 109–401</ref>, <date date="2006-12-18">Dec. 18, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2726">120 Stat. 2726</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of title I to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s8001">section 8001 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Atomic Energy Act of 1954, referred to in subsec. (a)(6), is <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-30/ch1073/s1">act Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/919">68 Stat. 919</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 23 (§ 2011 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2011">section 2011 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
