<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90f43ba7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003"><num value="8003">§ 8003.</num><heading> Waiver authority and congressional approval</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43ba8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the President makes the determination described in subsection (b), the President may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43ba9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> exempt a proposed agreement for cooperation with India arranged pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153">section 2153 of title 42</ref> from the requirement of subsection (a)(2) of such section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43baa-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> waive the application of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2157">section 2157 of title 42</ref> with respect to exports to India; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43bab-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> waive with respect to India the application of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43bac-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2158/a/1/D">section 2158(a)(1)(D) of title 42</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43bad-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2158">section 2158 of title 42</ref> regarding any actions that occurred before <date date="2005-07-18">July 18, 2005</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43bae-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination by the President</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The determination referred to in subsection (a) is a determination by the President that the following actions have occurred:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43baf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> India has provided the United States and the IAEA with a credible plan to separate civil and military nuclear facilities, materials, and programs, and has filed a declaration regarding its civil facilities and materials with the IAEA.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43bb0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> India and the IAEA have concluded all legal steps required prior to signature by the parties of an agreement requiring the application of IAEA safeguards in perpetuity in accordance with IAEA standards, principles, and practices (including IAEA Board of Governors Document GOV/1621 (1973)) to India’s civil nuclear facilities, materials, and programs as declared in the plan described in paragraph (1), including materials used in or produced through the use of India’s civil nuclear facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43bb1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> India and the IAEA are making substantial progress toward concluding an Additional Protocol consistent with IAEA principles, practices, and policies that would apply to India’s civil nuclear program.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43bb2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> India is working actively with the United States for the early conclusion of a multilateral treaty on the cessation of the production of fissile materials for use in nuclear weapons or other nuclear explosive devices.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43bb3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> India is working with and supporting United States and international efforts to prevent the spread of enrichment and reprocessing technology to any state that does not already possess full-scale, functioning enrichment or reprocessing plants.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43bb4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><chapeau> India is taking the necessary steps to secure nuclear and other sensitive materials and technology, including through—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43bb5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/b/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the enactment and effective enforcement of comprehensive export control legislation and regulations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43bb6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/b/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> harmonization of its export control laws, regulations, policies, and practices with the guidelines and practices of the Missile Technology Control Regime (MTCR) and the NSG; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43bb7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/b/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> adherence to the MTCR and the NSG in accordance with the procedures of those regimes for unilateral adherence.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f43bb8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> The NSG has decided by consensus to permit supply to India of nuclear items covered by the guidelines of the NSG.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43bb9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission to Congress</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43bba-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees the determination made pursuant to subsection (b), together with a report detailing the basis for the determination.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43bbb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Information to be included</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">To the fullest extent available to the United States, the report referred to in paragraph (1) shall include the following information:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43bbc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A summary of the plan provided by India to the United States and the IAEA to separate India’s civil and military nuclear facilities, materials, and programs, and the declaration made by India to the IAEA identifying India’s civil facilities to be placed under IAEA safeguards, including an analysis of the credibility of such plan and declaration, together with copies of the plan and declaration.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43bbd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> A summary of the agreement that has been entered into between India and the IAEA requiring the application of safeguards in accordance with IAEA practices to India’s civil nuclear facilities as declared in the plan described in subparagraph (A), together with a copy of the agreement, and a description of the progress toward its full implementation.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43bbe-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> A summary of the progress made toward conclusion and implementation of an Additional Protocol between India and the IAEA, including a description of the scope of such Additional Protocol.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43bbf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/c/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> A description of the steps that India is taking to work with the United States for the conclusion of a multilateral treaty banning the production of fissile material for nuclear weapons, including a description of the steps that the United States has taken and will take to encourage India to identify and declare a date by which India would be willing to stop production of fissile material for nuclear weapons unilaterally or pursuant to a multilateral moratorium or treaty.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43bc0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/c/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> A description of the steps India is taking to prevent the spread of nuclear-related technology, including enrichment and reprocessing technology or materials that can be used to acquire a nuclear weapons capability, as well as the support that India is providing to the United States to further United States objectives to restrict the spread of such technology.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43bc1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/c/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> A description of the steps that India is taking to secure materials and technology applicable for the development, acquisition, or manufacture of weapons of mass destruction and the means to deliver such weapons through the application of comprehensive export control legislation and regulations, and through harmonization with and adherence to MTCR, NSG, Australia Group, and Wassenaar Arrangement guidelines, compliance with United Nations Security Council Resolution 1540, and participation in the Proliferation Security Initiative.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43bc2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/c/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> A description and assessment of the specific measures that India has taken to fully and actively participate in United States and international efforts to dissuade, isolate, and, if necessary, sanction and contain Iran for its efforts to acquire weapons of mass destruction, including a nuclear weapons capability and the capability to enrich uranium or reprocess nuclear fuel and the means to deliver weapons of mass destruction.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43bc3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/c/2/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> A description of the decision of the NSG relating to nuclear cooperation with India, including whether nuclear cooperation by the United States under an agreement for cooperation arranged pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153">section 2153 of title 42</ref> is consistent with the decision, practices, and policies of the NSG.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43bc4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/c/2/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> A description of the scope of peaceful cooperation envisioned by the United States and India that will be implemented under the agreement for nuclear cooperation, including whether such cooperation will include the provision of enrichment and reprocessing technology.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43bc5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/c/2/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><content> A description of the steps taken to ensure that proposed United States civil nuclear cooperation with India will not in any way assist India’s nuclear weapons program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43bc6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Restrictions on nuclear transfers</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43bc7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Pursuant to the obligations of the United States under Article I of the NPT, nothing in this chapter constitutes authority to carry out any civil nuclear cooperation between the United States and a country that is not a nuclear-weapon State Party to the NPT that would in any way assist, encourage, or induce that country to manufacture or otherwise acquire nuclear weapons or nuclear explosive devices.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43bc8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> NSG transfer guidelines</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding the entry into force of an agreement for cooperation with India arranged pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153">section 2153 of title 42</ref> and pursuant to this chapter, no item subject to such agreement or subject to the transfer guidelines of the NSG, or to NSG decisions related thereto, may be transferred to India if such transfer would be inconsistent with the transfer guidelines of the NSG in effect on the date of the transfer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43bc9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Termination of nuclear transfers to India</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43bca-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding the entry into force of an agreement for cooperation with India arranged pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153">section 2153 of title 42</ref> and pursuant to this chapter, and except as provided under subparagraph (B), exports of nuclear and nuclear-related material, equipment, or technology to India shall be terminated if there is any materially significant transfer by an Indian person of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43bcb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> nuclear or nuclear-related material, equipment, or technology that is not consistent with NSG guidelines or decisions, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43bcc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> ballistic missiles or missile-related equipment or technology that is not consistent with MTCR guidelines,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">unless the President determines that cessation of such exports would be seriously prejudicial to the achievement of United States nonproliferation objectives or otherwise jeopardize the common defense and security.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43bcd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The President may choose not to terminate exports of nuclear and nuclear-related material, equipment, and technology to India under subparagraph (A) if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43bce-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the transfer covered under such subparagraph was made without the knowledge of the Government of India;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43bcf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> at the time of the transfer, either the Government of India did not own, control, or direct the Indian person that made the transfer or the Indian person that made the transfer is a natural person who acted without the knowledge of any entity described in subparagraph (B) or (C) of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s8008/5">section 8008(5) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43bd0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that the Government of India has taken or is taking appropriate judicial or other enforcement actions against the Indian person with respect to such transfer.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43bd1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Exports, reexports, transfers, and retransfers to India related to enrichment, reprocessing, and heavy water production</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43bd2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43bd3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/4/A/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Nuclear Regulatory Commission</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Nuclear Regulatory Commission may only issue licenses for the export or reexport to India of any equipment, components, or materials related to the enrichment of uranium, the reprocessing of spent nuclear fuel, or the production of heavy water if the requirements of subparagraph (B) are met.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43bd4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/4/A/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretary of Energy</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Secretary of Energy may only issue authorizations for the transfer or retransfer to India of any equipment, materials, or technology related to the enrichment of uranium, the reprocessing of spent nuclear fuel, or the production of heavy water (including under the terms of a subsequent arrangement under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2160">section 2160 of title 42</ref>) if the requirements of subparagraph (B) are met.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43bd5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements for approvals</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Exports, reexports, transfers, and retransfers referred to in subparagraph (A) may only be approved if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43bd6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> the end user—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43bd7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/4/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> is a multinational facility participating in an IAEA-approved program to provide alternatives to national fuel cycle capabilities; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43bd8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/4/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> is a facility participating in, and the export, reexport, transfer, or retransfer is associated with, a bilateral or multinational program to develop a proliferation-resistant fuel cycle;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43bd9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> appropriate measures are in place at any facility referred to in clause (i) to ensure that no sensitive nuclear technology, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3203/5">section 3203(5) of this title</ref>, will be diverted to any person, site, facility, location, or program not under IAEA safeguards; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43bda-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/4/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the President determines that the export, reexport, transfer, or retransfer will not assist in the manufacture or acquisition of nuclear explosive devices or the production of fissile material for military purposes.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43bdb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Nuclear export accountability program</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43bdc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The President shall ensure that all appropriate measures are taken to maintain accountability with respect to nuclear materials, equipment, and technology sold, leased, exported, or reexported to India so as to ensure—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43bdd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> full implementation of the protections required under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153/a/1">section 2153(a)(1) of title 42</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43bde-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> United States compliance with Article I of the NPT.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43bdf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Measures</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The measures taken pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall include the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43be0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/5/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Obtaining and implementing assurances and conditions pursuant to the export licensing authorities of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission and the Department of Commerce and the authorizing authorities of the Department of Energy, including, as appropriate, conditions regarding end-use monitoring.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43be1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/5/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> A detailed system of reporting and accounting for technology transfers, including any retransfers in India, authorized by the Department of Energy pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2077/b">section 2077(b) of title 42</ref>. Such system shall be capable of providing assurances that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43be2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/5/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the identified recipients of the nuclear technology are authorized to receive the nuclear technology;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43be3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/5/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the nuclear technology identified for transfer will be used only for peaceful safeguarded nuclear activities and will not be used for any military or nuclear explosive purpose; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43be4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/5/B/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the nuclear technology identified for transfer will not be retransferred without the prior consent of the United States, and facilities, equipment, or materials derived through the use of transferred technology will not be transferred without the prior consent of the United States.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43be5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/5/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> In the event the IAEA is unable to implement safeguards as required by an agreement for cooperation arranged pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153">section 2153 of title 42</ref>, appropriate assurance that arrangements will be put in place expeditiously that are consistent with the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153/a/1">section 2153(a)(1) of title 42</ref> regarding the maintenance of safeguards as set forth in the agreement regardless of whether the agreement is terminated or suspended for any reason.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43be6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/d/5/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Implementation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The measures described in subparagraph (B) shall be implemented to provide reasonable assurances that the recipient is complying with the relevant requirements, terms, and conditions of any licenses issued by the United States regarding such exports, including those relating to the use, retransfer, safe handling, secure transit, and storage of such exports.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43be7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43be8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Sunset</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The authority provided under subsection (a)(1) to exempt an agreement shall terminate upon <date date="2008-10-08">October 8, 2008</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43be9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Reporting to Congress</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43bea-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Information on nuclear activities of India</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President shall keep the appropriate congressional committees fully and currently informed of the facts and implications of any significant nuclear activities of India, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43beb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> any material noncompliance on the part of the Government of India with—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43bec-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the nonproliferation commitments undertaken in the Joint Statement of <date date="2005-07-18">July 18, 2005</date>, between the President of the United States and the Prime Minister of India;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43bed-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the separation plan presented in the national parliament of India on <date date="2006-03-07">March 7, 2006</date>, and in greater detail on <date date="2006-05-11">May 11, 2006</date>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43bee-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> a safeguards agreement between the Government of India and the IAEA;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43bef-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/1/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> an Additional Protocol between the Government of India and the IAEA;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43bf0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/1/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> an agreement for cooperation between the Government of India and the United States Government arranged pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153">section 2153 of title 42</ref> or any subsequent arrangement under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2160">section 2160 of title 42</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43bf1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/1/A/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> the terms and conditions of any approved licenses regarding the export or reexport of nuclear material or dual-use material, equipment, or technology; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43bf2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/1/A/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> United States laws and regulations regarding such licenses;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43bf3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any material inconsistencies between the content or timeliness of notifications by the Government of India pursuant to paragraph 14(a) of the Safeguards Agreement and the facilities and schedule described in paragraph (14) of the separation plan presented in the national parliament of India on <date date="2006-05-11">May 11, 2006</date>, taking into account the later initiation of safeguards than was anticipated in the separation plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43bf4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the construction of a nuclear facility in India after <date date="2006-12-18">December 18, 2006</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43bf5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> significant changes in the production by India of nuclear weapons or in the types or amounts of fissile material produced; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43bf6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> changes in the purpose or operational status of any unsafeguarded nuclear fuel cycle activities in India.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43bf7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Implementation and compliance report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after the date on which an agreement for cooperation with India arranged pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153">section 2153 of title 42</ref> enters into force, and annually thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43bf8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a description of any additional nuclear facilities and nuclear materials that the Government of India has placed or intends to place under IAEA safeguards;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43bf9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> a comprehensive listing of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43bfa-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> all licenses that have been approved by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission and the Secretary of Energy for exports and reexports to India under parts 110 and 810 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43bfb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> any licenses approved by the Department of Commerce for the export or reexport to India of commodities, related technology, and software which are controlled for nuclear nonproliferation reasons on the Nuclear Referral List of the Commerce Control List maintained under part 774 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulation,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002396">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002396"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “Regulations,”.</note> or any successor regulation;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43bfc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> any other United States authorizations for the export or reexport to India of nuclear materials and equipment; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43bfd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><chapeau> with respect to each such license or other form of authorization described in clauses (i), (ii), and (iii)—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43bfe-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/B/iv/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the number or other identifying information of each license or authorization;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43bff-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/B/iv/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the name or names of the authorized end user or end users;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43c00-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/B/iv/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the name of the site, facility, or location in India to which the export or reexport was made;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43c01-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/B/iv/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> the terms and conditions included on such licenses and authorizations;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43c02-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/B/iv/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> any post-shipment verification procedures that will be applied to such exports or reexports; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43c03-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/B/iv/VI"><num value="VI">(VI)</num><content> the term of validity of each such license or authorization;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43c04-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> a description of any significant nuclear commerce between India and other countries, including any such trade that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c05-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> is not consistent with applicable guidelines or decisions of the NSG; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c06-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> would not meet the standards applied to exports or reexports of such material, equipment, or technology of United States origin;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43c07-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> either—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c08-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> an assessment that India is in full compliance with the commitments and obligations contained in the agreements and other documents referenced in clauses (i) through (vi) of paragraph (1)(A); or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c09-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> an identification and analysis of all compliance issues arising with regard to the adherence by India to its commitments and obligations, including—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43c0a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/D/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the measures the United States Government has taken to remedy or otherwise respond to such compliance issues;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43c0b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/D/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the responses of the Government of India to such measures;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43c0c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/D/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the measures the United States Government plans to take to this end in the coming year; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43c0d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/D/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> an assessment of the implications of any continued noncompliance, including whether nuclear commerce with India remains in the national security interest of the United States;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43c0e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43c0f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> an assessment of whether India is fully and actively participating in United States and international efforts to dissuade, isolate, and, if necessary, sanction and contain Iran for its efforts to acquire weapons of mass destruction, including a nuclear weapons capability (including the capability to enrich uranium or reprocess nuclear fuel), and the means to deliver weapons of mass destruction, including a description of the specific measures that India has taken in this regard; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43c10-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> if India is not assessed to be fully and actively participating in such efforts, a description of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c11-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/E/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the measures the United States Government has taken to secure India’s full and active participation in such efforts;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c12-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/E/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the responses of the Government of India to such measures; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c13-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/E/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the measures the United States Government plans to take in the coming year to secure India’s full and active participation;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43c14-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><chapeau> an analysis of whether United States civil nuclear cooperation with India is in any way assisting India’s nuclear weapons program, including through—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c15-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/F/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the use of any United States equipment, technology, or nuclear material by India in an unsafeguarded nuclear facility or nuclear-weapons related complex;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c16-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/F/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the replication and subsequent use of any United States technology by India in an unsafeguarded nuclear facility or unsafeguarded nuclear weapons-related complex, or for any activity related to the research, development, testing, or manufacture of nuclear explosive devices; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c17-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/F/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the provision of nuclear fuel in such a manner as to facilitate the increased production by India of highly enriched uranium or plutonium in unsafeguarded nuclear facilities;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43c18-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><chapeau> a detailed description of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c19-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/G/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> United States efforts to promote national or regional progress by India and Pakistan in disclosing, securing, limiting, and reducing their fissile material stockpiles, including stockpiles for military purposes, pending creation of a worldwide fissile material cut-off regime, including the institution of a Fissile Material Cut-off Treaty;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c1a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/G/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the responses of India and Pakistan to such efforts; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c1b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/G/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> assistance that the United States is providing, or would be able to provide, to India and Pakistan to promote the objectives in clause (i), consistent with its obligations under international law and existing agreements;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43c1c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><chapeau> an estimate of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c1d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/H/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the amount of uranium mined and milled in India during the previous year;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c1e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/H/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the amount of such uranium that has likely been used or allocated for the production of nuclear explosive devices; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c1f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/H/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><chapeau> the rate of production in India of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43c20-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/H/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> fissile material for nuclear explosive devices; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43c21-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/H/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> nuclear explosive devices;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43c22-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> an estimate of the amount of electricity India’s nuclear reactors produced for civil purposes during the previous year and the proportion of such production that can be attributed to India’s declared civil reactors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43c23-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><content> an analysis as to whether imported uranium has affected the rate of production in India of nuclear explosive devices;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43c24-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/K"><num value="K">(K)</num><chapeau> a detailed description of efforts and progress made toward the achievement of India’s—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c25-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/K/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> full participation in the Proliferation Security Initiative;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c26-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/K/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> formal commitment to the Statement of Interdiction Principles of such Initiative;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c27-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/K/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> public announcement of its decision to conform its export control laws, regulations, and policies with the Australia Group and with the Guidelines, Procedures, Criteria, and Controls List of the Wassenaar Arrangement; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c28-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/K/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> effective implementation of the decision described in clause (iii);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43c29-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/L"><num value="L">(L)</num><content> the disposal during the previous year of spent nuclear fuel from India’s civilian nuclear program, and any plans or activities relating to future disposal of such spent nuclear fuel; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f43c2a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/M"><num value="M">(M)</num><chapeau> with respect to the United States-India Agreement for Cooperation on Peaceful Uses of Nuclear Energy (hereinafter in this subparagraph referred to as the “Agreement”) approved under section 101(a) of the United States-India Nuclear Cooperation Approval and Nonproliferation Enhancement Act—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c2b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/M/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> a listing of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43c2c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/M/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> all provision of sensitive nuclear technology to India, and other such information as may be so designated by the United States or India under Article 1(Q); and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43c2d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/M/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> all facilities in India notified pursuant to Article 7(1) of the Agreement;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c2e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/M/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> a description of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43c2f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/M/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> any agreed safeguards or any other form of verification for by-product material decided by mutual agreement pursuant to the terms of Article 1(A) of the Agreement;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43c30-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/M/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> research and development undertaken in such areas as may be agreed between the United States and India as detailed in Article 2(2)(a.) of the Agreement;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43c31-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/M/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the civil nuclear cooperation activities undertaken under Article 2(2)(d.) of the Agreement;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43c32-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/M/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> any United States efforts to help India develop a strategic reserve of nuclear fuel as called for in Article 2(2)(e.) of the Agreement;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43c33-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/M/ii/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> any United States efforts to fulfill political commitments made in Article 5(6) of the Agreement;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43c34-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/M/ii/VI"><num value="VI">(VI)</num><content> any negotiations that have occurred or are ongoing under Article 6(iii.) of the Agreement; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43c35-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/M/ii/VII"><num value="VII">(VII)</num><content> any transfers beyond the territorial jurisdiction of India pursuant to Article 7(2) of the Agreement, including a listing of the receiving country of each such transfer;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c36-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/M/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><chapeau> an analysis of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43c37-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/M/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> any instances in which the United States or India requested consultations arising from concerns over compliance with the provisions of Article 7(1) of the Agreement, and the results of such consultations; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43c38-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/M/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> any matters not otherwise identified in this report that have become the subject of consultations pursuant to Article 13(2) of the Agreement, and a statement as to whether such matters were resolved by the end of the reporting period; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f43c39-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/M/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><chapeau> a statement as to whether—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43c3a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/M/iv/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> any consultations are expected to occur under Article 16(5) of the Agreement; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="id90f43c3b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/2/M/iv/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> any enrichment is being carried out pursuant to Article 6 of the Agreement.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43c3c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Submittal with other annual reports</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43c3d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Report on proliferation prevention</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Each annual report submitted under paragraph (2) after the initial report may be submitted together with the annual report on proliferation prevention required under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3281/a">section 3281(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43c3e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Report on progress toward regional nonproliferation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The information required to be submitted under paragraph (2)(F) after the initial report may be submitted together with the annual report on progress toward regional nonproliferation required under section 2376(c) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002397">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002397"><num>2</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90f43c3f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8003/g/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Form</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each report submitted under this subsection shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id90f43c40-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/109/401/tI/s104">Pub. L. 109–401, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="2006-12-18">Dec. 18, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2729">120 Stat. 2729</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/369/tI">Pub. L. 110–369, title I</ref>, §§ 101(c), 105, <date date="2008-10-08">Oct. 8, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4029">122 Stat. 4029</ref>, 4030.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id90f43c41-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id90f43c42-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id90f43c43-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (d)(1), (2), (3)(A), was in the original “this title”, meaning title I of <ref href="/us/pl/109/401">Pub. L. 109–401</ref>, <date date="2006-12-18">Dec. 18, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2726">120 Stat. 2726</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of title I to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s8001">section 8001 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 101(a) of the United States-India Nuclear Cooperation Approval and Nonproliferation Enhancement Act, referred to in subsec. (g)(2)(M), is <ref href="/us/pl/110/369/s101/a">section 101(a) of Pub. L. 110–369</ref>, which is set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s8001">section 8001 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2376/c">Section 2376(c) of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (g)(3)(B), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/113/188/tXIV/s1401">Pub. L. 113–188, title XIV, § 1401</ref>, <date date="2014-11-26">Nov. 26, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/2023">128 Stat. 2023</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id90f43c44-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of <ref href="/us/pl/109/401/s104">section 104 of Pub. L. 109–401</ref>. Subsec. (e) of <ref href="/us/pl/109/401/s104">section 104 of Pub. L. 109–401</ref> amended <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153/d">section 2153(d) of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id90f43c45-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/110/369/s101/c">Pub. L. 110–369, § 101(c)</ref>, substituted “<date date="2008-10-08">October 8, 2008</date>” for “the enactment of a joint resolution under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153/d">section 2153(d) of title 42</ref> approving such an agreement”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1)(B) to (E). <ref href="/us/pl/110/369/s105/a">Pub. L. 110–369, § 105(a)</ref>, added subpar. (B) and redesignated former subpars. (B) to (D) as (C) to (E), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2)(M). <ref href="/us/pl/110/369/s105/b">Pub. L. 110–369, § 105(b)</ref>, added subpar. (M).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id90f43c46-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90f43c47-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Proposed Agreement for Cooperation Between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of India Concerning Peaceful Uses of Nuclear Energy</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Determination of President of the United States, No. 2008–26, <date date="2008-09-10">Sept. 10, 2008</date>, 73 F.R. 54287, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum for the Secretary of State [and] the Secretary of Energy</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">I have considered the Proposed Agreement for Cooperation Between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of India Concerning Peaceful Uses of Nuclear Energy, along with the views, recommendations, and statements of interested agencies.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">I have determined that the performance of the Agreement will promote, and will not constitute an unreasonable risk to, the common defense and security. Pursuant to section 123 b. of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153/B">42 U.S.C. 2153(B)</ref> [sic]), I hereby approve the proposed agreement and authorize the Secretary of State to arrange for its execution.</p>
<p>In addition, pursuant to the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the Henry J. Hyde United States-India Peaceful Atomic Energy Cooperation Act of 2006 (<ref href="/us/pl/109/401">Public Law 109–401</ref>), I hereby determine that:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1. India has provided the United States and the IAEA with a credible plan to separate civil and military nuclear facilities, materials, and programs, and has filed a declaration regarding its civil facilities and materials with the IAEA;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2. India and the IAEA have concluded all legal steps required prior to signature by the parties of an agreement requiring the application of IAEA safeguards in perpetuity in accordance with IAEA standards, principles, and practices (including IAEA Board of Governors Document GOV/1621 (1973)) to India’s civil nuclear facilities, materials, and programs as declared in the plan described in paragraph (1), including materials used in or produced through the use of India’s civil nuclear facilities;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">3. India and the IAEA are making substantial progress toward concluding an Additional Protocol consistent with IAEA principles, practices, and policies that would apply to India’s civil nuclear program;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">4. India is working actively with the United States for the early conclusion of a multilateral treaty on the cessation of the production of fissile materials for use in nuclear weapons or other nuclear explosive devices;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">5. India is working with and supporting United States and international efforts to prevent the spread of enrichment and reprocessing technology to any state that does not already possess full-scale, functioning enrichment or reprocessing plants;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">6. India is taking the necessary steps to secure nuclear and other sensitive materials and technology, including through (A) the enactment and effective enforcement of comprehensive export control legislation and regulations; (B) harmonization of its export control laws, regulations, policies, and practices with the guidelines and practices of the Missile Technology Control Regime (MTCR) and the Nuclear Suppliers Group (NSG); and (C) adherence to the MTCR and the NSG in accordance with the procedures of those regimes for unilateral adherence; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">7. The NSG has decided by consensus to permit supply to India of nuclear items covered by the guidelines of the NSG.</p>
<p>I therefore hereby (1) exempt the proposed Agreement for Cooperation Between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of India Concerning Peaceful Uses of Nuclear Energy arranged pursuant to section 123 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153">42 U.S.C. 2153</ref>) from the requirement of subsection 123 a.(2) of such section; (2) waive the application of section 128 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2157">42 U.S.C. 2157</ref>) with respect to exports to India; and (3) waive with respect to India the application of:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(A) subsection 129 a.(1)(D) of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2158/a/1/D">42 U.S.C. 2158(a)(1)(D)</ref>); and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(B) section 129 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2158">42 U.S.C. 2158</ref>) regarding any actions that occurred before <date date="2005-07-18">July 18, 2005</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Secretary of State is authorized and directed to publish this determination in the Federal Register.</p>
<signature>
<name>George W. Bush.</name>
</signature>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="miscellaneous" id="id90f43c48-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Certain Functions Under Section 104(g) of the United States-India Peaceful Atomic Energy Cooperation Act of 2006, as Amended by <ref href="/us/pl/110/369">Public Law 110–369</ref></heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2010-04-27">Apr. 27, 2010</date>, 75 F.R. 23563, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Memorandum for the Secretary of State</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, including <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref>, United States Code, I hereby delegate to you the functions and authority conferred upon the President by section 104(g) of the [Henry J. Hyde] United States-India Peaceful Atomic Energy Cooperation Act of 2006 (<ref href="/us/pl/109/401">Public Law 109–401</ref>), as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/110/369/s105">section 105 of Public Law 110–369</ref>, to make the specified report to the Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the Federal Register.</p>
<signature>
<name>Barack Obama.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
