<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90f6acd0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8123"><num value="8123">§ 8123.</num><heading> Consents, warrants, and complementary access</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90f6acd1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8123/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90f6acd2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8123/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedure</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90f6acd3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8123/a/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Consent</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Except as provided in paragraph (2), an appropriate official of the United States Government shall seek or have the consent of the owner, operator, occupant, or agent in charge of a location prior to entering that location in connection with complementary access pursuant to sections 8121 and 8122 of this title. The owner, operator, occupant, or agent in charge of the location may withhold consent for any reason or no reason.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="id90f6acd4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8123/a/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrative search warrant</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the absence of consent, the United States Government may seek an administrative search warrant from a judge of the United States under subsection (b). Proceedings regarding the issuance of an administrative search warrant shall be conducted ex parte, unless otherwise requested by the United States Government.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90f6acd5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8123/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Expedited access</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of obtaining access to a location pursuant to Article 4b.(ii) of the Additional Protocol in order to satisfy United States obligations under the Additional Protocol when notice of two hours or less is required, the United States Government may gain entry to such location in connection with complementary access, to the extent such access is consistent with the Fourth Amendment to the United States Constitution, without obtaining either a warrant or consent.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90f6acd6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8123/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Administrative search warrants for complementary access</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90f6acd7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8123/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Obtaining administrative search warrants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For complementary access conducted in the United States pursuant to the Additional Protocol, and for which the acquisition of a warrant is required, the United States Government shall first obtain an administrative search warrant from a judge of the United States. The United States Government shall provide to such judge all appropriate information regarding the basis for the selection of the facility, site, or other location to which complementary access is sought.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90f6acd8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8123/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Content of affidavits for administrative search warrants</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A judge of the United States shall promptly issue an administrative search warrant authorizing the requested complementary access upon an affidavit submitted by the United States Government—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f6acd9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8123/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> stating that the Additional Protocol is in force;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f6acda-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8123/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> stating that the designated facility, site, or other location is subject to complementary access under the Additional Protocol;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f6acdb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8123/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> stating that the purpose of the complementary access is consistent with Article 4 of the Additional Protocol;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f6acdc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8123/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> stating that the requested complementary access is in accordance with Article 4 of the Additional Protocol;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f6acdd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8123/b/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> containing assurances that the scope of the IAEA’s complementary access, as well as what it may collect, shall be limited to the access provided for in Article 6 of the Additional Protocol;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f6acde-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8123/b/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> listing the items, documents, and areas to be searched and seized;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f6acdf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8123/b/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> stating the earliest commencement and the anticipated duration of the complementary access period, as well as the expected times of day during which such complementary access will take place; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f6ace0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8123/b/2/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><chapeau> stating that the location to which entry in connection with complementary access is sought was selected either—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f6ace1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8123/b/2/H/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> because there is probable cause, on the basis of specific evidence, to believe that information required to be reported regarding a location pursuant to regulations promulgated under this chapter is incorrect or incomplete, and that the location to be accessed contains evidence regarding that violation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id90f6ace2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8123/b/2/H/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> pursuant to a reasonable general administrative plan based upon specific neutral criteria.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90f6ace3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8123/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Content of warrants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A warrant issued under paragraph (2) shall specify the same matters required of an affidavit under that paragraph. In addition, each warrant shall contain the identities of the representatives of the IAEA on the complementary access team and the identities of the representatives or designees of the United States Government required to display identifying credentials under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s8122/c">section 8122(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id90f6ace4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/109/401/tII/s223">Pub. L. 109–401, title II, § 223</ref>, <date date="2006-12-18">Dec. 18, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2745">120 Stat. 2745</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
