<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90f6ad1e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8153"><num value="8153">§ 8153.</num><heading> Application of national security exclusion to location-specific environmental sampling</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In accordance with Article 1(b) of the Additional Protocol, the United States shall not permit any location-specific environmental sampling in the United States under Article 5 of the Additional Protocol unless the President has determined and reported to the appropriate congressional committees with respect to that proposed use of environmental sampling that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f6ad1f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8153/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the proposed use of location-specific environmental sampling is necessary to increase the capability of the IAEA to detect undeclared nuclear activities in the territory of a non-nuclear-weapon State Party;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f6ad20-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8153/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the proposed use of location-specific environmental sampling will not result in access by the IAEA to locations, activities, or information of direct national security significance; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f6ad21-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8153/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> with respect to the proposed use of environmental sampling, the United States—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f6ad22-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8153/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> has been provided sufficient opportunity for consultation with the IAEA if the IAEA has requested complementary access involving location-specific environmental sampling; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f6ad23-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8153/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> has requested under Article 8 of the Additional Protocol that the IAEA engage in complementary access in the United States that involves the use of location-specific environmental sampling.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id90f6ad24-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/109/401/tII/s253">Pub. L. 109–401, title II, § 253</ref>, <date date="2006-12-18">Dec. 18, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2750">120 Stat. 2750</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
