<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90f91d5b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8202"><num value="8202">§ 8202.</num><heading> Statement of policy</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f91d5c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8202/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to promote freedom and democracy in foreign countries as a fundamental component of United States foreign policy, along with other key foreign policy goals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f91d5d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8202/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to affirm fundamental freedoms and internationally recognized human rights in foreign countries, as reflected in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights and the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights, and to condemn offenses against those freedoms and rights as a fundamental component of United States foreign policy, along with other key foreign policy goals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f91d5e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8202/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to protect and promote such fundamental freedoms and rights, including the freedoms of association, of expression, of the press, and of religion, and the right to own private property;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f91d5f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8202/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to commit to the long-term challenge of promoting universal democracy by promoting democratic institutions, including institutions that support the rule of law (such as an independent judiciary), an independent and professional media, strong legislatures, a thriving civil society, transparent and professional independent governmental auditing agencies, civilian control of the military, and institutions that promote the rights of minorities and women;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f91d60-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8202/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> to use instruments of United States influence to support, promote, and strengthen democratic principles, practices, and values, including the right to free, fair, and open elections, secret balloting, and universal suffrage, including by—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f91d61-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8202/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> providing appropriate support to individuals, nongovernmental organizations, and movements located in nondemocratic countries that aspire to live in freedom and establish full democracy in such countries; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90f91d62-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8202/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> providing political, economic, and other support to foreign countries and individuals, nongovernmental organizations, and movements that are willingly undertaking a transition to democracy; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f91d63-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8202/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> to strengthen cooperation with other democratic countries in order to better promote and defend shared values and ideals.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id90f91d64-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/110/53/tXXI/s2103">Pub. L. 110–53, title XXI, § 2103</ref>, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/527">121 Stat. 527</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
