<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90f91dbb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8241"><num value="8241">§ 8241.</num><heading> Training in democracy promotion and the protection of human rights</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90f91dbc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8241/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall continue to enhance training for members of the Foreign Service and civil service responsible for the promotion of democracy and the protection of human rights. Such training shall include appropriate instruction and training materials regarding:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f91dbd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8241/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> International documents and United States policy regarding the promotion of democracy and respect for human rights.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f91dbe-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8241/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> United States policy regarding the promotion and strengthening of democracy around the world, with particular emphasis on the transition to democracy in nondemocratic countries and democratic transition countries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f91dbf-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8241/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> For any member, chief of mission, or deputy chief of mission who is to be assigned to a nondemocratic country or democratic transition country, ways to promote democracy in such country and to assist individuals, nongovernmental organizations, and movements in such country that support democratic principles, practices, and values.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90f91dc0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8241/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The protection of internationally recognized human rights (including the protection of religious freedom) and standards related to such rights, provisions of United States law related to such rights, diplomatic tools to promote respect for such rights, and the protection of individuals who have fled their countries due to violations of such rights.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90f91dc1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8241/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Foreign Affairs Training Center of the Foreign Service Institute of the Department, shall consult, as appropriate, with nongovernmental organizations involved in the protection and promotion of such rights and the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom with respect to the training required by this subsection.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002400">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002400"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “section”.</note></p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90f91dc2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8241/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after <date date="2007-08-03">August 3, 2007</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report containing a description of the current and planned training provided to Foreign Service officers in human rights and democracy promotion, including such training provided to chiefs of mission serving or preparing to serve in nondemocratic countries or democratic transition countries.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id90f91dc3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/110/53/tXXI/s2141">Pub. L. 110–53, title XXI, § 2141</ref>, <date date="2007-08-03">Aug. 3, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/534">121 Stat. 534</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id90f91dc4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id90f91dc5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id90f91dc6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References to National Foreign Affairs Training Center considered to refer to George P. Shultz National Foreign Affairs Training Center, see <ref href="/us/pl/107/132/s1/b">section 1(b) of Pub. L. 107–132</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s4021">section 4021 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
