<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90fb67d9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8423"><num value="8423">§ 8423.</num><heading> Limitations on certain assistance</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90fb67da-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8423/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on security-related assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For fiscal years 2011 through 2014, no security-related assistance may be provided to Pakistan in a fiscal year until the Secretary of State, under the direction of the President, makes the certification required under subsection (c) for such fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90fb67db-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8423/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on arms transfers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For fiscal years 2012 through 2014, no letter of offer to sell major defense equipment to Pakistan may be issued pursuant to the Arms Export Control Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">22 U.S.C. 2751</ref> et seq.) and no license to export major defense equipment to Pakistan may be issued pursuant to such Act in a fiscal year until the Secretary of State, under the direction of the President, makes the certification required under subsection (c) for such fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90fb67dc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8423/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Certification</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The certification required by this subsection is a certification by the Secretary of State, under the direction of the President, to the appropriate congressional committees that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90fb67dd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8423/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Government of Pakistan is continuing to cooperate with the United States in efforts to dismantle supplier networks relating to the acquisition of nuclear weapons-related materials, such as providing relevant information from or direct access to Pakistani nationals associated with such networks;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90fb67de-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8423/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> the Government of Pakistan during the preceding fiscal year has demonstrated a sustained commitment to and is making significant efforts towards combating terrorist groups, consistent with the purposes of assistance described in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s8421">section 8421 of this title</ref>, including taking into account the extent to which the Government of Pakistan has made progress on matters such as—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90fb67df-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8423/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> ceasing support, including by any elements within the Pakistan military or its intelligence agency, to extremist and terrorist groups, particularly to any group that has conducted attacks against United States or coalition forces in Afghanistan, or against the territory or people of neighboring countries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90fb67e0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8423/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> preventing al Qaeda, the Taliban and associated terrorist groups, such as Lashkar-e-Taiba and Jaish-e-Mohammed, from operating in the territory of Pakistan, including carrying out cross-border attacks into neighboring countries, closing terrorist camps in the FATA, dismantling terrorist bases of operations in other parts of the country, including Quetta and Muridke, and taking action when provided with intelligence about high-level terrorist targets; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90fb67e1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8423/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> strengthening counterterrorism and anti-money laundering laws; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90fb67e2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8423/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the security forces of Pakistan are not materially and substantially subverting the political or judicial processes of Pakistan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90fb67e3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8423/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain payments</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90fb67e4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8423/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Subject to paragraph (2), none of the funds appropriated for security-related assistance for fiscal years 2010 through 2014, or any amounts appropriated to the Pakistan Counterinsurgency Capability Fund established under the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2009 (<ref href="/us/pl/111/32">Public Law 111–32</ref>), may be obligated or expended to make payments relating to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90fb67e5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8423/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Letter of Offer and Acceptance PK–D–YAD signed between the Governments of the United States of America and Pakistan on <date date="2006-09-30">September 30, 2006</date>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90fb67e6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8423/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Letter of Offer and Acceptance PK–D–NAP signed between the Governments of the United States of America and Pakistan on <date date="2006-09-30">September 30, 2006</date>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90fb67e7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8423/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the Letter of Offer and Acceptance PK–D–SAF signed between the Governments of the United States of America and Pakistan on <date date="2006-09-30">September 30, 2006</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90fb67e8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8423/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Funds appropriated for security-related assistance for fiscal years 2010 through 2014 may be used for construction and related activities carried out pursuant to the Letters of Offer and Acceptance described in paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90fb67e9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8423/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90fb67ea-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8423/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary of State, under the direction of the President, may waive the limitations contained in subsections (a), (b), and (d) for a fiscal year if the Secretary of State determines that is important to the national security interests of the United States to do so.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90fb67eb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8423/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Prior notice of waiver</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary of State, under the direction of the President, may not exercise the authority of paragraph (1) until 7 days after the Secretary of State provides to the appropriate congressional committees a written notice of the intent to issue to waiver <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002405">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002405"><num>1</num> So in original.</note> and the reasons therefor. The notice may be submitted in classified or unclassified form, as necessary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90fb67ec-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8423/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90fb67ed-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8423/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90fb67ee-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8423/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id90fb67ef-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/111/73/tII/s203">Pub. L. 111–73, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="2009-10-15">Oct. 15, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2071">123 Stat. 2071</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id90fb67f0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id90fb67f1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id90fb67f2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Arms Export Control Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/pl/90/629">Pub. L. 90–629</ref>, <date date="1968-10-22">Oct. 22, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1320">82 Stat. 1320</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 39 (§ 2751 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2751">section 2751 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2009, referred to in subsec. (d)(1), is <ref href="/us/pl/111/32">Pub. L. 111–32</ref>, <date date="2009-06-24">June 24, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1859">123 Stat. 1859</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id90fb67f3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="id90fb67f4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Reform of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 6, One Hundred Sixteenth Congress, <date date="2019-01-09">Jan. 9, 2019</date>. Committee on Oversight and Reform of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Oversight and Accountability of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Eighteenth Congress, <date date="2023-01-09">Jan. 9, 2023</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
