<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id90fdd846-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442"><num value="8442">§ 8442.</num><heading> Monitoring reports</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90fdd847-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Semi-annual monitoring report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after the submission of the Pakistan Assistance Strategy Report pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s8441/a">section 8441(a) of this title</ref>, and every 180 days thereafter through <date date="2014-09-30">September 30, 2014</date>, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that describes the assistance provided under this chapter during the preceding 180-day period. The report shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90fdd848-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a description of all assistance by program, project, and activity, as well as by geographic area, provided pursuant to subchapter I of this chapter during the period covered by the report, including the amount of assistance provided for each program or project, and with respect to the first report a description of all amounts made available for assistance to Pakistan during fiscal year 2009, including a description of each program, project, and activity for which funds were made available;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90fdd849-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a list of persons or entities from the United States or other countries that have received funds in excess of $100,000 to conduct projects under subchapter I of this chapter during the period covered by the report, which may be included in a classified annex, if necessary to avoid a security risk, and a justification for the classification;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90fdd84a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> with respect to the plan described in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s8441/a/3">section 8441(a)(3) of this title</ref>, updates to such plan and a description of best practices to improve the impact of the assistance authorized under subchapter I of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90fdd84b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> an assessment of the effectiveness of assistance provided under subchapter I of this chapter during the period covered by the report in achieving desired objectives and outcomes as guided by the plan described in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s8441/a/3">section 8441(a)(3) of this title</ref>, and as updated pursuant to paragraph (3) of this subsection, including a systematic, qualitative, and where possible, quantitative basis for assessing whether desired outcomes are achieved and a timeline for completion of each project and program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90fdd84c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> a description of any shortfall in United States financial, physical, technical, or human resources that hinder the effective use and monitoring of such funds;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90fdd84d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> a description of any negative impact, including the absorptive capacity of the region for which the resources are intended, of United States bilateral or multilateral assistance and recommendations for modification of funding, if any;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90fdd84e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> any incidents or reports of waste, fraud, and abuse of expenditures under subchapter I of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90fdd84f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> the amount of funds authorized to be appropriated pursuant to section 8412 that were used during the reporting period for administrative expenses or for audits and program reviews pursuant to the authority under sections 8411(c)(2) and 8413 of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90fdd850-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> a description of the expenditures made from any Chief of Mission Fund established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s8411/c/5">section 8411(c)(5) of this title</ref> during the period covered by the report, the purposes for which such expenditures were made, and a list of the recipients of any expenditures from the Chief of Mission Fund in excess of $100,000;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90fdd851-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> an accounting of assistance provided to Pakistan under subchapter I of this chapter, broken down into the categories set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s8441/a/6">section 8441(a)(6) of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90fdd852-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/a/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><chapeau> an evaluation of efforts undertaken by the Government of Pakistan to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90fdd853-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/a/11/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> disrupt, dismantle, and defeat al Qaeda, the Taliban, and other extremist and terrorist groups in the FATA and settled areas;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90fdd854-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/a/11/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> eliminate the safe havens of such forces in Pakistan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90fdd855-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/a/11/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> close terrorist camps, including those of Lashkar-e-Taiba and Jaish-e-Mohammed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90fdd856-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/a/11/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> cease all support for extremist and terrorist groups;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90fdd857-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/a/11/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> prevent attacks into neighboring countries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90fdd858-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/a/11/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> increase oversight over curriculum in madrassas, including closing madrassas with direct links to the Taliban or other extremist and terrorist groups; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90fdd859-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/a/11/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> improve counterterrorism financing and anti-money laundering laws, apply for observer status for the Financial Action Task Force, and take steps to adhere to the United Nations International Convention for the Suppression of Financing of Terrorism;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90fdd85a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/a/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> a detailed description of Pakistan’s efforts to prevent proliferation of nuclear-related material and expertise;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90fdd85b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/a/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> an assessment of whether assistance provided to Pakistan has directly or indirectly aided the expansion of Pakistan’s nuclear weapons program, whether by the diversion of United States assistance or the reallocation of Pakistan’s financial resources that would otherwise be spent for programs and activities unrelated to its nuclear weapons program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90fdd85c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/a/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> a detailed description of the extent to which funds obligated and expended pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s8422/b">section 8422(b) of this title</ref> meet the requirements of such section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90fdd85d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/a/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content> an assessment of the extent to which the Government of Pakistan exercises effective civilian control of the military, including a description of the extent to which civilian executive leaders and parliament exercise oversight and approval of military budgets, the chain of command, the process of promotion for senior military leaders, civilian involvement in strategic guidance and planning, and military involvement in civil administration.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90fdd85e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Government Accountability Office reports</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90fdd85f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Pakistan Assistance Strategy Report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than one year after the submission of the Pakistan Assistance Strategy Report pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s8441/a">section 8441(a) of this title</ref>, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90fdd860-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a review of, and comments addressing, the Pakistan Assistance Strategy Report;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90fdd861-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> recommendations relating to any additional actions the Comptroller General believes could help improve the efficiency and effectiveness of United States efforts to meet the objectives of this chapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90fdd862-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a detailed description of the expenditures made by Pakistan pursuant to grant assistance under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2763">section 2763 of this title</ref> (relating to the Foreign Military Financing program); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id90fdd863-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> an assessment of the impact of the assistance on the security and stability of Pakistan.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id90fdd864-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Certification report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 120 days after the date on which the President makes the certification described in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s8423/c">section 8423(c) of this title</ref> for a fiscal year, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct an independent analysis of the certification described in such section and shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report containing the results of the independent analysis.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90fdd865-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of State may submit the reports required by this section in conjunction with other reports relating to Pakistan required under other provisions of law, including sections 1116 and 1117 of the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2009 (<ref href="/us/pl/111/32">Public Law 111–32</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/123/1906">123 Stat. 1906</ref> and 1907).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id90fdd866-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Appropriate congressional committees defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90fdd867-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id90fdd868-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8442/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id90fdd869-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/111/73/tIII/s302">Pub. L. 111–73, title III, § 302</ref>, <date date="2009-10-15">Oct. 15, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/2077">123 Stat. 2077</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id90fdd86a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id90fdd86b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id90fdd86c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 1116 and 1117 of the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2009 (<ref href="/us/pl/111/32">Public Law 111–32</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/123/1906">123 Stat. 1906</ref> and 1907), referred to in subsec. (c), are not classified to the Code.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
