<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id910c3081-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8721"><num value="8721">§ 8721.</num><heading> Imposition of sanctions with respect to the provision of vessels or shipping services to transport certain goods related to proliferation or terrorism activities to Iran</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id910c3082-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8721/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as provided in subsection (c), if the President determines that a person, on or after <date date="2012-08-10">August 10, 2012</date>, knowingly sells, leases, or provides a vessel or provides insurance or reinsurance or any other shipping service for the transportation to or from Iran of goods that could materially contribute to the activities of the Government of Iran with respect to the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction or support for acts of international terrorism, the President shall, pursuant to Executive Order No. 13382 (70 Fed. Reg. 38567; relating to blocking of property of weapons of mass destruction proliferators and their supporters) or Executive Order No. 13224 (66 Fed. Reg. 49079; relating to blocking property and prohibiting transactions with persons who commit, threaten to commit, or support terrorism), or otherwise pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.), block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of the persons specified in subsection (b) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id910c3083-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8721/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Persons specified</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The persons specified in this subsection are—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id910c3084-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8721/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the person that sold, leased, or provided a vessel or provided insurance or reinsurance or another shipping service described in subsection (a); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id910c3085-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8721/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> any person that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id910c3086-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8721/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is a successor entity to the person referred to in paragraph (1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id910c3087-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8721/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> owns or controls the person referred to in paragraph (1), if the person that owns or controls the person referred to in paragraph (1) had actual knowledge or should have known that the person referred to in paragraph (1) sold, leased, or provided the vessel or provided the insurance or reinsurance or other shipping service; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id910c3088-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8721/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> is owned or controlled by, or under common ownership or control with, the person referred to in paragraph (1), if the person owned or controlled by, or under common ownership or control with (as the case may be), the person referred to in paragraph (1) knowingly engaged in the sale, lease, or provision of the vessel or the provision of the insurance or reinsurance or other shipping service.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id910c3089-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8721/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President may waive the requirement to impose sanctions with respect to a person under subsection (a) on or after the date that is 30 days after the President—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id910c308a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8721/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> determines that such a waiver is vital to the national security interests of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id910c308b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8721/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> submits to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains the reasons for that determination.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id910c308c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8721/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Report required</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id910c308d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8721/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2012-08-10">August 10, 2012</date>, and every 90 days thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report identifying operators of vessels and other persons that conduct or facilitate significant financial transactions with persons that manage ports in Iran that have been designated for the imposition of sanctions pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id910c308e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8721/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Form of report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A report submitted under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id910c308f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8721/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the President to designate persons for the imposition of sanctions pursuant to Executive Order No. 13382 (70 Fed. Reg. 38567; relating to the blocking of property of weapons of mass destruction proliferators and their supporters) or Executive Order No. 13224 (66 Fed. Reg. 49079; relating to blocking property and prohibiting transactions with persons who commit, threaten to commit, or support terrorism), or otherwise pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id910c3090-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/112/158/tII/s211">Pub. L. 112–158, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="2012-08-10">Aug. 10, 2012</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/1228">126 Stat. 1228</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id910c3091-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I84" topic="prospectiveAmendment" id="id910c3092-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered fontsize8 smallCaps">Termination of Section</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I88" class="indent1 fontsize8 italic">For termination of section, see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s8785/a">section 8785(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id910c3093-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id910c3094-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order No. 13382, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (e), is Ex. Ord. No. 13382, <date date="2005-06-28">June 28, 2005</date>, 70 F.R. 38567, which is listed in a table under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">section 1701 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order No. 13224, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (e), is Ex. Ord. No. 13224, <date date="2001-09-23">Sept. 23, 2001</date>, 66 F.R. 49079, which is listed in a table under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">section 1701 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The International Emergency Economic Powers Act, referred to in subsecs. (a), (d)(1), and (e), is title II of <ref href="/us/pl/95/223">Pub. L. 95–223</ref>, <date date="1977-12-28">Dec. 28, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1626">91 Stat. 1626</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 35 (§ 1701 et seq.) of Title 50, War and National Defense. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">section 1701 of Title 50</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
