<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9115a5e0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8905"><num value="8905">§ 8905.</num><heading> Democracy, civil society, governance, and technical assistance for Ukraine and other states in Central and Eastern Europe</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9115a5e1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8905/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of State shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, directly or through nongovernmental organizations—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9115a5e2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8905/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> improve democratic governance, transparency, accountability, rule of law, and anti-corruption efforts in Ukraine;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9115a5e3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8905/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> support efforts by the Government of Ukraine to foster greater unity among the people and regions of the country;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9115a5e4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8905/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> support the people and Government of Ukraine in preparing to conduct and contest free and fair elections, including through domestic and international election monitoring;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9115a5e5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8905/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> assist in diversifying Ukraine’s economy, trade, and energy supplies, including at the national, regional, and local levels;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9115a5e6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8905/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> strengthen democratic institutions and political and civil society organizations in Ukraine;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9115a5e7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8905/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> expand free and unfettered access to independent media of all kinds in Ukraine and assist with the protection of journalists and civil society activists who have been targeted for free speech activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9115a5e8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8905/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> support political and economic reform initiatives by Eastern Partnership countries; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9115a5e9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8905/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> support the efforts of the Government of Ukraine, civil society, and international organizations to enhance the economic and political empowerment of women in Ukraine and to prevent and address violence against women and girls in Ukraine, and support the inclusion of women in Ukraine in any negotiations to restore Ukraine’s security, independence, sovereignty, or territorial or economic integrity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9115a5ea-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8905/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of State $50,000,000 for fiscal year 2015 to carry out the activities set forth in subsection (a). Amounts appropriated for the activities set forth in subsection (a) shall be used pursuant to the authorization and requirements contained in this section. Additional amounts may be authorized to be appropriated under other provisions of law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9115a5eb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8905/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Strategy requirement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after <date date="2014-04-03">April 3, 2014</date>, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategy to carry out the activities set forth in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9115a5ec-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8905/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification requirement</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9115a5ed-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8905/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Funds appropriated or otherwise made available pursuant to subsection (b) may not be obligated until 15 days after the date on which the President has provided notice of intent to obligate such funds to the appropriate congressional committees.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9115a5ee-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8905/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President may waive the notification requirement under paragraph (1) if the President determines that failure to do so would pose a substantial risk to human health or welfare, in which case notification shall be provided as early as practicable, but in no event later than three days after taking the action to which such notification requirement was applicable in the context of the circumstances necessitating such waiver.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9115a5ef-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/113/95/s6">Pub. L. 113–95, § 6</ref>, <date date="2014-04-03">Apr. 3, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1091">128 Stat. 1091</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
