<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9115a5f0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8906"><num value="8906">§ 8906.</num><heading> Enhanced security cooperation with Ukraine and other countries in Central and Eastern Europe</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9115a5f1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8906/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall, subject to the availability of appropriations—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9115a5f2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8906/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> enhance security cooperation efforts and relationships amongst countries in Central and Eastern Europe and among the United States, the European Union, and countries in Central and Eastern Europe;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9115a5f3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8906/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> provide additional security assistance, including defense articles and defense services (as those terms are defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2794">section 2794 of this title</ref>) and military training, to countries in Central and Eastern Europe, including Ukraine; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9115a5f4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8906/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> support greater reform, professionalism, and capacity-building efforts within the military, intelligence, and security services in Central and Eastern Europe, including Ukraine.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9115a5f5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8906/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the President a total of $100,000,000 for fiscal years 2015 through 2017 to carry out this section. Amounts appropriated for the activities set forth in subsection (a) shall be used pursuant to the authorization and requirements contained in this section. Additional amounts may be authorized to be appropriated under other provisions of law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9115a5f6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8906/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Strategy requirement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after <date date="2014-04-03">April 3, 2014</date>, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategy to carry out the activities set forth in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9115a5f7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8906/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification requirement</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9115a5f8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8906/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Funds appropriated or otherwise made available pursuant to subsection (b) may not be obligated until 15 days after the date on which the President has provided notice of intent to obligate such funds to the appropriate congressional committees and the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id9115a5f9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s8906/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The President may waive the notification requirement under paragraph (1) if the President determines that failure to do so would pose a substantial risk to human health or welfare, in which case notification shall be provided as early as practicable, but in no event later than three days after taking the action to which such notification requirement was applicable in the context of the circumstances necessitating such waiver.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9115a5fa-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/113/95/s7">Pub. L. 113–95, § 7</ref>, <date date="2014-04-03">Apr. 3, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1092">128 Stat. 1092</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
