<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id911a61ef-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9006"><num value="9006">§ 9006.</num><heading> United States Central Authority</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id911a61f0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9006/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Designation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall designate a Federal agency to serve as the Central Authority for the United States under the Convention.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id911a61f1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9006/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Functions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The functions of the United States Central Authority are those ascribed to the Central Authority by the Convention and this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id911a61f2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9006/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulatory authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The United States Central Authority is authorized to issue such regulations as may be necessary to carry out its functions under the Convention and this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id911a61f3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9006/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Obtaining information from Parent Locator Service</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The United States Central Authority may, to the extent authorized by the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s301">42 U.S.C. 301</ref> et seq.], obtain information from the Parent Locator Service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id911a61f4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9006/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Grant authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The United States Central Authority is authorized to make grants to, or enter into contracts or agreements with, any individual, corporation, other Federal, State, or local agency, or private entity or organization in the United States for purposes of accomplishing its responsibilities under the Convention and this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id911a61f5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9006/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Limited liability of private entities acting under the direction of the United States Central Authority</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id911a61f6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9006/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on liability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), a private entity or organization that receives a grant from or enters into a contract or agreement with the United States Central Authority under subsection (e) of this section for purposes of assisting the United States Central Authority in carrying out its responsibilities and functions under the Convention and this chapter, including any director, officer, employee, or agent of such entity or organization, shall not be liable in any civil action sounding in tort for damages directly related to the performance of such responsibilities and functions as defined by the regulations issued under subsection (c) of this section that are in effect on <date date="2004-10-01">October 1, 2004</date>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id911a61f7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9006/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception for intentional, reckless, or other misconduct</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The limitation on liability under paragraph (1) shall not apply in any action in which the plaintiff proves that the private entity, organization, officer, employee, or agent described in paragraph (1), as the case may be, engaged in intentional misconduct or acted, or failed to act, with actual malice, with reckless disregard to a substantial risk of causing injury without legal justification, or for a purpose unrelated to the performance of responsibilities or functions under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id911a61f8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9006/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception for ordinary business activities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The limitation on liability under paragraph (1) shall not apply to any alleged act or omission related to an ordinary business activity, such as an activity involving general administration or operations, the use of motor vehicles, or personnel management.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id911a61f9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/300/s7">Pub. L. 100–300, § 7</ref>, <date date="1988-04-29">Apr. 29, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/439">102 Stat. 439</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dG/tXXII/s2213">Pub. L. 105–277, div. G, title XXII, § 2213</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-812">112 Stat. 2681–812</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/370/s2">Pub. L. 108–370, § 2</ref>, <date date="2004-10-25">Oct. 25, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1750">118 Stat. 1750</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id911a61fa-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id911a61fb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id911a61fc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (b), (c), (e), and (f), was in the original “this Act” meaning <ref href="/us/pl/100/300">Pub. L. 100–300</ref>, <date date="1988-04-29">Apr. 29, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/437">102 Stat. 437</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9001">section 9001 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Social Security Act, referred to in subsec. (d), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/620">49 Stat. 620</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 7 (§ 301 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1305">section 1305 of Title 42</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id911a61fd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s11606">section 11606 of Title 42</ref>, The Public Health and Welfare.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id911a61fe-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/108/370">Pub. L. 108–370</ref> added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref> added subsec. (e).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id911a61ff-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id911a6200-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 12648. Implementation of Convention on Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 12648, <date date="1988-08-11">Aug. 11, 1988</date>, 53 F.R. 30637, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The United States of America deposited its instrument of ratification of the Hague Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction (“Convention”) on <date date="1988-04-29">April 29, 1988</date>. The Convention entered into force for the United States on <date date="1988-07-01">July 1, 1988</date>. Article 6 of the Convention imposes upon Contracting States an obligation to designate a “Central Authority” for the purpose of discharging certain specified functions.</p>
<p>In order that the Government of the United States of America may give full and complete effect to the Convention, and pursuant to section 7 of the International Child Abduction Remedies Act, Public Law No. 100–300 (1988) [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9006">22 U.S.C. 9006</ref>], it is expedient and necessary that I designate a Central Authority within the Executive branch of said Government:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">NOW, THEREFORE, by virtue of the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, including <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of Title 3</ref> of the United States Code and section 7 of the International Child Abduction Remedies Act, it is ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Designation of Central Authority</i>. The Department of State is hereby designated as the Central Authority of the United States for purposes of the Hague Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction. The Secretary of State is hereby authorized and empowered, in accordance with such regulations as he may prescribe, to perform all lawful acts that may be necessary and proper in order to execute the functions of the Central Authority in a timely and efficient manner.</p>
<signature>
<name>Ronald Reagan.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
