<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id911f42d4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9203"><num value="9203">§ 9203.</num><heading> Strategy on North Korea</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id911f42d5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9203/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Report on strategy required</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 90 days after <date date="2017-12-12">December 12, 2017</date>, the President shall submit to Congress a report setting forth the strategy of the United States with respect to North Korea.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id911f42d6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9203/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Elements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id911f42d7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9203/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A description and assessment of the primary threats to United States national security interests from North Korea.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id911f42d8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9203/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A description of known foreign nation, foreign entity, or individual violations of current United Nations sanctions against North Korea, together with parameters for determining whether and on what timeline it serves United States interests to target such violators with unilateral secondary sanctions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id911f42d9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9203/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A description of the diplomatic, economic, and trade relationships between China and North Korea and between Russia and North Korea, including trends in such relationships and their impact on the Government of North Korea.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id911f42da-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9203/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> An identification of the diplomatic, economic, and security objectives for the Korean Peninsula and the desired end state in North Korea with respect to the security threats emanating from North Korea.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id911f42db-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9203/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> A detailed roadmap to reach the objectives and end state identified pursuant to paragraph (4), including timelines for each element of the roadmap.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id911f42dc-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9203/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> A description of the unilateral and multilateral options available to the United States regarding North Korea, together with an assessment of the degree to which such options would impose costs on North Korea.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id911f42dd-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9203/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> A description of the resources and authorities necessary to carry out the roadmap described in paragraph (5).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id911f42de-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9203/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> A description of operational plans and associated military requirements for the protection of United States interests with respect to North Korea.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id911f42df-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9203/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> An identification of any capability or resource gaps that would affect the implementation of the strategy described in subsection (a), and a mitigation plan to address such gaps.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id911f42e0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9203/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> An assessment of current and desired partner contributions to countering threats from North Korea, and a plan to enhance cooperation among countries with shared security interests with respect to North Korea.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id911f42e1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9203/b/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> Any other matters the President considers appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id911f42e2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9203/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual updates</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall submit to Congress in writing on an annual basis a report describing and assessing progress in the implementation of the strategy described in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id911f42e3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9203/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Form</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The report under subsection (a) and each report under subsection (c) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id911f42e4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tXII/s1256">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title XII, § 1256</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1682">131 Stat. 1682</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id911f42e5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id911f42e6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id911f42e7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section enacted as part of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018, and not as part of the North Korea Sanctions and Policy Enhancement Act of 2016 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id911f42e8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id911f42e9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">North Korea Strategy</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/409/tII/s210">Pub. L. 115–409, title II, § 210</ref>, <date date="2018-12-31">Dec. 31, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5398">132 Stat. 5398</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/409/tII/s210">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Findings</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The Government of the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea has flagrantly defied the international community by illicitly developing its nuclear and ballistic missile programs, in violation of United Nations Security Council Resolutions 1718 (2006), 1874 (2009), 2087 (2013), 2094 (2013), 2270 (2016), 2321 (2016), 2371 (2017), 2375 (2017), and 2397 (2017).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The Government of the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea engages in gross human rights abuses against its own people and citizens of other countries, including the United States, the Republic of Korea, and Japan.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The United States is committed to pursuing a peaceful denuclearization of the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea through a policy of maximum pressure and engagement, in close concert with its partners.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Policy of the United States With Respect to Sanctions Against the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Statement of policy</inline>.—</heading><content>It is the policy of the United States to continue to impose sanctions with respect to activities of the Government of the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea, persons acting for or on behalf of such government, or other persons in accordance with Executive Order No. 13551 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note; relating to blocking property of certain persons with respect to North Korea), Executive Order No. 13687 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note; relating to imposing additional sanctions), Executive Order No. 13694 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note; relating to blocking the property of certain persons engaging in significant malicious cyberenabled activities), Executive Order No. 13722 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note; relating to blocking the property of the Government of North Korea and the Workers’ Party of Korea, and prohibiting certain transactions with respect to North Korea), and Executive Order No. 13810 (82 Fed. Reg. 44705; relating to imposing additional sanctions with respect to North Korea) [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note], as such Executive orders are in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-12-31">Dec. 31, 2018</date>], until the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea is no longer engaged in the illicit activities described in such Executive orders, including actions in violation of the United Nations Security Council resolutions referred to in subsection (a)(1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 30 days after terminating any sanction with respect to the activities of the Government of the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea, a person acting for or on behalf of such government, or any other person provided for in an Executive order listed in subsection (a), the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees justifying the termination of the sanction and explaining the relationship between such termination and the cessation of any illicit activity that violates any of the United Nations Security Council resolutions referred to in subsection (a)(1) by such Government or person. The reporting requirement under this paragraph shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-12-31">Dec. 31, 2018</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rule of construction</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to limit the authority of the President pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Policy of the United States With Respect to Negotiation on the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea’s Nuclear and Ballistic Missile Programs</inline>.—</heading><content>It is the policy of the United States that the objective of negotiations with respect to the nuclear and ballistic missile programs of the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea be the complete, verifiable, and irreversible dismantlement of such programs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report on a Strategy to Address the Threats Posed by, and the Capabilities of, the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-12-31">Dec. 31, 2018</date>], and every 180 days thereafter for the following 5 years, the Secretary of State, or a designee of the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that describes actions taken by the United States to address the threats posed by, and the capabilities of, the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Elements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each report required under paragraph (1) shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> a summary of ongoing efforts by the United States to identify strategies and policies, including an assessment of the strengths and weaknesses of such strategies and policies—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> to achieve peaceful denuclearization of the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> to eliminate the threat posed by the ballistic missile program of the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> an assessment of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> potential road maps toward peaceful denuclearization of the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea and the elimination of the nuclear and ballistic missile threats posed by the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> specific actions that the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea would need to take for each such roadmap to become viable;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> a summary of the United States strategy to increase international coordination and cooperation, whether unilaterally, bilaterally, or multilaterally, including sanctions enforcement and interdiction, to address the threat posed by the nuclear and ballistic missile programs of the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea, which shall include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> a description of the actions taken by the Secretary of State, or designees of the Secretary, to consult with governments around the world, with the purpose of inducing such governments to fully implement the United Nations Security Council resolutions referred to in subsection (a)(1);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> a description of the actions taken by such governments to fully implement United Nations Security Council resolutions related to the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> a list of countries with governments that the Secretary has determined are noncooperative with respect to implementing the United Nations Security Council resolutions referred to in subsection (a)(1); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> a plan of action to engage, and increase cooperation with respect to the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea, with the governments of the countries on the list described in clause (iii);</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> an assessment of the adequacy of the national export control regimes of countries that are members of the United Nations, and multilateral export control regimes, that are necessary to enforce sanctions imposed with respect to the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea pursuant to the United Nations Security Council resolutions referred to in subsection (a)(1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> an action plan to encourage and assist countries in adopting and using authorities necessary to enforce export controls required by United Nations Security Council resolutions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Form of report</inline>.—</heading><content>Each report required under this subsection shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sense of Congress</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> representatives of the United States shall use the voice and vote of the United States in all international organizations, as appropriate, to advocate for the expulsion of the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea from such organizations, until such time as the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea meets its commitments under the United Nations Security Council resolutions referred to in subsection (a)(1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Secretary of State should work to induce countries to meet their commitments under the United Nations Security Council resolutions referred to in subsection (a)(1), including by considering appropriate adjustments to the diplomatic posture and foreign assistance of the United States with governments that the Secretary has determined are noncooperative with respect to implementing the United Nations Security Council resolutions referred to in subsection (a)(1).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Nothing in <ref href="/us/pl/115/409/s210">section 210 of Pub. L. 115–409</ref>, set out above, to be construed as authorizing the use of military force, see <ref href="/us/pl/115/409/s412">section 412 of Pub. L. 115–409</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s2656">section 2656 of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
