<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9123ff19-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9269c"><num value="9269c">§ 9269c.</num><heading> Procedures for review of classified and certain other information</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9123ff1a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9269c/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If a finding under this subtitle <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002434">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002434"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> or an amendment made by this subtitle, a prohibition, condition, or penalty imposed as a result of any such finding, or a penalty imposed under this subtitle <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002434">1</ref> or an amendment made by this subtitle, is based on classified information (as defined in section 1(a) of the Classified Information Procedures Act (18 U.S.C. App.)), law enforcement information, or any other information protected from disclosure by statute, and a court reviews the finding or the imposition of the prohibition, condition, or penalty, the Secretary of the Treasury may submit such information to the court ex parte and in camera.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9123ff1b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9269c/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to confer or imply any right to judicial review of any finding under this subtitle <sup>1</sup> or an amendment made by this subtitle, any prohibition, condition, or penalty imposed as a result of any such finding, or any penalty imposed under this subtitle <sup>1</sup> or an amendment made by this subtitle.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9123ff1c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dF/tLXXI/s7144">Pub. L. 116–92, div. F, title LXXI, § 7144</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2256">133 Stat. 2256</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9123ff1d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9123ff1e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id9123ff1f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subtitle, referred to in text, is subtitle A of title LXXI of div. F of <ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2244">133 Stat. 2244</ref>, which enacted this subchapter and sections 262p–13, 286yy, 9221b, and 9221c of this title, amended sections 9202, 9212, 9214, 9223, 9224, 9228, 9241, and 9251 of this title, repealed sections 262p–13 and 286yy of this title, and enacted provisions set out as notes under sections 262p–13 and 286yy of this title. For complete classification of this subtitle to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Classified Information Procedures Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/96/456">Pub. L. 96–456</ref>, <date date="1980-10-15">Oct. 15, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2025">94 Stat. 2025</ref>, which is set out in the Appendix to Title 18, Crimes and Criminal Procedure.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="id9123ff20-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Otto Warmbier North Korea Nuclear Sanctions and Enforcement Act of 2019, and also as part of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020, and not as part of the North Korea Sanctions and Policy Enhancement Act of 2016 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
