<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9128b919-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9404"><num value="9404">§ 9404.</num><heading> Imposition of terrorism-related sanctions with respect to the IRGC</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9128b91a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9404/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Findings</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Congress makes the following findings:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9128b91b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9404/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The IRGC is subject to sanctions pursuant to Executive Order No. 13382 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note; relating to blocking property of weapons of mass destruction delivery system proliferators and their supporters), the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 (<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s8501">22 U.S.C. 8501</ref> et seq.), Executive Order No. 13553 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note; relating to blocking property of certain persons with respect to serious human rights abuses by the Government of Iran), and Executive Order No. 13606 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note; relating to blocking the property and suspending entry into the United States of certain persons with respect to grave human rights abuses by the Governments of Iran and Syria via information technology).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9128b91c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9404/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Iranian Revolutionary Guard Corps–Quds Force (in this section referred to as the “IRGC–QF”) is the primary arm of the Government of Iran for executing its policy of supporting terrorist and insurgent groups. The IRGC–QF provides material, logistical assistance, training, and financial support to militants and terrorist operatives throughout the Middle East and South Asia and was designated for the imposition of sanctions by the Secretary of the Treasury pursuant to Executive Order No. 13224 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note; relating to blocking property and prohibiting transactions with persons who commit, threaten to commit, or support terrorism) in October 2007 for its support of terrorism.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9128b91d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9404/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The IRGC, not just the IRGC–QF, is responsible for implementing Iran’s international program of destabilizing activities, support for acts of international terrorism, and ballistic missile program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9128b91e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9404/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Beginning on the date that is 90 days after <date date="2017-08-02">August 2, 2017</date>, the President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (c) with respect to the IRGC and foreign persons that are officials, agents, or affiliates of the IRGC.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9128b91f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9404/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Sanctions described</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The sanctions described in this subsection are sanctions applicable with respect to a foreign person pursuant to Executive Order No. 13224 (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note; relating to blocking property and prohibiting transactions with persons who commit, threaten to commit, or support terrorism).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9128b920-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/115/44/tI/s105">Pub. L. 115–44, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="2017-08-02">Aug. 2, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/892">131 Stat. 892</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9128b921-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9128b922-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id9128b923-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order No. 13382, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is Ex. Ord. No. 13382, <date date="2005-06-28">June 28, 2005</date>, 70 F.R. 38567, which is listed in a table under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">section 1701 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is <ref href="/us/pl/111/195">Pub. L. 111–195</ref>, <date date="2010-07-01">July 1, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1312">124 Stat. 1312</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 92 (§ 8501 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s8501">section 8501 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order No. 13553, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is Ex. Ord. No. 13553, <date date="2010-09-28">Sept. 28, 2010</date>, 75 F.R. 60567, which is listed in a table under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">section 1701 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order No. 13606, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is Ex. Ord. No. 13606, <date date="2012-04-22">Apr. 22, 2012</date>, 77 F.R. 24571, which is listed in a table under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">section 1701 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order No. 13224, referred to in subsecs. (a)(2) and (c), is Ex. Ord. No. 13224, <date date="2001-09-23">Sept. 23, 2001</date>, 66 F.R. 49079, which is listed in a table under <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">section 1701 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id9128b924-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="id9128b925-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For delegation of functions of President under subsec. (b) of this section to the Secretary of State and the Secretary of the Treasury, see section 1(e)(i) of Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2017-10-11">Oct. 11, 2017</date>, 82 F.R. 50051, set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9403">section 9403 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
