<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9128b9b3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9422"><num value="9422">§ 9422.</num><heading> Statement of policy</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the policy of the United States—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9128b9b4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9422/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to urgently seek the extension of missile-related restrictions set forth in Annex B to United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9128b9b5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9422/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to use all available authorities to constrain Iran’s domestic ballistic missile production capabilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9128b9b6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9422/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to combat and deter the transfer of conventional and non-conventional arms, equipment, material, and technology to, or from Iran, or involving the Government of Iran; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9128b9b7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9422/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to ensure countries, individuals, and entities engaged in, or attempting to engage in, the acquisition, facilitation, or development of arms and related components and technology subject to restrictions under Annex B to United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 are held to account under United States and international law, including through the application and enforcement of sanctions and use of export controls, regardless of whether the restrictions under Annex B to United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 remain in effect following their anticipated expiration in October 2023.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="id9128b9b8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/118/50/dK/s3">Pub. L. 118–50, div. K, § 3</ref>, <date date="2024-04-24">Apr. 24, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/970">138 Stat. 970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
