<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id912fe4e3-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9526"><num value="9526">§ 9526.</num><heading> Sanctions with respect to the development of pipelines in the Russian Federation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id912fe4e4-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9526/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President, in coordination with allies of the United States, may impose five or more of the sanctions described in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9529">section 9529 of this title</ref> with respect to a person if the President determines that the person knowingly, on or after <date date="2017-08-02">August 2, 2017</date>, makes an investment described in subsection (b) or sells, leases, or provides to the Russian Federation, for the construction of Russian energy export pipelines, goods, services, technology, information, or support described in subsection (c)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id912fe4e5-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9526/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> any of which has a fair market value of $1,000,000 or more; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id912fe4e6-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9526/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> that, during a 12-month period, have an aggregate fair market value of $5,000,000 or more.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id912fe4e7-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9526/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Investment described</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An investment described in this subsection is an investment that directly and significantly contributes to the enhancement of the ability of the Russian Federation to construct energy export pipelines.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id912fe4e8-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9526/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Goods, services, technology, information, or support described</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Goods, services, technology, information, or support described in this subsection are goods, services, technology, information, or support that could directly and significantly facilitate the maintenance or expansion of the construction, modernization, or repair of energy export pipelines by the Russian Federation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id912fe4e9-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/115/44/tII/s232">Pub. L. 115–44, title II, § 232</ref>, <date date="2017-08-02">Aug. 2, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/917">131 Stat. 917</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id912fe4ea-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="id912fe4eb-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="id912fe4ec-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Protecting Europe’s Energy Security</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/92/dF/tLXXV">Pub. L. 116–92, div. F, title LXXV</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/2300">133 Stat. 2300</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXII/s1242/a">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1242(a)</ref>–(e), <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3945-3947">134 Stat. 3945–3947</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXII/s1242/a">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="7501">“SEC. 7501.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This title may be cited as the ‘Protecting Europe’s Energy Security Act of 2019’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="7502">“SEC. 7502.</num><heading> SENSE OF CONGRESS.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the United States and Europe share a common history, a common identity, and common values built upon the principles of democracy, rule of law, and individual freedoms;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the United States has encouraged and admired the European project, which has resulted in a common market and common policies, has achieved unprecedented prosperity and stability on the continent, and serves as a model for other countries to reform their institutions and prioritize anticorruption measures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the relationships between the United States and Europe and the United States and Germany are critical to the national security interests of the United States as well as to global prosperity and peace, and Germany in particular is a crucial partner for the United States in multilateral efforts aimed at promoting global prosperity and peace;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the United States should stand against any effort designed to weaken those relationships; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> Germany has demonstrated leadership within the European Union and in international fora to ensure that sanctions imposed with respect to the Russian Federation for its malign activities are maintained.</content>
</paragraph>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="7503">“SEC. 7503.</num><heading> IMPOSITION OF SANCTIONS WITH RESPECT TO PROVISION OF CERTAIN VESSELS FOR THE CONSTRUCTION OF CERTAIN RUSSIAN ENERGY EXPORT PIPELINES.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report Required.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>], and every 90 days thereafter, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that identifies, for the period specified in paragraph (2)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> vessels that engaged in pipe-laying or pipe-laying activities at depths of 100 feet or more below sea level for the construction of the Nord Stream 2 pipeline project, the TurkStream pipeline project, or any project that is a successor to either such project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> foreign persons that the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, determines have knowingly—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> sold, leased, or provided, or facilitated selling, leasing, or providing, those vessels for the construction of such a project;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> facilitated deceptive or structured transactions to provide those vessels for the construction of such a project;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> provided for those vessels underwriting services or insurance or reinsurance necessary or essential for the completion of such a project;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> provided services or facilities for technology upgrades or installation of welding equipment for, or retrofitting or tethering of, those vessels if the services or facilities are necessary or essential for the completion of such a project; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="v">“(v)</num><content> provided services for the testing, inspection, or certification necessary or essential for the completion or operation of the Nord Stream 2 pipeline; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the consultations carried out pursuant to subsection (i) and describes the nature of the consultations and any concerns raised by the government of Norway, Switzerland, the United Kingdom, or any member country of the European Union.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Period specified</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The period specified in this paragraph is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> in the case of the first report required to be submitted by paragraph (1), the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and ending on the date on which the report is submitted; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> in the case of any subsequent such report, the 90-day period preceding submission of the report.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Ineligibility for Visas, Admission, or Parole of Identified Persons and Corporate Officers.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Visas, admission, or parole</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An alien described in paragraph (2) is—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> inadmissible to the United States;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</ref> et seq.).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Current visas revoked.—</inline></heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The visa or other entry documentation of an alien described in paragraph (2) shall be revoked, regardless of when such visa or other entry documentation is or was issued.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Immediate effect</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A revocation under clause (i) shall—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="I">     “(I)</num><content> take effect immediately; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I36" class="indent4 firstIndent-4"><num value="II">     “(II)</num><content> automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Aliens described</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>An alien is described in this paragraph if the alien is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a foreign person identified under subsection (a)(1)(B);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a corporate officer of a person described in subparagraph (A); or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> a principal shareholder with a controlling interest in a person described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Blocking of Property of Identified Persons</inline>.—</heading><content>The President shall exercise all powers granted to the President by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> et seq.) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of any person identified under subsection (a)(1)(B) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Wind-down Period</inline>.—</heading><content>The President may not impose sanctions under this section with respect to a person identified in the first report submitted under subsection (a) if the President certifies in that report that the person has, not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, engaged in good faith efforts to wind down operations that would otherwise subject the person to the imposition of sanctions under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception for intelligence, law enforcement, and national security activities</inline>.—</heading><content>Sanctions under this section shall not apply to any authorized intelligence, law enforcement, or national security activities of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception to comply with united nations headquarters agreement</inline>.—</heading><content>Sanctions under this section shall not apply with respect to the admission of an alien to the United States if the admission of the alien is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success <date date="1947-06-26">June 26, 1947</date>, and entered into force <date date="1947-11-21">November 21, 1947</date>, between the United Nations and the United States, the Convention on Consular Relations, done at Vienna <date date="1963-04-24">April 24, 1963</date>, and entered into force <date date="1967-03-19">March 19, 1967</date>, or other applicable international obligations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception for safety of vessels and crew</inline>.—</heading><content>Sanctions under this section shall not apply with respect to a person providing provisions to a vessel identified under subsection (a)(1)(A) if such provisions are intended for the safety and care of the crew aboard the vessel, the protection of human life aboard the vessel, or the maintenance of the vessel to avoid any environmental or other significant damage.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception for repair or maintenance of pipelines</inline>.—</heading><content>Sanctions under this section shall not apply with respect to a person for engaging in activities necessary for or related to the repair or maintenance of, or environmental remediation with respect to, a pipeline project described in subsection (a)(1)(A).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception relating to importation of goods.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the authorities and requirements to impose sanctions authorized under this section shall not include the authority or a requirement to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Good defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this paragraph, the term ‘good’ means any article, natural or man-made substance, material, supply or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment, and excluding technical data.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception for certain governments and governmental entities</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Sanctions under this section shall not apply with respect to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the European Union;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the government of Norway, Switzerland, the United Kingdom, or any member country of the European Union; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> any entity of the European Union or a government described in subparagraph (B) that is not operating as a business enterprise.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">National Interest Waiver</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The President may waive the application of sanctions under this section with respect to a person if the President—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> determines that the waiver is in the national interests of the United States; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> submits to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the waiver and the reasons for the waiver.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation; Penalties.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Implementation</inline>.—</heading><content>The President may exercise all authorities provided to the President under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1702">50 U.S.C. 1702</ref> and 1704) to carry out this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Penalties</inline>.—</heading><content>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of this section or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out this section shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</ref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination and Sunset</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The authority to impose sanctions under this section with respect to a person involved in the construction of a pipeline project described in subsection (a)(1)(A), and any sanctions imposed under this section with respect to that project, shall terminate on the date that is the earlier of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> the date on which the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that appropriate safeguards have been put in place—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> to minimize the ability of the Government of the Russian Federation to use that project as a tool of coercion and political leverage, including by achieving the unbundling of energy production and transmission so that entities owned or controlled by that Government do not control the transmission network for the pipeline; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> to ensure, barring unforeseen circumstances, that the project would not result in a decrease of more than 25 percent in the volume of Russian energy exports transiting through existing pipelines in other countries, particularly Ukraine, relative to the average monthly volume of Russian energy exports transiting through such pipelines in 2018; or</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultations</inline>.—</heading><content>Before imposing sanctions under this section, the Secretary of State shall consult with the relevant governments of Norway, Switzerland, the United Kingdom, and member countries of the European Union with respect to the imposition of such sanctions.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="j">“(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report on Impact of Sanctions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 [<date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>], and annually thereafter until all sanctions imposed under this section have terminated under subsection (h), the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report detailing the impact of the imposition of sanctions under this section that includes information on—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> whether the goals of the sanctions have been met;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the diplomatic impact of the sanctions, including on relationships with the governments of Norway, Switzerland, the United Kingdom, and member countries of the European Union; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the economic impact of the sanctions, including the impact on United States persons.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="k">“(k)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Admission; admitted; alien</inline>.—</heading><content>The terms ‘admission’, ‘admitted’, and ‘alien’ have the meanings given those terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriate congressional committees</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘appropriate congressional committees’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Foreign person</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘foreign person’ means an individual or entity that is not a United States person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Knowingly</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘knowingly’, with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person has actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pipe-laying activities</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘pipe-laying activities’ means activities that facilitate pipe-laying, including site preparation, trenching, surveying, placing rocks, backfilling, stringing, bending, welding, coating, and lowering of pipe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">United states person</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘United States person’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> any person within the United States.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>[<ref href="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXII/s1242/f">Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1242(f)</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3947">134 Stat. 3947</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/283/dA/tXII/s1242/f">“The President may not impose sanctions with respect to a person identified in the first report submitted under section 7503(a) of the Protecting Europe’s Energy Security Act of 2019 [set out above], as amended by this section, after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>] for operations subject to sanctions by reason of the amendments made by this section [amending <ref href="/us/pl/116/92/s7503">section 7503 of Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, set out above] if the President certifies in that report that the person has, not later than 30 days after such date of enactment, engaged in good faith efforts to wind down such operations.”</quotedContent>
]</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[Functions and authorities of President under sections 7503(d), (f), and (h) of <ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Pub. L. 116–92</ref>, set out above, delegated to Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, and under sections 7503(c) and (g) of <ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Pub. L. 116–92</ref> to Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, by section 1(a)(i)–(iii) and (b)(i), (ii) of Memorandum of President of the United States, <date date="2020-02-21">Feb. 21, 2020</date>, 85 F.R. 13717, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s286yy">section 286yy of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="id912fe4ed-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="id912fe4ee-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 14039. Blocking Property With Respect to Certain Russian Energy Export Pipelines</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 14039, <date date="2021-08-20">Aug. 20, 2021</date>, 86 F.R. 47205, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> <i>et seq</i>.) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1601">50 U.S.C. 1601</ref> <i>et seq</i>.) (NEA), the Protecting Europe’s Energy Security Act of 2019 (Title LXXV, National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020, <ref href="/us/pl/116/92">Public Law 116–92</ref>) [set out above], as amended by section 1242 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</ref>) (PEESA), and <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref>, United States Code,</p>
<p>I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, in order to take additional steps with respect to the national emergency declared in Executive Order 14024 of <date date="2021-04-15">April 15, 2021</date> (Blocking Property With Respect To Specified Harmful Foreign Activities of the Government of the Russian Federation) [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</ref> note], hereby order:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. (a) With respect to any foreign person identified by the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, in a report to the Congress pursuant to section 7503(a)(1)(B) of PEESA, all property and interests in property of such person that are in the United States, that hereafter come within the United States, or that are or hereafter come within the possession or control of any United States person are blocked and may not be transferred, paid, exported, withdrawn, or otherwise dealt in.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Sanctions under subsection (a) of this section shall not apply to any foreign person with respect to whom a waiver under section 7503(f) of PEESA has been issued.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The prohibitions in subsection (a) of this section apply except to the extent provided by statutes, or in regulations, orders, directives, or licenses that may be issued pursuant to this order, and notwithstanding any contract entered into or any license or permit granted prior to the date of this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 2. The Secretary of State shall implement section 7503(b) of PEESA as it applies to visas, and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall implement section 7503(b) of PEESA as it applies to admission and parole. Such implementation shall be consistent with any exceptions or waivers provided by statute, or in regulations, orders, or directives that may be issued pursuant to this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 3. The prohibitions in section 1 of this order include:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) the making of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services by, to, or for the benefit of any person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this order; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) the receipt of any contribution or provision of funds, goods, or services from any such person.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 4. (a) Any transaction that evades or avoids, has the purpose of evading or avoiding, causes a violation of, or attempts to violate any of the prohibitions set forth in this order is prohibited.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) Any conspiracy formed to violate any of the prohibitions set forth in this order is prohibited.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 5. I hereby determine that the making of donations of the types of articles specified in section 203(b)(2) of IEEPA (<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s1702/b/2">50 U.S.C. 1702(b)(2)</ref>) by, to, or for the benefit of any person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this order would seriously impair my ability to deal with the national emergency declared in Executive Order 14024, and I hereby prohibit such donations as provided by section 1 of this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 6. For the purposes of this order:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(a) the term “entity” means a partnership, association, trust, joint venture, corporation, group, subgroup, or other organization;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) the term “foreign person” means an individual or entity that is not a United States person;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) the term “person” means an individual or entity; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) the term “United States person” means any United States citizen, lawful permanent resident, entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States (including foreign branches), or any person in the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 7. For those persons whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this order who might have a constitutional presence in the United States, I find that because of the ability to transfer funds or other assets instantaneously, prior notice to such persons of measures to be taken pursuant to this order would render those measures ineffectual. I therefore determine that for these measures to be effective in addressing the national emergency declared in Executive Order 14024, there need be no prior notice of a listing or determination made pursuant to section 1 of this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 8. The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, is hereby authorized to take such actions, including the promulgation of rules and regulations, and to employ all powers granted to the President by IEEPA and PEESA, as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this order. The Secretary of the Treasury may, consistent with applicable law, redelegate any of these functions within the Department of the Treasury. All departments and agencies of the United States shall take all appropriate measures within their authority to carry out the provisions of this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 9. Nothing in this order shall prohibit transactions for the conduct of the official business of the Federal Government or the United Nations, including its programs, funds, and other entities and bodies, as well as its specialized agencies and related organizations, by employees, grantees, and contractors thereof.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 10. (a) Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>
<signature>
<name>J.R. Biden, Jr.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
