<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id91456911-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9632"><num value="9632">§ 9632.</num><heading> Corporate powers</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id91456912-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9632/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Corporation—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91456913-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9632/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> may adopt, alter, and use a seal, to include an identifiable symbol of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91456914-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9632/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> may make and perform such contracts, including no-cost contracts (as defined by the Corporation), grants, and other agreements notwithstanding division C of subtitle I of title 41, with any person or government however designated and wherever situated, as may be necessary for carrying out the functions of the Corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91456915-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9632/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> may lease, purchase, or otherwise acquire, improve, and use such real property wherever situated, as may be necessary for carrying out the functions of the Corporation, except that, if the real property is for the Corporation’s own occupancy, the lease, purchase, acquisition, improvement, or use of the real property shall be entered into or conducted in consultation with the Administrator of General Services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91456916-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9632/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> may accept cash gifts or donations of services or of property (real, personal, or mixed), tangible or intangible, for the purpose of carrying out the functions of the Corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91456917-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9632/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> may use the United States mails in the same manner and on the same conditions as the Executive departments (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s101">section 101 of title 5</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91456918-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9632/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> may contract with individuals for personal services, who shall not be considered Federal employees for any provision of law administered by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id91456919-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9632/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> may hire or obtain passenger motor vehicles;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9145691a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9632/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> may sue and be sued in its corporate name;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9145691b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9632/a/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> may acquire, hold, or dispose of, upon such terms and conditions as the Corporation may determine, any property, real, personal, or mixed, tangible or intangible, or any interest in such property, except that, in the case of real property that is for the Corporation’s own occupancy, the acquisition, holding, or disposition of the real property shall be conducted in consultation with the Administrator of General Services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9145691c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9632/a/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> may lease office space for the Corporation’s own use, with the obligation of amounts for such lease limited to the current fiscal year for which payments are due;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9145691d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9632/a/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> may indemnify directors, officers, employees, and agents of the Corporation for liabilities and expenses incurred in connection with their activities on behalf of the Corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9145691e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9632/a/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> notwithstanding any other provision of law, may represent itself or contract for representation in any legal or arbitral proceeding;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9147b20f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9632/a/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> may exercise any priority of the Government of the United States in collecting debts from bankrupt, insolvent, or decedents’ estates;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9147b210-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9632/a/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> may collect, notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3711/g/1">section 3711(g)(1) of title 31</ref>, or compromise any obligations assigned to or held by the Corporation, including any legal or equitable rights accruing to the Corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9147b211-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9632/a/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content> may make arrangements with foreign governments (including agencies, instrumentalities, or political subdivisions of such governments) or with multilateral organizations or institutions for sharing liabilities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9147b212-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9632/a/16"><num value="16">(16)</num><content> may sell direct investments of the Corporation to private investors upon such terms and conditions as the Corporation may determine; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9147b213-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9632/a/17"><num value="17">(17)</num><content> shall have such other powers as may be necessary and incident to carrying out the functions of the Corporation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9147b214-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9632/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of property</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law relating to the acquisition, handling, or disposal of property by the United States, the Corporation shall have the right in its discretion to complete, recondition, reconstruct, renovate, repair, maintain, operate, or sell any property acquired by the Corporation pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, except that, in the case of real property that is for the Corporation’s own occupancy, the completion, reconditioning, reconstruction, renovation, repair, maintenance, operation, or sale of the real property shall be conducted in consultation with the Administrator of General Services.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9147b215-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/115/254/dF/tIII/s1432">Pub. L. 115–254, div. F, title III, § 1432</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3500">132 Stat. 3500</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dH/tLXXXVII/s8752">Pub. L. 119–60, div. H, title LXXXVII, § 8752</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1964">139 Stat. 1964</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9147b216-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9147b217-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id9147b218-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (b), was in the original “this division”, meaning division F of <ref href="/us/pl/115/254">Pub. L. 115–254</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3485">132 Stat. 3485</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of division F to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9601">section 9601 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9147b219-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (a)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60">Pub. L. 119–60</ref> struck out “until the expiration of the current lease under predecessor authority, as of the day before <date date="2018-10-05">October 5, 2018</date>” after “payments are due”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
