<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id9147b280-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653"><num value="9653">§ 9653.</num><heading> Annual report</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9147b281-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After the end of each fiscal year, the Corporation shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a complete and detailed report of its operations during that fiscal year, including an assessment of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9147b282-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the economic and social development impact, including with respect to matters described in subsections (d), (e), and (f) of <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9651">section 9651 of this title</ref>, of projects supported by the Corporation under subchapter II of this chapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9147b283-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the extent to which the operations of the Corporation complement or are compatible with the development assistance programs of the United States and qualifying sovereign entities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9147b284-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the Corporation’s institutional linkages with other relevant United States Government department <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002459">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002459"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “departments”.</note> and agencies, including efforts to strengthen such linkages;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9147b285-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the compliance of projects supported by the Corporation under subchapter II of this chapter with human rights, environmental, labor, and social policies, or other such related policies that govern the Corporation’s support for projects, promulgated or otherwise administered by the Corporation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9147b286-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the United States strategic, foreign policy, and development objectives advanced through projects supported by the Corporation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9147b287-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> the health of the Corporation’s portfolio, including an annual overview of funds committed, funds disbursed, default and recovery rates, capital mobilized, equity investments’ year on year returns, and any difference between how investments were modeled at commitment and how they ultimately performed, to include a narrative explanation explaining any changes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id9147b288-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Elements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each annual report required by subsection (a) shall include analyses of the effects of projects supported by the Corporation under subchapter II of this chapter, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9147b289-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> reviews and analyses of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9147b28a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the desired development impact and strategic outcomes for projects, and whether or not the Corporation is meeting the associated metrics, goals, and development objectives, including, to the extent practicable, in the years after conclusion of projects;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9147b28b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> whether the Corporation’s support for projects that focus on achieving strategic outcomes are achieving such strategic objectives of such investments over the duration of the support and lasting after the Corporation’s support is completed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9147b28c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the value of private sector assets brought to bear relative to the amount of support provided by the Corporation and the value of any other public sector support;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9147b28d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the total private capital projected to be mobilized by projects supported by the Corporation during that year, including an analysis of the lenders and investors involved and investment instruments used;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9147b28e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><chapeau> the total private capital actually mobilized by projects supported by the Corporation that were fully funded by the end of that year, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9147b28f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/b/1/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> an analysis of the lenders and investors involved and investment instruments used; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9147b290-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/b/1/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a comparison with the private capital projected to be mobilized for the projects described in this paragraph;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9147b291-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/b/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><chapeau> a breakdown of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9147b292-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/b/1/F/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the amount and percentage of Corporation support provided to less developed countries, advancing income countries, and high-income countries in the previous fiscal year; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="id9147b293-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/b/1/F/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the amount and percentage of Corporation support provided to less developed countries, advancing income countries and high-income countries averaged over the last 5 fiscal years;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9147b294-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/b/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> a breakdown of the aggregate amounts and percentage of the maximum contingent liability of the Corporation authorized to be outstanding pursuant to section 1433 in less developed countries, advancing income countries, and high-income countries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9147b295-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/b/1/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> the risk appetite of the Corporation to undertake projects in less developed countries and in sectors that are critical to development but less likely to deliver substantial financial returns; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9147b296-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/b/1/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> efforts by the Chief Executive Officer to incentivize calculated risk-taking by transaction teams, including through the conduct of development performance reviews and provision of development performance rewards;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9147b297-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> an explanation of any partnership arrangement or cooperation with a qualifying sovereign entity in support of each project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9147b298-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> projections of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9147b299-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> development outcomes, and whether or not support for projects are meeting the associated performance measures, both during the start-up phase and over the duration of the support, and to the extent practicable, measures of such development outcomes should be on a gender-disaggregated basis, such as changes in employment, access to financial services, enterprise development and growth, and composition of executive boards and senior leadership of enterprises receiving support under subchapter II of this chapter; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id9147b29a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the value of private sector assets brought to bear relative to the amount of support provided by the Corporation and the value of any other public sector support;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9147b29b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to the extent practicable, recommendations for measures that could enhance the strategic goals of projects to adapt to changing circumstances; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id9147b29c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9653/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> an assessment of the extent to which lessons learned from the monitoring and evaluation activities of the Corporation, and from annual reports from previous years compiled by the Corporation, have been applied to projects.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id9147b29d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/115/254/dF/tIV/s1443">Pub. L. 115–254, div. F, title IV, § 1443</ref>, <date date="2018-10-05">Oct. 5, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3505">132 Stat. 3505</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dH/tLXXXVII/s8755">Pub. L. 119–60, div. H, title LXXXVII, § 8755</ref>, <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1966">139 Stat. 1966</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id9147b29e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id9147b29f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="id9147b2a0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (a)(5), (6). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s8755/1">Pub. L. 119–60, § 8755(1)</ref>, added pars. (5) and (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A) to (I). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s8755/2/A">Pub. L. 119–60, § 8755(2)(A)</ref>, added pars. (A) to (I) and struck out former pars. (A) and (B) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(A) the desired development outcomes for projects and whether or not the Corporation is meeting the associated metrics, goals, and development objectives, including, to the extent practicable, in the years after conclusion of projects; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) the effect of the Corporation’s support on access to capital and ways in which the Corporation is addressing identifiable market gaps or inefficiencies and what impact, if any, such support has on access to credit for a specific project, country, or sector;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/s8755/2/B">Pub. L. 119–60, § 8755(2)(B)</ref> to (D), added par. (4) and redesignated former par. (4) as (5).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
