<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id914ede3b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9809"><num value="9809">§ 9809.</num><heading> Improving and leveraging assistance for the global fragility strategy</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id914ede3c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9809/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that the President, the Secretary of State, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, the Secretary of Defense, and the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies should—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id914ede3d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9809/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> develop more adaptive and responsive policy and program planning, implementation, and scaling under the Global Fragility Strategy established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9803">section 9803 of this title</ref>, and work with the appropriate congressional committees to identify any legislative changes that may be necessary to support such efforts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id914ede3e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9809/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> better integrate the strategy and other conflict and violence reduction objectives and activities into other policy and program areas, where appropriate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id914ede3f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9809/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> support transparent and accountable multilateral funds, initiatives, and strategies to enhance and better coordinate private and public efforts to stabilize conflict-affected areas and prevent violence and fragility globally.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id914ede40-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9809/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Other funding and cost matching</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Global Fragility Strategy established pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9803">section 9803 of this title</ref>—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id914ede41-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9809/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> may, after consultation with the appropriate congressional committees, be supported with funds other than funds authorized to be appropriated pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9808">section 9808 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="id914ede42-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9809/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> shall seek to leverage funds from sources other than the United States Government in order to promote coordination and cost-matching to the maximum extent practicable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id914ede43-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9809/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Multi-donor Global Fragility Fund</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id914ede44-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9809/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Pursuant to sections 2357 and 2392 of this title, and consistent with subsection (b), and after consultation with the appropriate congressional committees, the Secretary of State is authorized to establish funding mechanisms, to include the establishment of a Global Fragility Fund, to leverage, receive, coordinate, and program funds provided by other donors and private sector partners to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id914ede45-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9809/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A funding mechanism established pursuant to paragraph (1) should—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id914ede46-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9809/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> include input from and participation by key bilateral and multilateral donors, representatives of civil society, relevant nongovernmental organizations and private sector entities, and developing countries where fragility threatens to exacerbate violent extremism and undermine development;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id914ede47-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9809/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> enhance donor coordination and cooperation;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id914ede48-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9809/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> advance clearly defined goals, objectives, and metrics for monitoring, evaluating, and measuring progress; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="id914ede49-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9809/c/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> focus on strengthening national and local good governance and conflict resolution capacity in fragile and conflict-affected areas over the long-term through comprehensive, compact-based agreements that support country-led strategies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id914ede4a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9809/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Congressional notification</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Funds may not be obligated under this section except in consultation with the appropriate congressional committees and subject to the notification of such committees of the amount and proposed uses of such funds at least 15 days in advance of such proposed obligation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id914ede4b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dJ/tV/s510">Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title V, § 510</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3067">133 Stat. 3067</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
