<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="id914ede98-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9905"><num value="9905">§ 9905.</num><heading> Private sector consultation and coordination</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id914ede99-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9905/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation with private sector by embassy</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In developing the priorities for trade expansion initiatives described in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9904/d">section 9904(d) of this title</ref>, embassy mission teams shall convene local representatives of the United States private sector and the private sector of host countries to consult on issues affecting trade at the borders of such countries and take into account the private sector’s operational expertise and experience confronting the trade barriers in such countries as well as its recommendations for reform and best practices.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id914ede9a-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9905/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Inclusion of private-sector comments in mission plans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Written comments from local United States private sector representatives shall be included in the trade expansion component of mission plans submitted by the chief of mission to the Secretary of State, with recommendations and comments from the mission team, for the purpose of informing the development of the joint strategic plan on trade expansion priorities required pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9904/c/4">section 9904(c)(4) of this title</ref> and recommended funding for the implementation of such plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id914ede9b-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9905/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Designated embassy point of contact for private sector consultation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each chief of mission shall designate an appropriate point of contact within the embassy who shall receive recommendations from appropriate private sector representatives regarding the implementation of the strategic plan required under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9904/c/4">section 9904(c)(4) of this title</ref> and ongoing trade barriers negatively impacting priority trade expansion. The chief of mission shall ensure that the designated point of contact shall be reasonably available for consultations with appropriate private sector representatives and to receive recommendations with respect to country-specific issues that may arise that will foreseeably disrupt trade.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="id914ede9c-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9905/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement to protect business confidential information</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id914ede9d-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9905/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary of State, Secretary of Commerce, and United States Trade Representative as well as the heads of all other agencies involved in the Economic Diplomacy Action Group established under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9904/c">section 9904(c) of this title</ref> shall protect from disclosure any proprietary information submitted by any private sector representative and marked as “business confidential information”, unless the party submitting the confidential business information had notice, at the time of submission, that such information would be released by the head of any such department or agency, or such party subsequently consents to the release of the information. To the extent business confidential information is provided, a non-confidential version of the information shall also be provided, in which the business confidential information is summarized or, if necessary, deleted.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="id914ede9e-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6" identifier="/us/usc/t22/s9905/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment as trade secrets</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Proprietary information submitted by a private party in accordance with this chapter shall be considered to be a matter falling within the meaning of trade secrets and commercial or financial information exemption under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552/b/4">section 552(b)(4) of title 5</ref> and shall be exempt from disclosure without the express approval of the private party.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="id914ede9f-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">(<ref href="/us/pl/116/94/dJ/tVII/s709">Pub. L. 116–94, div. J, title VII, § 709</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3074">133 Stat. 3074</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="id914edea0-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="id914edea1-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="id914edea2-2930-11f1-8918-be39dde81dc6">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (d)(2), was in the original “this Act” and was translated as reading “this title”, meaning title VII of div. J of <ref href="/us/pl/116/94">Pub. L. 116–94</ref>, <date date="2019-12-20">Dec. 20, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/3069">133 Stat. 3069</ref>, known as the Championing American Business Through Diplomacy Act of 2019, to reflect the probable intent of Congress, notwithstanding <ref href="/us/pl/116/94/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 116–94</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s1">section 1 of Title 1</ref>, General Provisions. Title VII is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of title VII to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s9901">section 9901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
