<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbf0e015d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10107"><num value="10107">§ 10107.</num><heading> Applicability to atomic energy defense activities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf0e015e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10107/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Atomic energy defense activities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to the provisions of subsection (c), the provisions of this chapter shall not apply with respect to any atomic energy defense activity or to any facility used in connection with any such activity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf0e015f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10107/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Evaluation by President</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf0e0160-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10107/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not later than 2 years after <date date="1983-01-07">January 7, 1983</date>, the President shall evaluate the use of disposal capacity at one or more repositories to be developed under part A of subchapter I for the disposal of high-level radioactive waste resulting from atomic energy defense activities. Such evaluation shall take into consideration factors relating to cost efficiency, health and safety, regulation, transportation, public acceptability, and national security.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf0e0161-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10107/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Unless the President finds, after conducting the evaluation required in paragraph (1), that the development of a repository for the disposal of high-level radioactive waste resulting from atomic energy defense activities only is required, taking into account all of the factors described in such subsection, the Secretary shall proceed promptly with arrangement for the use of one or more of the repositories to be developed under part A of subchapter I for the disposal of such waste. Such arrangements shall include the allocation of costs of developing, constructing, and operating this repository or repositories. The costs resulting from permanent disposal of high-level radioactive waste from atomic energy defense activities shall be paid by the Federal Government, into the special account established under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10222">section 10222 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf0e0162-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10107/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Any repository for the disposal of high-level radioactive waste resulting from atomic energy defense activities only shall (A) be subject to licensing under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5842">section 5842 of this title</ref>; and (B) comply with all requirements of the Commission for the siting, development, construction, and operation of a repository.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf0e0163-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10107/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability to certain repositories</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of this chapter shall apply with respect to any repository not used exclusively for the disposal of high-level radioactive waste or spent nuclear fuel resulting from atomic energy defense activities, research and development activities of the Secretary, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbf0e0164-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/425/s8">Pub. L. 97–425, § 8</ref>, <date date="1983-01-07">Jan. 7, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2205">96 Stat. 2205</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
