<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbf12bb57-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138"><num value="10138">§ 10138.</num><heading> Participation of Indian tribes</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf12bb58-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Participation of Indian tribes in repository siting decisions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon the submission by the President to the Congress of a recommendation of a site for a repository located on the reservation of an affected Indian tribe, the governing body of such Indian tribe may disapprove the site designation and submit to the Congress a notice of disapproval. The governing body of such Indian tribe may submit such a notice of disapproval to the Congress not later than the 60 days after the date that the President recommends such site to the Congress under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10134">section 10134 of this title</ref>. A notice of disapproval shall be considered to be submitted to the Congress on the date of the transmittal of such notice of disapproval to the Speaker of the House and the President pro tempore of the Senate. Such notice of disapproval shall be accompanied by a statement of reasons explaining why the governing body of such Indian tribe disapproved the recommended repository site involved.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf12bb59-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Financial assistance</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf12bb5a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall make grants to each affected tribe notified under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10136/a">section 10136(a) of this title</ref> for the purpose of participating in activities required by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10137">section 10137 of this title</ref> or authorized by written agreement entered into pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10137/c">section 10137(c) of this title</ref>. Any salary or travel expense that would ordinarily be incurred by such tribe, may not be considered eligible for funding under this paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf12bb5b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf12bb5c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall make grants to each affected Indian tribe where a candidate site for a repository is approved under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10132/c">section 10132(c) of this title</ref>. Such grants may be made to each such Indian tribe only for purposes of enabling such Indian tribe—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf12bb5d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to review activities taken under this part with respect to such site for purposes of determining any potential economic, social, public health and safety, and environmental impacts of such repository on the reservation and its residents;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf12bb5e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to develop a request for impact assistance under paragraph (2);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf12bb5f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> to engage in any monitoring, testing, or evaluation activities with respect to site characterization programs with regard to such site;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf12bb60-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b/2/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> to provide information to the residents of its reservation regarding any activities of such Indian tribe, the Secretary, or the Commission with respect to such site; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf12bb61-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b/2/A/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> to request information from, and make comments and recommendations to, the Secretary regarding any activities taken under this part with respect to such site.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf12bb62-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The amount of funds provided to any affected Indian tribe under this paragraph in any fiscal year may not exceed 100 percent of the costs incurred by such Indian tribe with respect to the activities described in clauses (i) through (v) of subparagraph (A). Any salary or travel expense that would ordinarily be incurred by such Indian tribe may not be considered eligible for funding under this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf12bb63-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf12bb64-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary shall provide financial and technical assistance to any affected Indian tribe requesting such assistance and where there is a site with respect to which the Commission has authorized construction of a repository. Such assistance shall be designed to mitigate the impact on such Indian tribe of the development of such repository. Such assistance to such Indian tribe shall commence within 6 months following the granting by the Commission of a construction authorization for such repository and following the initiation of construction activities at such site.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf12bb65-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Any affected Indian tribe desiring assistance under this paragraph shall prepare and submit to the Secretary a report on any economic, social, public health and safety, and environmental impacts that are likely as a result of the development of a repository at a site on the reservation of such Indian tribe. Such report shall be submitted to the Secretary following the completion of site characterization activities at such site and before the recommendation of such site to the President by the Secretary for application for a construction authorization for a repository. As soon as practicable following the granting of a construction authorization for such repository, the Secretary shall seek to enter into a binding agreement with the Indian tribe involved setting forth the amount of assistance to be provided to such Indian tribe under this paragraph and the procedures to be followed in providing such assistance.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf12bb66-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Secretary shall grant to each affected Indian tribe where a site for a repository is approved under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10132/c">section 10132(c) of this title</ref> an amount each fiscal year equal to the amount such Indian tribe would receive were it authorized to tax site characterization activities at such site, and the development and operation of such repository, as such Indian tribe taxes the other commercial activities occurring on such reservation. Such grants shall continue until such time as all such activities, development, and operation are terminated at such site.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf12bb67-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003934">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003934"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be designated “(5)(A)”.</note> An affected Indian tribe may not receive any grant under paragraph (1) after the expiration of the 1-year period following—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf12bb68-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b/5/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the date on which the Secretary notifies such Indian tribe of the termination of site characterization activities at the candidate site involved on the reservation of such Indian tribe;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf12bb69-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b/5/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the date on which such site is disapproved under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10135">section 10135 of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf12bb6a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b/5/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the date on which the Commission disapproves an application for a construction authorization for a repository at such site; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003935">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003935"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by “or”.</note></content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf12bb6b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b/5/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> <date date="1987-12-22">December 22, 1987</date>;</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">whichever occurs first, unless there is another candidate site on the reservation of such Indian tribe that is approved under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10132/c">section 10132(c) of this title</ref> and with respect to which the actions described in clauses (i), (ii), and (iii) have not been taken.</continuation>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf12bb6c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> An affected Indian tribe may not receive any further assistance under paragraph (2) with respect to a site if repository construction activities at such site are terminated by the Secretary or if such activities are permanently enjoined by any court.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf12bb6d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> At the end of the 2-year period beginning on the effective date of any license to receive and possess for a repository at a site on the reservation of an affected Indian tribe, no Federal funds shall be made available under paragraph (1) or (2) to such Indian tribe, except for—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf12bb6e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b/5/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> such funds as may be necessary to support activities of such Indian tribe related to any other repository where a license to receive and possess has not been in effect for more than 1 year; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf12bb6f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b/5/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> such funds as may be necessary to support activities of such Indian tribe pursuant to agreements or contracts for impact assistance entered into, under paragraph (2), by such Indian tribe with the Secretary during such 2-year period.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf12bb70-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10138/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Financial assistance authorized in this subsection shall be made out of amounts held in the Nuclear Waste Fund established in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10222">section 10222 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbf12bb71-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/425/tI/s118">Pub. L. 97–425, title I, § 118</ref>, <date date="1983-01-07">Jan. 7, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2225">96 Stat. 2225</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101/d/tIII/s300">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(d) [title III, § 300]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1329-104">101 Stat. 1329–104</ref>, 1329–121; <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tV/s5033">Pub. L. 100–203, title V, § 5033</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-243">101 Stat. 1330–243</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbf12bb72-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbf12bb73-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbf12bb74-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (b)(5)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/100/202">Pub. L. 100–202</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref> amended par. (5) identically, adding cl. (iv).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
