<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbf1776ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10171"><num value="10171">§ 10171.</num><heading> Financial arrangements for low-level radioactive waste site closure</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf1776bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10171/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Financial arrangements</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf1776bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10171/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Commission shall establish by rule, regulation, or order, after public notice, and in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2231">section 2231 of this title</ref>, such standards and instructions as the Commission may deem necessary or desirable to ensure in the case of each license for the disposal of low-level radioactive waste that an adequate bond, surety, or other financial arrangement (as determined by the Commission) will be provided by a licensee to permit completion of all requirements established by the Commission for the decontamination, decommissioning, site closure, and reclamation of sites, structures, and equipment used in conjunction with such low-level radioactive waste. Such financial arrangements shall be provided and approved by the Commission, or, in the case of sites within the boundaries of any agreement State under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2021">section 2021 of this title</ref>, by the appropriate State or State entity, prior to issuance of licenses for low-level radioactive waste disposal or, in the case of licenses in effect on <date date="1983-01-07">January 7, 1983</date>, prior to termination of such licenses.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf1776bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10171/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If the Commission determines that any long-term maintenance or monitoring, or both, will be necessary at a site described in paragraph (1), the Commission shall ensure before termination of the license involved that the licensee has made available such bonding, surety, or other financial arrangements as may be necessary to ensure that any necessary long-term maintenance or monitoring needed for such site will be carried out by the person having title and custody for such site following license termination.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf1776be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10171/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Title and custody</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf1776bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10171/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall have authority to assume title and custody of low-level radioactive waste and the land on which such waste is disposed of, upon request of the owner of such waste and land and following termination of the license issued by the Commission for such disposal, if the Commission determines that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf1776c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10171/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the requirements of the Commission for site closure, decommissioning, and decontamination have been met by the licensee involved and that such licensee is in compliance with the provisions of subsection (a);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf1776c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10171/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such title and custody will be transferred to the Secretary without cost to the Federal Government; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf1776c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10171/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Federal ownership and management of such site is necessary or desirable in order to protect the public health and safety, and the environment.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf1776c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10171/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If the Secretary assumes title and custody of any such waste and land under this subsection, the Secretary shall maintain such waste and land in a manner that will protect the public health and safety, and the environment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf1776c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10171/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Special sites</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the low-level radioactive waste involved is the result of a licensed activity to recover zirconium, hafnium, and rare earths from source material, the Secretary, upon request of the owner of the site involved, shall assume title and custody of such waste and the land on which it is disposed when such site has been decontaminated and stabilized in accordance with the requirements established by the Commission and when such owner has made adequate financial arrangements approved by the Commission for the long-term maintenance and monitoring of such site.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbf1776c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/425/tI/s151">Pub. L. 97–425, title I, § 151</ref>, <date date="1983-01-07">Jan. 7, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2244">96 Stat. 2244</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
