<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbf19e785-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197"><num value="10197">§ 10197.</num><heading> Research and development on disposal of high-level radioactive waste</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf19e786-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 64 months after <date date="1983-01-07">January 7, 1983</date>, the Secretary is authorized to, to the extent practicable, begin at a site evaluated under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10194">section 10194 of this title</ref>, as part of and as an extension of siting research activities of such site under such section, the mining and construction of a test and evaluation facility. Prior to the mining and construction of such facility, the Secretary shall prepare an environmental assessment. The purpose of such facility shall be—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e787-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to supplement and focus the repository site characterization process;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e788-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to provide the conditions under which known technological components can be integrated to demonstrate a functioning repository-like system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e789-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to provide a means of identifying, evaluating, and resolving potential repository licensing issues that could not be resolved during the siting research program conducted under section 10192 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003949">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003949"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “10194”.</note> of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e78a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to validate, under actual conditions, the scientific models used in the design of a repository;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e78b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> to refine the design and engineering of repository components and systems and to confirm the predicted behavior of such components and systems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e78c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> to supplement the siting data, the generic and specific geological characteristics developed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10194">section 10194 of this title</ref> relating to isolating disposal materials in the physical environment of a repository;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e78d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> to evaluate the design concepts for packaging, handling, and emplacement of high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel at the design rate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e78e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> to establish operating capability without exposing workers to excessive radiation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf19e78f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Design</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall design each test and evaluation facility—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e790-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to be capable of receiving not more than 100 full-sized canisters of solidified high-level radioactive waste (which canisters shall not exceed an aggregate weight of 100 metric tons), except that spent nuclear fuel may be used instead of such waste if such waste cannot be obtained under reasonable conditions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e791-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to permit full retrieval of solidified high-level radioactive waste, or other radioactive material used by the Secretary for testing, upon completion of the technology demonstration activities; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e792-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> based upon the principle that the high-level radioactive waste, spent nuclear fuel, or other radioactive material involved shall be isolated from the biosphere in such a way that the initial isolation is provided by engineered barriers functioning as a system with the geologic environment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf19e793-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Operation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf19e794-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Not later than 88 months after <date date="1983-01-07">January 7, 1983</date>, the Secretary shall begin an in situ testing program at the test and evaluation facility in accordance with the mission plan developed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10221">section 10221 of this title</ref>, for purposes of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e795-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> conducting in situ tests of bore hole sealing, geologic media fracture sealing, and room closure to establish the techniques and performance for isolation of high-level radioactive waste, spent nuclear fuel, or other radioactive materials from the biosphere;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e796-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> conducting in situ tests with radioactive sources and materials to evaluate and improve reliable models for radionuclide migration, absorption, and containment within the engineered barriers and geologic media involved, if the Secretary finds there is reasonable assurance that such radioactive sources and materials will not threaten the use of such site as a repository;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e797-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> conducting in situ tests to evaluate and improve models for ground water or brine flow through fractured geologic media;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e798-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/c/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> conducting in situ tests under conditions representing the real time and the accelerated time behavior of the engineered barriers within the geologic environment involved;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e799-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/c/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> conducting in situ tests to evaluate the effects of heat and pressure on the geologic media involved, on the hydrology of the surrounding area, and on the integrity of the disposal packages;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e79a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/c/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><chapeau> conducting in situ tests under both normal and abnormal repository conditions to establish safe design limits for disposal packages and to determine the effects of the gross release of radionuclides into surroundings, and the effects of various credible failure modes, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf19e79b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/c/1/F/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> seismic events leading to the coupling of aquifers through the test and evaluation facility;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf19e79c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/c/1/F/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> thermal pulses significantly greater than the maximum calculated; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf19e79d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/c/1/F/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> human intrusion creating a direct pathway to the biosphere; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e79e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/c/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> conducting such other research and development activities as the Secretary considers appropriate, including such activities necessary to obtain the use of high-level radioactive waste, spent nuclear fuel, or other radioactive materials (such as any highly radioactive material from the Three Mile Island nuclear powerplant or from the West Valley Demonstration Project) for test and evaluation purposes, if such other activities are reasonably necessary to support the repository program and if there is reasonable assurance that the radioactive sources involved will not threaten the use of such site as a repository.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf19e79f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The in situ testing authorized in this subsection shall be designed to ensure that the suitability of the site involved for licensing by the Commission as a repository will not be adversely affected.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf19e7a0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of existing Department facilities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">During the conducting of siting research activities under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10194">section 10194 of this title</ref> and for such period thereafter as the Secretary considers appropriate, the Secretary shall use Department facilities owned by the Federal Government on <date date="1983-01-07">January 7, 1983</date>, for the conducting of generically applicable tests regarding packaging, handling, and emplacement technology for solidified high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel from civilian nuclear activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf19e7a1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Engineered barriers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The system of engineered barriers and selected geology used in a test and evaluation facility shall have a design life at least as long as that which the Commission requires by regulations issued under this chapter, or under the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2011">42 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et seq.), for repositories.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf19e7a2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Role of Commission</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf19e7a3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf19e7a4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Not later than 1 year after <date date="1983-01-07">January 7, 1983</date>, the Secretary and the Commission shall reach a written understanding establishing the procedures for review, consultation, and coordination in the planning, construction, and operation of the test and evaluation facility under this section. Such understanding shall establish a schedule, consistent with the deadlines set forth in this subchapter,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003950">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003950"><num>2</num> See References in Text note below.</note> for submission by the Secretary of, and review by the Commission of and necessary action on—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e7a5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/f/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the mission plan prepared under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10221">section 10221 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e7a6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/f/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> such reports and other information as the Commission may reasonably require to evaluate any health and safety impacts of the test and evaluation facility.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf19e7a7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Such understanding shall also establish the conditions under which the Commission may have access to the test and evaluation facility for the purpose of assessing any public health and safety concerns that it may have. No shafts may be excavated for the test and evaluation until the Secretary and the Commission enter into such understanding.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf19e7a8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10225">section 10225 of this title</ref>, the test and evaluation facility, and the facilities authorized in this section, shall be constructed and operated as research, development, and demonstration facilities, and shall not be subject to licensing under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5842">section 5842 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf19e7a9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf19e7aa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/f/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Commission shall carry out a continuing analysis of the activities undertaken under this section to evaluate the adequacy of the consideration of public health and safety issues.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf19e7ab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/f/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Commission shall report to the President, the Secretary, and the Congress as the Commission considers appropriate with respect to the conduct of activities under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf19e7ac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Environmental review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall prepare an environmental impact statement under section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4332/2/C">42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)</ref>) prior to conducting tests with radioactive materials at the test and evaluation facility. Such environmental impact statement shall incorporate, to the extent practicable, the environmental assessment prepared under subsection (a). Nothing in this subsection may be construed to limit siting research activities conducted under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10194">section 10194 of this title</ref>. This subsection shall apply only to activities performed exclusively for a test and evaluation facility.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf19e7ad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf19e7ae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If the test and evaluation facility is not located at the site of a repository, the Secretary shall obtain the concurrence of the Commission with respect to the decontamination and decommissioning of such facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf19e7af-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If the test and evaluation facility is not located at a candidate site or repository site, the Secretary shall conduct only the portion of the in situ testing program required in subsection (c) determined by the Secretary to be useful in carrying out the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf19e7b0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The operation of the test and evaluation facility shall terminate not later than—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e7b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/h/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> 5 years after the date on which the initial repository begins operation; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e7b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/h/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> at such time as the Secretary determines that the continued operation of a test and evaluation facility is not necessary for research, development, and demonstration purposes;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">whichever occurs sooner.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf19e7b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10197/h/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provisions of this subsection, as soon as practicable following any determination by the Secretary, with the concurrence of the Commission, that the test and evaluation facility is unsuitable for continued operation, the Secretary shall take such actions as are necessary to remove from such site any radioactive material placed on such site as a result of testing and evaluation activities conducted under this section. Such requirement may be waived if the Secretary, with the concurrence of the Commission, finds that short-term testing and evaluation activities using radioactive material will not endanger the public health and safety.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbf19e7b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/425/tII/s217">Pub. L. 97–425, title II, § 217</ref>, <date date="1983-01-07">Jan. 7, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2249">96 Stat. 2249</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbf19e7b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbf19e7b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbf19e7b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Atomic Energy Act of 1954, referred to in subsec. (e), is <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-30/ch1073/s1">act Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/919">68 Stat. 919</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 23 (§ 2011 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2011">section 2011 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subchapter, referred to in subsec. (f)(1)(A), was in the original “this subtitle”, and was translated as this subchapter to reflect the probable intent of Congress because title II of <ref href="/us/pl/97/425">Pub. L. 97–425</ref>, which enacted this subchapter, does not contain subtitles.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
