<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbf177764-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10194"><num value="10194">§ 10194.</num><heading> Siting research and related activities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf177765-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10194/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 30 months after the date on which the Secretary completes the identification of sites under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10193">section 10193 of this title</ref>, the Secretary is authorized to complete sufficient evaluation of 3 sites to select a site for expanded siting research activities and for other activities under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10198">section 10198 of this title</ref>. The Secretary is authorized to conduct such preconstruction activities relative to such site selection for the test and evaluation facility as he deems appropriate. Additional sites for the location of the test and evaluation facility authorized in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10222/d">section 10222(d) of this title</ref> may be evaluated after such 30-month period, following the same procedures as if such sites were to be evaluated within such period.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf177766-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10194/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Public meetings and environmental assessment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 6 months after the date on which the Secretary completes the identification of sites under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10193">section 10193 of this title</ref>, and before beginning siting research activities, the Secretary shall hold at least 1 public meeting in the vicinity of each site to inform the residents of the area of the activities to be conducted at such site and to receive their views.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf177767-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10194/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Restrictions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10198">section 10198 of this title</ref> with respect to a test and evaluation facility, in conducting siting research activities pursuant to subsection (a)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf177768-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10194/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the Secretary shall use the minimum quantity of high-level radioactive waste or other radioactive materials, if any, necessary to achieve the test or research objectives;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf177769-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10194/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the Secretary shall ensure that any radioactive material used or placed on a site shall be fully retrievable; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf17776a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10194/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> upon termination of siting research activities at a site for any reason, the Secretary shall remove any radioactive material at or in the site as promptly as practicable.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf17776b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10194/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Title to material</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may take title, in the name of the Federal Government, to the high-level radioactive waste, spent nuclear fuel, or other radioactive material emplaced in a test and evaluation facility. If the Secretary takes title to any such material, the Secretary shall enter into the appropriate financial arrangements described in subsection (a) or (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10222">section 10222 of this title</ref> for the disposal of such material.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbf17776c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/425/tII/s214">Pub. L. 97–425, title II, § 214</ref>, <date date="1983-01-07">Jan. 7, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2247">96 Stat. 2247</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
