<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbf19e7b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10198"><num value="10198">§ 10198.</num><heading> Research and development on spent nuclear fuel</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf19e7b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10198/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Demonstration and cooperative programs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish a demonstration program, in cooperation with the private sector, for the dry storage of spent nuclear fuel at civilian nuclear power reactor sites, with the objective of establishing one or more technologies that the Commission may, by rule, approve for use at the sites of civilian nuclear power reactors without, to the maximum extent practicable, the need for additional site-specific approvals by the Commission. Not later than 1 year after <date date="1983-01-07">January 7, 1983</date>, the Secretary shall select at least 1, but not more than 3, sites evaluated under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10194">section 10194 of this title</ref> at such power reactors. In selecting such site or sites, the Secretary shall give preference to civilian nuclear power reactors that will soon have a shortage of interim storage capacity for spent nuclear fuel. Subject to reaching agreement as provided in subsection (b), the Secretary shall undertake activities to assist such power reactors with demonstration projects at such sites, which may use one of the following types of alternate storage technologies: spent nuclear fuel storage casks, caissons, or silos. The Secretary shall also undertake a cooperative program with civilian nuclear power reactors to encourage the development of the technology for spent nuclear fuel rod consolidation in existing power reactor water storage basins.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf19e7ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10198/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Cooperative agreements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To carry out the programs described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall enter into a cooperative agreement with each utility involved that specifies, at a minimum, that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e7bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10198/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> such utility shall select the alternate storage technique to be used, make the land and spent nuclear fuel available for the dry storage demonstration, submit and provide site-specific documentation for a license application to the Commission, obtain a license relating to the facility involved, construct such facility, operate such facility after licensing, pay the costs required to construct such facility, and pay all costs associated with the operation and maintenance of such facility;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e7bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10198/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the Secretary shall provide, on a cost-sharing basis, consultative and technical assistance, including design support and generic licensing documentation, to assist such utility in obtaining the construction authorization and appropriate license from the Commission; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e7bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10198/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the Secretary shall provide generic research and development of alternative spent nuclear fuel storage techniques to enhance utility-provided, at-reactor storage capabilities, if authorized in any other provision of this chapter or in any other provision of law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf19e7be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10198/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Dry storage research and development</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf19e7bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10198/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The consultative and technical assistance referred to in subsection (b)(2) may include, but shall not be limited to, the establishment of a research and development program for the dry storage of not more than 300 metric tons of spent nuclear fuel at facilities owned by the Federal Government on <date date="1983-01-07">January 7, 1983</date>. The purpose of such program shall be to collect necessary data to assist the utilities involved in the licensing process.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf19e7c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10198/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> To the extent available, and consistent with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10155">section 10155 of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall provide spent nuclear fuel for the research and development program authorized in this subsection from spent nuclear fuel received by the Secretary for storage under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10155">section 10155 of this title</ref>. Such spent nuclear fuel shall not be subject to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10155/e">section 10155(e) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf19e7c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10198/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Funding</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The total contribution from the Secretary from Federal funds and the use of Federal facilities or services shall not exceed 25 percent of the total costs of the demonstration program authorized in subsection (a), as estimated by the Secretary. All remaining costs of such program shall be paid by the utilities involved or shall be provided by the Secretary from the Interim Storage Fund established in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10156">section 10156 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf19e7c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10198/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Relation to spent nuclear fuel storage program</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The spent nuclear fuel storage program authorized in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10155">section 10155 of this title</ref> shall not be construed to authorize the use of research development or demonstration facilities owned by the Department unless—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e7c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10198/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a period of 30 calendar days (not including any day in which either House of Congress is not in session because of adjournment of more than 3 calendar days to a day certain) has passed after the Secretary has transmitted to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a written report containing a full and complete statement concerning (A) the facility involved; (B) any necessary modifications; (C) the cost thereof; and (D) the impact on the authorized research and development program; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf19e7c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10198/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> each such committee, before the expiration of such period, has transmitted to the Secretary a written notice to the effect that such committee has no objection to the proposed use of such facility.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbf19e7c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/425/tII/s218">Pub. L. 97–425, title II, § 218</ref>, <date date="1983-01-07">Jan. 7, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2252">96 Stat. 2252</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/437/s15/c/10">Pub. L. 103–437, § 15(c)(10)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4592">108 Stat. 4592</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbf19e7c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbf19e7c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbf19e7c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/437">Pub. L. 103–437</ref> substituted “Committee on Science, Space, and Technology” for “Committee on Science and Technology”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
