<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbf19e7d3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10203"><num value="10203">§ 10203.</num><heading> Technical assistance to non-nuclear weapon states in field of spent fuel storage and disposal</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf19e7d4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10203/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Statement of policy</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be the policy of the United States to cooperate with and provide technical assistance to non-nuclear weapon states in the field of spent fuel storage and disposal.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf19e7d5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10203/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Publication of joint notice; update</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf19e7d6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10203/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Within 90 days of <date date="1983-01-07">January 7, 1983</date>, the Secretary and the Commission shall publish a joint notice in the Federal Register stating that the United States is prepared to cooperate with and provide technical assistance to non-nuclear weapon states in the fields of at-reactor spent fuel storage; away-from-reactor spent fuel storage; monitored, retrievable spent fuel storage; geologic disposal of spent fuel; and the health, safety, and environmental regulation of such activities. The notice shall summarize the resources that can be made available for international cooperation and assistance in these fields through existing programs of the Department and the Commission, including the availability of: (i) data from past or ongoing research and development projects; (ii) consultations with expert Department or Commission personnel or contractors; and (iii) liaison with private business entities and organizations working in these fields.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf19e7d7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10203/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The joint notice described in the preceding subparagraph shall be updated and reissued annually for 5 succeeding years.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf19e7d8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10203/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification to non-nuclear weapon states; expressions of interest</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Following publication of the annual joint notice referred to in paragraph (2),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003951">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003951"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “paragraph (2) of subsection (b),”.</note> the Secretary of State shall inform the governments of non-nuclear weapon states and, as feasible, the organizations operating nuclear powerplants in such states, that the United States is prepared to cooperate with and provide technical assistance to non-nuclear weapon states in the fields of spent fuel storage and disposal, as set forth in the joint notice. The Secretary of State shall also solicit expressions of interest from non-nuclear weapon state governments and non-nuclear weapon state nuclear power reactor operators concerning their participation in expanded United States cooperation and technical assistance programs in these fields. The Secretary of State shall transmit any such expressions of interest to the Department and the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf19e7d9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10203/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Funding requests</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With his budget presentation materials for the Department and the Commission for fiscal years 1984 through 1989, the President shall include funding requests for an expanded program of cooperation and technical assistance with non-nuclear weapon states in the fields of spent fuel storage and disposal as appropriate in light of expressions of interest in such cooperation and assistance on the part of non-nuclear weapon state governments and non-nuclear weapon state nuclear power reactor operators.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf19e7da-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10203/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> “Non-nuclear weapon state” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this subsection,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003952">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003952"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “section”.</note> the term “non-nuclear weapon state” shall have the same meaning as that set forth in article IX of the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons (21 U.S.C.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003953">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003953"><num>3</num> So in original. Probably should be “UST”.</note> 438).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf19e7db-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10203/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Unauthorized actions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this subsection <sup>2</sup> shall authorize the Department or the Commission to take any action not authorized under existing law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbf19e7dc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/97/425/tII/s223">Pub. L. 97–425, title II, § 223</ref>, <date date="1983-01-07">Jan. 7, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2254">96 Stat. 2254</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbf19e7dd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbf19e7de-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbf19e7df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons, referred to in subsec. (e), is set out in 21 UST 483; TIAS 6839.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
