<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbf1ea23c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303"><num value="10303">§ 10303.</num><heading> Water resources research and technology institutes</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf1ea23d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment; designation of site by State legislature or Governor</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to the approval of the Secretary of the Interior (hereafter in this chapter referred to as the “Secretary”) under this section, one water resources research and technology institute, center, or equivalent agency (hereafter in this chapter referred to as the “institute”) may be established in each State (as used in this chapter, the term “State” includes the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the District of Columbia, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Mariana Islands and the Federated States of Micronesia) at a college or university which was established in accordance with the Act approved <date date="1862-07-02">July 2, 1862</date> (<ref href="/us/stat/12/503">12 Stat. 503</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s301">7 U.S.C. 301</ref> et seq.], or at some other institution designated by act of the legislature of the State concerned. If there is more than one such college or university in a State established in accordance with such Act of <date date="1862-07-02">July 2, 1862</date>, the institute in such State shall, in the absence of a designation to the contrary by act of the legislature of the State, be established at the one such college or university designated by the Governor of the State. Two or more States may cooperate in the establishment of a single institute or regional institute, in which event the sums otherwise allocated to institutes in each of the cooperating States shall be paid to such single or regional institute.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf1ea23e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Scope of research; other activities; cooperation and coordination</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each institute shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf1ea23f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> plan, conduct, or otherwise arrange for competent applied and peer reviewed research that fosters—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf1ea240-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> improvements in water supply reliability;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf1ea241-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> the exploration of new ideas that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbf1ea242-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/b/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> address water problems; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbf1ea243-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/b/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> expand understanding of water and water resources;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf1ea244-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the entry of new research scientists, engineers, and technicians into water resources fields; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf1ea245-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the dissemination of research results to water managers and the public; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf1ea246-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> cooperate closely with other colleges and universities in the State that have demonstrated capabilities for research, information dissemination, and graduate training in order to develop a statewide program designed to resolve State and regional water and related land problems.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Each institute shall also cooperate closely with other institutes and other organizations in the region to increase the effectiveness of the institutes and for the purpose of promoting regional coordination.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf1ea247-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Grants</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf1ea248-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">From the sums appropriated pursuant to subsection (f), the Secretary shall make grants to each institute to be matched on a basis of no less than 1 non-Federal dollar for every 1 Federal dollar.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf1ea249-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than December 31 of each fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate, the Committee on the Budget of the Senate, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives a report regarding the compliance of each funding recipient with this subsection for the immediately preceding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf1ea24a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission and approval of water research program; requisite assurances</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Prior to and as a condition of the receipt each fiscal year of funds appropriated under subsection (f) of this section, each institute shall submit to the Secretary for his approval a water research program that includes assurances, satisfactory to the Secretary, that such program was developed in close consultation and collaboration with the director of that State’s department of water resources or similar agency, other leading water resources officials within the State, and interested members of the public. The program described in the preceding sentence shall include plans to promote research, training, information dissemination, and other activities meeting the needs of the State and Nation, and shall encourage regional cooperation among institutes in research into areas of water management, development, and conservation that have a regional or national character.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf1ea24b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Evaluation of water resources research program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf1ea24c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall conduct a careful and detailed evaluation of each institute at least once every 5 years to determine—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf21134d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the quality and relevance of the water resources research of the institute;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf21134e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the effectiveness of the institute at producing measured results and applied water supply research; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf21134f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> whether the effectiveness of the institute as an institution for planning, conducting, and arranging for research warrants continued support under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf211350-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition on further support</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If, as a result of an evaluation under paragraph (1), the Secretary determines that an institute does not qualify for further support under this section, no further grants to the institute may be provided until the qualifications of the institute are reestablished to the satisfaction of the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf211351-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations in general</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf211352-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, to remain available until expended, $12,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2025.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf211353-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Any sums appropriated under this subsection but which fail to be obligated by the close of the fiscal year for which they were appropriated shall be transferred by the Secretary and available for obligation during the succeeding fiscal year under the terms of subsection (g) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf211354-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional appropriations where research focused on water problems of interstate nature</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf211355-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> There is further authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of the Interior the sum of $3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2025 only for reimbursement of the direct cost expenses of additional research or synthesis of the results of research by institutes which focuses on water problems and issues of a regional or interstate nature beyond those of concern only to a single State and which relate to specific program priorities identified jointly by the Secretary and the institutes. Such funds when appropriated shall be matched on a not less than dollar-for-dollar basis by funds made available to institutes or groups of institutes, by States or other non-Federal sources. Funds made available under this subsection shall remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf211356-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Research funds made available under this subsection shall be made on a competitive basis subject to the merit of the proposal, the need for the information to be produced, and the opportunity such funds will provide for training of water resources scientists or professionals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf211357-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf211358-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">To carry out this chapter, the Secretary—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf211359-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall encourage other Federal departments, agencies (including agencies within the Department of the Interior), and instrumentalities to use and take advantage of the expertise and capabilities that are available through the institutes established by this section, on a cooperative or other basis;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf21135a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> shall encourage cooperation and coordination with other Federal programs concerned with water resources problems and issues;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf21135b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/h/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> may enter into contracts, cooperative agreements, and other transactions without regard to <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf21135c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/h/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> may accept funds from other Federal departments, agencies (including agencies within the Department of the Interior), and instrumentalities to pay for and add to grants made, and contracts entered into, by the Secretary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf21135d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/h/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> may promulgate such regulations as the Secretary considers appropriate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf21135e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/h/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> may support a program of internships for qualified individuals at the undergraduate and graduate levels to carry out the educational and training objectives of this chapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf21135f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall report to Congress annually on coordination efforts with other Federal departments, agencies, and instrumentalities under paragraph (1). As part of the annual budget submission to Congress, the Secretary shall also provide a crosscut budget detailing the expenditures on activities listed under subsection (a)(1) and a report which details the level of applied research and the results of the activities authorized by this chapter, including potential and actual—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf211360-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> increases in annual water supplies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf211361-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> increases in annual water yields;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf211362-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/h/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> advances in water infrastructure and water quality improvements; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf211363-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/h/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> methods for identifying, and determining the effectiveness of, treatment technologies and efficiencies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf211364-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10303/h/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Relationship to State rights</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this chapter shall preempt the rights and authorities of any State with respect to its water resources or management of those resources.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbf211365-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/242/tI/s104">Pub. L. 98–242, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1984-03-22">Mar. 22, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/98">98 Stat. 98</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/397/s1/b">Pub. L. 101–397, § 1(b)</ref>–(h), (m), <date date="1990-09-28">Sept. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/852">104 Stat. 852</ref>, 853; <ref href="/us/pl/104/147">Pub. L. 104–147</ref>, §§ 3–6, <date date="1996-05-24">May 24, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1376">110 Stat. 1376</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/374">Pub. L. 106–374</ref>, <date date="2000-10-27">Oct. 27, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1434">114 Stat. 1434</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/471/s2/a">Pub. L. 109–471, § 2(a)</ref>–(e), <date date="2007-01-11">Jan. 11, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3552">120 Stat. 3552</ref>, 3553; <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/dE/tII/s50221">Pub. L. 117–58, div. E, title II, § 50221</ref>, <date date="2021-11-15">Nov. 15, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1180">135 Stat. 1180</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbf211366-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbf211367-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbf211368-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (h), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/98/242">Pub. L. 98–242</ref>, <date date="1984-03-22">Mar. 22, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/97">98 Stat. 97</ref>, known as the Water Resources Research Act of 1984, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10301">section 10301 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act approved <date date="1862-07-02">July 2, 1862</date>, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1862-07-02/ch130">act July 2, 1862, ch. 130</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/12/503">12 Stat. 503</ref>, popularly known as the “Morrill Act” and also as the “First Morrill Act”, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 301 et seq.) of chapter 13 of Title 7, Agriculture. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s301">section 301 of Title 7</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbf211369-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (h)(1)(C), “<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>” substituted for “section 3709 of the Revised Statutes (<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s5">41 U.S.C. 5</ref>)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s6/c">Pub. L. 111–350, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3854">124 Stat. 3854</ref>, which Act enacted Title 41, Public Contracts.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbf21136a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (b)(1)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s50221/a/1">Pub. L. 117–58, § 50221(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “water resources” for “water-related phenomena”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s50221/a/2">Pub. L. 117–58, § 50221(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “; and” for period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s50221/b">Pub. L. 117–58, § 50221(b)</ref>, added subsec. (c) and struck out former subsec. (c). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “From the sums appropriated pursuant to subsection (f) of this section, the Secretary shall make grants to each institute to be matched on a basis of no less than 2 non-Federal dollars for every 1 Federal dollar, such sums to be used only for the reimbursement of the direct cost expenditures incurred for the conduct of the water resources research program.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s50221/c">Pub. L. 117–58, § 50221(c)</ref>, added subsec. (e) and struck out former subsec. (e). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Secretary shall conduct a careful and detailed evaluation of each institute at least once every 3 years to determine that the quality and relevance of its water resources research and its effectiveness at producing measured results and applied water supply research as an institution for planning, conducting, and arranging for research warrants its continued support under this section. If, as a result of any such evaluation, the Secretary determines that an institute does not qualify for further support under this section, then no further grants to the institute may be made until the institute’s qualifications are reestablished to the satisfaction of the Secretary.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s50221/d">Pub. L. 117–58, § 50221(d)</ref>, substituted “fiscal years 2022 through 2025” for “fiscal years 2007 through 2011”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/58/s50221/e">Pub. L. 117–58, § 50221(e)</ref>, substituted “$3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2025” for “$6,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2007 through 2011”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/471/s2/a">Pub. L. 109–471, § 2(a)</ref>, amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “plan, conduct, or otherwise arrange for competent research that fosters (A) the entry of new research scientists into the water resources fields, (B) the training and education of future water scientists, engineers, and technicians, (C) the preliminary exploration of new ideas that address water problems or expand understanding of water and water-related phenomena, and (D) the dissemination of research results to water managers and the public, and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/109/471/s2/b">Pub. L. 109–471, § 2(b)</ref>, substituted “3” for “5” and inserted “at producing measured results and applied water supply research” after “effectiveness”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/471/s2/c">Pub. L. 109–471, § 2(c)</ref>, amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “For the purpose of carrying out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary the sum of $9,000,000 for fiscal year 2001, $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2002 and 2003, and $12,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2004 and 2005, such sums to remain available until expended.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/109/471/s2/d">Pub. L. 109–471, § 2(d)</ref>, substituted “$6,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2007 through 2011” for “$3,000,000 for fiscal year 2001, $4,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2002 and 2003, and $6,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2004 and 2005”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/109/471/s2/e">Pub. L. 109–471, § 2(e)</ref>, substituted “Reports” for “Report” in heading and inserted after first sentence “As part of the annual budget submission to Congress, the Secretary shall also provide a crosscut budget detailing the expenditures on activities listed under subsection (a)(1) and a report which details the level of applied research and the results of the activities authorized by this chapter, including potential and actual—” and subpars. (A) to (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/106/374/s1">Pub. L. 106–374, § 1</ref>, substituted “$9,000,000 for fiscal year 2001, $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2002 and 2003, and $12,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2004 and 2005” for “$5,000,000 for fiscal year 1996, $7,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1997 and 1998, and $9,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1999 and 2000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/106/374/s2">Pub. L. 106–374, § 2</ref>, in first sentence, substituted “$3,000,000 for fiscal year 2001, $4,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2002 and 2003, and $6,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2004 and 2005” for “$3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1996 through 2000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/104/147/s3">Pub. L. 104–147, § 3</ref>, substituted “2 non-Federal dollars for every 1 Federal dollar” for “one non-Federal dollar for every Federal dollar during the fiscal years ending <date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>, and <date date="1986-09-30">September 30, 1986</date>, one and one-half non-Federal dollars for each Federal dollar during the fiscal years ending <date date="1987-09-30">September 30, 1987</date>, and <date date="1988-09-30">September 30, 1988</date>, and two non-Federal dollars for each Federal dollar during the fiscal year ending <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date> and thereafter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/147/s4">Pub. L. 104–147, § 4</ref>, substituted “of $5,000,000 for fiscal year 1996, $7,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1997 and 1998, and $9,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1999 and 2000” for “of $10,000,000 for each of the fiscal years ending <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>, through <date date="1995-09-30">September 30, 1995</date>,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/147/s5">Pub. L. 104–147, § 5</ref>, substituted “of $3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1996 through 2000” for “of $5,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1991, 1992, 1993, 1994, and 1995”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/104/147/s6">Pub. L. 104–147, § 6</ref>, added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/397/s1/b">Pub. L. 101–397, § 1(b)</ref>, substituted “Federated States of Micronesia” for “Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/101/397/s1/c">Pub. L. 101–397, § 1(c)</ref>, inserted “promoting” after “for the purpose of” in last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/397/s1/d">Pub. L. 101–397, § 1(d)</ref>, amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “plan, conduct, or otherwise arrange for competent research with respect to water resources, including investigations and experiments of either a basic or practical nature, or both; promote the dissemination and application of the results of these efforts; and provide for the training of scientists and engineers through such research, investigations, and experiments, and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/101/397/s1/e">Pub. L. 101–397, § 1(e)</ref>, substituted for period at end “and thereafter, such sums to be used only for the reimbursement of the direct cost expenditures incurred for the conduct of the water resources research program.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/397/s1/f">Pub. L. 101–397, § 1(f)</ref>, amended subsec. (e) generally, substituting provisions directing that evaluation be conducted at least once every 5 years for provisions directing evaluation within two years after establishment of institute and at least once every four years thereafter and striking out provisions relating to composition and function of evaluation team and setting forth criteria for determination.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/397/s1/g">Pub. L. 101–397, § 1(g)</ref>, substituted “<date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>, through <date date="1995-09-30">September 30, 1995</date>,” for “<date date="1985-09-30">September 30, 1985</date>, through <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/397/s1/h">Pub. L. 101–397, § 1(h)</ref>, substituted reference to subsec. (g) of this section for reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10305">section 10305 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/101/397/s1/m">Pub. L. 101–397, § 1(m)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbf21136b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbf21136c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Contracts or Cooperative Agreements With National Laboratories</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/397/s2">Pub. L. 101–397, § 2</ref>, <date date="1990-09-28">Sept. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/854">104 Stat. 854</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/397/s2">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> The Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, is authorized to enter into contracts or cooperative agreements, as the Secretary deems appropriate, with national laboratories (including Los Alamos National Laboratory) to carry out water resources research, development, and demonstration projects within the authorities of <ref href="/us/pl/98/242">Public Law 98–242</ref> [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10301">42 U.S.C. 10301</ref> et seq.] (including the effects of potential climate changes on surface and ground water quality and quantity and the elimination of contamination of ground water aquifers).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The water resources research authorized in this section shall be undertaken under such rules and regulations as the Secretary deems appropriate and shall be carried out in close consultation and collaboration with the institutes established pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/98/242">Public Law 98–242</ref> [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10301">42 U.S.C. 10301</ref> et seq.], to the extent such research work affects the State in which the institute exists, and to the extent such institute agrees to consult and collaborate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><content> For the purposes of carrying out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of the Interior the sum of $10,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1991 through 1995.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
