<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbf211377-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10305"><num value="10305">§ 10305.</num><heading> Development of water-related technology</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf211378-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10305/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Grants; matching funds</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf211379-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10305/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall make grants in addition to those authorized under sections 10303 and 10304 of this title for technology development concerning any aspect of water resources including water-related technology which the Secretary may deem to be of State, regional, or national importance. Activities funded under this section may be carried out by educational institutions, private firms, foundations, individuals, or agencies of State or local government. Care shall be taken to protect proprietary information of private individuals or firms associated with the technology.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf21137a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10305/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary may establish any condition for the matching of funds by the recipient of any grant or contract under this section which the Secretary considers to be in the best interest of the Nation considering the information transfer and technology needs of the Nation. However, in the case of institutes established by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10303">section 10303 of this title</ref> no match greater than that required under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10303">section 10303 of this title</ref> may be required.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf21137b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10305/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Applications for grants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each application for a grant under this section shall state the nature of the project to be undertaken, the qualifications of the personnel who will direct and conduct it, facilities of the organization performing any technology development, the importance of the project to the Nation, region, and State concerned, and the potential benefit to be accrued.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf21137c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10305/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary the sum of $6,000,000 for the purpose of carrying out this section for each of the fiscal years ending <date date="1990-09-30">September 30, 1990</date>, through <date date="1995-09-30">September 30, 1995</date>; such sums to remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbf21137d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/242/tI/s106">Pub. L. 98–242, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1984-03-22">Mar. 22, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/100">98 Stat. 100</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/397/s1/n">Pub. L. 101–397, § 1(n)</ref>, <date date="1990-09-28">Sept. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/853">104 Stat. 853</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbf21137e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbf21137f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbf211380-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—<ref href="/us/pl/101/397">Pub. L. 101–397</ref>, in amending section generally, in subsec. (a)(1) struck out provision directing that grant be made on basis of merit and feasibility of project, in subsec. (a)(2) inserted provisions relating to match in the case of institutes established by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10303">section 10303 of this title</ref>, and in subsec. (c) substituted provisions authorizing $6,000,000 appropriation for fiscal years 1990 through 1995, for provisions authorizing the same sum for fiscal years 1985 through 1989, and struck out provisions authorizing obligation of funds under this section and par. (1) and (2) designations.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
