<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbf2f4443-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10706"><num value="10706">§ 10706.</num><heading> Limitations on grants and contracts</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf2f4444-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10706/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties of Institute</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With respect to grants made and contracts or cooperative agreements entered into under this chapter, the Institute shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf2f4445-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10706/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> ensure that no funds made available to recipients by the Institute shall be used at any time, directly or indirectly, to influence the issuance, amendment, or revocation of any Executive order or similar promulgation by any Federal, State, or local agency, or to undertake to influence the passage or defeat of any legislation or constitutional amendment by the Congress of the United States, or by any State or local legislative body, or any State proposal by initiative petition, or of any referendum, unless a governmental agency, legislative body, a committee, or a member thereof—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf2f4446-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10706/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> requests personnel of the recipients to testify, draft, or review measures or to make representations to such agency, body, committee, or member; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf2f4447-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10706/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is considering a measure directly affecting the activities under this chapter of the recipient or the Institute; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf2f4448-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10706/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> ensure all personnel engaged in grant, cooperative agreement or contract assistance activities supported in whole or part by the Institute refrain, while so engaged, from any partisan political activity.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf2f4449-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10706/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of funds for training programs for advocacy of nonjudicial public policies or encouraging nonjudicial political activities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No funds made available by the Institute under this chapter, either by grant, cooperative agreement, or contract, may be used to support or conduct training programs for the purpose of advocating particular nonjudicial public policies or encouraging nonjudicial political activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf2f444a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10706/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority coextensive with appropriation Acts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The authorization to enter into cooperative agreements, contracts or any other obligation under this chapter shall be effective only to the extent, and in such amounts, as are provided in advance in appropriation Acts.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf2f444b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10706/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibited uses of funds</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To ensure that funds made available under this chapter are used to supplement and improve the operation of State courts, rather than to support basic court services, funds shall not be used—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf2f444c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10706/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to supplant State or local funds currently supporting a program or activity; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf2f444d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s10706/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to construct court facilities or structures, except to remodel existing facilities to demonstrate new architectural or technological techniques, or to provide temporary facilities for new personnel or for personnel involved in a demonstration or experimental program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbf2f444e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/98/620/tII/s207">Pub. L. 98–620, title II, § 207</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3342">98 Stat. 3342</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/702/tVI/s605">Pub. L. 100–702, title VI, § 605</ref>, <date date="1988-11-19">Nov. 19, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4653">102 Stat. 4653</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbf2f444f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbf2f4450-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbf2f4451-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this title”, except in subsec. (d) where it was in the original “this Act”, meaning title II of <ref href="/us/pl/98/620">Pub. L. 98–620</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3336">98 Stat. 3336</ref>, known as the State Justice Institute Act of 1984, which enacted this chapter and amended <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s620">section 620 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure. For complete classification of title II to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s17101">section 17101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbf2f4452-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/702">Pub. L. 100–702</ref> struck out par. (3) which read as follows: “ensure that each recipient that files with the Institute a timely application for refunding is provided interim funding necessary to maintain its current level of activities until—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) the application for refunding has been approved and funds pursuant thereto received; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) the application for refunding has been finally denied in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10708">section 10708 of this title</ref>.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbf2f4453-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idbf2f4454-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1985-10-01">Oct. 1, 1985</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/620/s216">section 216 of Pub. L. 98–620</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10701">section 10701 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
