<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbf3426a9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022"><num value="11022">§ 11022.</num><heading> Emergency and hazardous chemical inven­tory forms</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf3426aa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Basic requirement</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf3426ab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The owner or operator of any facility which is required to prepare or have available a material safety data sheet for a hazardous chemical under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s651">29 U.S.C. 651</ref> et seq.] and regulations promulgated under that Act shall prepare and submit an emergency and hazardous chemical inventory form (hereafter in this chapter referred to as an “inventory form”) to each of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf3426ac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The appropriate local emergency planning committee.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf3426ad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The State emergency response commission.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf3426ae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The fire department with jurisdiction over the facility.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf3426af-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The inventory form containing tier I information (as described in subsection (d)(1)) shall be submitted on or before <date date="1988-03-01">March 1, 1988</date>, and annually thereafter on March 1, and shall contain data with respect to the preceding calendar year. The preceding sentence does not apply if an owner or operator provides, by the same deadline and with respect to the same calendar year, tier II information (as described in subsection (d)(2)) to the recipients described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbf3426b0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> An owner or operator may meet the requirements of this section with respect to a hazardous chemical which is a mixture by doing one of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf3426b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Providing information on the inventory form on each element or compound in the mixture which is a hazardous chemical. If more than one mixture has the same element or compound, only one listing on the inventory form for the element or compound at the facility is necessary.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf3426b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Providing information on the inventory form on the mixture itself.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf3426b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Thresholds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator may establish threshold quantities for hazardous chemicals covered by this section below which no facility shall be subject to the provisions of this section. The threshold quantities may, in the Administrator’s discretion, be based on classes of chemicals or categories of facilities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf3426b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Hazardous chemicals covered</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A hazardous chemical subject to the requirements of this section is any hazardous chemical for which a material safety data sheet or a listing is required under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s11021">section 11021 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf3426b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents of form</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf3426b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Tier I information</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbf3426b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/d/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Aggregate information by category</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">An inventory form shall provide the information described in subparagraph (B) in aggregate terms for hazardous chemicals in categories of health and physical hazards as set forth under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s651">29 U.S.C. 651</ref> et seq.] and regulations promulgated under that Act.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbf3426b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/d/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Required information</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The information referred to in subparagraph (A) is the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbf3426b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/d/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> An estimate (in ranges) of the maximum amount of hazardous chemicals in each category present at the facility at any time during the preceding calendar year.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbf3426ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/d/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> An estimate (in ranges) of the average daily amount of hazardous chemicals in each category present at the facility during the preceding calendar year.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbf3426bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/d/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> The general location of hazardous chemicals in each category.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbf3426bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/d/1/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Modifications</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of reporting information under this paragraph, the Administrator may—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbf3426bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/d/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> modify the categories of health and physical hazards as set forth under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s651">29 U.S.C. 651</ref> et seq.] and regulations promulgated under that Act by requiring information to be reported in terms of groups of hazardous chemicals which present similar hazards in an emergency, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbf3426be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/d/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> require reporting on individual hazardous chemicals of special concern to emergency response personnel.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf3426bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Tier II information</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">An inventory form shall provide the following additional information for each hazardous chemical present at the facility, but only upon request and in accordance with subsection (e):</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf3426c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The chemical name or the common name of the chemical as provided on the material safety data sheet.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf3426c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> An estimate (in ranges) of the maximum amount of the hazardous chemical present at the facility at any time during the preceding calendar year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf3426c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> An estimate (in ranges) of the average daily amount of the hazardous chemical present at the facility during the preceding calendar year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf3426c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/d/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> A brief description of the manner of storage of the hazardous chemical.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf3426c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/d/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> The location at the facility of the hazardous chemical.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf3426c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/d/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> An indication of whether the owner elects to withhold location information of a specific hazardous chemical from disclosure to the public under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s11044">section 11044 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf3426c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability of tier II information</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf3426c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability to State commissions, local committees, and fire departments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon request by a State emergency response commission, a local emergency planning committee, or a fire department with jurisdiction over the facility, the owner or operator of a facility shall provide tier II information, as described in subsection (d), to the person making the request. Any such request shall be with respect to a specific facility.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf3426c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability to other State and local officials</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A State or local official acting in his or her official capacity may have access to tier II information by submitting a request to the State emergency response commission or the local emergency planning committee. Upon receipt of a request for tier II information, the State commission or local committee shall, pursuant to paragraph (1), request the facility owner or operator for the tier II information and make available such information to the official.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf3426c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability to public</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbf3426ca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/e/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any person may request a State emergency response commission or local emergency planning committee for tier II information relating to the preceding calendar year with respect to a facility. Any such request shall be in writing and shall be with respect to a specific facility.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbf3426cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/e/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Automatic provision of information to public</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any tier II information which a State emergency response commission or local emergency planning committee has in its possession shall be made available to a person making a request under this paragraph in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s11044">section 11044 of this title</ref>. If the State emergency response commission or local emergency planning committee does not have the tier II information in its possession, upon a request for tier II information the State emergency response commission or local emergency planning committee shall, pursuant to paragraph (1), request the facility owner or operator for tier II information with respect to a hazardous chemical which a facility has stored in an amount in excess of 10,000 pounds present at the facility at any time during the preceding calendar year and make such information available in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s11044">section 11044 of this title</ref> to the person making the request.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbf3426cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/e/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Discretionary provision of information to public</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of tier II information which is not in the possession of a State emergency response commission or local emergency planning committee and which is with respect to a hazardous chemical which a facility has stored in an amount less than 10,000 pounds present at the facility at any time during the preceding calendar year, a request from a person must include the general need for the information. The State emergency response commission or local emergency planning committee may, pursuant to paragraph (1), request the facility owner or operator for the tier II information on behalf of the person making the request. Upon receipt of any information requested on behalf of such person, the State emergency response commission or local emergency planning committee shall make the information available in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s11044">section 11044 of this title</ref> to the person.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbf3670bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/e/3/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Response in 45 days</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A State emergency response commission or local emergency planning committee shall respond to a request for tier II information under this paragraph no later than 45 days after the date of receipt of the request.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf3670be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/e/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability to community water systems</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbf3670bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/e/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">An affected community water system may have access to tier II information by submitting a request to the State emergency response commission or the local emergency planning committee. Upon receipt of a request for tier II information, the State commission or local committee shall, pursuant to paragraph (1), request the facility owner or operator for the tier II information and make available such information to the affected community water system.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbf3670c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/e/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In this paragraph, the term “affected community water system” means a community water system (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300f/15">section 300f(15) of this title</ref>) that receives supplies of drinking water from a source water area, delineated under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300j–13">section 300j–13 of this title</ref>, in which a facility that is required to prepare and submit an inventory form under subsection (a)(1) is located.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf3670c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Fire department access</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon request to an owner or operator of a facility which files an inventory form under this section by the fire department with jurisdiction over the facility, the owner or operator of the facility shall allow the fire department to conduct an on-site inspection of the facility and shall provide to the fire department specific location information on hazardous chemicals at the facility.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf3670c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11022/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Format of forms</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Administrator shall publish a uniform format for inventory forms within three months after <date date="1986-10-17">October 17, 1986</date>. If the Administrator does not publish such forms, owners and operators of facilities subject to the requirements of this section shall provide the information required under this section by letter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbf3670c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/499/tIII/s312">Pub. L. 99–499, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1738">100 Stat. 1738</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/270/tII/s2018/b">Pub. L. 115–270, title II, § 2018(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-23">Oct. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3858">132 Stat. 3858</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbf3670c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbf3670c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbf3670c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1) and (d)(1)(A), (C)(i), is <ref href="/us/pl/91/596">Pub. L. 91–596</ref>, <date date="1970-12-29">Dec. 29, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1590">84 Stat. 1590</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 15 (§ 651 et seq.) of Title 29, Labor. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s651">section 651 of Title 29</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbf3670c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/115/270/s2018/b/1">Pub. L. 115–270, § 2018(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “State emergency response commission” for “State emergency planning commission”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/115/270/s2018/b/2">Pub. L. 115–270, § 2018(b)(2)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
