<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbf36715d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11043"><num value="11043">§ 11043.</num><heading> Provision of information to health professionals, doctors, and nurses</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf36715e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11043/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Diagnosis or treatment by health professional</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An owner or operator of a facility which is subject to the requirements of section 11021, 11022, or 11023 of this title shall provide the specific chemical identity, if known, of a hazardous chemical, extremely hazardous substance, or a toxic chemical to any health professional who requests such information in writing if the health professional provides a written statement of need under this subsection and a written confidentiality agreement under subsection (d). The written statement of need shall be a statement that the health professional has a reasonable basis to suspect that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf36715f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11043/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the information is needed for purposes of diagnosis or treatment of an individual,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf367160-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11043/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the individual or individuals being diagnosed or treated have been exposed to the chemical concerned, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf367161-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11043/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> knowledge of the specific chemical identity of such chemical will assist in diagnosis or treatment.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Following such a written request, the owner or operator to whom such request is made shall promptly provide the requested information to the health professional. The authority to withhold the specific chemical identity of a chemical under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s11042">section 11042 of this title</ref> when such information is a trade secret shall not apply to information required to be provided under this subsection, subject to the provisions of subsection (d).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf367162-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11043/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Medical emergency</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An owner or operator of a facility which is subject to the requirements of section 11021, 11022, or 11023 of this title shall provide a copy of a material safety data sheet, an inventory form, or a toxic chemical release form, including the specific chemical identity, if known, of a hazardous chemical, extremely hazardous substance, or a toxic chemical, to any treating physician or nurse who requests such information if such physician or nurse determines that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf367163-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11043/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a medical emergency exists,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf367164-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11043/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the specific chemical identity of the chemical concerned is necessary for or will assist in emergency or first-aid diagnosis or treatment, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf367165-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11043/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the individual or individuals being diagnosed or treated have been exposed to the chemical concerned.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Immediately following such a request, the owner or operator to whom such request is made shall provide the requested information to the physician or nurse. The authority to withhold the specific chemical identity of a chemical from a material safety data sheet, an inventory form, or a toxic chemical release form under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s11042">section 11042 of this title</ref> when such information is a trade secret shall not apply to information required to be provided to a treating physician or nurse under this subsection. No written confidentiality agreement or statement of need shall be required as a precondition of such disclosure, but the owner or operator disclosing such information may require a written confidentiality agreement in accordance with subsection (d) and a statement setting forth the items listed in paragraphs (1) through (3) as soon as circumstances permit.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf367166-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11043/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Preventive measures by local health professionals</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf367167-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11043/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Provision of information</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">An owner or operator of a facility subject to the requirements of section 11021, 11022, or 11023 of this title shall provide the specific chemical identity, if known, of a hazardous chemical, an extremely hazardous substance, or a toxic chemical to any health professional (such as a physician, toxicologist, or epidemiologist)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf367168-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11043/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> who is a local government employee or a person under contract with the local government, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf367169-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11043/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> who requests such information in writing and provides a written statement of need under paragraph (2) and a written confidentiality agreement under subsection (d).</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">Following such a written request, the owner or operator to whom such request is made shall promptly provide the requested information to the local health professional. The authority to withhold the specific chemical identity of a chemical under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s11042">section 11042 of this title</ref> when such information is a trade secret shall not apply to information required to be provided under this subsection, subject to the provisions of subsection (d).</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf36716a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11043/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Written statement of need</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The written statement of need shall be a statement that describes with reasonable detail one or more of the following health needs for the information:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf36716b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11043/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> To assess exposure of persons living in a local community to the hazards of the chemical concerned.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf36716c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11043/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> To conduct or assess sampling to determine exposure levels of various population groups.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf36716d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11043/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> To conduct periodic medical surveillance of exposed population groups.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf36716e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11043/c/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> To provide medical treatment to exposed individuals or population groups.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf36716f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11043/c/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> To conduct studies to determine the health effects of exposure.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf367170-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11043/c/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> To conduct studies to aid in the identification of a chemical that may reasonably be anticipated to cause an observed health effect.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf367171-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11043/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Confidentiality agreement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person obtaining information under subsection (a) or (c) shall, in accordance with such subsection (a) or (c), be required to agree in a written confidentiality agreement that he will not use the information for any purpose other than the health needs asserted in the statement of need, except as may otherwise be authorized by the terms of the agreement or by the person providing such information. Nothing in this subsection shall preclude the parties to a confidentiality agreement from pursuing any remedies to the extent permitted by law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf367172-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11043/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As soon as practicable after <date date="1986-10-17">October 17, 1986</date>, the Administrator shall promulgate regulations describing criteria and parameters for the statement of need under subsection <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003984">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003984"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “subsections”.</note> (a) and (c) and the confidentiality agreement under subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbf367173-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/99/499/tIII/s323">Pub. L. 99–499, title III, § 323</ref>, <date date="1986-10-17">Oct. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1750">100 Stat. 1750</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
