<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbf4256cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s11341"><num value="11341">§ 11341.</num><heading> Grants by Director</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 30 days following the date on which appropriations become available to carry out this part, the Director shall award a grant for the full amount that the Congress appropriates for the program under this part to the National Board for the purpose of providing emergency food and shelter to needy individuals through private nonprofit organizations and local governments in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s11343">section 11343 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbf4256ce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/100/77/tIII/s311">Pub. L. 100–77, title III, § 311</ref>, <date date="1987-07-22">July 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/492">101 Stat. 492</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbf4256cf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbf4256d0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbf4256d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of all functions, personnel, assets, components, authorities, grant programs, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Under Secretary for Federal Emergency Management relating thereto, to the Federal Emergency Management Agency, see <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s315/a/1">section 315(a)(1) of Title 6</ref>, Domestic Security.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see former section 313(1) and sections 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
