<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbf63c29c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12185"><num value="12185">§ 12185.</num><heading> Study</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf63c29d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12185/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Office of Technology Assessment shall undertake a study to determine—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf63c29e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12185/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the access needs of individuals with disabilities to over-the-road buses and over-the-road bus service; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf63c29f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12185/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the most cost-effective methods for providing access to over-the-road buses and over-the-road bus service to individuals with disabilities, particularly individuals who use wheelchairs, through all forms of boarding options.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf63c2a0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12185/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The study shall include, at a minimum, an analysis of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf63c2a1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12185/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The anticipated demand by individuals with disabilities for accessible over-the-road buses and over-the-road bus service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf6632a2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12185/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The degree to which such buses and service, including any service required under sections 12184(b)(4) and 12186(a)(2) of this title, are readily accessible to and usable by individuals with disabilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf6632a3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12185/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The effectiveness of various methods of providing accessibility to such buses and service to individuals with disabilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf6632a4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12185/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The cost of providing accessible over-the-road buses and bus service to individuals with disabilities, including consideration of recent technological and cost saving developments in equipment and devices.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf6632a5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12185/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Possible design changes in over-the-road buses that could enhance accessibility, including the installation of accessible restrooms which do not result in a loss of seating capacity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf6632a6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12185/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The impact of accessibility requirements on the continuation of over-the-road bus service, with particular consideration of the impact of such requirements on such service to rural communities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf6632a7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12185/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Advisory committee</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In conducting the study required by subsection (a), the Office of Technology Assessment shall establish an advisory committee, which shall consist of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf6632a8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12185/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> members selected from among private operators and manufacturers of over-the-road buses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf6632a9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12185/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> members selected from among individuals with disabilities, particularly individuals who use wheelchairs, who are potential riders of such buses; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf6632aa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12185/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> members selected for their technical expertise on issues included in the study, including manufacturers of boarding assistance equipment and devices.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The number of members selected under each of paragraphs (1) and (2) shall be equal, and the total number of members selected under paragraphs (1) and (2) shall exceed the number of members selected under paragraph (3).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf6632ab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12185/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Deadline</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The study required by subsection (a), along with recommendations by the Office of Technology Assessment, including any policy options for legislative action, shall be submitted to the President and Congress within 36 months after <date date="1990-07-26">July 26, 1990</date>. If the President determines that compliance with the regulations issued pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12186/a/2/B">section 12186(a)(2)(B) of this title</ref> on or before the applicable deadlines specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12186/a/2/B">section 12186(a)(2)(B) of this title</ref> will result in a significant reduction in intercity over-the-road bus service, the President shall extend each such deadline by 1 year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf6632ac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12185/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In developing the study required by subsection (a), the Office of Technology Assessment shall provide a preliminary draft of such study to the Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board established under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s792">section 792 of title 29</ref>. The Board shall have an opportunity to comment on such draft study, and any such comments by the Board made in writing within 120 days after the Board’s receipt of the draft study shall be incorporated as part of the final study required to be submitted under subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbf6632ad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/336/tIII/s305">Pub. L. 101–336, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1990-07-26">July 26, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/360">104 Stat. 360</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbf6632ae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbf6632af-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idbf6632b0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1990-07-26">July 26, 1990</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/336/s310/c">section 310(c) of Pub. L. 101–336</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12181">section 12181 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbf6632b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Advisory Committees</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Advisory committees established after <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on the date of their establishment, unless, in the case of a committee established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such committee is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a committee established by Congress, its duration is otherwise provided for by law. See <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1013">section 1013 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
