<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbf6632f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12201"><num value="12201">§ 12201.</num><heading> Construction</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf6632f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12201/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, nothing in this chapter shall be construed to apply a lesser standard than the standards applied under title V of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s790">29 U.S.C. 790</ref> et seq.) or the regulations issued by Federal agencies pursuant to such title.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf6632fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12201/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Relationship to other laws</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to invalidate or limit the remedies, rights, and procedures of any Federal law or law of any State or political subdivision of any State or jurisdiction that provides greater or equal protection for the rights of individuals with disabilities than are afforded by this chapter. Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to preclude the prohibition of, or the imposition of restrictions on, smoking in places of employment covered by subchapter I, in transportation covered by subchapter II or III, or in places of public accommodation covered by subchapter III.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf6632fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12201/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Insurance</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subchapters I through III of this chapter and title IV of this Act shall not be construed to prohibit or restrict—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf6632fc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12201/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an insurer, hospital or medical service company, health maintenance organization, or any agent, or entity that administers benefit plans, or similar organizations from underwriting risks, classifying risks, or administering such risks that are based on or not inconsistent with State law; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf6632fd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12201/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a person or organization covered by this chapter from establishing, sponsoring, observing or administering the terms of a bona fide benefit plan that are based on underwriting risks, classifying risks, or administering such risks that are based on or not inconsistent with State law; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf6632fe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12201/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a person or organization covered by this chapter from establishing, sponsoring, observing or administering the terms of a bona fide benefit plan that is not subject to State laws that regulate insurance.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) shall not be used as a subterfuge to evade the purposes of subchapter <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004035">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn004035"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “subchapters”.</note> I and III.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf6632ff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12201/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Accommodations and services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to require an individual with a disability to accept an accommodation, aid, service, opportunity, or benefit which such individual chooses not to accept.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf663300-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12201/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Benefits under State worker’s compensation laws</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter alters the standards for determining eligibility for benefits under State worker’s compensation laws or under State and Federal disability benefit programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf663301-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12201/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Fundamental alteration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter alters the provision of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12182/b/2/A/ii">section 12182(b)(2)(A)(ii) of this title</ref>, specifying that reasonable modifications in policies, practices, or procedures shall be required, unless an entity can demonstrate that making such modifications in policies, practices, or procedures, including academic requirements in postsecondary education, would fundamentally alter the nature of the goods, services, facilities, privileges, advantages, or accommodations involved.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf663302-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12201/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Claims of no disability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall provide the basis for a claim by an individual without a disability that the individual was subject to discrimination because of the individual’s lack of disability.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf663303-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12201/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Reasonable accommodations and modifications</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A covered entity under subchapter I, a public entity under subchapter II, and any person who owns, leases (or leases to), or operates a place of public accommodation under subchapter III, need not provide a reasonable accommodation or a reasonable modification to policies, practices, or procedures to an individual who meets the definition of disability in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12102/1">section 12102(1) of this title</ref> solely under subparagraph (C) of such section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbf663304-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/336/tV/s501">Pub. L. 101–336, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1990-07-26">July 26, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/369">104 Stat. 369</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/325/s6/a/1">Pub. L. 110–325, § 6(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2008-09-25">Sept. 25, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3557">122 Stat. 3557</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbf663305-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbf663306-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbf663307-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/101/336">Pub. L. 101–336</ref>, <date date="1990-07-26">July 26, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/327">104 Stat. 327</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12101">section 12101 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Rehabilitation Act of 1973, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/112">Pub. L. 93–112</ref>, <date date="1973-09-26">Sept. 26, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/355">87 Stat. 355</ref>. Title V of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 is classified generally to subchapter V (§ 790 et seq.) of chapter 16 of Title 29, Labor. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s701">section 701 of Title 29</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Title IV of this Act, referred to in subsec. (c), means title IV of <ref href="/us/pl/101/336">Pub. L. 101–336</ref>, <date date="1990-07-26">July 26, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/366">104 Stat. 366</ref>, which enacted <ref href="/us/usc/t47/s225">section 225 of Title 47</ref>, Telecommunications, and amended sections 152, 221, and 611 of Title 47.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbf663308-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsecs. (e) to (h). <ref href="/us/pl/110/325">Pub. L. 110–325</ref> added subsecs. (e) to (h).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbf663309-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbf66330a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2008 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/110/325">Pub. L. 110–325</ref> effective <date date="2009-01-01">Jan. 1, 2009</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/325/s8">section 8 of Pub. L. 110–325</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s705">section 705 of Title 29</ref>, Labor.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
