<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbf6d5e92-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12405"><num value="12405">§ 12405.</num><heading> Technology transfer program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf6d5e93-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12405/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall conduct a program designed to accelerate wider application of hydrogen production, storage, utilization, and other technologies available in near term as a result of aerospace experience as well as other research progress by transferring critical technologies to the private sector. The Secretary shall direct the program with the advice and assistance of the Hydrogen Technical Advisory Panel established under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12407">section 12407 of this title</ref>. The objective in seeking this advice is to increase participation of private industry in the demonstration of near commercial applications through cooperative research and development arrangements, joint ventures or other appropriate arrangements involving the private sector.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf6d5e94-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12405/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Information</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, in carrying out the program authorized by subsection (a), shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf6d5e95-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12405/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> undertake an inventory and assessment of hydrogen technologies and their commercial capability to economically produce, store, or utilize hydrogen in aerospace, transportation, electric utilities, petrochemical, chemical, merchant hydrogen, and other industrial sectors; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf6d5e96-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12405/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> develop a National Aeronautics Space Administration, Department of Energy, and industry information exchange program to improve technology transfer for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf6d5e97-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12405/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> application of aerospace experience by industry;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf6d5e98-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12405/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> application of research progress by industry and aerospace;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf6d5e99-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12405/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> application of commercial capability of industry by aerospace; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf6d5e9a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12405/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> expression of industrial needs to research organizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The information exchange program may consist of workshops, publications, conferences, and a data base for the use by the public and private sectors. The Secretary shall also foster the exchange of generic, nonproprietary information and technology, developed pursuant to this chapter, among industry, academia, and the Federal Government, to help the United States economy attain the economic benefits of this information and technology.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbf6d5e9b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/566/s106">Pub. L. 101–566, § 106</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2799">104 Stat. 2799</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/271/tI/s105">Pub. L. 104–271, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1996-10-09">Oct. 9, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3306">110 Stat. 3306</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbf6d5e9c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbf6d5e9d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbf6d5e9e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/104/271">Pub. L. 104–271</ref> inserted at end “The Secretary shall also foster the exchange of generic, nonproprietary information and technology, developed pursuant to this chapter, among industry, academia, and the Federal Government, to help the United States economy attain the economic benefits of this information and technology.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
