<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbf7e00de-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604"><num value="12604">§ 12604.</num><heading> Disbursement of educational awards</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf7e00df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Amounts in the Trust shall be available—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf7e00e0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to repay student loans in accordance with subsection (b);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf7e00e1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to pay all or part of the cost of attendance or other educational expenses at an institution of higher education in accordance with subsection (c);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf7e00e2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to pay expenses incurred in participating in an approved school-to-work program in accordance with subsection (d);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf7e00e3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to pay expenses incurred in enrolling in an educational institution or training establishment that is approved under chapter 36 of title 38, or other applicable provisions of law, for offering programs of education, apprenticeship, or on-job training for which educational assistance may be provided by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf7e00e4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> to pay interest expenses in accordance with regulations prescribed pursuant to subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf7e00e5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of educational award to repay outstanding student loans</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf7e00e6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Application by eligible individuals</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">An eligible individual under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12602">section 12602 of this title</ref> who desires to apply the national service educational award of the individual, an eligible individual under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12602/a">section 12602(a) of this title</ref> who served in a summer of service program and desires to apply that individual’s summer of service educational award, or an eligible individual under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12602/a">section 12602(a) of this title</ref> who served in a silver scholar program and desires to apply that individual’s silver scholar educational award, to the repayment of qualified student loans shall submit, in a manner prescribed by the Corporation, an application to the Corporation that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf7e00e7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> identifies, or permits the Corporation to identify readily, the holder or holders of such loans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf7e00e8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> indicates, or permits the Corporation to determine readily, the amounts of principal and interest outstanding on the loans;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf7e00e9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> specifies, if the outstanding balance is greater than the amount disbursed under paragraph (2), which of the loans the individual prefers to be paid by the Corporation; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf7e00ea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> contains or is accompanied by such other information as the Corporation may require.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf7e00eb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Disbursement of repayments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon receipt of an application from an eligible individual of an application that complies with paragraph (1), the Corporation shall, as promptly as practicable consistent with paragraph (5), disburse the amount of the national service educational award, the summer of service educational award, or the silver scholar educational award, as applicable, that the eligible individual has earned. Such disbursement shall be made by check or other means that is payable to the holder of the loan and requires the endorsement or other certification by the eligible individual.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf7e00ec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Application of disbursed amounts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the amount disbursed under paragraph (2) is less than the principal and accrued interest on any qualified student loan, such amount shall be applied according to the specified priorities of the individual.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf7e00ed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports by holders</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Any holder receiving a loan payment pursuant to this subsection shall submit to the Corporation such information as the Corporation may require to verify that such payment was applied in accordance with this subsection and any regulations prescribed to carry out this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf7e00ee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/b/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification of individual</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Corporation upon disbursing the national service educational award, the summer of service educational award, or the silver scholar educational award, as applicable, shall notify the individual of the amount paid for each outstanding loan and the date of payment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf7e00ef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/b/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to aggregate payments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Corporation may, by regulation, provide for the aggregation of payments to holders under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf7e00f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/b/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> “Qualified student loans” defined</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">As used in this subsection, the term “qualified student loans” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf7e00f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/b/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> any loan made, insured, or guaranteed pursuant to title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070">20 U.S.C. 1070</ref> et seq.), other than a loan to a parent of a student pursuant to section 428B of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1078–2">20 U.S.C. 1078–2</ref>);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf7e00f2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/b/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> any loan made pursuant to title VII or VIII of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s292">42 U.S.C. 292</ref> et seq., 296 et seq.]; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf7e00f3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/b/7/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> any loan (other than a loan described in subparagraph (A) or (B)) determined by an institution of higher education to be necessary to cover a student’s educational expenses and made, insured, or guaranteed by—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbf7e00f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/b/7/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> an eligible lender, as defined in section 435 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1085">20 U.S.C. 1085</ref>);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbf7e00f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/b/7/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the direct student loan program under part D of title IV of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1087a">20 U.S.C. 1087a</ref> et seq.);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbf7e00f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/b/7/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> a State agency; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbf7e00f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/b/7/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> a lender otherwise determined by the Corporation to be eligible to receive disbursements from the National Service Trust.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf7e00f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/b/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> “Holder” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">As used in this subsection, the term “holder” with respect to any eligible loan means the original lender or, if the loan is subsequently sold, transferred, or assigned to some other person, and such other person acquires a legally enforceable right to receive payments from the borrower, such other person.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf7e00f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of educational awards to pay current educational expenses</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf7e00fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Application by eligible individual</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">An eligible individual under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12602">section 12602 of this title</ref> who desires to apply the individual’s national service educational award, an eligible individual under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12602/a">section 12602(a) of this title</ref> who desires to apply the individual’s summer of service educational award, or an eligible individual under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12602/a">section 12602(a) of this title</ref> who served in a silver scholar program and desires to apply that individual’s silver scholar educational award, to the payment of current full-time or part-time educational expenses shall, on a form prescribed by the Corporation, submit an application to the institution of higher education in which the student will be enrolled that contains such information as the Corporation may require to verify the individual’s eligibility.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf7e00fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission of requests for payment by institutions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">An institution of higher education that receives one or more applications that comply with paragraph (1) shall submit to the Corporation a statement, in a manner prescribed by the Corporation, that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf7e00fc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> identifies each eligible individual filing an application under paragraph (1) for a disbursement of the individual’s national service educational award, summer of service educational award, or silver scholar educational award, as applicable, under this subsection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf7e00fd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> specifies the amounts for which such eligible individuals are, consistent with paragraph (6), qualified for disbursement under this subsection;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf7e00fe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> certifies that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbf7e00ff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/c/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the institution of higher education has in effect a program participation agreement under section 487 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1094">20 U.S.C. 1094</ref>);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbf7e0100-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/c/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the institution’s eligibility to participate in any of the programs under title IV of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070">20 U.S.C. 1070</ref> et seq.) has not been limited, suspended, or terminated; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbf7e0101-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/c/2/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> individuals using national service educational awards, summer of service educational awards, or silver scholar educational awards, as applicable, received under this division to pay for educational costs do not comprise more than 15 percent of the total student population of the institution; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf7e0102-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/c/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> contains such provisions concerning financial compliance as the Corporation may require.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf7e0103-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Disbursement of payments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon receipt of a statement from an institution of higher education that complies with paragraph (2), the Corporation shall, subject to paragraph (4), disburse the total amount of the national service educational awards <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004067">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn004067"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma.</note> summer of service educational awards, or silver scholar educational awards for which eligible individuals who have submitted applications to that institution under paragraph (1) are scheduled to receive. Such disbursement shall be made by check or other means that is payable to the institution and requires the endorsement or other certification by the eligible individual.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf7e0104-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Multiple disbursements required</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The total amount required to be disbursed to an institution of higher education under paragraph (3) for any period of enrollment shall be disbursed by the Corporation in 2 or more installments, none of which exceeds ½ of such total amount. The interval between the first and second such installment shall not be less than ½ of such period of enrollment, except as necessary to permit the second installment to be paid at the beginning of the second semester, quarter, or similar division of such period of enrollment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf7e0105-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/c/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Refund rules</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Corporation shall, by regulation, provide for the refund to the Corporation (and the crediting to the national service educational award, summer of service educational award, or silver scholar educational award, as applicable, of an eligible individual) of amounts disbursed to institutions for the benefit of eligible individuals who withdraw or otherwise fail to complete the period of enrollment for which the assistance was provided. Such regulations shall be consistent with the fair and equitable refund policies required of institutions pursuant to section 484B of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1091b">20 U.S.C. 1091b</ref>). Amounts refunded to the Trust pursuant to this paragraph may be used by the Corporation to fund additional approved national service positions under division C, additional approved summer of service positions, and additional approved silver scholar positions.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf807206-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/c/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Maximum award</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The portion of an eligible individual’s total available national service educational award, summer of service educational award, or silver scholar educational award that may be disbursed under this subsection for any period of enrollment shall not exceed the difference between—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf807207-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/c/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the eligible individual’s cost of attendance and other educational expenses for such period of enrollment, determined in accordance with section 472 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1087">20 U.S.C. 1087</ref><i>ll</i>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf807208-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/c/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the student’s estimated financial assistance for such period under part A of title IV of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070">20 U.S.C. 1070</ref> et seq.).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf807209-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of educational award to participate in approved school-to-work programs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Corporation shall by regulation provide for the payment of national service educational awards, summer of service educational awards, and silver scholar educational awards to permit eligible individuals to participate in school-to-work programs approved by the Secretaries of Labor and Education.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf80720a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Interest payments during forbearance on loan repayment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Corporation shall provide by regulation for the payment on behalf of an eligible individual of interest that accrues during a period for which such individual has obtained forbearance in the repayment of a qualified student loan (as defined in subsection (b)(7)), if the eligible individual successfully completes the individual’s required term of service (as determined under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12602/b">section 12602(b) of this title</ref>). Such regulations shall be prescribed after consultation with the Secretary of Education.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf80720b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of educational awards</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf80720c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">An individual who is eligible to receive a national service educational award or silver scholar educational award due to service in a program described in paragraph (2) may elect to receive the award (in the amount described in the corresponding provision of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12603">section 12603 of this title</ref>) and transfer the award to a designated individual. Subsections (b), (c), and (d) shall apply to the designated individual in lieu of the individual who is eligible to receive the national service educational award or silver scholar educational award, except that amounts refunded to the account under subsection (c)(5) on behalf of a designated individual may be used by the Corporation to fund additional placements in the national service program in which the eligible individual who transferred the national service educational award or silver scholar educational award participated for such award.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf80720d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditions for transfer</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">An educational award may be transferred under this subsection if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf80720e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf80720f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/f/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the award is a national service educational award for service in a national service program that receives a grant under division C; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf807210-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/f/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> before beginning the term of service involved, the eligible individual is age 55 or older; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf807211-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the award is a silver scholarship educational award under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12653c/a">section 12653c(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf807212-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Modification or revocation</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbf807213-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/f/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">An individual transferring an educational award under this subsection may, on any date on which a portion of the educational award remains unused, modify or revoke the transfer of the educational award with respect to that portion.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbf807214-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/f/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A modification or revocation of the transfer of an educational award under this paragraph shall be made by the submission of written notice to the Corporation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf807215-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/f/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition on treatment of transferred award as marital property</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">An educational award transferred under this subsection may not be treated as marital property, or the asset of a marital estate, subject to division in a divorce or other civil proceeding.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf807216-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/f/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Death of transferor</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The death of an individual transferring an educational award under this subsection shall not affect the use of the educational award by the child, foster child, or grandchild to whom the educational award is transferred if such educational award is transferred prior to the death of the individual.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf807217-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/f/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedures to prevent waste, fraud, or abuse</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Corporation shall establish requirements to prevent waste, fraud, or abuse in connection with the transfer of an educational award and to protect the integrity of the educational award under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf807218-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/f/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Technical assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Corporation may, as appropriate, provide technical assistance, to individuals and eligible entities carrying out national service programs, concerning carrying out this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf807219-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/f/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition of a designated individual</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In this subsection, the term “designated individual” is an individual—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf80721a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/f/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> whom an individual who is eligible to receive a national service educational award or silver scholar educational award due to service in a program described in paragraph (2) designates to receive the educational award;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf80721b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/f/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> who meets the eligibility requirements of paragraphs (3) and (4) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12602/a">section 12602(a) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf80721c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/f/8/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> who is a child, foster child, or grandchild of the individual described in subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf80721d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With the approval of the Chief Executive Officer, an approved national service program funded under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12571">section 12571 of this title</ref>, may offer participants the option of waiving their right to receive a national service educational award, summer of service educational award, or silver scholar educational award, as appropriate, in order to receive an alternative post-service benefit funded by the program entirely with non-Federal funds.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf80721e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12604/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> “Institution of higher education” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12511">section 12511 of this title</ref>, for purposes of this section the term “institution of higher education” has the meaning provided by section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 [<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</ref>].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbf80721f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/610/tI/s148">Pub. L. 101–610, title I, § 148</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/tI/s102/a">Pub. L. 103–82, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-09-21">Sept. 21, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/820">107 Stat. 820</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/105/244/tI/s102/c/2">Pub. L. 105–244, title I, § 102(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-07">Oct. 7, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/1622">112 Stat. 1622</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/tI/s1405">Pub. L. 111–13, title I, § 1405</ref>, <date date="2009-04-21">Apr. 21, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/1515">123 Stat. 1515</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbf807220-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbf807221-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbf807222-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Higher Education Act of 1965, referred to in subsecs. (b)(7)(A), (C)(ii) and (c)(2)(C)(ii), (6)(B), is <ref href="/us/pl/89/329">Pub. L. 89–329</ref>, <date date="1965-11-08">Nov. 8, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1219">79 Stat. 1219</ref>. Title IV of the Act is classified generally to subchapter IV (§ 1070 et seq.) of chapter 28 of Title 20, Education. Parts A and D of title IV of the Act are classified generally to parts A (§ 1070 et seq.) and D (§ 1087a et seq.), respectively, of subchapter IV of chapter 28 of Title 20. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">section 1001 of Title 20</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Public Health Service Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(7)(B), is <ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">act July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/58/682">58 Stat. 682</ref>. Titles VII and VIII of the Act are classified generally to subchapters V (§ 292 et seq.) and VI (§ 296 et seq.), respectively, of chapter 6A of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">section 201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idbf807223-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior <ref href="/us/pl/101/610/s148">section 148 of Pub. L. 101–610</ref> was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12578">section 12578 of this title</ref> prior to the general amendment of subtitle D of title I of <ref href="/us/pl/101/610">Pub. L. 101–610</ref> [former part D of this subchapter] by <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s102/a">Pub. L. 103–82, § 102(a)</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbf807224-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2009—<ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s1405/1">Pub. L. 111–13, § 1405(1)</ref>, substituted section catchline for former section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2) to (5). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s1405/2">Pub. L. 111–13, § 1405(2)</ref>, substituted “cost of attendance or other educational expenses” for “cost of attendance” in par. (2), added par. (4), and redesignated former par. (4) as (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s1405/3/A">Pub. L. 111–13, § 1405(3)(A)</ref>, inserted “, an eligible individual under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12602/a">section 12602(a) of this title</ref> who served in a summer of service program and desires to apply that individual’s summer of service educational award, or an eligible individual under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12602/a">section 12602(a) of this title</ref> who served in a silver scholar program and desires to apply that individual’s silver scholar educational award,” after “the national service educational award of the individual” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s1405/3/B">Pub. L. 111–13, § 1405(3)(B)</ref>, inserted “, the summer of service educational award, or the silver scholar educational award, as applicable,” after “the national service educational award”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s1405/3/C">Pub. L. 111–13, § 1405(3)(C)</ref>, inserted “, the summer of service educational award, or the silver scholar educational award, as applicable” after “the national service educational award”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(7)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s1405/3/D">Pub. L. 111–13, § 1405(3)(D)</ref>, added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s1405/4/A">Pub. L. 111–13, § 1405(4)(A)</ref>, inserted “, an eligible individual under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12602/a">section 12602(a) of this title</ref> who desires to apply the individual’s summer of service educational award, or an eligible individual under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12602/a">section 12602(a) of this title</ref> who served in a silver scholar program and desires to apply that individual’s silver scholar educational award,” after “national service educational award”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s1405/4/B/i">Pub. L. 111–13, § 1405(4)(B)(i)</ref>, inserted “, summer of service educational award, or silver scholar educational award, as applicable,” after “national service educational award”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(C)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s1405/4/B/ii">Pub. L. 111–13, § 1405(4)(B)(ii)</ref>, inserted “, summer of service educational awards, or silver scholar educational awards, as applicable,” after “national service educational awards”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s1405/4/C">Pub. L. 111–13, § 1405(4)(C)</ref>, inserted “summer of service educational awards, or silver scholar educational awards” after “national service educational awards”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s1405/4/D">Pub. L. 111–13, § 1405(4)(D)</ref>, inserted “, summer of service educational award, or silver scholar educational award, as applicable,” after “national service educational award” and “, additional approved summer of service positions, and additional approved silver scholar positions” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s1405/4/E/i">Pub. L. 111–13, § 1405(4)(E)(i)</ref>, inserted “, summer of service educational award, or silver scholar educational award” after “national service educational award” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s1405/4/E/ii">Pub. L. 111–13, § 1405(4)(E)(ii)</ref>, inserted “and other educational expenses” after “cost of attendance”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(6)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s1405/4/E/iii">Pub. L. 111–13, § 1405(4)(E)(iii)</ref>, added subpar. (B) and struck out former subpar. (B) which read as follows: “the sum of—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) the student’s estimated financial assistance for such period under part A of title IV of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1070">20 U.S.C. 1070</ref> et seq.); and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) the student’s veterans’ education benefits, determined in accordance with section 480(c) of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1087vv/c">20 U.S.C. 1087vv(c)</ref>).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s1405/5">Pub. L. 111–13, § 1405(5)</ref>, inserted “, summer of service educational awards, and silver scholar educational awards” after “national service educational awards”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s1405/6">Pub. L. 111–13, § 1405(6)</ref>, substituted “subsection (b)(7)” for “subsection (b)(6)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s1405/9">Pub. L. 111–13, § 1405(9)</ref>, added subsec. (f). Former subsec. (f) redesignated (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s1405/7">Pub. L. 111–13, § 1405(7)</ref>, substituted “Chief Executive Officer” for “Director” and inserted “, summer of service educational award, or silver scholar educational award, as appropriate,” after “national service educational award”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (g), (h). <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s1405/8">Pub. L. 111–13, § 1405(8)</ref>, redesignated subsecs. (f) and (g) as (g) and (h), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/105/244">Pub. L. 105–244</ref> substituted “section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965” for “section 481(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1088/a">20 U.S.C. 1088(a)</ref>)”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbf807225-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbf807226-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2009 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/111/13">Pub. L. 111–13</ref> effective <date date="2009-10-01">Oct. 1, 2009</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/13/s6101/a">section 6101(a) of Pub. L. 111–13</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4950">section 4950 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbf807227-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/244">Pub. L. 105–244</ref> effective <date date="1998-10-01">Oct. 1, 1998</date>, except as otherwise provided in <ref href="/us/pl/105/244">Pub. L. 105–244</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/244/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 105–244</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">section 1001 of Title 20</ref>, Education.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idbf807228-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1993-10-01">Oct. 1, 1993</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/82/s123">section 123 of Pub. L. 103–82</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1993 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t16/s1701">section 1701 of Title 16</ref>, Conservation.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
