<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbf9ab078-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12710"><num value="12710">§ 12710.</num><heading> Capacity study</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9ab079-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12710/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall ensure that the Department of Housing and Urban Development has adequate capacity and resources, including staff and training programs, to carry out its mission and responsibilities to implement the provisions of this Act, including the ability of the Department to carry out the multifamily mortgage insurance program, and the ability to respond to areas identified as “material weaknesses” by the Office of the Inspector General in financial audits or other reports.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9ab07a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12710/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 60 days after <date date="1990-11-28">November 28, 1990</date>, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives a study detailing the Department’s plan to maintain such capacity, together with any recommendations for legislative and administrative action as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbf9ab07b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/625/tI/s110">Pub. L. 101–625, title I, § 110</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4093">104 Stat. 4093</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tIV/s407">Pub. L. 102–550, title IV, § 407</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3778">106 Stat. 3778</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbf9ab07c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbf9ab07d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbf9ab07e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/101/625">Pub. L. 101–625</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4079">104 Stat. 4079</ref>, known as the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12701">section 12701 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbf9ab07f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550">Pub. L. 102–550</ref> struck out “, and” after “responsibilities” and substituted for period at end “and the ability to respond to areas identified as ‘material weaknesses’ by the Office of the Inspector General in financial audits or other reports.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbf9ab080-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idbf9ab081-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Banking and Financial Services of House of Representatives by <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/a">section 1(a) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress. Committee on Banking and Financial Services of House of Representatives abolished and replaced by Committee on Financial Services of House of Representatives, and jurisdiction over matters relating to securities and exchanges and insurance generally transferred from Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Seventh Congress, <date date="2001-01-03">Jan. 3, 2001</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
