<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbf9cfa0d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12744"><num value="12744">§ 12744.</num><heading> Income targeting</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each participating jurisdiction shall invest funds made available under this part within each fiscal year so that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf9cfa0e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12744/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> with respect to rental assistance and rental units—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf9cfa0f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12744/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> not less than 90 percent of (i) the families receiving such rental assistance are families whose incomes do not exceed 60 percent of the median family income for the area, as determined by the Secretary with adjustments for smaller and larger families, (except that the Secretary may establish income ceilings higher or lower than 60 percent of the median for the area on the basis of the Secretary’s findings that such variations are necessary because of prevailing levels of construction cost or fair market rent, or unusually high or low family income) at the time of occupancy or at the time funds are invested, whichever is later, or (ii) the dwelling units assisted with such funds are occupied by families having such incomes; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf9cfa10-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12744/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the remainder of (i) the families receiving such rental assistance are households that qualify as low-income families (other than families described in subparagraph (A)) at the time of occupancy or at the time funds are invested, whichever is later, or (ii) the dwelling units assisted with such funds are occupied by such households;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf9cfa11-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12744/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> with respect to homeownership assistance, 100 percent of such funds are invested with respect to dwelling units that are occupied by households that qualify as low-income families; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf9cfa12-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12744/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> all such funds are invested with respect to housing that qualifies as affordable housing under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12745">section 12745 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idbf9cfa13-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/625/tII/s214">Pub. L. 101–625, title II, § 214</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4101">104 Stat. 4101</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/233/tII/s202">Pub. L. 103–233, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1994-04-11">Apr. 11, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/364">108 Stat. 364</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/276/tV/s599B/a">Pub. L. 105–276, title V, § 599B(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2660">112 Stat. 2660</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbf9cfa14-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbf9cfa15-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbf9cfa16-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Par. (2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/276">Pub. L. 105–276</ref> struck out “at the time of occupancy or at the time funds are invested, whichever is later” before “; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Par. (1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/103/233/s202/1">Pub. L. 103–233, § 202(1)</ref>, substituted “(i) the families receiving such rental assistance are” for “such funds are invested with respect to dwelling units that are occupied by”, “, or” for “, and” before cl. (ii), and added cl. (ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Par. (1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/103/233/s202/2">Pub. L. 103–233, § 202(2)</ref>, substituted “(i) the families receiving such rental assistance are” for “such funds are invested with respect to dwelling units that are occupied by” and added cl. (ii).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbf9cfa17-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbf9cfa18-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/276/tV/s599B/c">Pub. L. 105–276, title V, § 599B(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2660">112 Stat. 2660</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/276/tV/s599B/c">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12745">section 12745 of this title</ref>] are made on, and shall apply beginning upon, the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbf9cfa19-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/233">Pub. L. 103–233</ref> applicable with respect to any amounts made available to carry out this subchapter after <date date="1994-04-11">Apr. 11, 1994</date>, and any amounts made available to carry out this subchapter before that date that remain uncommitted on that date, with Secretary to issue any regulations necessary to carry out such amendment not later than end of 45-day period beginning on that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/233/s209">section 209 of Pub. L. 103–233</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
