<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbf9cfa67-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747"><num value="12747">§ 12747.</num><heading> Allocation of resources</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9cfa68-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9cfa69-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> States and units of general local government</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">After reserving amounts under paragraph (3) for the insular areas, the Secretary shall allocate funds approved in an appropriation Act to carry out this subchapter by formula as provided in subsection (b). Of the funds made available under the preceding sentence, the Secretary shall initially allocate 60 percent among units of general local government and 40 percent among States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9cfa6a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/104/330/tV/s505/a/1/B">Pub. L. 104–330, title V, § 505(a)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-26">Oct. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/4044">110 Stat. 4044</ref></heading><content />
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9cfa6b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004108">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn004108"><num>1</num> See 1992 Amendment note below.</note> Insular areas</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For each fiscal year, of any amounts approved in appropriation Acts to carry out this subchapter, the Secretary shall reserve for grants to the insular areas the greater of (A) $750,000, or (B) 0.2 percent of the amounts appropriated under such Acts. The Secretary shall provide for the distribution of amounts reserved under this paragraph among the insular areas pursuant to specific criteria for such distribution, which shall be contained in a regulation issued by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9cfa6c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Formula allocation</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9cfa6d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9cfa6e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/b/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Basic formula</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall establish in <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004109">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn004109"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “by”.</note> regulation an allocation formula that reflects each jurisdiction’s share of total need among eligible jurisdiction <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004110">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn004110"><num>3</num> So in original. Probably should be “jurisdictions”.</note> for an increased supply of affordable housing for very low-income and low-income families of different size, as identified by objective measures of inadequate housing supply, substandard housing, the number of low-income families in housing likely to be in need of rehabilitation, the costs of producing housing, poverty, and the relative fiscal incapacity of the jurisdiction to carry out housing activities eligible under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12742">section 12742 of this title</ref> without Federal assistance. Allocation among units of general local government shall take into account the housing needs of metropolitan cities, urban counties, and approved consortia of units of general local government.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9cfa6f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/b/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Source of data</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The data to be used for formula allocation of funds within a fiscal year shall be data obtained from a standard source that are available to the Secretary 90 days prior to the beginning of that fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9cfa70-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/b/1/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of basic formula</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The basic formula established under subparagraph (A) shall be used for all formula allocations and reallocations provided for in this part.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9cfa71-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/b/1/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Weights</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">When allocation is made among States, the Secretary shall apply the formula in subparagraph (A) giving 20 percent weight to measures of need for the whole State and 80 percent weight to measures of need among units of general local government that are not receiving an allocation under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12746/1">section 12746(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9cfa72-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/b/1/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In developing the basic formula in subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall (i) avoid the allocation of an excessively large share of amounts made available under this part to any one State or unit of general local government, and (ii) take into account the need for a geographic distribution of amounts made available under this part that appropriately reflects the housing need in each region of the Nation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9cfa73-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/b/1/F"><num value="F" class="bold">(F)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall develop the formula in subparagraph (A) in ongoing consultation with (i) the Subcommittee on Housing and Urban Affairs of the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, (ii) the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Development of the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives, and (iii) organizations representing States and units of general local government. Not less than 60 days prior to publishing a formula for comment, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives a copy of the formula the Secretary intends to propose.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9cfa74-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Minimum State allocation</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9cfa75-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/b/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the formula, when applied to funds approved under this section in appropriations Acts for a fiscal year, would allocate less than $3,000,000 to any State, the allocation for such State shall be $3,000,000, and the increase shall be deducted pro rata from the allocations of other States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9cfa76-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/b/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Increased minimum allocation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If no unit of general local government within a State receives an allocation under paragraph (3), the State’s allocation shall be increased by $500,000. Priority for use of such increased allocation shall go to the provision of affordable housing within the boundaries of metropolitan cities, urban counties, and approved consortia within the State, based on the need for such funds. The increased allocation to a State under the preceding sentence shall be derived by a pro rata deduction from the allocations to units of general local government in all States, except that such pro rata deduction shall not reduce the allocation of any unit of general local government below $500,000.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9cfa77-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Minimum local allocation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall allocate funds available for formula allocation to units of general local government that, as of the end of the previous fiscal year, qualified as metropolitan cities, urban counties, and consortia approved by the Secretary in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12746/2">section 12746(2) of this title</ref> so that, when all such funds are initially allocated by formula, jurisdictions that are allocated an amount of $500,000 or more, and participating jurisdictions (other than consortia that fail to renew the membership of all of their member jurisdictions) that are allocated an amount less than $500,000, shall receive an allocation. Prior to announcing initial allocations, the Secretary shall successively recalculate the allocations to jurisdictions under this subsection so that the maximum number of such jurisdictions can receive initial allocations, except as provided in paragraph (4).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9cfa78-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Threshold reduction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the amount appropriated pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12724">section 12724 of this title</ref> for any fiscal year is less than $1,500,000,000, then this section shall be applied during that year by substituting “$335,000” for “$500,000” where it appears in paragraph (3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9cfa79-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Criteria for direct reallocation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish objective criteria for making direct reallocations to any participating jurisdiction and other eligible entities. A jurisdiction shall be eligible for a direct reallocation under this subsection only if the jurisdiction, in a form acceptable to the Secretary, submits an application that demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the jurisdiction is engaged, or has made good faith efforts to engage, in cooperative efforts between the State and appropriate participating jurisdictions within the State to develop, coordinate, and implement housing strategies under this subchapter. The Secretary shall by regulation establish objective selection criteria for such direct reallocations, which criteria shall take into account—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf9cfa7a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the applicant’s demonstrated commitment to expand the supply of affordable rental housing, including units developed by public housing agencies, as indicated by the additional number of units of affordable housing made available through production or rehabilitation within the previous 2 years, making adjustment for regional variations in construction and rehabilitation costs and giving special consideration to the number of additional units made available under this subchapter through production or rehabilitation, including units developed by public housing agencies, in relation to the amounts made available under this program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf9cfa7b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> the applicant’s actions that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf9cfa7c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> direct funds made available under this part to benefit very low-income families, with a range of incomes, in amounts that exceed the income targeting requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12744">section 12744 of this title</ref>, with extra consideration given for activities that expand the supply of affordable housing for very low-income families whose incomes do not exceed 30 percent of the median family income for the area, as determined by the Secretary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf9cfa7d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> apply the tenant selection preference categories applicable under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437f">section 1437f of this title</ref> to the selection of tenants for housing assisted under this part;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf9cfa7e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> provide matching resources in excess of funds required under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12750">section 12750 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf9cfa7f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/c/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> stimulate a high degree of investment and participation in development by the private sector, including nonprofit organizations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbf9cfa80-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> the degree to which the applicant is pursuing policies that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf9cfa81-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> make existing housing more affordable;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf9cfa82-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> remove or ameliorate any negative effects that public policies identified by the applicant pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12705/b/4">section 12705(b)(4) of this title</ref> may have on the cost of housing or the incentives to develop, maintain, or improve affordable housing in the jurisdiction;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf9cfa83-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> preserve the affordability of privately-owned housing that is vulnerable to conversion, demolition, disinvestment, or abandonment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf9cfa84-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/c/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> increase the supply of housing that is affordable to very low-income and low-income persons, particularly in areas that are accessible to expanding job opportunities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbf9cfa85-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/c/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> remedy the effects of discrimination and improve housing opportunities for disadvantaged minorities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9cfa86-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Reallocations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9cfa87-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall make any reallocations periodically throughout each fiscal year so as to ensure that all funds to be reallocated are made available to eligible jurisdictions as soon as possible, consistent with orderly program administration. Jurisdictions eligible for such reallocations shall include participating jurisdictions and jurisdictions meeting the requirements of paragraphs (3), (4), and (5) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12746">section 12746 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9cfa88-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Commitments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish procedures according to which participating jurisdictions may make commitments to invest funds made available under this section. Such procedures shall provide for appropriate stages of commitment of funds to a project from initial reservation through binding commitment. Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, funds that the Secretary determines are needed to fulfill binding commitments shall not be available for reallocation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9cfa89-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12747/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Unless otherwise specified in this part, any reallocation of funds from a State shall be made only among all participating States, and any reallocation of funds from units of general local government shall be made only among all participating units of general local government.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbf9cfa8a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/625/tII/s217">Pub. L. 101–625, title II, § 217</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4105">104 Stat. 4105</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/229/tI">Pub. L. 102–229, title I</ref>, <date date="1991-12-12">Dec. 12, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1709">105 Stat. 1709</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/230/s1">Pub. L. 102–230, § 1</ref>, <date date="1991-12-12">Dec. 12, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1720">105 Stat. 1720</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/273/s1">Pub. L. 102–273, § 1</ref>, <date date="1992-04-21">Apr. 21, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/113">106 Stat. 113</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/389/tII">Pub. L. 102–389, title II</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1581">106 Stat. 1581</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tII">Pub. L. 102–550, title II</ref>, §§ 202(b), 203(b), 211(a)(2), <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3751">106 Stat. 3751</ref>, 3752, 3756; <ref href="/us/pl/104/330/tV/s505/a/1">Pub. L. 104–330, title V, § 505(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-26">Oct. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/4044">110 Stat. 4044</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/65/tII/s214">Pub. L. 105–65, title II, § 214</ref>, <date date="1997-10-27">Oct. 27, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/1366">111 Stat. 1366</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbf9cfa8b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbf9cfa8c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbf9cfa8d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/105/65">Pub. L. 105–65</ref>, in first sentence, substituted “jurisdictions that are allocated an amount of $500,000 or more, and participating jurisdictions (other than consortia that fail to renew the membership of all of their member jurisdictions) that are allocated an amount less than $500,000, shall receive an allocation” for “only those jurisdictions that are allocated an amount of $500,000 or greater shall receive an allocation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/330/s505/a/1/A">Pub. L. 104–330, § 505(a)(1)(A)</ref>, struck out “reserving amounts under paragraph (2) for Indian tribes and after” after “After”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/330/s505/a/1/B">Pub. L. 104–330, § 505(a)(1)(B)</ref>, struck out heading and text of par. (2). Text read as follows: “For each fiscal year, of the amount approved in an appropriations Act to carry out this subchapter, the Secretary shall reserve for grants to Indian tribes 1 percent of the amount appropriated under such section. The Secretary shall provide for distribution of amounts under this paragraph to Indian tribes on the basis of a competition conducted pursuant to specific criteria for the selection of Indian tribes to receive such amounts. The criteria shall be contained in a regulation promulgated by the Secretary after notice and public comment.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s211/a/2/A">Pub. L. 102–550, § 211(a)(2)(A)</ref>, added first sentence and struck out former first sentence which read as follows: “After reserving amounts for Indian tribes as required by paragraph (2) of this subsection and after reserving amounts for the insular areas under paragraph (3), the Secretary shall allocate funds approved in an appropriations Act to carry out this subchapter by formula as provided in subsection (b) of this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/389">Pub. L. 102–389</ref> made identical amendment to those made by <ref href="/us/pl/102/229">Pub. L. 102–229</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/102/230/s1/1">Pub. L. 102–230, § 1(1)</ref>. See 1991 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s211/a/2/D">Pub. L. 102–550, § 211(a)(2)(D)</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/102/389">Pub. L. 102–389</ref> both added new pars. (3) related to insular areas. The text reflects the par. (3) added by <ref href="/us/pl/102/550">Pub. L. 102–550</ref>. The par. (3) added by <ref href="/us/pl/102/389">Pub. L. 102–389</ref> read as follows: “For each fiscal year, of any amounts approved in appropriations Acts to carry out this subchapter, the Secretary shall reserve for grants to the insular areas the greater of (A) $750,000, or (B) 0.2 percent of the amounts appropriated under such Acts. The Secretary shall provide for the distribution of amounts reserved under this paragraph among the insular areas pursuant to specific criteria for such distribution. The criteria shall be contained in a regulation promulgated by the Secretary after notice and public comment.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s211/a/2/C">Pub. L. 102–550, § 211(a)(2)(C)</ref>, struck out par. (3), as added by <ref href="/us/pl/102/230/s1/2">Pub. L. 102–230, § 1(2)</ref>, which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(A) <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—For each fiscal year, of any amount approved in an appropriations Act to carry out this subchapter, the Secretary shall reserve for grants to the insular areas an amount that reflects—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) their share of the total population of eligible jurisdictions; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) any adjustments that the Secretary determines are reasonable in light of available data that are related to factors set forth in subsection (b)(1)(B) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) <inline class="small-caps">Specific criteria</inline>.—The Secretary shall provide for the distribution of amounts reserved under this paragraph among the insular areas in accordance with specific criteria to be set forth in a regulation promulgated by the Secretary after notice and public comment.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(C) <inline class="small-caps">Transitional provisions</inline>.—For fiscal year 1992, the reservation for insular areas specified in subparagraph (A) shall be made from any funds which become available for reallocation in accordance with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12746/6/A">section 12746(6)(A) of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s211/a/2/B">Pub. L. 102–550, § 211(a)(2)(B)</ref>, struck out par. (3), as added by <ref href="/us/pl/102/229">Pub. L. 102–229</ref>, which read as follows: “For each fiscal year, of any amounts approved in appropriations Acts to carry out this subchapter, the Secretary shall reserve for grants to the insular areas the greater of (A) $750,000, or (B) 0.5 percent of the amounts appropriated under such Acts. The Secretary shall provide for the distribution of amounts reserved under this paragraph among the insular areas pursuant to specific criteria for such distribution. The criteria shall be contained in a regulation promulgated by the Secretary after notice and public comment.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s203/b/1">Pub. L. 102–550, § 203(b)(1)</ref>, (6), redesignated subpar. (B) as (A) and struck out former subpar. (A) which provided for a formula for allocation of funds for production of affordable rental housing through new construction or substantial rehabilitation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/273">Pub. L. 102–273</ref> added cl. (iii) reading as follows: “Notwithstanding clauses (i) and (ii), any jurisdiction receiving amounts made available under such clause may, at the discretion of the jurisdiction, use such amounts for other eligible uses in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12742">section 12742 of this title</ref> if the jurisdiction determines that such use will better meet the housing needs within the jurisdiction. This clause shall be effective only with respect to funds provided under the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1992 (<ref href="/us/pl/102/139">Public Law 102–139</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/105/744">105 Stat. 744</ref>), which suspends the requirement of contributions by participating jurisdictions, and shall become ineffective if such requirement is reimposed.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B), (C). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s203/b/6">Pub. L. 102–550, § 203(b)(6)</ref>, redesignated subpars. (C) and (D) as (B) and (C), respectively. Former subpar. (B) redesignated (A).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s203/b/6">Pub. L. 102–550, § 203(b)(6)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (E) as (D). Former subpar. (D) redesignated (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s203/b/2">Pub. L. 102–550, § 203(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “The basic formula established under subparagraph (A)” for “Except as provided in subparagraph (A), the basic formula established under subparagraph (B)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s203/b/6">Pub. L. 102–550, § 203(b)(6)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (F) as (E). Former subpar. (E) redesignated (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s203/b/3">Pub. L. 102–550, § 203(b)(3)</ref>, substituted “formula in subparagraph (A)” for “formulas in subparagraph (B)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(F). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s203/b/6">Pub. L. 102–550, § 203(b)(6)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (G) as (F). Former subpar. (F) redesignated (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s203/b/4">Pub. L. 102–550, § 203(b)(4)</ref>, substituted “basic formula in subparagraph (A)” for “basic formula in subparagraph (B)” and struck out at end “If a jurisdiction receives an allocation under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall make such adjustments in the jurisdiction’s allocation under the formula in subparagraph (B) as may be necessary to ensure that the combined effect of the formulas in subparagraphs (A) and (B) does not reduce the allocation of any jurisdiction below the allocation it would receive if allocations were made according to the formula under subparagraph (B) alone.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(G). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s203/b/6">Pub. L. 102–550, § 203(b)(6)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (G) as (F).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s203/b/5">Pub. L. 102–550, § 203(b)(5)</ref>, substituted “formula in subparagraph (A)” for “formulas in subparagraphs (A) and (B)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s202/b/1">Pub. L. 102–550, § 202(b)(1)</ref>, inserted before period at end “, except as provided in paragraph (4)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s202/b/2">Pub. L. 102–550, § 202(b)(2)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/102/229">Pub. L. 102–229</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/102/230/s1/1">Pub. L. 102–230, § 1(1)</ref>, amended par. (1) identically, inserting before first comma “and after reserving amounts for the insular areas under paragraph (3)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/102/229">Pub. L. 102–229</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/102/230/s1/2">Pub. L. 102–230, § 1(2)</ref>, which were enacted on the same day, both added new pars. (3) relating to insular areas.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbf9f6b8e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idbf9f6b8f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Banking and Financial Services of House of Representatives by <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/a">section 1(a) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress. Committee on Banking and Financial Services of House of Representatives abolished and replaced by Committee on Financial Services of House of Representatives, and jurisdiction over matters relating to securities and exchanges and insurance generally transferred from Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Seventh Congress, <date date="2001-01-03">Jan. 3, 2001</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbf9f6b90-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/330">Pub. L. 104–330</ref> effective <date date="1997-10-01">Oct. 1, 1997</date>, except as otherwise expressly provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/330/s107">section 107 of Pub. L. 104–330</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s4101">section 4101 of Title 25</ref>, Indians.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/104/330/tV/s505/b">Pub. L. 104–330, title V, § 505(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-26">Oct. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/4044">110 Stat. 4044</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/330/tV/s505/b">“The amendments under subsection (a) [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12838">section 12838 of this title</ref>] shall apply with respect to amounts made available for assistance under title II of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12721">42 U.S.C. 12721</ref> et seq.] for fiscal year 1998 and fiscal years thereafter.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbf9f6b91-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s211/a/2">section 211(a)(2) of Pub. L. 102–550</ref> applicable with respect to fiscal year 1993 and thereafter, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s211/b">section 211(b) of Pub. L. 102–550</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12704">section 12704 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by sections 202(b) and 203(b) of <ref href="/us/pl/102/550">Pub. L. 102–550</ref> applicable to unexpended funds allocated under subchapter II of this chapter in fiscal year 1992, except as otherwise specifically provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s223">section 223 of Pub. L. 102–550</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12704">section 12704 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbf9f6b92-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Applicability of Grant Thresholds</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Grant thresholds provided for in subsec. (b) of this section as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/102/550">Pub. L. 102–550</ref> to apply notwithstanding any other provision of law, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s202/c">section 202(c) of Pub. L. 102–550</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12746">section 12746 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbf9f6b93-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Expedited Issuance of Regulation</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tII/s211/a/3">Pub. L. 102–550, title II, § 211(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3757">106 Stat. 3757</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/550/tII/s211/a/3">“The regulation referred to in the amendment made by paragraph (2)(D) [amending this section] shall take effect not later than the expiration of the 90-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>]. The regulation shall not be subject to the requirements of subsections (b) and (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>, United States Code, or section 7(<i>o</i>) of the Department of Housing and Urban Development Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3535">42 U.S.C. 3535</ref>(<i>o</i>)].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
