<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbf9f6bfa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12771"><num value="12771">§ 12771.</num><heading> Set-aside for community housing development organizations</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9f6bfb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12771/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For a period of 24 months after funds under part A are made available to a jurisdiction, the jurisdiction shall reserve not less than 15 percent of such funds for investment only in housing to be developed, sponsored, or owned by community housing development organizations. Each participating jurisdiction shall make reasonable efforts to identify community housing development organizations that are capable or can reasonably be expected to become capable of carrying out elements of the jurisdiction’s housing strategy and to encourage such community housing development organizations to do so. If during the first 24 months of its participation under this subchapter, a participating jurisdiction is unable to identify a sufficient number of capable community housing development organizations, then up to 20 percent of the funds allocated to that jurisdiction under this section, but not to exceed $150,000, may be made available to carry out activities that develop the capacity of community housing development organizations in that jurisdiction. A participating jurisdiction is authorized to enter into contracts with community housing development organizations to carry out this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9f6bfc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12771/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Recapture and reuse</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If any funds reserved under subsection (a) remain uninvested for a period of 24 months, then the Secretary shall deduct such funds from the line of credit in the participating jurisdiction’s HOME Investment Trust Fund and make such funds available by direct reallocation (1) to other participating jurisdictions for affordable housing developed, sponsored or owned by community housing development organizations, or (2) to nonprofit intermediary organizations to carry out activities that develop the capacity of community housing development organizations consistent with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12773">section 12773 of this title</ref>, with preference to community housing development organizations serving the jurisdiction from which the funds were recaptured.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbf9f6bfd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12771/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Direct reallocation criteria</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Insofar as practicable, direct reallocations under this section shall be made according to the selection criteria established under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12747/c">section 12747(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbf9f6bfe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/625/tII/s231">Pub. L. 101–625, title II, § 231</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4114">104 Stat. 4114</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tII/s212/a">Pub. L. 102–550, title II, § 212(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3757">106 Stat. 3757</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbf9f6bff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbf9f6c00-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbf9f6c01-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550">Pub. L. 102–550</ref> substituted “24” for “18” in first sentence and inserted after second sentence “If during the first 24 months of its participation under this subchapter, a participating jurisdiction is unable to identify a sufficient number of capable community housing development organizations, then up to 20 percent of the funds allocated to that jurisdiction under this section, but not to exceed $150,000, may be made available to carry out activities that develop the capacity of community housing development organizations in that jurisdiction.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s212/a">Pub. L. 102–550, § 212(a)</ref>, substituted “24” for “18”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbf9f6c02-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbf9f6c03-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1992 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/102/550">Pub. L. 102–550</ref> applicable to unexpended funds allocated under subchapter II of this chapter in fiscal year 1992, except as otherwise specifically provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/102/550/s223">section 223 of Pub. L. 102–550</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12704">section 12704 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
