<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbfa1b58b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12805"><num value="12805">§ 12805.</num><heading> Sweat equity model program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfa1b58c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12805/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall make available a model program to provide grants to public and private nonprofit organizations and community housing development organizations to provide technical and supervisory assistance to low-income and very low-income families, including the homeless, in acquiring, rehabilitating, and constructing housing by the self-help housing method.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfa1b58d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12805/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Rehabilitation of properties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The program shall target for rehabilitation properties which have been acquired by the Federal, State, or local governments.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfa1b58e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12805/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Homeownership opportunities through sweat equity</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbfa1b58f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12805/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The program shall utilize the skilled or unskilled labor of eligible families in exchange for acquisition of the property.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbfa1b590-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12805/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Training shall be provided to eligible families in building and home maintenance skills.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfa1b591-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12805/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Rental opportunities through sweat equity</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbfa1b592-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12805/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The program shall include rental opportunities for eligible families which will help expand the stock of affordable housing which is most appropriate for the target group.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbfa1b593-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12805/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The use of the tenant’s skilled or unskilled labor shall be encouraged in lieu of or as a supplement to rent payments by the tenant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfa1b594-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12805/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> “Self-help housing” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The term “self-help housing” means the same as in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1490c">section 1490c of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfa1b595-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12805/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional restrictions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The guidelines for the model program shall generally comport with the additional protections and restrictions specified under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1490c">section 1490c of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbfa1b596-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/625/tII/s255">Pub. L. 101–625, title II, § 255</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4121">104 Stat. 4121</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbfa1b597-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbfa1b598-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbfa1b599-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Assistance for Self-Help Housing Providers</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/120/s11">Pub. L. 104–120, § 11</ref>, <date date="1996-03-28">Mar. 28, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/841">110 Stat. 841</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/276/tV/s599E/a">Pub. L. 105–276, title V, § 599E(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2663">112 Stat. 2663</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/569/tII/s202">Pub. L. 106–569, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="2000-12-27">Dec. 27, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2951">114 Stat. 2951</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/285/s2">Pub. L. 108–285, § 2</ref>, <date date="2004-08-02">Aug. 2, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/917">118 Stat. 917</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/201/tV/s502">Pub. L. 114–201, title V, § 502</ref>, <date date="2016-07-29">July 29, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/811">130 Stat. 811</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/201/tV/s502">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Grant Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may, to the extent amounts are available to carry out this section and the requirements of this section are met, make grants for use in accordance with this section to national and regional organizations and consortia that have experience in providing or facilitating self-help housing homeownership opportunities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Goals and Accountability</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In making grants under this section, the Secretary shall take such actions as may be necessary to ensure that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> assistance provided under this section is used to facilitate and encourage innovative homeownership opportunities through the provision of self-help housing, under which the homeowner contributes a significant amount of sweat equity toward the construction of the new dwellings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> assistance provided under this section for land acquisition and infrastructure development results in the development of not less than 4,000 new dwellings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> the dwellings constructed in connection with assistance provided under this section are quality dwellings that comply with local building and safety codes and standards and are available at prices below the prevailing market prices;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> the provision of assistance under this section establishes and fosters a partnership between the Federal Government and organizations and consortia, resulting in efficient development of affordable housing with minimal governmental intervention, limited governmental regulation, and significant involvement by private entities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> activities to develop housing assisted pursuant to this section involve community participation in which volunteers assist in the construction of dwellings; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> dwellings are developed in connection with assistance under this section on a geographically diverse basis, which includes areas having high housing costs, rural areas, and areas underserved by other homeownership opportunities that are populated by low-income families unable to otherwise afford housing.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">If, at any time, the Secretary determines that the goals under this subsection cannot be met by providing assistance in accordance with the terms of this section, the Secretary shall immediately notify the applicable Committees in writing of such determination and any proposed changes for such goals or this section.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">National Competition</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall select organizations and consortia referred to in subsection (a) to receive grants through a national competitive process, which the Secretary shall establish.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Purpose</inline>.—</heading><content>Amounts from grants made under this section, including any recaptured amounts, shall be used only for eligible expenses in connection with developing new decent, safe, and sanitary nonluxury dwellings in the United States for families and persons who otherwise would be unable to afford to purchase a dwelling.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible expenses</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of paragraph (1), the term ‘eligible expenses’ means costs only for the following activities:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Land acquisition</inline>.—</heading><content>Acquiring land (including financing and closing costs), which may include reimbursing an organization, consortium, or affiliate, upon approval of any required environmental review, for nongrant amounts of the organization, consortium, or affiliate advanced before such review to acquire land.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Infrastructure improvement</inline>.—</heading><content>Installing, extending, constructing, rehabilitating, or otherwise improving utilities and other infrastructure.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I31" class="indent1 firstIndent0">Such term does not include any costs for the rehabilitation, improvement, or construction of dwellings.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment of Grant Fund.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Any amounts from any grant made under this section shall be deposited by the grantee organization or consortium in a fund that is established by such organization or consortium for such amounts, administered by such organization or consortium, and available for use only for the purposes under subsection (d). Any interest, fees, or other earnings of the fund shall be deposited in the fund and shall be considered grant amounts for purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Assistance to affiliates</inline>.—</heading><content>Any organization or consortia that receives a grant under this section may use amounts in the fund established for such organization or consortia pursuant to paragraph (1) for the purposes under subsection (d) by providing assistance from the fund to local affiliates of such organization or consortia.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements for Assistance</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary may make a grant to an organization or consortium under subsection (a) only pursuant to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> an expression of interest by such organization or consortia to the Secretary for a grant for such purposes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> a determination by the Secretary that the organization or consortia has the capability and has obtained financial commitments (or has the capacity to obtain financial commitments) necessary to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> develop not less than 30 dwellings in connection with the grant amounts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> otherwise comply with a grant agreement under subsection (i); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> a grant agreement entered into under subsection (i).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Energy Efficiency Requirements</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may not require any dwelling developed using amounts from a grant made under this section to meet any energy efficiency standards other than the standards applicable at such time pursuant to section 109 of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12709">42 U.S.C. 12709</ref>) to housing specified in subsection (a) of such section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Geographical Diversity</inline>.—</heading><content>In making grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall ensure that grants are provided and grant amounts are used in a manner that results in national geographic diversity among housing developed using grant amounts under this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Grant Agreement</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A grant under this section shall be made only pursuant to a grant agreement entered into by the Secretary and the organization or consortia receiving the grant, which shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> require such organization or consortia to use grant amounts only as provided in this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> provide for the organization or consortia to develop a specific and reasonable number of dwellings using the grant amounts, which number shall be established taking into consideration costs and economic conditions in the areas in which the dwellings will be developed, but in no case shall be less than 30;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> require the organization or consortia to use the grant amounts in a manner that leverages other sources of funding (other than grants under this section), including private or public funds, in developing the dwellings;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> require the organization or consortia to comply with the other provisions of this section;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> provide that the Secretary shall recapture any grant amounts provided to the organization or consortia that are not used within 24 months after such amounts are first disbursed to the organization or consortia, except that such period shall be 36 months in the case of grant amounts from amounts made available for fiscal year 1996 to carry out this section, and in the case of a [sic] grant amounts provided to a local affiliate of the organization or consortia that is developing five or more dwellings in connection with such grant amounts; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> contain such other terms as the Secretary may require to provide for compliance with subsection (b) and the requirements of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="j">“(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Fulfillment of Grant Agreement</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Secretary determines that an organization or consortia awarded a grant under this section has not, within 24 months after grant amounts are first made available to the organization or consortia (or, in the case of grant amounts from amounts made available for fiscal year 1996 to carry out this section and grant amounts provided to a local affiliate of the organization or consortia that is developing five or more dwellings in connection with such grant amounts, within 36 months), substantially fulfilled the obligations under the grant agreement, including development of the appropriate number of dwellings under the agreement, the Secretary shall use any such undisbursed amounts remaining from such grant for other grants in accordance with this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="k">“(k)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Records and Audits</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>During the period beginning upon the making of a grant under this section and ending upon close-out of the grant under subsection (<i>l</i>)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the organization awarded the grant shall keep such records and adopt such administrative practices as the Secretary may require to ensure compliance with the provisions of this section and the grant agreement; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Secretary and the Comptroller General of the United States, and any of their duly authorized representatives, shall have access for the purpose of audit and examination to any books, documents, papers, and records of the grantee organization or consortia and its affiliates that are pertinent to the grant made under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="l">“(l)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Close-Out</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall close out a grant made under this section upon determining that the aggregate amount of any assistance provided from the fund established under subsection (e)(1) by the grantee organization or consortium exceeds the amount of the grant. For purposes of this paragraph, any interest, fees, and other earnings of the fund shall be excluded from the amount of the grant.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="m">“(m)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Environmental Review</inline>.—</heading><content>A grant under this section shall be considered to be funds for a special project for purposes of section 305(c) of the Multifamily Housing Property Disposition Reform Act of 1994 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3547">42 U.S.C. 3547</ref>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="n">“(n)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after close-out of all grants under this section is completed, the Secretary shall submit a report to the applicable Committees describing the grants made under this section, the grantees, the housing developed in connection with the grant amounts, and the purposes for which the grant amounts were used.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="o">“(o)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applicable committees</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘applicable Committees’ means the Committee on Banking and Financial Services [now Committee on Financial Services] of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Secretary’ means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">United states</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘United States’ includes the States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="p">“(p)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2001.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="q">“(q)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Regulations</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall issue any final regulations necessary to carry out this section not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1996-03-28">Mar. 28, 1996</date>]. The regulations shall take effect upon issuance and may not exceed, in length, 5 full pages in the Federal Register.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>[<ref href="/us/pl/105/276/tV/s599E/b">Pub. L. 105–276, title V, § 599E(b)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2664">112 Stat. 2664</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/276/tV/s599E/b">“Notwithstanding the amendments made by subsection (a) [amending <ref href="/us/pl/104/120/s11">section 11 of Pub. L. 104–120</ref>, set out above], any grant under section 11 of the Housing Opportunity Program Extension Act of 1996 [<ref href="/us/pl/104/120">Pub. L. 104–120</ref>] (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s12805">42 U.S.C. 12805</ref> note) from amounts appropriated in fiscal year 1998 or any prior fiscal year shall be governed by the provisions of such section 11 as in effect immediately before the enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>], except that the amendments made by paragraphs (8) and (9) of subsection (a) of this section shall apply to such grants.”</quotedContent>
]</p>
<p>[<ref href="/us/pl/105/276/tV/s599E/c">Pub. L. 105–276, title V, § 599E(c)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2664">112 Stat. 2664</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/276/tV/s599E/c">“This section [amending <ref href="/us/pl/104/120/s11">section 11 of Pub. L. 104–120</ref>, set out above, and enacting provisions set out as a note above] shall take effect, and the amendments made by this section are made on, and shall apply beginning upon, the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>].”</quotedContent>
]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbfa1b59a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Funding for Self-Help Housing Assistance, National Cities in Schools Community Development Program, and Capacity Building Through National Community Development Initiative</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/120/s12">Pub. L. 104–120, § 12</ref>, <date date="1996-03-28">Mar. 28, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/845">110 Stat. 845</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/120/s12">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority to Use Assisted Housing Amounts</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>To the extent and for the purposes specified in subsection (b), the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may use amounts in the account of the Department of Housing and Urban Development known as the Annual Contributions for Assisted Housing account, but only such amounts which—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> have been appropriated for a fiscal year that occurs before the fiscal year for which the Secretary uses the amounts; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> have been obligated before becoming available for use under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Fiscal Year</inline> 1996.—</heading><chapeau>Of the amounts described in subsection (a), $60,000,000 shall be available to the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development for fiscal year 1996 in the following amounts for the following purposes:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Self-help housing assistance</inline>.—</heading><content>$40,000,000 for carrying out section 11 of this Act [set out above].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">National cities in schools community development program</inline>.—</heading><content>$10,000,000 for carrying out section 930 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 (<ref href="/us/pl/102/550">Public Law 102–550</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/106/3887">106 Stat. 3887</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Capacity building through national community development initiative</inline>.—</heading><content>$10,000,000 for carrying out section 4 of the HUD Demonstration Act of 1993 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s9816">42 U.S.C. 9816</ref> note).”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
