<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbfa4262d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12840"><num value="12840">§ 12840.</num><heading> Suspension of requirements for disaster areas</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For funds designated under this subchapter by a recipient to address the damage in an area for which the President has declared a disaster under title IV of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</ref> et seq.], the Secretary may suspend all statutory requirements for purposes of assistance under this subchapter for that area, except for those related to public notice of funding availability, nondiscrimination, fair housing, labor standards, environmental standards, and low-income housing affordability.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbfa4262e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/625/tII/s290">Pub. L. 101–625, title II, § 290</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/103/233/tII/s208">Pub. L. 103–233, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1994-04-11">Apr. 11, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/366">108 Stat. 366</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbfa4262f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbfa42630-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbfa42631-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/pl/93/288">Pub. L. 93–288</ref>, <date date="1974-05-22">May 22, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/143">88 Stat. 143</ref>. Title IV of the Act is classified generally to subchapter IV (§ 5170 et seq.) of chapter 68 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5121">section 5121 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbfa42632-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idbfa42633-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section applicable with respect to any amounts made available to carry out this subchapter after <date date="1994-04-11">Apr. 11, 1994</date>, and any amounts made available to carry out this subchapter before that date that remain uncommitted on that date, with Secretary to issue any regulations necessary to carry out this section not later than end of 45-day period beginning on that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/233/s209">section 209 of Pub. L. 103–233</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1994 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5301">section 5301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
