<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbfa8e1ea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12895"><num value="12895">§ 12895.</num><heading> Other program requirements</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfa8e1eb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12895/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Cost limitations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may establish cost limitations on eligible activities under this part, subject to the provisions of this part.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfa8e1ec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12895/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of proceeds from sales to eligible families</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any entity that transfers ownership interests in, or shares representing, units to eligible families, or another entity specified in the approved application, may use the proceeds, if any, from the initial sale for costs of the homeownership program, including operating expenses, improvements to the project, business opportunities for low-income families, supportive services related to the homeownership program, additional homeownership opportunities, and other activities approved by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfa8e1ed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12895/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Restrictions on resale by homeowners</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbfa8e1ee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12895/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbfa8e1ef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12895/c/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer permitted</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A homeowner under a homeownership program may transfer the homeowner’s ownership interest in, or shares representing, the unit, except that a homeownership program may establish restrictions on the resale of units under the program.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbfa8e1f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12895/c/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Right to purchase</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Where a resident management corporation, resident council, or cooperative has jurisdiction over the unit, the corporation, council, or cooperative shall have the right to purchase the ownership interest in, or shares representing, the unit from the homeowner for the amount specified in a firm contract between the homeowner and a prospective buyer. If such an entity does not have jurisdiction over the unit or elects not to purchase and if the prospective buyer is not a low-income family, the public housing agency or the implementation grant recipient shall have the right to purchase the ownership interest in, or shares representing, the unit for the same amount.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbfa8e1f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12895/c/1/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Promissory note required</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The homeowner shall execute a promissory note equal to the difference between the market value and the purchase price, payable to the public housing agency or other entity designated in the homeownership plan, together with a mortgage securing the obligation of the note.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbfa8e1f2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12895/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> 6 years or less</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of a transfer within 6 years of the acquisition under the program, the homeownership program shall provide for appropriate restrictions to assure that an eligible family may not receive any undue profit. The plan shall provide for limiting the family’s consideration for its interest in the property to the total of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbfa8e1f3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12895/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the contribution to equity paid by the family;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbfa8e1f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12895/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the value, as determined by such means as the Secretary shall determine through regulation, of any improvements installed at the expense of the family during the family’s tenure as owner; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbfa8e1f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12895/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the appreciated value determined by an inflation allowance at a rate which may be based on a cost-of-living index, an income index, or market index as determined by the Secretary through regulation and agreed to by the purchaser and the entity that transfers ownership interests in, or shares representing, units to eligible families (or another entity specified in the approved application), at the time of initial sale, and applied against the contribution to equity.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">Such an entity may, at the time of initial sale, enter into an agreement with the family to set a maximum amount which this appreciation may not exceed.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbfa8e1f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12895/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> 6–20 years</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of a transfer during the period beginning 6 years after the acquisition and ending 20 years after the acquisition, the homeownership program shall provide for the recapture by the Secretary or the program of an amount equal to the amount of the declining balance on the note described in paragraph (1)(C).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbfa8e1f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12895/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of recaptured funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Fifty percent of any portion of the net sales proceeds that may not be retained by the homeowner under the plan approved pursuant to this subsection shall be paid to the entity that transferred ownership interests in, or shares representing, units to eligible families, or another entity specified in the approved application, for use for improvements to the project, business opportunities for low-income families, supportive services related to the homeownership program, additional homeownership opportunities, and other activities approved by the Secretary. The remaining 50 percent shall be returned to the Secretary for use under this part, subject to limitations contained in appropriations Acts. Such entity shall keep and make available to the Secretary all records necessary to calculate accurately payments due the Secretary under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfa8e1f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12895/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Third party rights</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The requirements under this part regarding quality standards, resale, or transfer of the ownership interest of a homeowner shall be judicially enforceable against the grant recipient with respect to actions involving rehabilitation, and against purchasers of property under this subsection or their successors in interest with respect to other actions by affected low-income families, resident management corporations, resident councils, public housing agencies, and any agency, corporation, or authority of the United States Government. The parties specified in the preceding sentence shall be entitled to reasonable attorney fees upon prevailing in any such judicial action.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfa8e1f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12895/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Protection of nonpurchasing families</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No tenant residing in a dwelling unit in a property on the date the Secretary approves an application for an implementation grant may be evicted by reason of a homeownership program approved under this part.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfa8e1fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12895/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004131">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn004131"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “(f)”.</note> Records and audit of recipients of assistance</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbfa8e1fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12895/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each recipient shall keep such records as may be reasonably necessary to fully disclose the amount and the disposition by such recipient of the proceeds of assistance received under this part (and any proceeds from financing obtained or sales under subsections (b) and (c)), the total cost of the homeownership program in connection with which such assistance is given or used, and the amount and nature of that portion of the program supplied by other sources, and such other sources as will facilitate an effective audit.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbfa8e1fc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12895/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Access by Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall have access for the purpose of audit and examination to any books, documents, papers, and records of the recipient that are pertinent to assistance received under this part.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbfa8e1fd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s12895/h/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Access by Comptroller General</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Comptroller General of the United States, or any of the duly authorized representatives of the Comptroller General, shall also have access for the purpose of audit and examination to any books, documents, papers, and records of the recipient that are pertinent to assistance received under this part.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbfa8e1fe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/625/tIV/s445">Pub. L. 101–625, title IV, § 445</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4177">104 Stat. 4177</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
