<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb81b2279-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1307"><num value="1307">§ 1307.</num><heading> Penalty for fraud</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb81b227a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1307/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Whoever, with the intent to defraud any person, shall make or cause to be made any false representation concerning the requirements of this chapter, of chapter 2, 21, or 23 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, or of any provision of subtitle F of such Code which corresponds (within the meaning of section 7852(b) of such Code) to a provision contained in subchapter E of chapter 9 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939, or of any rules or regulations issued thereunder, knowing such representations to be false, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and, upon conviction thereof, shall be punished by a fine not exceeding $1,000, or by imprisonment not exceeding one year, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb81b227b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1307/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Whoever, with the intent to elicit information as to the social security account number, date of birth, employment, wages, or benefits of any individual (1) falsely represents to the Commissioner of Social Security or the Secretary that he is such individual, or the wife, husband, widow, widower, divorced wife, divorced husband, surviving divorced wife, surviving divorced husband, surviving divorced mother, surviving divorced father, child, or parent of such individual, or the duly authorized agent of such individual, or of the wife, husband, widow, widower, divorced wife, divorced husband, surviving divorced wife, surviving divorced husband, surviving divorced mother, surviving divorced father, child, or parent of such individual, or (2) falsely represents to any person that he is an employee or agent of the United States, shall be deemed guilty of a felony, and, upon conviction thereof, shall be punished by a fine not exceeding $10,000 for each occurrence of a violation, or by imprisonment not exceeding 5 years, or both.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb81b227c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, title XI, § 1107, as added <ref href="/us/act/1939-08-10/ch666">Aug. 10, 1939, ch. 666</ref>, title VIII, § 802, <ref href="/us/stat/53/1398">53 Stat. 1398</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/act/1950-08-28/ch809">Aug. 28, 1950, ch. 809</ref>, title IV, § 403(e), (f), <ref href="/us/stat/64/560">64 Stat. 560</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tVI/s2663/e/2/A">Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title VI, § 2663(e)(2)(A)</ref>, (3), (j)(2)(D)(iii), (<i>l</i>)(1), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1168">98 Stat. 1168</ref>, 1170, 1171; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/tI/s108/b/6">Pub. L. 103–296, title I, § 108(b)(6)</ref>, title III, § 313(b), <date date="1994-08-15">Aug. 15, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1482">108 Stat. 1482</ref>, 1530.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb81b227d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb81b227e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb81b227f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subchapter E of chapter 9 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939, referred to in subsec. (a), was comprised of sections 1631 to 1636 of the 1939 Code, and was repealed (subject to certain exceptions) by section 7851(a)(1)(A), (3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954, Title 26. The Internal Revenue Code of 1954 was redesignated the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>. For table of comparisons of the 1939 Code to the 1986 Code, see Table I preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code. See also <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s7852/b">section 7852(b) of Title 26</ref> for provision that references in any other law to a provision of the 1939 Code, unless expressly incompatible with the intent thereof, shall be deemed a reference to the corresponding provision of the 1986 Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provision deeming a reference in other laws to a provision of the 1939 Code as a reference to the corresponding provisions of the 1986 Code, see section 7852(b) of the 1986 Code. For table of comparisons of the 1939 Code to the 1986 Code, see table preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s1">section 1 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code. The Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is classified generally to Title 26.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb81b2280-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s313/b">Pub. L. 103–296, § 313(b)</ref>, inserted “social security account number,” after “information as to the” and substituted “felony” for “misdemeanor”, “$10,000 for each occurrence of a violation” for “$1,000”, and “5 years” for “one year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s108/b/6">Pub. L. 103–296, § 108(b)(6)</ref>, which directed that subsec. (b) be amended by substituting “the Commissioner of Social Security or the Secretary” for “the Secretary of Health and Human Services”, was executed by making the substitution for “the Secretary” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> substituted “Internal Revenue Code of 1986” for “Internal Revenue Code of 1954”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2663/e/2/A">Pub. L. 98–369, § 2663(e)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “of chapter 2, 21, or 23 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954, or of any provision of subtitle F of such Code which corresponds (within the meaning of section 7852(b) of such Code) to a provision contained in subchapter E of chapter 9 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939,” for “subchapter E of chapter 1 or subchapter A, C, or E of chapter 9 of the Internal Revenue Code [of 1939]”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2663">Pub. L. 98–369, § 2663</ref>(<i>l</i>)(1), substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2663/j/2/D/iii">Pub. L. 98–369, § 2663(j)(2)(D)(iii)</ref>, which directed the substitution of “Health and Human Services” for “Health, Education, and Welfare” could not be executed because “Health, Education, and Welfare” did not appear in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2663/e/3">Pub. L. 98–369, § 2663(e)(3)</ref>, substituted “divorced wife, divorced husband, surviving divorced wife, surviving divorced husband, surviving divorced mother, surviving divorced father,” for “former wife divorced,” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1950—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1950-08-28">Aug. 28, 1950</date>, § 403(e), substituted “subchapter E of chapter 1 or subchapter A, C, or E of chapter 9 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939,” for “the Federal Insurance Contributions Act, or the Federal Unemployment Tax Act,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). Act <date date="1950-08-28">Aug. 28, 1950</date>, § 403(f), substituted “Administrator” for “Board” and “wife, husband, widow, widower, former wife divorced, child, or parent” for “wife, parent, or child” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb81d6c71-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb81d6c72-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s108/b/6">section 108(b)(6) of Pub. L. 103–296</ref> effective <date date="1995-03-31">Mar. 31, 1995</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s110/a">section 110(a) of Pub. L. 103–296</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s313/b">section 313(b) of Pub. L. 103–296</ref> applicable to violations occurring on or after <date date="1994-08-15">Aug. 15, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s313/c">section 313(c) of Pub. L. 103–296</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1306">section 1306 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb81d6c73-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tVI/s2663/e/2/B">Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title VI, § 2663(e)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1168">98 Stat. 1168</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tVI/s2663/e/2/B">“The amendment made by subparagraph (A) [amending this section] shall not apply to returns filed or representations made on or before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 2663(e)(3), (j)(2)(D)(iii), (<i>l</i>)(1) of <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> effective <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, but not to be construed as changing or affecting any right, liability, status, or interpretation which existed (under the provisions of law involved) before that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2664/b">section 2664(b) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
