<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb84d2e8c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11"><num value="1320b–11">§ 1320b–11.</num><heading> Blood donor locator service</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb84d2e8d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commissioner of Social Security shall establish and conduct a Blood Donor Locator Service, which shall be used to obtain and transmit to any authorized person (as defined in subsection (h)(1)) the most recent mailing address of any blood donor who, as indicated by the donated blood or products derived therefrom or by the history of the subsequent use of such blood or blood products, has or may have the virus for acquired immune deficiency syndrome, in order to inform such donor of the possible need for medical care and treatment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb84d2e8e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Provision of address information</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever the Commissioner of Social Security receives a request, filed by an authorized person (as defined in subsection (h)(1)), for the mailing address of a donor described in subsection (a) and the Commissioner of Social Security is reasonably satisfied that the requirements of this section have been met with respect to such request, the Commissioner of Social Security shall promptly undertake to provide the requested address information from—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb84d2e8f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the files and records maintained by the Social Security Administration, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb84d2e90-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> such files and records obtained pursuant to section 6103(m)(6) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 as the Commissioner of Social Security considers necessary to comply with such request.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb84d2e91-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Manner and form of requests</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A request for address information under this section shall be filed in such manner and form as the Commissioner of Social Security shall by regulation prescribe, shall include the blood donor’s social security account number, and shall be accompanied or supported by such documents as the Commissioner of Social Security may determine to be necessary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb84d2e92-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedures and safeguards</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any authorized person shall, as a condition for receiving address information from the Blood Donor Locator Service—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb84d2e93-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> establish and maintain, to the satisfaction of the Commissioner of Social Security, a system for standardizing records with respect to any request, the reason for such request, and the date of such request made by or of it and any disclosure of address information made by or to it,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb84d2e94-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> establish and maintain, to the satisfaction of the Commissioner of Social Security, a secure area or place in which such address information and all related blood donor records shall be stored,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb84d2e95-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> restrict, to the satisfaction of the Commissioner of Social Security, access to the address information and related blood donor records only to persons whose duties or responsibilities require access and to whom disclosure may be made under the provisions of this section,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb84d2e96-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> provide such other safeguards which the Commissioner of Social Security determines (and which the Commissioner of Social Security prescribes in regulations) to be necessary or appropriate to protect the confidentiality of the address information and related blood donor records,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb84d2e97-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> furnish a report to the Commissioner of Social Security, at such time and containing such information as the Commissioner of Social Security may prescribe, which describes the procedures established and utilized by the authorized person for ensuring the confidentiality of address information and related blood donor records required under this subsection, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb84d2e98-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> destroy such address information and related blood donor records, upon completion of their use in providing the notification for which the information was obtained, so as to make such information and records undisclosable.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">If the Commissioner of Social Security determines that any authorized person has failed to, or does not, meet the requirements of this subsection, the Commissioner of Social Security may, after any proceedings for review established under subsection (f), take such actions as are necessary to ensure such requirements are met, including refusing to disclose address information to such authorized person until the Commissioner of Social Security determines that such requirements have been or will be met. In the case of any authorized person who discloses any address information received pursuant to this section or any related blood donor records to any agent, this subsection shall apply to such authorized person and each such agent (except that, in the case of an agent, any report to the Commissioner of Social Security or other action with respect to the Commissioner of Social Security shall be made or taken through such authorized person). The Commissioner of Social Security shall destroy all related blood donor records in the possession of the Social Security Administration upon completion of their use in transmitting mailing addresses as required under subsection (a), so as to make such records undisclosable.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb84d2e99-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Arrangements with State agencies and authorized persons</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commissioner of Social Security, in carrying out the Commissioner’s duties and functions under this section, shall enter into arrangements—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb84d2e9a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> with State agencies to accept and to transmit to the Commissioner of Social Security requests for address information under this section and to accept and to transmit such information to authorized persons, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb84d2e9b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> with State agencies and authorized persons otherwise to cooperate with the Commissioner of Social Security in carrying out the purposes of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb84d2e9c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedures for administrative review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commissioner of Social Security shall by regulation prescribe procedures which provide for administrative review of any determination that any authorized person has failed to meet the requirements of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb84d2e9d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Unauthorized disclosure of information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of section 7213(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall apply with respect to the unauthorized willful disclosure to any person of address information or related blood donor records acquired or maintained by or under the Commissioner of Social Security, or pursuant to this section by any authorized person, or of information derived from any such address information or related blood donor records, in the same manner and to the same extent as such paragraphs apply with respect to unauthorized disclosures of return and return information described in such paragraphs. Paragraph (4) of section 7213(a) of such Code shall apply with respect to the willful offer of any item of material value in exchange for any such address information or related blood donor record in the same manner and to the same extent as such paragraph applies with respect to offers (in exchange for any return or return information) described in such paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb84d2e9e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb84d2e9f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorized person</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “authorized person” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb84d2ea0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> any agency of a State (or of a political subdivision of a State) which has duties or authority under State law relating to the public health or otherwise has the duty or authority under State law to regulate blood donations, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb84d2ea1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> any entity engaged in the acceptance of blood donations which is licensed or registered by the Food and Drug Administration in connection with the acceptance of such blood donations, and which, in accordance with such regulations as may be prescribed by the Commissioner of Social Security, provides for—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb84d2ea2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/h/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the confidentiality of any address information received pursuant to this section and related blood donor records,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb84d2ea3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/h/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> blood donor notification procedures for individuals with respect to whom such information is requested and a finding has been made that they have or may have the virus for acquired immune deficiency syndrome, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb84d2ea4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/h/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> counseling services for such individuals who have been found to have such virus.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb84d2ea5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Related blood donor record</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “related blood donor record” means any record, list, or compilation which indicates, directly or indirectly, the identity of any individual with respect to whom a request for address information has been made pursuant to this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb84d2ea6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–11/h/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> State</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Marianas, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb84d2ea7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, title XI, § 1141, as added <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tVIII/s8008/b/1">Pub. L. 100–647, title VIII, § 8008(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3784">102 Stat. 3784</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/tI/s108/b/13">Pub. L. 103–296, title I, § 108(b)(13)</ref>, <date date="1994-08-15">Aug. 15, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1484">108 Stat. 1484</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb84d2ea8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb84d2ea9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb84d2eaa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Internal Revenue Code of 1986, referred to in subsecs. (b)(2) and (g), is classified generally to Title 26, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb84d2eab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s108/b/13/A">Pub. L. 103–296, § 108(b)(13)(A)</ref>, (C), substituted “The Commissioner of Social Security” for “The Secretary” and struck out “under the direction of the Commissioner of Social Security,” before “which shall be used”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s108/b/13/A">Pub. L. 103–296, § 108(b)(13)(A)</ref>, substituted “Commissioner of Social Security” for “Secretary” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s108/b/13/D">Pub. L. 103–296, § 108(b)(13)(D)</ref>, which directed amendment of par. (6) by substituting “Social Security Administration” for “Department of Health Services”, was executed by substituting “Social Security Administration” for “Department of Health and Human Services” in closing provisions to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s108/b/13/A">Pub. L. 103–296, § 108(b)(13)(A)</ref>, substituted “Commissioner of Social Security” for “Secretary” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s108/b/13/A">Pub. L. 103–296, § 108(b)(13)(A)</ref>, (B), substituted “Commissioner of Social Security” for “Secretary” wherever appearing and “Commissioner’s” for “Secretary’s” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (f), (g), (h)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s108/b/13/A">Pub. L. 103–296, § 108(b)(13)(A)</ref>, substituted “Commissioner of Social Security” for “Secretary”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb84d2eac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb84d2ead-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/296">Pub. L. 103–296</ref> effective <date date="1995-03-31">Mar. 31, 1995</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s110/a">section 110(a) of Pub. L. 103–296</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb84d2eae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Time Limit for Establishment of Blood Donor Locator Service</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tVIII/s8008/b/2">Pub. L. 100–647, title VIII, § 8008(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3786">102 Stat. 3786</ref>, required the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish the Blood Donor Locator Service pursuant to this section no later than 180 days after <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idb84d2eaf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb84d2eb0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, see note set out preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1681">section 1681 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
