<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb829531e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1"><num value="1320a–1">§ 1320a–1.</num><heading> Limitation on use of Federal funds for capital expenditures</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb829531f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of reimbursement for planning activities for health services and facilities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The purpose of this section is to assure that Federal funds appropriated under subchapters XVIII and XIX are not used to support unnecessary capital expenditures made by or on behalf of health care facilities which are reimbursed under any of such subchapters and that, to the extent possible, reimbursement under such subchapters shall support planning activities with respect to health services and facilities in the various States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8295320-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Agreement between Secretary and State for submission of proposed capital expenditures related to health care facilities and procedures for appeal from recommendations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, after consultation with the Governor (or other chief executive officer) and with appropriate local public officials, shall make an agreement with any State which is able and willing to do so under which a designated planning agency (which shall be an agency described in clause (ii) of subsection (d)(1)(B) that has a governing body or advisory board at least half of whose members represent consumer interests) will—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8295321-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> make, and submit to the Secretary together with such supporting materials as he may find necessary, findings and recommendations with respect to capital expenditures proposed by or on behalf of any health care facility in such State within the field of its responsibilities,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8295322-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> receive from other agencies described in clause (ii) of subsection (d)(1)(B), and submit to the Secretary together with such supporting material as he may find necessary, the findings and recommendations of such other agencies with respect to capital expenditures proposed by or on behalf of health care facilities in such State within the fields of their respective responsibilities, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8295323-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> establish and maintain procedures pursuant to which a person proposing any such capital expenditure may appeal a recommendation by the designated agency and will be granted an opportunity for a fair hearing by such agency or person other than the designated agency as the Governor (or other chief executive officer) may designate to hold such hearings,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">whenever and to the extent that the findings of such designated agency or any such other agency indicate that any such expenditure is not consistent with the standards, criteria, or plans developed pursuant to the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">42 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.] to meet the need for adequate health care facilities in the area covered by the plan or plans so developed.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb82bc424-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Manner of payment to States for carrying out agreement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall pay any such State from the general fund in the Treasury, in advance or by way of reimbursement as may be provided in the agreement with it (and may make adjustments in such payments on account of overpayments or underpayments previously made), for the reasonable cost of performing the functions specified in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb82bc425-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination of amount of exclusions from Federal payments</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb82bc426-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in paragraph (2), if the Secretary determines that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb82bc427-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> neither the planning agency designated in the agreement described in subsection (b) nor an agency described in clause (ii) of subparagraph (B) of this paragraph had been given notice of any proposed capital expenditure (in accordance with such procedure or in such detail as may be required by such agency) at least 60 days prior to obligation for such expenditure; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb82bc428-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb82bc429-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/d/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the planning agency so designated or an agency so described had received such timely notice of the intention to make such capital expenditure and had, within a reasonable period after receiving such notice and prior to obligation for such expenditure, notified the person proposing such expenditure that the expenditure would not be in conformity with the standards, criteria, or plans developed by such agency or any other agency described in clause (ii) for adequate health care facilities in such State or in the area for which such other agency has responsibility, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb82bc42a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/d/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> the planning agency so designated had, prior to submitting to the Secretary the findings referred to in subsection (b)—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb82bc42b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/d/1/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> consulted with, and taken into consideration the findings and recommendations of, the State planning agencies established pursuant to sections 314(a) and 604(a) of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s246/a">42 U.S.C. 246(a)</ref>, 291d(a)] (to the extent that either such agency is not the agency so designated) as well as the public or nonprofit private agency or organization responsible for the comprehensive regional, metropolitan area, or other local area plan or plans referred to in section 314(b) of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s246/b">42 U.S.C. 246(b)</ref>] and covering the area in which the health care facility proposing such capital expenditure is located (where such agency is not the agency designated in the agreement), or, if there is no such agency, such other public or nonprofit private agency or organization (if any) as performs, as determined in accordance with criteria included in regulations, similar functions, and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb82bc42c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/d/1/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> granted to the person proposing such capital expenditure an opportunity for a fair hearing with respect to such findings;</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">then, for such period as he finds necessary in any case to effectuate the purpose of this section, he shall, in determining the Federal payments to be made under subchapters XVIII and XIX with respect to services furnished in the health care facility for which such capital expenditure is made, not include any amount which is attributable to depreciation, interest on borrowed funds, a return on equity capital (in the case of proprietary facilities), or other expenses related to such capital expenditure. With respect to any organization which is reimbursed on a per capita or a fixed fee or negotiated rate basis, in determining the Federal payments to be made under subchapters XVIII and XIX, the Secretary shall exclude an amount which in his judgment is a reasonable equivalent to the amount which would otherwise be excluded under this subsection if payment were to be made on other than a per capita or a fixed fee or negotiated rate basis.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb82bc42d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If the Secretary, after submitting the matters involved to the advisory council established or designated under subsection (i), determines that an exclusion of expenses related to any capital expenditure of any health care facility would discourage the operation or expansion of such facility which has demonstrated to his satisfaction proof of capability to provide comprehensive health care services (including institutional services) efficiently, effectively, and economically, or would otherwise be inconsistent with the effective organization and delivery of health services or the effective administration of subchapter XVIII or XIX, he shall not exclude such expenses pursuant to paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb82bc42e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of lease or comparable arrangement of any facility or equipment for a facility in determining amount of exclusions from Federal payments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Where a person obtains under lease or comparable arrangement any facility or part thereof, or equipment for a facility, which would have been subject to an exclusion under subsection (d) if the person had acquired it by purchase, the Secretary shall (1) in computing such person’s rental expense in determining the Federal payments to be made under subchapters XVIII and XIX with respect to services furnished in such facility, deduct the amount which in his judgment is a reasonable equivalent of the amount that would have been excluded if the person had acquired such facility or such equipment by purchase, and (2) in computing such person’s return on equity capital deduct any amount deposited under the terms of the lease or comparable arrangement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb82bc42f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Reconsideration by Secretary of determinations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person dissatisfied with a determination by the Secretary under this section may within six months following notification of such determination request the Secretary to reconsider such determination. A determination by the Secretary under this section shall not be subject to administrative or judicial review.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb82bc430-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> “Capital expenditure” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this section, a “capital expenditure” is an expenditure which, under generally accepted accounting principles, is not properly chargeable as an expense of operation and maintenance and which (1) exceeds $600,000 (or such lesser amount as the State may establish), (2) changes the bed capacity of the facility with respect to which such expenditure is made, or (3) substantially changes the services of the facility with respect to which such expenditure is made. For purposes of clause (1) of the preceding sentence, the cost of the studies, surveys, designs, plans, working drawings, specifications, and other activities essential to the acquisition, improvement, expansion, or replacement of the plant and equipment with respect to which such expenditure is made shall be included in determining whether such expenditure exceeds the dollar amount specified in clause (1).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb82bc431-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability to Christian Science sanatoriums</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of this section shall not apply to a religious nonmedical health care institution (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/ss/1">section 1395x(ss)(1) of this title</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb82bc432-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> National advisory council; establishment or designation of existing council; functions; consultations with other appropriate national advisory councils; composition; compensation and travel expenses</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb82bc433-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/i/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary shall establish a national advisory council, or designate an appropriate existing national advisory council, to advise and assist him in the preparation of general regulations to carry out the purposes of this section and on policy matters arising in the administration of this section, including the coordination of activities under this section with those under other parts of this chapter or under other Federal or federally assisted health programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb82bc434-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/i/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall make appropriate provision for consultation between and coordination of the work of the advisory council established or designated under paragraph (1) and the Federal Hospital Council, the National Advisory Health Council, the Health Insurance Benefits Advisory Council, and other appropriate national advisory councils with respect to matters bearing on the purposes and administration of this section and the coordination of activities under this section with related Federal health programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb82bc435-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/i/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If an advisory council is established by the Secretary under paragraph (1), it shall be composed of members who are not otherwise in the regular full-time employ of the United States, and who shall be appointed by the Secretary without regard to the civil service laws from among leaders in the fields of the fundamental sciences, the medical sciences, and the organization, delivery, and financing of health care, and persons who are State or local officials or are active in community affairs or public or civic affairs or who are representative of minority groups. Members of such advisory council, while attending meetings of the council or otherwise serving on business of the council, shall be entitled to receive compensation at rates fixed by the Secretary, but not exceeding the maximum rate specified at the time of such service for grade GS–18 in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5332">section 5332 of title 5</ref>, including traveltime, and while away from their homes or regular places of business they may also be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized by section 5703 of such title 5 for persons in the Government service employed intermittently.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb82bc436-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Capital expenditure review exception for eligible organization health care facilities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A capital expenditure made by or on behalf of a health care facility shall not be subject to review pursuant to this section if 75 percent of the patients who can reasonably be expected to use the service with respect to which the capital expenditure is made will be individuals enrolled in an eligible organization as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395mm/b">section 1395mm(b) of this title</ref>, and if the Secretary determines that such capital expenditure is for services and facilities which are needed by such organization in order to operate efficiently and economically and which are not otherwise readily accessible to such organization because—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb82bc437-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the facilities do not provide common services at the same site (as usually provided by the organization),</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb82bc438-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the facilities are not available under a contract of reasonable duration,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb82bc439-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/j/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> full and equal medical staff privileges in the facilities are not available,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb82bc43a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/j/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> arrangements with such facilities are not administratively feasible, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb82bc43b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1/j/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the purchase of such services is more costly than if the organization provided the services directly.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb82bc43c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, title XI, § 1122, as added <ref href="/us/pl/92/603/tII/s221/a">Pub. L. 92–603, title II, § 221(a)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-30">Oct. 30, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1386">86 Stat. 1386</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/93/233/s18/z">Pub. L. 93–233, § 18(z)</ref>, (z–1), <date date="1973-12-31">Dec. 31, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/973">87 Stat. 973</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/559/s14/b">Pub. L. 95–559, § 14(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2141">92 Stat. 2141</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/32/s2/c">Pub. L. 96–32, § 2(c)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-10">July 10, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/82">93 Stat. 82</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXI/s2193/c/3">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXI, § 2193(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/827">95 Stat. 827</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/tI/s137/a/5">Pub. L. 97–248, title I, § 137(a)(5)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/376">96 Stat. 376</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/21/tVI/s607/a">Pub. L. 98–21, title VI, § 607(a)</ref>, (b)(1), (c), <date date="1983-04-20">Apr. 20, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/171">97 Stat. 171</ref>, 172; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tIII/s2354/a/1">Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title III, § 2354(a)(1)</ref>, (2), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1100">98 Stat. 1100</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tIV/s4454/c/1">Pub. L. 105–33, title IV, § 4454(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/431">111 Stat. 431</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb82bc43d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb82bc43e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb82bc43f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Public Health Service Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">act July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/58/682">58 Stat. 682</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 6A (201 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">section 201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb82bc440-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref> substituted “a religious nonmedical health care institution (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/ss/1">section 1395x(ss)(1) of this title</ref>).” for “Christian Science sanatoriums operated, or listed and certified, by the First Church of Christ, Scientist, Boston, Massachusetts.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2354/a/1">Pub. L. 98–369, § 2354(a)(1)</ref>, substituted a comma for the period at end of par. (1), and struck out “(or the Mental Retardation Facilities and Community Mental Health Centers Construction Act of 1963)” before “to meet the need” in provisions following par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2354/a/2">Pub. L. 98–369, § 2354(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “5703” for “5703(b)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/98/21/s607/a">Pub. L. 98–21, § 607(a)</ref>, substituted “the general fund in the Treasury” for “the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/98/21/s607/b/1">Pub. L. 98–21, § 607(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “$600,000 (or such lesser amount as the State may establish)” for “$100,000” and <ref href="/us/pl/98/21/s607/b/1/B">Pub. L. 98–21, § 607(b)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “the dollar amount specified in clause (1)” for “$100,000” the second time it appeared.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/98/21/s607/c">Pub. L. 98–21, § 607(c)</ref>, added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248">Pub. L. 97–248</ref> amended directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2193/c/3/B">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2193(c)(3)(B)</ref>, to correct typographical error, and did not involve any change in text. See 1981 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2193/c/3/A">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2193(c)(3)(A)</ref>, substituted “subchapters XVIII and XIX” for “subchapters V, XVIII, and XIX”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2193/c/3/A">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2193(c)(3)(A)</ref>, substituted in provision following subpar. (B)(ii)(II) “subchapters XVIII and XIX” for “subchapters V, XVIII, and XIX” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2193/c/3/B">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2193(c)(3)(B)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s137/a/5">Pub. L. 97–248, § 137(a)(5)</ref>, substituted “subchapter XVIII or XIX” for “subchapter V, XVIII, or XIX”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2193/c/3/A">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2193(c)(3)(A)</ref>, substituted “subchapters XVIII and XIX” for “subchapters V, XVIII, and XIX”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—<ref href="/us/pl/96/32">Pub. L. 96–32</ref> amended directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/95/559">Pub. L. 95–559</ref> and required no change in text of section. See 1978 Amendment notes below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsecs. (a), (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/559/s14/b/1">Pub. L. 95–559, § 14(b)(1)</ref>, (2), as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/96/32">Pub. L. 96–32</ref>, struck out references to health maintenance organizations wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/559/s14/b/1">Pub. L. 95–559, § 14(b)(1)</ref>, (3), as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/96/32">Pub. L. 96–32</ref>, struck out references to health maintenance organizations wherever appearing and in par. (2) “or organization, or of any facility of such organization,” after “expansion of such facility”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/93/233/s18/z">Pub. L. 93–233, § 18(z)</ref>, inserted “or a fixed fee or negotiated rate” after “per capita” wherever appearing in last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/93/233/s18">Pub. L. 93–233, § 18</ref>(z–1), substituted “exclude” for “include” where last appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb82bc441-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb82bc442-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref> effective <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, and applicable to items and services furnished on or after such date, with provision that Secretary of Health and Human Services issue regulations to carry out such amendment by not later than <date date="1998-07-01">July 1, 1998</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s4454/d">section 4454(d) of Pub. L. 105–33</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395i–5">section 1395i–5 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb82bc443-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tIII/s2354/e">Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title III, § 2354(e)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1102">98 Stat. 1102</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tIII/s2354/e">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 1316, 1320a–7a, 1320a–8, 1395f, 1395i, 1395i–2, 1395k, 1395<i>l</i>, 1395n, 1395p, 1395s to 1395z, 1395aa, 1395cc, 1395ff, 1395ii, 1395<i>ll</i>, 1395mm, 1395<i>oo</i>, 1395rr, and 1395ww of this title and <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s162">section 162 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code, and amending provisions set out as notes under sections 1320c, 1395x, and 1395mm of this title] shall be effective on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>]; but none of such amendments shall be construed as changing or affecting any right, liability, status, or interpretation which existed (under the provisions of law involved) before that date.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The amendments made by paragraphs (1) [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395f">section 1395f of this title</ref> and provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x">section 1395x of this title</ref>], (2) [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1316">section 1316 of this title</ref>], and (3) [amending provisions set out as notes under sections 1320c and 1395mm of this title] of subsection (c) shall be effective as if they had been originally included in Public Laws 96–499, 97–35, and 97–248, respectively.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb82bc444-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/248">Pub. L. 97–248</ref> effective as if originally included as part of this section as this section was amended by the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1981, <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s137/d/2">section 137(d)(2) of Pub. L. 97–248</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396a">section 1396a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb82bc445-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment, Savings, and Transitional Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date, savings, and transitional provisions relating to amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2194">section 2194 of Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s701">section 701 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb82bc446-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/92/603/tII/s221/b">Pub. L. 92–603, title II, § 221(b)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-30">Oct. 30, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1389">86 Stat. 1389</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/92/603/tII/s221/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [enacting this section] shall apply only with respect to a capital expenditure the obligation for which is incurred by or on behalf of a health care facility or health maintenance organization subsequent to whichever of the following is earlier: (A) <date date="1972-12-31">December 31, 1972</date>, or (B) with respect to any State or any part thereof specified by such State, the last day of the calendar quarter in which the State requests that the amendment made by subsection (a) of this section [enacting this section] apply in such State or such part thereof.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb82bc447-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Advisory Councils</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Advisory councils in existence on <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period following <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, unless, in the case of a council established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such council is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a council established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided by law. Advisory councils established after <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on the date of their establishment, unless, in the case of a council established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such council is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a council established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided by law. See sections 1001(2) and 1013 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb82bc448-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Other Laws to GS–16, 17, or 18 Pay Rates</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References in laws to the rates of pay for GS–16, 17, or 18, or to maximum rates of pay under the General Schedule, to be considered references to rates payable under specified sections of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, see section 529 [title I, § 101(c)(1)] of <ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref>, set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5376">section 5376 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb82bc449-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Expenditures or Obligations of Health Care Facilities Providing Health Care Services Prior to <date date="1970-12-18">December 18, 1970</date>; <inline class="small-caps">Limitations on Federal Participation</inline></heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/92/603/tII/s221/d">Pub. L. 92–603, title II, § 221(d)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-30">Oct. 30, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1389">86 Stat. 1389</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/92/603/tII/s221/d">“In the case of a health care facility providing health care services as of <date date="1970-12-18">December 18, 1970</date>, which on such date is committed to a formal plan of expansion or replacement, the amendments made by the preceding provisions of this section [enacting this section and amending sections 705, 706, 709, 1395x, 1396a, and 1396b of this title] shall not apply with respect to such expenditures as may be made or obligations incurred for capital items included in such plan where preliminary expenditures toward the plan of expansion or replacement (including payments for studies, surveys, designs, plans, working drawings, specifications, and site acquisition, essential to the acquisition, improvement, expansion, or replacement of the health care facility or equipment concerned) of $100,000 or more, had been made during the three-year period ended <date date="1970-12-17">December 17, 1970</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
