<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb8591550-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320c–5"><num value="1320c–5">§ 1320c–5.</num><heading> Obligations of health care practitioners and providers of health care services; sanctions and penalties; hearings and review</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8591551-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320c–5/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Assurances regarding services and items ordered or provided by practitioner or provider</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be the obligation of any health care practitioner and any other person (including a hospital or other health care facility, organization, or agency) who provides health care services for which payment may be made (in whole or in part) under this chapter, to assure, to the extent of his authority that services or items ordered or provided by such practitioner or person to beneficiaries and recipients under this chapter—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8591552-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320c–5/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> will be provided economically and only when, and to the extent, medically necessary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8591553-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320c–5/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> will be of a quality which meets professionally recognized standards of health care; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8591554-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320c–5/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> will be supported by evidence of medical necessity and quality in such form and fashion and at such time as may reasonably be required by a reviewing quality improvement organization in the exercise of its duties and responsibilities.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8591555-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320c–5/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Sanctions and penalties; hearings and review</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8591556-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320c–5/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> If after reasonable notice and opportunity for discussion with the practitioner or person concerned, and, if appropriate, after the practitioner or person has been given a reasonable opportunity to enter into and complete a corrective action plan (which may include remedial education) agreed to by the organization, and has failed successfully to complete such plan, any organization having a contract with the Secretary under this part determines that such practitioner or person has—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8591557-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320c–5/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> failed in a substantial number of cases substantially to comply with any obligation imposed on him under subsection (a), or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8591558-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320c–5/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> grossly and flagrantly violated any such obligation in one or more instances,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">such organization shall submit a report and recommendations to the Secretary. If the Secretary agrees with such determination, the Secretary (in addition to any other sanction provided under law) may exclude (permanently or for such period as the Secretary may prescribe, except that such period may not be less than 1 year) such practitioner or person from eligibility to provide services under this chapter on a reimbursable basis. If the Secretary fails to act upon the recommendations submitted to him by such organization within 120 days after such submission, such practitioner or person shall be excluded from eligibility to provide services on a reimbursable basis until such time as the Secretary determines otherwise.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8591559-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320c–5/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A determination made by the Secretary under this subsection to exclude a practitioner or person shall be effective on the same date and in the same manner as an exclusion from participation under the programs under this chapter becomes effective under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–7/c">section 1320a–7(c) of this title</ref>, and shall (subject to the minimum period specified in the second sentence of paragraph (1)) remain in effect until the Secretary finds and gives reasonable notice to the public that the basis for such determination has been removed and that there is reasonable assurance that it will not recur.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb859155a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320c–5/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In lieu of the sanction authorized by paragraph (1), the Secretary may require that (as a condition to the continued eligibility of such practitioner or person to provide such health care services on a reimbursable basis) such practitioner or person pays <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002724">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002724"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “pay”.</note> to the United States, in case such acts or conduct involved the provision or ordering by such practitioner or person of health care services which were medically improper or unnecessary, an amount not in excess of up to $10,000 for each instance of the medically improper or unnecessary services so provided. Such amount may be deducted from any sums owing by the United States (or any instrumentality thereof) to the practitioner or person from whom such amount is claimed.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb859155b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320c–5/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Any practitioner or person furnishing services described in paragraph (1) who is dissatisfied with a determination made by the Secretary under this subsection shall be entitled to reasonable notice and opportunity for a hearing thereon by the Secretary to the same extent as is provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s405/b">section 405(b) of this title</ref>, and to judicial review of the Secretary’s final decision after such hearing as is provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s405/g">section 405(g) of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb859155c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320c–5/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Before the Secretary may effect an exclusion under paragraph (2) in the case of a provider or practitioner located in a rural health professional shortage area or in a county with a population of less than 70,000, the provider or practitioner adversely affected by the determination is entitled to a hearing before an administrative law judge (described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s405/b">section 405(b) of this title</ref>) respecting whether the provider or practitioner should be able to continue furnishing services to individuals entitled to benefits under this chapter, pending completion of the administrative review procedure under paragraph (4). If the judge does not determine, by a preponderance of the evidence, that the provider or practitioner will pose a serious risk to such individuals if permitted to continue furnishing such services, the Secretary shall not effect the exclusion under paragraph (2) until the provider or practitioner has been provided reasonable notice and opportunity for an administrative hearing thereon under paragraph (4).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb859155d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320c–5/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> When the Secretary effects an exclusion of a physician under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall notify the State board responsible for the licensing of the physician of the exclusion.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb859155e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320c–5/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Enlistment of support of other organizations to assure practitioner’s or provider’s compliance with obligations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be the duty of each quality improvement organization to use such authority or influence it may possess as a professional organization, and to enlist the support of any other professional or governmental organization having influence or authority over health care practitioners and any other person (including a hospital or other health care facility, organization, or agency) providing health care services in the area served by such review organization, in assuring that each practitioner or person (referred to in subsection (a)) providing health care services in such area shall comply with all obligations imposed on him under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb859155f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, title XI, § 1156, as added <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/tI/s143">Pub. L. 97–248, title I, § 143</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/388">96 Stat. 388</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/93/s6">Pub. L. 100–93, § 6</ref>, <date date="1987-08-18">Aug. 18, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/691">101 Stat. 691</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tIV/s4095/a">Pub. L. 100–203, title IV, § 4095(a)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-138">101 Stat. 1330–138</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tIV/s4039/h/5">Pub. L. 100–203, title IV, § 4039(h)(5)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/100/360/tIV/s411/e/3">Pub. L. 100–360, title IV, § 411(e)(3)</ref>, <date date="1988-07-01">July 1, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/775">102 Stat. 775</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tIV/s4205/a/1">Pub. L. 101–508, title IV, § 4205(a)(1)</ref>, (d)(2)(A), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-112">104 Stat. 1388–112</ref>, 1388–114; <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/tIV/s401/c/1">Pub. L. 101–597, title IV, § 401(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3035">104 Stat. 3035</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/432/tI/s156/b/1">Pub. L. 103–432, title I, § 156(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4441">108 Stat. 4441</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/191/tII">Pub. L. 104–191, title II</ref>, §§ 214, 231(f), <date date="1996-08-21">Aug. 21, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2005">110 Stat. 2005</ref>, 2014; <ref href="/us/pl/112/40/tII/s261/a/2/C">Pub. L. 112–40, title II, § 261(a)(2)(C)</ref>, <date date="2011-10-21">Oct. 21, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/423">125 Stat. 423</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb8591560-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb8591561-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idb8591562-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 1320c–5, <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531/tXI/s1156">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531, title XI, § 1156</ref>, as added <date date="1972-10-30">Oct. 30, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/92/603/tII/s249F/b">Pub. L. 92–603, title II, § 249F(b)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1435">86 Stat. 1435</ref>, provided for development of norms of health care services by Professional Standards Review Organizations, prior to the general revision of this part by <ref href="/us/pl/97/248">Pub. L. 97–248</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb8591563-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/112/40">Pub. L. 112–40</ref> substituted “quality improvement” for “peer review”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/112/40">Pub. L. 112–40</ref> substituted “quality improvement” for “utilization and quality control peer review”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/104/191/s214/b/2">Pub. L. 104–191, § 214(b)(2)</ref>, struck out in concluding provisions “In determining whether a practitioner or person has demonstrated an unwillingness or lack of ability substantially to comply with such obligations, the Secretary shall consider the practitioner’s or person’s willingness or lack of ability, during the period before the organization submits its report and recommendations, to enter into and successfully complete a corrective action plan.” after “chapter on a reimbursable basis.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/191/s214/b/1">Pub. L. 104–191, § 214(b)(1)</ref>, struck out in concluding provisions “and determines that such practitioner or person, in providing health care services over which such organization has review responsibility and for which payment (in whole or in part) may be made under this chapter, has demonstrated an unwillingness or a lack of ability substantially to comply with such obligations,” after “agrees with such determination,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/191/s214/a/1">Pub. L. 104–191, § 214(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “may prescribe, except that such period may not be less than 1 year)” for “may prescribe)” in concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/104/191/s214/a/2">Pub. L. 104–191, § 214(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “shall (subject to the minimum period specified in the second sentence of paragraph (1)) remain” for “shall remain”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/104/191/s231/f">Pub. L. 104–191, § 231(f)</ref>, substituted “up to $10,000 for each instance” for “the actual or estimated cost”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/432">Pub. L. 103–432</ref> substituted “whether” for “whehter” in third sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s4205/a/1">Pub. L. 101–508, § 4205(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “and, if appropriate, after the practitioner or person has been given a reasonable opportunity to enter into and complete a corrective action plan (which may include remedial education) agreed to by the organization, and has failed successfully to complete such plan,” after “concerned,” in introductory provisions and inserted after second sentence “In determining whehter [sic] a practitioner or person has demonstrated an unwillingness or lack of ability substantially to comply with such obligations, the Secretary shall consider the practitioner’s or person’s willingness or lack of ability, during the period before the organization submits its report and recommendations, to enter into and successfully complete a corrective action plan.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597">Pub. L. 101–597</ref> substituted “health professional shortage area” for “health manpower shortage area (HMSA)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s4205/d/2/A">Pub. L. 101–508, § 4205(d)(2)(A)</ref>, added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/360">Pub. L. 100–360</ref> added <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/s4039/h/5">Pub. L. 100–203, § 4039(h)(5)</ref>, see 1987 Amendment notes below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/93/s6/1">Pub. L. 100–93, § 6(1)</ref>, substituted “this chapter” for “subchapter XVIII of this chapter” and “this subchapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/s4039/h/5/A">Pub. L. 100–203, § 4039(h)(5)(A)</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/100/360">Pub. L. 100–360</ref>, substituted “services under this chapter” for “such services”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/93/s6/2">Pub. L. 100–93, § 6(2)</ref>, substituted “this chapter” for “subchapter XVIII of this chapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/s4039/h/5/B">Pub. L. 100–203, § 4039(h)(5)(B)</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/100/360">Pub. L. 100–360</ref>, substituted “on the same date and in the same manner as an exclusion from participation under the programs under this chapter becomes effective under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–7/c">section 1320a–7(c) of this title</ref>” for “at such time and upon such reasonable notice to the public and to the practitioner or person furnishing the services involved as may be specified in regulations. Such determination shall be effective with respect to services furnished to an individual on or after the effective date of such determination (except that in the case of institutional health care services such determination shall be effective in the manner provided in this chapter with respect to terminations of provider agreements)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/93/s6/2">Pub. L. 100–93, § 6(2)</ref>, substituted “this chapter” for “subchapter XVIII of this chapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref> added par. (5).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb8591564-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8591565-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2011 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/40">Pub. L. 112–40</ref> applicable to contracts entered into or renewed on or after <date date="2012-01-01">Jan. 1, 2012</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/40/s261/e">section 261(e) of Pub. L. 112–40</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320c">section 1320c of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8591566-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/191/s214">section 214 of Pub. L. 104–191</ref> effective <date date="1997-01-01">Jan. 1, 1997</date>, except as otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/191/s218">section 218 of Pub. L. 104–191</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–7">section 1320a–7 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/104/191/s231/f">section 231(f) of Pub. L. 104–191</ref> applicable to acts or omissions occurring on or after <date date="1997-01-01">Jan. 1, 1997</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/104/191/s231/i">section 231(i) of Pub. L. 104–191</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–7a">section 1320a–7a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8591567-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/432">Pub. L. 103–432</ref> effective as if included in the enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/432/s156/b/6/A">section 156(b)(6)(A) of Pub. L. 103–432</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320c–9">section 1320c–9 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8591568-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tIV/s4205/a/2">Pub. L. 101–508, title IV, § 4205(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-113">104 Stat. 1388–113</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/508/tIV/s4205/a/2">“The amendments made by paragraph (1) [amending this section] shall apply to initial determinations made by organizations on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tIV/s4205/d/2/B">Pub. L. 101–508, title IV, § 4205(d)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-114">104 Stat. 1388–114</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/103/432/tI/s156/b/3">Pub. L. 103–432, title I, § 156(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4441">108 Stat. 4441</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/432/tI/s156/b/3">“The amendment made by this paragraph [amending this section] shall apply to sanctions effected more than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8591569-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Except as specifically provided in <ref href="/us/pl/100/360/s411">section 411 of Pub. L. 100–360</ref>, amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/360">Pub. L. 100–360</ref>, as it relates to a provision in the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1987, <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref>, effective as if included in the enactment of that provision in <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/360/s411/a">section 411(a) of Pub. L. 100–360</ref>, set out as a Reference to OBRA; Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s106">section 106 of Title 1</ref>, General Provisions.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb859156a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1987 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tIV/s4095/b">Pub. L. 100–203, title IV, § 4095(b)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-138">101 Stat. 1330–138</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/203/tIV/s4095/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to determinations made by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under section 1156(b) of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320c–5/b">42 U.S.C. 1320c–5(b)</ref>] on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/93">Pub. L. 100–93</ref> effective at end of fourteen-day period beginning <date date="1987-08-18">Aug. 18, 1987</date>, and inapplicable to administrative proceedings commenced before end of such period, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/93/s15/a">section 15(a) of Pub. L. 100–93</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–7">section 1320a–7 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb859156b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Telecommunications Demonstration Projects</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tIV/s4094/e">Pub. L. 100–203, title IV, § 4094(e)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-138">101 Stat. 1330–138</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/360/tIV/s411/j/3/C">Pub. L. 100–360, title IV, § 411(j)(3)(C)</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/100/485/tVI/s608/d/25/A">Pub. L. 100–485, title VI, § 608(d)(25)(A)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-13">Oct. 13, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2421">102 Stat. 2421</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/485/tVI/s608/d/25/A">“The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall enter into agreements with entities submitting applications under this subsection (in such form as the Secretary may provide) to establish demonstration projects to examine the feasibility of requiring instruction and oversight of rural physicians, in lieu of imposing sanctions, through use of video communication between rural hospitals and teaching hospitals under this title [probably means title XI of the Social Security Act, <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1301">42 U.S.C. 1301</ref> et seq.]. Under such demonstration projects, the Secretary may provide for payments to physicians consulted via video communication systems. No funds may be expended under the demonstration projects for the acquisition of capital items including computer hardware.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb859156c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Preexclusion Hearings; Transition for Current Cases and Redetermination in Certain Cases</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tIV/s4095/c">Pub. L. 100–203, title IV, § 4095(c)</ref>, (d), <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-138">101 Stat. 1330–138</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/203/tIV/s4095/c">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transition for Current Cases</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In the case of a practitioner or person—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> for whom a notice of determination under section 1156(b) of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320c–5/b">42 U.S.C. 1320c–5(b)</ref>] has been provided within 365 days before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>],</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> who has not exhausted the administrative remedies available under section 1156(b)(4) of such Act for review of the determination, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> who requests, within 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, a hearing established under this subsection,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall provide for a hearing described in section 1156(b)(5) of the Social Security Act (as amended by subsection (a) of this section).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Redeterminations in Certain Cases</inline>.—</heading><content>If, in hearing under subsection (c), the judge does not determine, by a preponderance of the evidence, that the provider or practitioner will pose a serious risk to individuals entitled to benefits under title XVIII of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395">42 U.S.C. 1395</ref> et seq.] if permitted to continue or resume furnishing such services, the Secretary shall not effect the exclusion (or shall suspend the exclusion, if previously effected) under paragraph (2) of section 1156(b) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320c–5/b">42 U.S.C. 1320c–5(b)</ref>] until the provider or practitioner has been provided an administrative hearing thereon under paragraph (4) of such section, notwithstanding any failure by the provider or practitioner to request the hearing on a timely basis.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
