<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb82e34df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–5"><num value="1320a–5">§ 1320a–5.</num><heading> Disclosure by institutions, organizations, and agencies of owners, officers, etc., convicted of offenses related to programs; notification requirements; “managing employee” defined</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb82e34e0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–5/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> As a condition of participation in or certification or recertification under the programs established by subchapters XVIII,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002680">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002680"><num>1</num> So in original. The comma probably should not appear.</note> and XIX, any hospital, nursing facility, or other entity (other than an individual practitioner or group of practitioners) shall be required to disclose to the Secretary or to the appropriate State agency the name of any person that is a person described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–7/b/8">section 1320a–7(b)(8) of this title</ref>. The Secretary or the appropriate State agency shall promptly notify the Inspector General in the Department of Health and Human Services of the receipt from any entity of any application or request for such participation, certification, or recertification which discloses the name of any such person, and shall notify the Inspector General of the action taken with respect to such application or request.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb82e34e1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–5/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> For the purposes of this section, the term “managing employee” means, with respect to an entity, an individual, including a general manager, business manager, administrator, and director, who exercises operational or managerial control over the entity, or who directly or indirectly conducts the day-to-day operations of the entity.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb82e34e2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, title XI, § 1126, as added <ref href="/us/pl/95/142/s8/a">Pub. L. 95–142, § 8(a)</ref>, <date date="1977-10-25">Oct. 25, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1194">91 Stat. 1194</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXIII/s2353/j">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXIII, § 2353(j)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/873">95 Stat. 873</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tVI/s2663/j/2/D/vi">Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title VI, § 2663(j)(2)(D)(vi)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1170">98 Stat. 1170</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/93/s8/b">Pub. L. 100–93, § 8(b)</ref>, <date date="1987-08-18">Aug. 18, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/692">101 Stat. 692</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb82e34e3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb82e34e4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb82e34e5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/93/s8/b/1">Pub. L. 100–93, § 8(b)(1)</ref>, in first sentence substituted “or other entity (other than an individual practitioner or group of practitioners) shall be required to disclose to the Secretary or to the appropriate State agency the name of any person that is a person described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–7/b/8">section 1320a–7(b)(8) of this title</ref>.” for “or other institution, organization, or agency shall be required to disclose to the Secretary or to the appropriate State agency the name of any person who—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) has a direct or indirect ownership or control interest of 5 percent or more in such institution, organization, or agency or is an officer, director, agent, or managing employee (as defined in subsection (b) of this section) of such institution, organization, or agency, and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) has been convicted (on or after <date date="1977-10-25">October 25, 1977</date>, or within such period prior to that date as the Secretary shall specify in regulations) of a criminal offense related to the involvement of such person in any of such programs.”,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">and in second sentence substituted “entity” for “institution, organization, or agency”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/93/s8/b/2">Pub. L. 100–93, § 8(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “entity” for “institution, organization, or agency” in three places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> substituted “Health and Human Services” for “Health, Education, and Welfare” in provisions following par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> substituted in provision preceding par. (1) “and XIX” for “XIX, and XX”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb82e34e6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb82e34e7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1987 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/93">Pub. L. 100–93</ref> effective at end of fourteen-day period beginning <date date="1987-08-18">Aug. 18, 1987</date>, and inapplicable to administrative proceedings commenced before end of such period, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/93/s15/a">section 15(a) of Pub. L. 100–93</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–7">section 1320a–7 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb82e34e8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> effective <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, but not to be construed as changing or affecting any right, liability, status, or interpretation which existed (under the provisions of law involved) before that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2664/b">section 2664(b) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb82e34e9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> effective <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, except as otherwise explicitly provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2354">section 2354 of Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1397">section 1397 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb82e34ea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/142/s8/e">Pub. L. 95–142, § 8(e)</ref>, <date date="1977-10-25">Oct. 25, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1195">91 Stat. 1195</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/142/s8/e">“The amendments made by this section [enacting this section and amending sections 1395cc, 1396b, and 1397a of this title] shall apply with respect to contracts, agreements, and arrangements entered into and approvals given pursuant to applications or requests made on and after the first day of the fourth month beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1977-10-25">Oct. 25, 1977</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
