<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb864fcb3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–2"><num value="1320f–2">§ 1320f–2.</num><heading> Manufacturer agreements</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb864fcb4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–2/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320f/a/2">section 1320f(a)(2) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall enter into agreements with manufacturers of selected drugs with respect to a price applicability period, by not later than February 28 following the selected drug publication date with respect to such selected drug, under which—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb864fcb5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–2/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> during the negotiation period for the initial price applicability year for the selected drug, the Secretary and the manufacturer, in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–3">section 1320f–3 of this title</ref>, negotiate to determine (and, by not later than the last date of such period, agree to) a maximum fair price for such selected drug of the manufacturer in order for the manufacturer to provide access to such price—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb864fcb6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–2/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to maximum fair price eligible individuals who with respect to such drug are described in subparagraph (A) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320f/c/2">section 1320f(c)(2) of this title</ref> and are dispensed such drug (and to pharmacies, mail order services, and other dispensers, with respect to such maximum fair price eligible individuals who are dispensed such drugs) during, subject to paragraph (2), the price applicability period; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb864fcb7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–2/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to hospitals, physicians, and other providers of services and suppliers with respect to maximum fair price eligible individuals who with respect to such drug are described in subparagraph (B) of such section and are furnished or administered such drug during, subject to paragraph (2), the price applicability period;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb864fcb8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–2/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> the Secretary and the manufacturer shall, in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–3">section 1320f–3 of this title</ref>, renegotiate (and, by not later than the last date of the period of renegotiation, agree to) the maximum fair price for such drug, in order for the manufacturer to provide access to such maximum fair price (as so renegotiated)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb864fcb9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–2/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to maximum fair price eligible individuals who with respect to such drug are described in subparagraph (A) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320f/c/2">section 1320f(c)(2) of this title</ref> and are dispensed such drug (and to pharmacies, mail order services, and other dispensers, with respect to such maximum fair price eligible individuals who are dispensed such drugs) during any year during the price applicability period (beginning after such renegotiation) with respect to such selected drug; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb864fcba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–2/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to hospitals, physicians, and other providers of services and suppliers with respect to maximum fair price eligible individuals who with respect to such drug are described in subparagraph (B) of such section and are furnished or administered such drug during any year described in subparagraph (A);</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb864fcbb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–2/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> subject to subsection (d), access to the maximum fair price (including as renegotiated pursuant to paragraph (2)), with respect to such a selected drug, shall be provided by the manufacturer to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb864fcbc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–2/a/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> maximum fair price eligible individuals, who with respect to such drug are described in subparagraph (A) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320f/c/2">section 1320f(c)(2) of this title</ref>, at the pharmacy, mail order service, or other dispenser at the point-of-sale of such drug (and shall be provided by the manufacturer to the pharmacy, mail order service, or other dispenser, with respect to such maximum fair price eligible individuals who are dispensed such drugs), as described in paragraph (1)(A) or (2)(A), as applicable; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb864fcbd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–2/a/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> hospitals, physicians, and other providers of services and suppliers with respect to maximum fair price eligible individuals who with respect to such drug are described in subparagraph (B) of such section and are furnished or administered such drug, as described in paragraph (1)(B) or (2)(B), as applicable;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb864fcbe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–2/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> the manufacturer submits to the Secretary, in a form and manner specified by the Secretary, for the negotiation period for the price applicability period (and, if applicable, before any period of renegotiation pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–3/f">section 1320f–3(f) of this title</ref>), and for <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–1/f">section 1320f–1(f) of this title</ref>, with respect to such drug—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb864fcbf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–2/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> information on the non-Federal average manufacturer price (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t38/s8126/h/5">section 8126(h)(5) of title 38</ref>) for the drug for the applicable year or period;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb864fcc0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–2/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> information that the Secretary requires to carry out the negotiation (or renegotiation process) under this part; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb864fcc1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–2/a/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> information that the Secretary requires to carry out <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–1/f">section 1320f–1(f) of this title</ref>, including rebates under paragraph (4) of such section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb864fcc2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–2/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the manufacturer complies with requirements determined by the Secretary to be necessary for purposes of administering the program and monitoring compliance with the program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb864fcc3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–2/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Agreement in effect until drug is no longer a selected drug</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An agreement entered into under this section shall be effective, with respect to a selected drug, until such drug is no longer considered a selected drug under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–1/c">section 1320f–1(c) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb864fcc4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–2/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Confidentiality of information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Information submitted to the Secretary under this part by a manufacturer of a selected drug that is proprietary information of such manufacturer (as determined by the Secretary) shall be used only by the Secretary or disclosed to and used by the Comptroller General of the United States for purposes of carrying out this part.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb864fcc5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–2/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Nonduplication with 340B ceiling price</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Under an agreement entered into under this section, the manufacturer of a selected drug—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb864fcc6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–2/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> shall not be required to provide access to the maximum fair price under subsection (a)(3), with respect to such selected drug and maximum fair price eligible individuals who are eligible to be furnished, administered, or dispensed such selected drug at a covered entity described in section 340B(a)(4) of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s256b/a/4">42 U.S.C. 256b(a)(4)</ref>], to such covered entity if such selected drug is subject to an agreement described in section 340B(a)(1) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s256b/a/1">42 U.S.C. 256b(a)(1)</ref>] and the ceiling price (defined in section 340B(a)(1) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s256b/a/1">42 U.S.C. 256b(a)(1)</ref>]) is lower than the maximum fair price for such selected drug; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb864fcc7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–2/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> shall be required to provide access to the maximum fair price to such covered entity with respect to maximum fair price eligible individuals who are eligible to be furnished, administered, or dispensed such selected drug at such entity at such ceiling price in a nonduplicated amount to the ceiling price if such maximum fair price is below the ceiling price for such selected drug.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb864fcc8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, title XI, § 1193, as added and amended <ref href="/us/pl/117/169/tI">Pub. L. 117–169, title I</ref>, §§ 11001(a), 11002(a)(2), <date date="2022-08-16">Aug. 16, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/1841">136 Stat. 1841</ref>, 1861.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb864fcc9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb864fcca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb864fccb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (a)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/117/169/s11002/a/2/A">Pub. L. 117–169, § 11002(a)(2)(A)</ref>, inserted “, and for <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–1/f">section 1320f–1(f) of this title</ref>,” after “<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320f–3/f">section 1320f–3(f) of this title</ref>)” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/117/169/s11002/a/2/B">Pub. L. 117–169, § 11002(a)(2)(B)</ref>, (C), added subpar. (C).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
