<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbfb9aadc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316"><num value="13316">§ 13316.</num><heading> Innovative renewable energy technology transfer program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfb9aadd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, through the Agency for International Development, and in consultation with the other members of the interagency working group established under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6276/d">section 6276(d) of this title</ref> (in this section referred to as the “interagency working group”), shall establish a renewable energy technology transfer program to carry out the purposes described in subsection (b). Within 150 days after <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, the Secretary and the Administrator of the Agency for International Development shall enter into a written agreement to carry out this section. The agreement shall establish a procedure for resolving any disputes between the Secretary and the Administrator regarding the implementation of specific projects. With respect to countries not assisted by the Agency for International Development, the Secretary may enter into agreements with other appropriate Federal agencies. If the Secretary and the Administrator, or the Secretary and an agency described in the previous sentence, are unable to reach an agreement, each shall send a memorandum to the President outlining an appropriate agreement. Within 90 days after receipt of either memorandum, the President shall determine which version of the agreement shall be in effect. Any agreement entered into under this subsection shall be provided to the appropriate committees of the Congress and made available to the public.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfb9aade-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Purposes of program</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The purposes of the technology transfer program under this section are to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9aadf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> reduce the United States balance of trade deficit through the export of United States renewable energy technologies and technological expertise;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9aae0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> retain and create manufacturing and related service jobs in the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9aae1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> encourage the export of United States renewable energy technologies, including services related thereto, to those countries that have a need for developmentally sound facilities to provide energy derived from renewable resources;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9aae2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> develop markets for United States renewable energy technologies to be utilized in meeting the energy and environmental requirements of foreign countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9aae3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> better ensure that United States participation in energy-related projects in foreign countries includes participation by United States firms as well as utilization of United States technologies that have been developed or demonstrated in the United States through publicly or privately funded demonstration programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9aae4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> ensure the introduction of United States firms and expertise in foreign countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9aae5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> provide financial assistance by the Federal Government to foster greater participation by United States firms in the financing, ownership, design, construction, or operation of renewable energy technology projects in foreign countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9aae6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> assist foreign countries in meeting their energy needs through the use of renewable energy in an environmentally acceptable manner, consistent with sustainable development policies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9aae7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> assist United States firms, especially firms that are in competition with firms in foreign countries, to obtain opportunities to transfer technologies to, or undertake projects in, foreign countries.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfb9aae8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Identification</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Pursuant to the agreements required by subsection (a), the Secretary, through the Agency for International Development, and after consultation with the interagency working group, United States firms, and representatives from foreign countries, shall develop mechanisms to identify potential energy projects in host countries, and shall identify a list of such projects within 240 days after <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, and periodically thereafter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfb9aae9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Financial mechanisms</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbfb9aaea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Pursuant to the agreements under subsection (a), the Secretary, through the Agency for International Development, shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9aaeb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> establish appropriate financial mechanisms to increase the participation of United States firms in energy projects utilizing United States renewable energy technologies, and services related thereto, in developing countries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9aaec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> utilize available financial assistance authorized by this section to counterbalance assistance provided by foreign governments to non-United States firms; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9aaed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> provide financial assistance to support projects.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbfb9aaee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The financial assistance authorized by this section may be—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9aaef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> provided in combination with other forms of financial assistance, including non-United States funding that is available to the project; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9aaf0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> utilized to assist United States firms in the development of innovative financing packages for renewable energy technology projects that utilize other financial assistance programs available through the Federal Government.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbfb9aaf1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> United States obligations under the Arrangement on Guidelines for Officially Supported Export Credits established through the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development shall be applicable to this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfb9aaf2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Solicitations for project proposals</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbfb9aaf3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Pursuant to the agreements under subsection (a), the Secretary, through the Agency for International Development, within one year after <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, and subsequently as appropriate thereafter, shall solicit proposals from United States firms for the design, construction, testing, and operation of the project or projects identified under subsection (c) which propose to utilize a United States renewable energy technology. Each solicitation under this section shall establish a closing date for receipt of proposals.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbfb9aaf4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The solicitation under this subsection shall, to the extent appropriate, be modeled after the RFP No. DE–PS01–90FE62271 Clean Coal Technology IV, as administered by the Department of Energy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbfb9aaf5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Any solicitation made under this subsection shall include the following requirements:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9aaf6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The United States firm that submits a proposal in response to the solicitation shall have an equity interest in the proposed project.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9aaf7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The project shall utilize a United States renewable energy technology, including services related thereto, in meeting the applicable energy and environmental requirements of the host country.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9aaf8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/e/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Proposals for projects shall be submitted by and undertaken with a United States firm, although a joint venture or other teaming arrangement with a non-United States manufacturer or other non-United States entity is permissible.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfb9aaf9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Assistance to United States firms</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Pursuant to the agreements under subsection (a), the Secretary, through the Agency for International Development, and in consultation with the interagency working group, shall establish a procedure to provide financial assistance to United States firms under this section for a project identified under subsection (c) where solicitations for the project are being conducted by the host country or by a multilateral lending institution.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfb9aafa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Other program requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Pursuant to the agreements under subsection (a), the Secretary, through the Agency for International Development, and in consultation with the working group, shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9aafb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> establish eligibility criteria for host countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9aafc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> periodically review the energy needs of such countries and export opportunities for United States firms for the development of projects in such countries;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9aafd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> consult with government officials in host countries and, as appropriate, with representatives of utilities or other entities in host countries, to determine interest in and support for potential projects; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9aafe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/g/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> determine whether each project selected under this section is developmentally sound, as determined under the criteria developed by the Development Assistance Committee of the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfb9aaff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Selection of projects</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbfb9ab00-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Pursuant to the agreements under subsection (a), the Secretary, through the Agency for International Development, shall, not later than 120 days after receipt of proposals in response to a solicitation under subsection (e), select one or more proposals under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbfb9ab01-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> In selecting a proposal under this section, the Secretary, through the Agency for International Development, shall consider—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab02-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/h/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the ability of the United States firm, in cooperation with the host country, to undertake and complete the project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab03-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/h/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the degree to which the equipment to be included in the project is designed and manufactured in the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab04-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/h/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the long-term technical and competitive viability of the United States technology, and services related thereto, and the ability of the United States firm to compete in the development of additional energy projects using such technology in the host country and in other foreign countries;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab05-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/h/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the extent of technical and financial involvement of the host country in the project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab06-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/h/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the extent to which the proposed project meets the purposes stated in section 13311(b) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004158">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn004158"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be section “13316(b)”.</note> of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab07-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/h/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> the extent of technical, financial, management, and marketing capabilities of the participants in the project, and the commitment of the participants to completion of a successful project in a manner that will facilitate acceptance of the United States technology for future application; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab08-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/h/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> such other criteria as may be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbfb9ab09-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> In selecting among proposed projects, the Secretary shall seek to ensure that, relative to otherwise comparable projects in the host country, a selected project will meet 1 or more of the following criteria:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab0a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/h/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> It will reduce environmental emissions to an extent greater than required by applicable provisions of law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab0b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/h/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> It will make greater use of indigenous renewable energy resources.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab0c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/h/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> It will be a more cost-effective technological alternative, based on life cycle capital and operating costs per unit of energy produced and, where applicable, costs per unit of product produced.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Priority in selection shall be given to those projects which, in the judgment of the Secretary, best meet one or more of these criteria.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfb9ab0d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> United States-Asia Environmental Partnership</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Activities carried out under this section shall be coordinated with the United States-Asia Environmental Partnership.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfb9ab0e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Buy America</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out this section, the Secretary, through the Agency for International Development, and pursuant to the agreements under subsection (a), shall ensure—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab0f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the maximum percentage, but in no case less than 50 percent, of the cost of any equipment furnished in connection with a project authorized under this section shall be attributable to the manufactured United States components of such equipment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab10-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the maximum participation of United States firms.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">In determining whether the cost of United States components equals or exceeds 50 percent, the cost of assembly of such United States components in the host country shall not be considered a part of the cost of such United States component.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfb9ab11-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary and the Administrator of the Agency for International Development shall report annually to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the appropriate committees of the House of Representatives on the progress being made to introduce renewable energy technologies into foreign countries.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfb9ab12-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab13-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/l/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> the term “host country” means a foreign country which is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbfb9ab14-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/l/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the participant in or the site of the proposed renewable energy technology project; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbfb9ab15-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/l/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> either—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbfb9ab16-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/l/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> classified as a country eligible to participate in development assistance programs of the Agency for International Development pursuant to applicable law or regulation; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbfb9ab17-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/l/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a developing country.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab18-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/l/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the term “developing country” includes, but is not limited to, countries in Central and Eastern Europe or in the independent states of the former Soviet Union.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfb9ab19-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13316/m"><num value="m" class="bold">(m)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out the program required by this section, $100,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1993, 1994, 1995, 1996, 1997, and 1998.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbfb9ab1a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tXII/s1211">Pub. L. 102–486, title XII, § 1211</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2965">106 Stat. 2965</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
