<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbfb9ab3c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331"><num value="13331">§ 13331.</num><heading> Coal research, development, demonstration, and commercial application programs</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfb9ab3d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall, in accordance with section <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004160">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn004160"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “sections”.</note> 13541 and 13542 of this title, conduct programs for research, development, demonstration, and commercial application on coal-based technologies. Such research, development, demonstration, and commercial application programs shall include the programs established under this part, and shall have the goals and objectives of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab3e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> ensuring a reliable electricity supply;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab3f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> complying with applicable environmental requirements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab40-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> achieving the control of sulfur oxides, oxides of nitrogen, air toxics, solid and liquid wastes, greenhouse gases, or other emissions resulting from coal use or conversion at levels of proficiency greater than or equal to applicable currently available commercial technology;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab41-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> achieving the cost competitive conversion of coal into energy forms usable in the transportation sector;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab42-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> demonstrating the conversion of coal to synthetic gaseous, liquid, and solid fuels;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab43-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> demonstrating, in cooperation with other Federal and State agencies, the use of coal-derived fuels in mobile equipment, with opportunities for industrial cost sharing participation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab44-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><chapeau> ensuring the timely commercial application of cost-effective technologies or energy production processes or systems utilizing coal which achieve—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbfb9ab45-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/a/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> greater efficiency in the conversion of coal to useful energy when compared to currently available commercial technology for the use of coal; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbfb9ab46-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/a/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the control of emissions from the utilization of coal; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab47-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/a/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> ensuring the availability for commercial use of such technologies by the year 2010.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfb9ab48-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Demonstration and commercial application programs</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbfb9ab49-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In selecting either a demonstration project or a commercial application project for financial assistance under this part, the Secretary shall seek to ensure that, relative to otherwise comparable commercially available technologies or products, the selected project will meet one or more of the following criteria:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab4a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> It will reduce environmental emissions to an extent greater than required by applicable provisions of law.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab4b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> It will increase the overall efficiency of the utilization of coal, including energy conversion efficiency and, where applicable, production of products derived from coal.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfb9ab4c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> It will be a more cost-effective technological alternative, based on life cycle capital and operating costs per unit of energy produced and, where applicable, costs per unit of product produced.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Priority in selection shall be given to those projects which, in the judgment of the Secretary, best meet one or more of these criteria.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbfb9ab4d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In administering demonstration and commercial application programs authorized by this part, the Secretary shall establish accounting and project management controls that will be adequate to control costs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbfbbf43e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbfbbf43f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Not later than 180 days after <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, the Secretary shall establish procedures and criteria for the recoupment of the Federal share of each cost shared demonstration and commercial application project authorized pursuant to this part. Such recoupment shall occur within a reasonable period of time following the date of completion of such project, but not later than 20 years following such date, taking into account the effect of recoupment on—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfbbf440-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/b/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the commercial competitiveness of the entity carrying out the project;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfbbf441-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/b/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the profitability of the project; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfbbf442-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/b/3/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the commercial viability of the coal-based technology utilized.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbfbbf443-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary may at any time waive or defer all or some portion of the recoupment requirement as necessary for the commercial viability of the project.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbfbbf444-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Projects selected by the Secretary under this part for demonstration or commercial application of a technology shall, in the judgment of the Secretary, be capable of enhancing the state of the art for such technology.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfbbf445-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within 240 days after <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, the Secretary shall transmit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report which shall include each of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfbbf446-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A detailed description of ongoing research, development, demonstration, and commercial application activities regarding coal-based technologies undertaken by the Department of Energy, other Federal or State government departments or agencies and, to the extent such information is publicly available, other public or private organizations in the United States and other countries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfbbf447-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A listing and analysis of current Federal and State government regulatory and financial incentives that could further the goals of the programs established under this part.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfbbf448-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Recommendations regarding the manner in which any ongoing coal-based demonstration and commercial application program might be modified and extended in order to ensure the timely demonstrations of advanced coal-based technologies so as to ensure that the goals established under this section are achieved and that such demonstrated technologies are available for commercial use by the year 2010.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfbbf449-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Recommendations, if any, regarding the manner in which the cost sharing demonstrations conducted pursuant to the Clean Coal Program established by <ref href="/us/pl/98/473">Public Law 98–473</ref> might be modified and extended in order to ensure the timely demonstration of advanced coal-based technologies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfbbf44a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><chapeau> A detailed plan for conducting the research, development, demonstration, and commercial application programs to achieve the goals and objectives of subsection (a) of this section, which plan shall include a description of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbfbbf44b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/c/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the program elements and management structure to be utilized;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbfbbf44c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/c/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the technical milestones to be achieved with respect to each of the advanced coal-based technologies included in the plan; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbfbbf44d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/c/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the dates at which further deadlines for additional cost sharing demonstrations shall be established.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfbbf44e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Status reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within one year after transmittal of the report described in subsection (c), and every 2 years thereafter for a period of 6 years, the Secretary shall transmit to the Congress a report that provides a detailed description of the status of development of the advanced coal-based technologies and the research, development, demonstration, and commercial application activities undertaken to carry out the programs required by this part.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfbbf44f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13331/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out research, development, demonstration, and commercial application activities under this part, the Secretary shall consult with the National Coal Council and other representatives of the public and private sectors as the Secretary considers appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbfbbf450-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tXIII/s1301">Pub. L. 102–486, title XIII, § 1301</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2970">106 Stat. 2970</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbfbbf451-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbfbbf452-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbfbbf453-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/473">Public Law 98–473</ref>, referred to in subsec. (c)(4), is <ref href="/us/pl/98/473">Pub. L. 98–473</ref>, <date date="1984-10-12">Oct. 12, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1837">98 Stat. 1837</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbfbbf454-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idbfbbf455-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Commerce of House of Representatives by <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/a">section 1(a) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress. Committee on Commerce of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives, and jurisdiction over matters relating to securities and exchanges and insurance generally transferred to Committee on Financial Services of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Seventh Congress, <date date="2001-01-03">Jan. 3, 2001</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
