<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbfbe65c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13381"><num value="13381">§ 13381.</num><heading> Report</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 2 years after <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Congress that includes an assessment of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfbe65c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13381/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the feasibility and economic, energy, social, environmental, and competitive implications, including implications for jobs, of stabilizing the generation of greenhouse gases in the United States by the year 2005;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfbe65c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13381/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the recommendations made in chapter 9 of the 1991 National Academy of Sciences report entitled “Policy Implications of Greenhouse Warming”, including an analysis of the benefits and costs of each recommendation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfbe65c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13381/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the extent to which the United States is responding, compared with other countries, to the recommendations made in chapter 9 of the 1991 National Academy of Sciences report;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfbe65c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13381/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the feasibility of reducing the generation of greenhouse gases;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfbe65c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13381/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the feasibility and economic, energy, social, environmental, and competitive implications, including implications for jobs, of achieving a 20 percent reduction from 1988 levels in the generation of carbon dioxide by the year 2005 as recommended by the 1988 Toronto Scientific World Conference on the Changing Atmosphere;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfbe65c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13381/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> the potential economic, energy, social, environmental, and competitive implications, including implications for jobs, of implementing the policies necessary to enable the United States to comply with any obligations under the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change or subsequent international agreements.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idbfbe65c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tXVI/s1601">Pub. L. 102–486, title XVI, § 1601</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2999">106 Stat. 2999</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
