<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbfc0d6a8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13401"><num value="13401">§ 13401.</num><heading> Goals</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the goal of the United States in carrying out energy supply and energy conservation research and development—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfc0d6a9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13401/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to strengthen national energy security by reducing dependence on imported oil;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfc0d6aa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13401/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to increase the efficiency of the economy by meeting future needs for energy services at the lowest total cost to the Nation, including environmental costs, giving comparable consideration to technologies that enhance energy supply and technologies that improve the efficiency of energy end uses;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfc0d6ab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13401/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to reduce the air, water, and other environmental impacts (including emissions of greenhouse gases) of energy production, distribution, transportation, and utilization, through the development of an environmentally sustainable energy system;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfc0d6ac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13401/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to maintain the technological competitiveness of the United States and stimulate economic growth through the development of advanced materials and technologies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfc0d6ad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13401/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> to foster international cooperation by developing international markets for domestically produced sustainable energy technologies, and by transferring environmentally sound, advanced energy systems and technologies to developing countries to promote sustainable development;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfc0d6ae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13401/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> to consider the comparative environmental and public health impacts of the energy to be produced or saved by the specific activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfc0d6af-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13401/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> to consider the obstacles inherent in private industry’s development of new energy technologies and steps necessary for establishing or maintaining technological leadership in the area of energy and energy efficiency resource technologies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfc0d6b0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13401/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> to consider the contribution of a given activity to fundamental scientific knowledge.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idbfc0d6b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tXX/s2001">Pub. L. 102–486, title XX, § 2001</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3057">106 Stat. 3057</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
