<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbfc801cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13541"><num value="13541">§ 13541.</num><heading> Research, development, demonstration, and commercial application activities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfc801cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13541/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Research, development, and demonstration</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbfc801ce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13541/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except as otherwise provided in this Act, research, development, and demonstration activities under this Act may be carried out under the procedures of the Federal Nonnuclear Research and Development Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5901–592">42 U.S.C. 5901–592</ref>0), the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2011">42 U.S.C. 2011</ref> et seq.), or any other Act under which the Secretary is authorized to carry out such activities, but only to the extent the Secretary is authorized to carry out such activities under each such Act. An objective of any demonstration program under this Act shall be to determine the technical and commercial feasibility of energy technologies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbfc801cf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13541/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Except as otherwise provided in this Act, in carrying out research, development, and demonstration programs and activities under this Act, the Secretary may use, to the extent authorized under applicable provisions of law, contracts, cooperative agreements, cooperative research and development agreements under the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3701">15 U.S.C. 3701</ref> et seq.], grants, joint ventures, and any other form of agreement available to the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfc801d0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13541/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Commercial application</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as otherwise provided in this Act, in carrying out commercial application programs and commercial application activities under this Act, the Secretary may use, to the extent authorized under applicable provisions of law, contracts, cooperative agreements, cooperative research and development agreements under the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3701">15 U.S.C. 3701</ref> et seq.], grants, joint ventures, and any other form of agreement available to the Secretary. An objective of any commercial application program under this Act shall be to accelerate the transition of technologies from the research and development stage.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfc801d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13541/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> “Joint venture” defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section, the term “joint venture” has the meaning given the term “joint research and development venture” under section 4301(a)(6) and (b) of title 15, except that such term may apply under this section to research, development, demonstration, and commercial application joint ventures.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfc801d2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13541/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Protection of information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Section 12(c)(7) of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3710a/c/7">15 U.S.C. 3710a(c)(7)</ref>], relating to the protection of information, shall apply to research, development, demonstration, and commercial application programs and activities under this Act.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfc801d3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13541/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Guidelines and procedures</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall provide guidelines and procedures for the transition, where appropriate, of energy technologies from research through development and demonstration under subsection (a) to commercial application under subsection (b). Nothing in this section shall preclude the Secretary from—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfc801d4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13541/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> entering into a contract, cooperative agreement, cooperative research and development agreement under the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3701">15 U.S.C. 3701</ref> et seq.], grant, joint venture, or any other form of agreement available to the Secretary under this section that relates to research, development, demonstration, and commercial application; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfc801d5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13541/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> extending a contract, cooperative agreement, cooperative research and development agreement under the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980, grant, joint venture, or any other form of agreement available to the Secretary that relates to research, development, and demonstration to cover commercial application.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfc801d6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13541/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Application of section</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section shall not apply to any contract, cooperative agreement, cooperative research and development agreement under the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 [<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3701">15 U.S.C. 3701</ref> et seq.], grant, joint venture, or any other form of agreement available to the Secretary that is in effect as of <date date="1992-10-24">October 24, 1992</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbfc801d7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tXXX/s3001">Pub. L. 102–486, title XXX, § 3001</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3126">106 Stat. 3126</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbfc801d8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbfc801d9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbfc801da-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsecs. (a), (b), and (d), is <ref href="/us/pl/102/486">Pub. L. 102–486</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2776">106 Stat. 2776</ref>, known as the Energy Policy Act of 1992. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s13201">section 13201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Federal Nonnuclear Research and Development Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), probably means the Federal Nonnuclear Energy Research and Development Act of 1974, <ref href="/us/pl/93/577">Pub. L. 93–577</ref>, <date date="1974-12-31">Dec. 31, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/1878">88 Stat. 1878</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 74 (§ 5901 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5901">section 5901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Atomic Energy Act of 1954, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-30/ch1073/s1">act Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/919">68 Stat. 919</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 23 (§ 2011 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2011">section 2011 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980, referred to in subsecs. (a)(2), (b), (e)(1), (2), and (f), is <ref href="/us/pl/96/480">Pub. L. 96–480</ref>, <date date="1980-10-21">Oct. 21, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2311">94 Stat. 2311</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 63 (§ 3701 et seq.) of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3701">section 3701 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
