<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbfc8028e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603"><num value="13603">§ 13603.</num><heading> Establishment of criteria for occupancy</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfc8028f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Task force</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbfc80290-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">To assist the Secretary in establishing reasonable criteria for occupancy in federally assisted housing, the Secretary shall establish a task force to review all rules, policy statements, handbooks, technical assistance memoranda, and other relevant documents issued by the Department of Housing and Urban Development on the standards and obligations governing residency in federally assisted housing and make recommendations to the Secretary for the establishment of such criteria for occupancy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbfc80291-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Members</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall appoint members to the task force, which shall include individuals representing the interests of owners, managers, and tenants of federally assisted housing, public housing agencies, owner and tenant advocacy organizations, persons with disabilities and disabled families, organizations assisting homeless individuals, and social service, mental health, and other nonprofit servicer providers who serve federally assisted housing.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbfc80292-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Members of the task force shall not receive compensation for serving on the task force.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbfc80293-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The task force shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbfc80294-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603/a/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> review all existing standards, regulations, and guidelines governing occupancy and tenant selection policies in federally assisted housing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbfc80295-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603/a/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> review all existing standards, regulations, and guidelines governing lease provisions and other rules of occupancy for federally assisted housing;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbfc80296-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603/a/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> determine whether the standards, regulations, and guidelines reviewed under subparagraphs (A) and (B) provide sufficient guidance to owners and managers of federally assisted housing to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbfc80297-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603/a/4/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> develop procedures for preselection inquiries sufficient to determine the capacity of applicants to comply with reasonable lease terms and conditions of occupancy;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbfc80298-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603/a/4/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> utilize leases that prohibit behavior which endangers the health or safety of other tenants or violates the rights of other tenants to peaceful enjoyment of the premises;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbfc80299-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603/a/4/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> assess the need to provide, and appropriate measures for providing, reasonable accommodations required under the Fair Housing Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3601">42 U.S.C. 3601</ref> et seq.] and <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s794">section 794 of title 29</ref> for persons with various types of disabilities; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbfc8029a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603/a/4/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> comply with civil rights laws and regulations;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbfc8029b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603/a/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> propose criteria for occupancy in federally assisted housing, standards for the reasonable performance and behavior of tenants of federally assisted housing, compliance standards consistent with the reasonable accommodation of the requirements of the Fair Housing Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3601">42 U.S.C. 3601</ref> et seq.] and <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s794">section 794 of title 29</ref>, standards for compliance with other civil rights laws, and procedures for the eviction of tenants not complying with such standards consistent with sections 1437d and 1437f of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbfc8029c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603/a/4/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> report to the Congress and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development pursuant to paragraph (7).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbfc8029d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603/a/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedure</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In carrying out its duties, the task force shall hold public hearings and receive written comments for a period of not less than 60 days.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbfc8029e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603/a/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Support</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall cooperate fully with the task force and shall provide support staff and office space to assist the task force in carrying out its duties.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbfc8029f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603/a/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 3 months after <date date="1992-10-28">October 28, 1992</date>, the task force shall submit to the Secretary and the Congress a preliminary report describing its initial actions. Not later than 6 months after <date date="1992-10-28">October 28, 1992</date>, the task force shall submit a report to the Secretary and the Congress, which shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbfc802a0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603/a/7/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a description of its findings; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbfc802a1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603/a/7/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> recommendations to revise such standards, regulations, and guidelines to provide accurate and complete guidance to owners and managers of federally assisted housing as determined necessary under paragraph (4).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfc802a2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Rulemaking</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbfc802a3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall, by regulation, establish criteria for selection of tenants for occupancy in federally assisted housing and lease provisions for such housing.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbfc802a4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Standards</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The criteria shall provide sufficient guidance to owners and managers of federally assisted housing to enable them to (A) select tenants capable of complying with reasonable lease terms, (B) utilize leases prohibiting behavior which endangers the health or safety of others or violates the right of other tenants to peaceful enjoyment of the premises, (C) comply with legal requirements to make reasonable accommodations for persons with disabilities, and (D) comply with civil rights laws. The criteria shall be consistent with the requirements under subsections (k) and (<i>l</i>) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437d">section 1437d of this title</ref> and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437f/d/1">section 1437f(d)(1) of this title</ref> and any similar contract and lease requirements for federally assisted housing. In establishing the criteria, the Secretary shall take into consideration the report of the task force under subsection (a)(7).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbfc802a5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13603/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Procedure</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 90 days after the submission of the final report under subsection (a)(7), the Secretary shall issue a notice of proposed rulemaking of the regulations under this subsection providing for notice and opportunity for public comment regarding the regulations, pursuant to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref> (notwithstanding subsections (a)(2), (b)(B), and (d)(3) of such section). The duration of the period for public comment under such section 553 shall not be less than 60 days. The Secretary shall issue final regulations under this subsection not later than the expiration of the 60-day period beginning upon the conclusion of the comment period, which shall take effect upon issuance.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbfc802a6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/102/550/tVI/s643">Pub. L. 102–550, title VI, § 643</ref>, <date date="1992-10-28">Oct. 28, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3821">106 Stat. 3821</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbfc802a7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbfc802a8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbfc802a9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Fair Housing Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(4)(C)(iii), (D), is title VIII of <ref href="/us/pl/90/284">Pub. L. 90–284</ref>, <date date="1968-04-11">Apr. 11, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/81">82 Stat. 81</ref>, which is classified principally to subchapter I (§ 3601 et seq.) of chapter 45 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3601">section 3601 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
