<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbfca4c2d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13662"><num value="13662">§ 13662.</num><heading> Termination of tenancy and assistance for illegal drug users and alcohol abusers in federally assisted housing</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfca4c2e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13662/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a public housing agency or an owner of federally assisted housing (as applicable), shall establish standards or lease provisions for continued assistance or occupancy in federally assisted housing that allow the agency or owner (as applicable) to terminate the tenancy or assistance for any household with a member—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfca4c2f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13662/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> who the public housing agency or owner determines is illegally using a controlled substance; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfca4c30-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13662/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> whose illegal use (or pattern of illegal use) of a controlled substance, or whose abuse (or pattern of abuse) of alcohol, is determined by the public housing agency or owner to interfere with the health, safety, or right to peaceful enjoyment of the premises by other residents.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfca4c31-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13662/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Consideration of rehabilitation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In determining whether, pursuant to subsection (a)(2), to terminate tenancy or assistance to any household based on a pattern of illegal use of a controlled substance or a pattern of abuse of alcohol by a household member, a public housing agency or an owner may consider whether such household member—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfca4c32-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13662/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> has successfully completed a supervised drug or alcohol rehabilitation program (as applicable) and is no longer engaging in the illegal use of a controlled substance or abuse of alcohol (as applicable);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfca4c33-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13662/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> has otherwise been rehabilitated successfully and is no longer engaging in the illegal use of a controlled substance or abuse of alcohol (as applicable); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfca4c34-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s13662/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> is participating in a supervised drug or alcohol rehabilitation program (as applicable) and is no longer engaging in the illegal use of a controlled substance or abuse of alcohol (as applicable).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbfca4c35-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/105/276/tV/s577">Pub. L. 105–276, title V, § 577</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2640">112 Stat. 2640</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbfca4c36-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbfca4c37-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbfca4c38-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Quality Housing and Work Responsibility Act of 1998, and not as part of subtitles C to F of title VI of <ref href="/us/pl/102/550">Pub. L. 102–550</ref> which comprise this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbfca4c39-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idbfca4c3a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective and applicable beginning upon <date date="1999-10-01">Oct. 1, 1999</date>, except as otherwise provided, with provision that Secretary may implement any provision of this section before such date, except to extent otherwise provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/276/s503">section 503 of Pub. L. 105–276</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1998 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437">section 1437 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
