<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb8759ee1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1382d"><num value="1382d">§ 1382d.</num><heading> Rehabilitation services for blind and disabled individuals</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8759ee2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1382d/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Referral by Commissioner of eligible individuals to appropriate State agency</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of any blind or disabled individual who—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8759ee3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1382d/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> has not attained age 16; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8759ee4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1382d/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> with respect to whom benefits are paid under this subchapter,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Commissioner of Social Security shall make provision for referral of such individual to the appropriate State agency administering the State program under subchapter V.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8759ee5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1382d/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXI/s2193/c/8/B">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXI, § 2193(c)(8)(B)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/828">95 Stat. 828</ref></heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8759ee6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1382d/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/106/170/tI/s101/b/2/B">Pub. L. 106–170, title I, § 101(b)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1999-12-17">Dec. 17, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1874">113 Stat. 1874</ref></heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8759ee7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1382d/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Reimbursement by Commissioner to State agency of costs of providing services to referred individuals</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commissioner of Social Security is authorized to reimburse the State agency administering or supervising the administration of a State plan for vocational rehabilitation services approved under title I of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s720">29 U.S.C. 720</ref> et seq.] for the costs incurred under such plan in the provision of rehabilitation services to individuals who are referred for such services pursuant to subsection (a), (1) in cases where the furnishing of such services results in the performance by such individuals of substantial gainful activity for a continuous period of nine months, (2) in cases where such individuals receive benefits as a result of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1383/a/6">section 1383(a)(6) of this title</ref> (except that no reimbursement under this subsection shall be made for services furnished to any individual receiving such benefits for any period after the close of such individual’s ninth consecutive month of substantial gainful activity or the close of the month with which his or her entitlement to such benefits ceases, whichever first occurs), and (3) in cases where such individuals, without good cause, refuse to continue to accept vocational rehabilitation services or fail to cooperate in such a manner as to preclude their successful rehabilitation. The determination that the vocational rehabilitation services contributed to the successful return of an individual to substantial gainful activity, the determination that an individual, without good cause, refused to continue to accept vocational rehabilitation services or failed to cooperate in such a manner as to preclude successful rehabilitation, and the determination of the amount of costs to be reimbursed under this subsection shall be made by the Commissioner of Social Security in accordance with criteria determined by the Commissioner in the same manner as under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s422/d/1">section 422(d)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8780ee8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1382d/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Reimbursement for vocational rehabilitation services furnished during certain months of nonpayment of insurance benefits</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commissioner of Social Security may reimburse the State agency described in subsection (d) for the costs described therein incurred in the provision of rehabilitation services—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8780ee9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1382d/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> for any month for which an individual received—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8780eea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1382d/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> benefits under section 1382 or 1382h(a) of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8780eeb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1382d/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> assistance under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1382h/b">section 1382h(b) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8780eec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1382d/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a federally administered State supplementary payment under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1382e">section 1382e of this title</ref> or <ref href="/us/pl/93/66/s212/b">section 212(b) of Public Law 93–66</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8780eed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1382d/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> for any month before the 13th consecutive month for which an individual, for a reason other than cessation of disability or blindness, was ineligible for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8780eee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1382d/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> benefits under section 1382 or 1382h(a) of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8780eef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1382d/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> assistance under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1382h/b">section 1382h(b) of this title</ref>; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8780ef0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1382d/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a federally administered State supplementary payment under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1382e">section 1382e of this title</ref> or <ref href="/us/pl/93/66/s212/b">section 212(b) of Public Law 93–66</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb8780ef1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, title XVI, § 1615, as added <ref href="/us/pl/92/603/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 92–603, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1972-10-30">Oct. 30, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1474">86 Stat. 1474</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/94/566/tV/s501/a">Pub. L. 94–566, title V, § 501(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-20">Oct. 20, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2683">90 Stat. 2683</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/272/tIII/s304">Pub. L. 96–272, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="1980-06-17">June 17, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/529">94 Stat. 529</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXI/s2193/a/4">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXI, § 2193(a)(4)</ref>, (c)(8), title XXIII, § 2344, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/827">95 Stat. 827</ref>, 828, 867; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tVI/s2663/g/8">Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title VI, § 2663(g)(8)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1169">98 Stat. 1169</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/460/s11/b">Pub. L. 98–460, § 11(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-09">Oct. 9, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1806">98 Stat. 1806</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tV/s5037/a">Pub. L. 101–508, title V, § 5037(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-226">104 Stat. 1388–226</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/tI/s107/a/4">Pub. L. 103–296, title I, § 107(a)(4)</ref>, <date date="1994-08-15">Aug. 15, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1478">108 Stat. 1478</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tV/s5523">Pub. L. 105–33, title V, § 5523</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/623">111 Stat. 623</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/170/tI/s101/b/2/A">Pub. L. 106–170, title I, § 101(b)(2)(A)</ref>, (B), <date date="1999-12-17">Dec. 17, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1874">113 Stat. 1874</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb8780ef2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb8780ef3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb8780ef4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Rehabilitation Act of 1973, referred to in subsec. (d), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/112">Pub. L. 93–112</ref>, <date date="1973-09-26">Sept. 26, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/355">87 Stat. 355</ref>. Title I of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 720 et seq.) of chapter 16 of Title 29, Labor. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s701">section 701 of Title 29</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/93/66/s212/b">Section 212(b) of Public Law 93–66</ref>, referred to in subsec. (e)(1)(C), (2)(C), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/66/s212/b">section 212(b) of Pub. L. 93–66</ref>, title II, <date date="1973-07-09">July 9, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/155">87 Stat. 155</ref>, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1382">section 1382 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb8780ef5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/106/170/s101/b/2/A">Pub. L. 106–170, § 101(b)(2)(A)</ref>, amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) read as follows: “In the case of any blind or disabled individual who—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) has not attained age 65, and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) is receiving benefits (or with respect to whom benefits are paid) under this subchapter,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Commissioner of Social Security shall make provision for referral of such individual to the appropriate State agency administering the State plan for vocational rehabilitation services approved under title I of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, or, in the case of any such individual who has not attained age 16, to the State agency administering the State program under subchapter V of this chapter, and (except for individuals who have not attained age 16 and except in such other cases as the Commissioner may determine) for a review not less often than quarterly of such individual’s blindness or disability and his need for and utilization of the services made available to him under such plan.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/106/170/s101/b/2/B">Pub. L. 106–170, § 101(b)(2)(B)</ref>, struck out subsec. (c) which read as follows: “Every individual age 16 or over with respect to whom the Commissioner of Social Security is required to make provision for referral under subsection (a) of this section shall accept such services as are made available to him under the State plan for vocational and rehabilitation services approved under title I of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973; and no such individual shall be an eligible individual or eligible spouse for purposes of this subchapter if he refuses without good cause to accept services for which he is referred under subsection (a) of this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s5523/2">Pub. L. 105–33, § 5523(2)</ref>, substituted “the Commissioner” for “him” after “determined by” in last sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s5523/1">Pub. L. 105–33, § 5523(1)</ref>, which directed insertion of comma after “subsection (a)(1)” in first sentence, was executed by making the insertion after “subsection (a)” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/296">Pub. L. 103–296</ref> in closing provisions substituted “Commissioner of Social Security” for “Secretary” and “the Commissioner may” for “he may”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/296">Pub. L. 103–296</ref> substituted “Commissioner of Social Security” for “Secretary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/103/296">Pub. L. 103–296</ref> substituted “The Commissioner of Social Security is” for “The Secretary is”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/103/296">Pub. L. 103–296</ref> substituted “Commissioner of Social Security” for “Secretary” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsecs. (a), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2663/g/8">Pub. L. 98–369, § 2663(g)(8)</ref>, substituted “title I of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973” for “the Vocational Rehabilitation Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/98/460/s11/b">Pub. L. 98–460, § 11(b)</ref>, designated existing provisions of first sentence as cl. (1), added cls. (2) and (3), and inserted requirement that the determination that the vocational rehabilitation services contributed to the successful return of an individual to substantial gainful activity and the determination that an individual, without good cause, refused to continue to accept vocational rehabilitation services or failed to cooperate in such a manner as to preclude successful rehabilitation be made by the Commissioner of Social Security in accordance with criteria determined by him in the same manner as under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s422/d/1">section 422(d)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2663/g/8">Pub. L. 98–369, § 2663(g)(8)</ref>, substituted “title I of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973” for “the Vocational Rehabilitation Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2193/c/8/A">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2193(c)(8)(A)</ref>, substituted “State agency administering the State program under subchapter V of this chapter (except for individuals who have not attained age 16 and except in such other cases” for “appropriate State agency administering the State plan under subsection (b) of this section, and (except in such cases”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2193/c/8/B">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2193(c)(8)(B)</ref>, struck out subsec. (b) which provided criteria for approval of State plans.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2344">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2344</ref>, substituted “is authorized to reimburse” for “is authorized to pay to”, “for the costs incurred” for “the costs incurred”, and “individuals who are referred for such services pursuant to subsection (a) if such services result in their performance of substantial gainful activity which lasts for a continuous period of nine months” for “individuals referred for such services pursuant to subsection (a)” and inserted provision that determination of the amount to be reimbursed be made by the Commissioner of Social Security in accordance with criteria determined by him in the same manner as under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s422/d/1">section 422(d)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2193/c/8/B">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2193(c)(8)(B)</ref>, struck out subsec. (e) which provided for payment by the Secretary to a State agency charged with administering a State plan under subsec. (b), of the costs incurred each fiscal year from <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, to <date date="1982-10-01">Oct. 1, 1982</date>, in carrying out such State plan.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2193/a/4/A">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2193(a)(4)(A)</ref>, inserted “and subject to section 2194(b)(3) of the Maternal and Child Health Services Block Grant Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2193/a/4/B">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2193(a)(4)(B)</ref>, substituted “$24,070,000” for “$30,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/96/272">Pub. L. 96–272</ref> corrected the error under which subsec. (e) had been added as (c) by <ref href="/us/pl/94/566">Pub. L. 94–566</ref> and, in subsec. (e)(1) as so designated, substituted “<date date="1982-10-01">October 1, 1982</date>” for “<date date="1979-10-01">October 1, 1979</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/566">Pub. L. 94–566</ref> inserted “or, in the case of any such individual who has not attained age 16, to the appropriate State agency administering the State plan under subsection (b) of this section,” after “Vocational Rehabilitation Act,” and substituted “need for and utilization of the services” for “need for and utilization of the rehabilitation services”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/94/566">Pub. L. 94–566</ref> added subsec. (b). Former subsec. (b) was split up and its parts were redistributed into subsecs. (c) and (d), respectively, and amended.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/94/566">Pub. L. 94–566</ref> combined into subsec. (c) the existing provisions of subsec. (c) covering the refusal by referred individuals to accept services and added thereto a part of former subsec. (b) covering the required acceptance of vocational and rehabilitation services by the referred individual, and in that provision substituted “Every individual age 16 or over” for “Every individual”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/94/566">Pub. L. 94–566</ref> redesignated as subsec. (d) the part of former subsec. (b) covering the payment by the Secretary to the State agency administering a State plan and in the provisions so redesignated substituted “administration of a State plan for vocational rehabilitation services approved under the Vocational Rehabilitation Act” for “administration of such State plan”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/94/566">Pub. L. 94–566</ref> added subsec. (e). See 1980 Amendment note above.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb8780ef6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8780ef7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1999 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/170">Pub. L. 106–170</ref> effective with the first month following one year after <date date="1999-12-17">Dec. 17, 1999</date>, subject to <ref href="/us/pl/106/170/s101/d">section 101(d) of Pub. L. 106–170</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/106/170/s101/c">section 101(c) of Pub. L. 106–170</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320b–19">section 1320b–19 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8780ef8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref> effective as if included in the enactment of title II of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996, <ref href="/us/pl/104/193">Pub. L. 104–193</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s5528/a">section 5528(a) of Pub. L. 105–33</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s903">section 903 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8780ef9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/296">Pub. L. 103–296</ref> effective <date date="1995-03-31">Mar. 31, 1995</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s110/a">section 110(a) of Pub. L. 103–296</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8780efa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tV/s5037/b">Pub. L. 101–508, title V, § 5037(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-226">104 Stat. 1388–226</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/508/tV/s5037/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>] and shall apply to claims for reimbursement pending on or after such date.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8780efb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/460">Pub. L. 98–460</ref> applicable with respect to individuals who receive benefits as a result of section 425(b) or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1383/a/6">section 1383(a)(6) of this title</ref>, or who refuse to continue to accept rehabilitation services or fail to cooperate in an approved vocational rehabilitation program, in or after November 1984, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/460/s11/c">section 11(c) of Pub. L. 98–460</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s422">section 422 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> effective <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, but not to be construed as changing or affecting any right, liability, status, or interpretation which existed (under the provisions of law involved) before that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2664/b">section 2664(b) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8780efc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective and Termination Dates of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXI/s2193/a/4/B">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXI, § 2193(a)(4)(B)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/827">95 Stat. 827</ref>, provided that the amendment made by that section is effective for fiscal year 1982.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date, savings, and transitional provisions relating to amendments by section 2193(a)(4)(A) and (c)(8) of <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2194">section 2194 of Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s701">section 701 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXIII/s2344">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXIII, § 2344</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/867">95 Stat. 867</ref>, provided that the amendment made by that section is effective <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb8780efd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/92/603/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 92–603, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1972-10-30">Oct. 30, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1465">86 Stat. 1465</ref>, provided that this section is effective <date date="1974-01-01">Jan. 1, 1974</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8780efe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Publication of Criteria</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/94/566/tV/s501/b">Pub. L. 94–566, title V, § 501(b)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-20">Oct. 20, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2685">90 Stat. 2685</ref>, directed Secretary, within 120 days after <date date="1976-10-20">Oct. 20, 1976</date>, to publish criteria to be employed to determine disability (as defined in subsec. (a)(3) of this section) in the case of persons who have not attained the age of 18.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8780eff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Application to Northern Mariana Islands</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For applicability of this section to the Northern Mariana Islands, see section 502(a)(1) of the Covenant to Establish a Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands in Political Union with the United States of America and Proc. No. 4534, <date date="1977-10-24">Oct. 24, 1977</date>, 42 F.R. 6593, set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1801">section 1801 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8780f00-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Puerto Rico, Guam, and Virgin Islands</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Enactment of provisions of <ref href="/us/pl/92/603">Pub. L. 92–603</ref>, eff. <date date="1974-01-01">Jan. 1, 1974</date>, not applicable to Puerto Rico, Guam, and the Virgin Islands, see <ref href="/us/pl/92/603/s303/b">section 303(b) of Pub. L. 92–603</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s301">section 301 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
