<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idba0b0b78-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff"><num value="1395fff">§ 1395fff.</num><heading> Prospective payment for home health services</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b79-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/v">section 1395x(v) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall provide, for portions of cost reporting periods occurring on or after <date date="2000-10-01">October 1, 2000</date>, for payments for home health services in accordance with a prospective payment system established by the Secretary under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b7a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> System of prospective payment for home health services</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b7b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish under this subsection a prospective payment system for payment for all costs of home health services. Under the system under this subsection all services covered and paid on a reasonable cost basis under the medicare home health benefit as of <date date="1997-08-05">August 5, 1997</date>, including medical supplies, shall be paid for on the basis of a prospective payment amount determined under this subsection and applicable to the services involved. In implementing the system, the Secretary may provide for a transition (of not longer than 4 years) during which a portion of such payment is based on agency-specific costs, but only if such transition does not result in aggregate payments under this subchapter that exceed the aggregate payments that would be made if such a transition did not occur.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b7c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Unit of payment</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b7d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In defining a prospective payment amount under the system under this subsection, the Secretary shall consider an appropriate unit of service and the number, type, and duration of visits provided within that unit, potential changes in the mix of services provided within that unit and their cost, and a general system design that provides for continued access to quality services.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b7e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> 30-day unit of service</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of implementing the prospective payment system with respect to home health units of service furnished during a year beginning with 2020, the Secretary shall apply a 30-day unit of service as the unit of service applied under this paragraph.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b7f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment basis</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b80-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Initial basis</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b81-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/A/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Under such system the Secretary shall provide for computation of a standard prospective payment amount (or amounts) as follows:</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idba0b0b82-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> Such amount (or amounts) shall initially be based on the most current audited cost report data available to the Secretary and shall be computed in a manner so that the total amounts payable under the system for the 12-month period beginning on the date the Secretary implements the system shall be equal to the total amount that would have been made if the system had not been in effect and if <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/v/1/L/ix">section 1395x(v)(1)(L)(ix) of this title</ref> had not been enacted.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idba0b0b83-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> For the 12-month period beginning after the period described in subclause (I), such amount (or amounts) shall be equal to the amount (or amounts) determined under subclause (I), updated under subparagraph (B).</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idba0b0b84-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/A/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> Subject to clause (iii), for periods beginning after the period described in subclause (II), such amount (or amounts) shall be equal to the amount (or amounts) that would have been determined under subclause (I) that would have been made for fiscal year 2001 if the system had not been in effect and if <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/v/1/L/ix">section 1395x(v)(1)(L)(ix) of this title</ref> had not been enacted but if the reduction in limits described in clause (ii) had been in effect, updated under subparagraph (B).</content>
</subclause>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I66" class="indent3 firstIndent-1"> Each such amount shall be standardized in a manner that eliminates the effect of variations in relative case mix and area wage adjustments among different home health agencies in a budget neutral manner consistent with the case mix and wage level adjustments provided under paragraph (4)(A). Under the system, the Secretary may recognize regional differences or differences based upon whether or not the services or agency are in an urbanized area.</continuation>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b85-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/A/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Reduction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The reduction described in this clause is a reduction by 15 percent in the cost limits and per beneficiary limits described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/v/1/L">section 1395x(v)(1)(L) of this title</ref>, as those limits are in effect on <date date="2000-09-30">September 30, 2000</date>.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b86-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/A/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustment for 2014 and subsequent years</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b87-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/A/iii/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">Subject to subclause (II), for 2014 and subsequent years, the amount (or amounts) that would otherwise be applicable under clause (i)(III) shall be adjusted by a percentage determined appropriate by the Secretary to reflect such factors as changes in the number of visits in an episode, the mix of services in an episode, the level of intensity of services in an episode, the average cost of providing care per episode, and other factors that the Secretary considers to be relevant. In conducting the analysis under the preceding sentence, the Secretary may consider differences between hospital-based and freestanding agencies, between for-profit and nonprofit agencies, and between the resource costs of urban and rural agencies. Such adjustment shall be made before the update under subparagraph (B) is applied for the year.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b88-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/A/iii/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Transition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The Secretary shall provide for a 4-year phase-in (in equal increments) of the adjustment under subclause (I), with such adjustment being fully implemented for 2017. During each year of such phase-in, the amount of any adjustment under subclause (I) for the year may not exceed 3.5 percent of the amount (or amounts) applicable under clause (i)(III) as of <date date="2010-03-23">March 23, 2010</date>.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b89-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/A/iv"><num value="iv" class="bold">(iv)</num><heading class="bold"> Budget neutrality for 2020</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">With respect to payments for home health units of service furnished that end during the 12-month period beginning <date date="2020-01-01">January 1, 2020</date>, the Secretary shall calculate a standard prospective payment amount (or amounts) for 30-day units of service (as described in paragraph (2)(B)) for the prospective payment system under this subsection. Such standard prospective payment amount (or amounts) shall be calculated in a manner such that the estimated aggregate amount of expenditures under the system during such period with application of paragraph (2)(B) is equal to the estimated aggregate amount of expenditures that otherwise would have been made under the system during such period if paragraph (2)(B) had not been enacted. The previous sentence shall be applied before (and not affect the application of) paragraph (3)(B). In calculating such amount (or amounts), the Secretary shall make assumptions about behavior changes that could occur as a result of the implementation of paragraph (2)(B) and the case-mix adjustment factors established under paragraph (4)(B) and shall provide a description of such assumptions in the notice and comment rulemaking used to implement this clause.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b8a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual update</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b8b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The standard prospective payment amount (or amounts) shall be adjusted for fiscal year 2002 and for fiscal year 2003 and for each subsequent year (beginning with 2004) in a prospective manner specified by the Secretary by the home health applicable increase percentage (as defined in clause (ii)) applicable to the fiscal year or year involved.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b8c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Home health applicable increase percentage</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">For purposes of this subparagraph, the term “home health applicable increase percentage” means, with respect to—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idba0b0b8d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> each of fiscal years 2002 and 2003, the home health market basket percentage increase (as defined in clause (iii)) minus 1.1 percentage points;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idba0b0b8e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> for <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002972">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002972"><num>1</num> So in original. The word “for” probably should not appear.</note> the last calendar quarter of 2003 and the first calendar quarter of 2004, the home health market basket percentage increase;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idba0b0b8f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/B/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the last 3 calendar quarters of 2004, and all of 2005 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002973">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002973"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma.</note> the home health market basket percentage increase minus 0.8 percentage points;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idba0b0b90-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/B/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> 2006, 0 percent; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idba0b0b91-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/B/ii/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> any subsequent year, subject to clauses (v) and (vi), the home health market basket percentage increase.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b92-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/B/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Home health market basket percentage increase</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">For purposes of this subsection, the term “home health market basket percentage increase” means, with respect to a fiscal year or year, a percentage (estimated by the Secretary before the beginning of the fiscal year or year) determined and applied with respect to the mix of goods and services included in home health services in the same manner as the market basket percentage increase under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ww/b/3/B/iii">section 1395ww(b)(3)(B)(iii) of this title</ref> is determined and applied to the mix of goods and services comprising inpatient hospital services for the fiscal year or year. Notwithstanding the previous sentence, the home health market basket percentage increase for 2018 shall be 1 percent and for 2020 shall be 1.5 percent.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b93-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/B/iv"><num value="iv" class="bold">(iv)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustment for case mix changes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Insofar as the Secretary determines that the adjustments under paragraph (4)(A)(i) for a previous fiscal year or year (or estimates that such adjustments for a future fiscal year or year) did (or are likely to) result in a change in aggregate payments under this subsection during the fiscal year or year that are a result of changes in the coding or classification of different units of services that do not reflect real changes in case mix, the Secretary may adjust the standard prospective payment amount (or amounts) under paragraph (3) for subsequent fiscal years or years so as to eliminate the effect of such coding or classification changes.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b94-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/B/v"><num value="v" class="bold">(v)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustment if quality data not submitted</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b95-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/B/v/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">For purposes of clause (ii)(V), for 2007 and each subsequent year, in the case of a home health agency that does not submit data to the Secretary in accordance with subclauses (II) and (IV) with respect to such a year, the home health market basket percentage increase applicable under such clause for such year shall be reduced by 2 percentage points. Such reduction shall apply only with respect to the year involved, and the Secretary shall not take into account such reduction in computing the prospective payment amount under this section for a subsequent year, and the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission shall carry out the requirements under section 5201(d) of the Deficit Reduction Act of 2005.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b96-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/B/v/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission of quality data</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">Subject to subclause (V), for 2007 and each subsequent year, each home health agency shall submit to the Secretary such data that the Secretary determines are appropriate for the measurement of health care quality. Such data shall be submitted in a form and manner, and at a time, specified by the Secretary for purposes of this clause.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b97-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/B/v/III"><num value="III" class="bold">(III)</num><heading class="bold"> Public availability of data submitted</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">The Secretary shall establish procedures for making data submitted under subclause (II) and subclause (IV)(aa) available to the public. Such procedures shall ensure that a home health agency has the opportunity to review the data that is to be made public with respect to the agency prior to such data being made public.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b98-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/B/v/IV"><num value="IV" class="bold">(IV)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission of additional data</heading><item style="-uslm-lc:I580469" class="indent7 firstIndent-2 bold" id="idba0b0b99-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/B/v/IV/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><heading> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5">For the year beginning on the specified application date (as defined in subsection (a)(2)(E) of section 1395<i>lll</i> of this title), as applicable with respect to home health agencies and quality measures under subsection (c)(1) of such section and measures under subsection (d)(1) of such section, and each subsequent year, in addition to the data described in subclause (II), each home health agency shall submit to the Secretary data on such quality measures and any necessary data specified by the Secretary under such subsection (d)(1).</p>
</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580469" class="indent7 firstIndent-2 bold" id="idba0b0b9a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/B/v/IV/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><heading> Standardized patient assessment data</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5">For 2019 and each subsequent year, in addition to such data described in item (aa), each home health agency shall submit to the Secretary standardized patient assessment data required under subsection (b)(1) of section 1395<i>lll</i> of this title.</p>
</content>
</item>
<item style="-uslm-lc:I580469" class="indent7 firstIndent-2 bold" id="idba0b0b9b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/B/v/IV/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><heading> Submission</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I580434" class="indent5">Data shall be submitted under items (aa) and (bb) in the form and manner, and at the time, specified by the Secretary for purposes of this clause.</p>
</content>
</item>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b9c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/B/v/V"><num value="V" class="bold">(V)</num><heading class="bold"> Non-duplication</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">To the extent data submitted under subclause (IV) duplicates other data required to be submitted under subclause (II), the submission of such data under subclause (IV) shall be in lieu of the submission of such data under subclause (II). The previous sentence shall not apply insofar as the Secretary determines it is necessary to avoid a delay in the implementation of section 1395<i>lll</i> of this title, taking into account the different specified application dates under subsection (a)(2)(E) of such section.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0b9d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/B/vi"><num value="vi" class="bold">(vi)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustments</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">After determining the home health market basket percentage increase under clause (iii), and after application of clause (v), the Secretary shall reduce such percentage—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idba0b0b9e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/B/vi/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> for 2015 and each subsequent year (except 2018 and 2020), by the productivity adjustment described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ww/b/3/B/xi/II">section 1395ww(b)(3)(B)(xi)(II) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idba0b0b9f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/B/vi/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> for each of 2011, 2012, and 2013, by 1 percentage point.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I66" class="indent3 firstIndent-1"> The application of this clause may result in the home health market basket percentage increase under clause (iii) being less than 0.0 for a year, and may result in payment rates under the system under this subsection for a year being less than such payment rates for the preceding year.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0ba0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustment for outliers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall reduce the standard prospective payment amount (or amounts) under this paragraph applicable to home health services furnished during a period by such proportion as will result in an aggregate reduction in payments for the period equal to 5 percent of the total payments estimated to be made based on the prospective payment system under this subsection for the period.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0ba1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Behavior assumptions and adjustments</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0ba2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/D/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Secretary shall annually determine the impact of differences between assumed behavior changes (as described in paragraph (3)(A)(iv)) and actual behavior changes on estimated aggregate expenditures under this subsection with respect to years beginning with 2020 and ending with 2026.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0ba3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/D/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Permanent adjustments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Secretary shall, at a time and in a manner determined appropriate, through notice and comment rulemaking, provide for one or more permanent increases or decreases to the standard prospective payment amount (or amounts) for applicable years, on a prospective basis, to offset for such increases or decreases in estimated aggregate expenditures (as determined under clause (i)).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0ba4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/D/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Temporary adjustments for retrospective behavior</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Secretary shall, at a time and in a manner determined appropriate, through notice and comment rulemaking, provide for one or more temporary increases or decreases to the payment amount for a unit of home health services (as determined under paragraph (4)) for applicable years, on a prospective basis, to offset for such increases or decreases in estimated aggregate expenditures (as determined under clause (i)). Such a temporary increase or decrease shall apply only with respect to the year for which such temporary increase or decrease is made, and the Secretary shall not take into account such a temporary increase or decrease in computing such amount under this subsection for a subsequent year.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0ba5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment computation</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0ba6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The payment amount for a unit of home health services shall be the applicable standard prospective payment amount adjusted as follows:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0ba7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/4/A/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Case mix adjustment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The amount shall be adjusted by an appropriate case mix adjustment factor (established under subparagraph (B)).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0ba8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/4/A/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Area wage adjustment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The portion of such amount that the Secretary estimates to be attributable to wages and wage-related costs shall be adjusted for geographic differences in such costs by an area wage adjustment factor (established under subparagraph (C)) for the area in which the services are furnished or such other area as the Secretary may specify.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0ba9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of case mix adjustment factors</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0baa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/4/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Secretary shall establish appropriate case mix adjustment factors for home health services in a manner that explains a significant amount of the variation in cost among different units of services.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0bab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/4/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of therapy thresholds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">For 2020 and subsequent years, the Secretary shall eliminate the use of therapy thresholds (established by the Secretary) in case mix adjustment factors established under clause (i) for calculating payments under the prospective payment system under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0bac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/4/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of area wage adjustment factors</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall establish area wage adjustment factors that reflect the relative level of wages and wage-related costs applicable to the furnishing of home health services in a geographic area compared to the national average applicable level. Such factors may be the factors used by the Secretary for purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ww/d/3/E">section 1395ww(d)(3)(E) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0bad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Outliers</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0bae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary may provide for an addition or adjustment to the payment amount otherwise made in the case of outliers because of unusual variations in the type or amount of medically necessary care. The total amount of the additional payments or payment adjustments made under this paragraph with respect to a fiscal year or year may not exceed 2.5 percent of the total payments projected or estimated to be made based on the prospective payment system under this subsection in that year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0baf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Program specific outlier cap</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The estimated total amount of additional payments or payment adjustments made under subparagraph (A) with respect to a home health agency for a year (beginning with 2011) may not exceed an amount equal to 10 percent of the estimated total amount of payments made under this section (without regard to this paragraph) with respect to the home health agency for the year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0bb0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Proration of prospective payment amounts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If a beneficiary elects to transfer to, or receive services from, another home health agency within the period covered by the prospective payment amount, the payment shall be prorated between the home health agencies involved.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0bb1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements for payment information</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With respect to home health services furnished on or after <date date="1998-10-01">October 1, 1998</date>, no claim for such a service may be paid under this subchapter unless—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba0b0bb2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the claim has the unique identifier for the physician <sup>2</sup> the nurse practitioner or clinical nurse specialist (as those terms are defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/aa/5">section 1395x(aa)(5) of this title</ref>), or the physician assistant (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/aa/5">section 1395x(aa)(5) of this title</ref>) who prescribed the services or made the certification described in section 1395f(a)(2) or 1395n(a)(2)(A) of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba0b0bb3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> in the case of a service visit described in paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (4) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/m">section 1395x(m) of this title</ref>, the claim contains a code (or codes) specified by the Secretary that identifies the length of time of the service visit, as measured in 15 minute increments; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba0b0bb4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> in the case of home health services furnished on or after <date date="2019-01-01">January 1, 2019</date>, the claim contains the code for the county (or equivalent area) in which the home health service was furnished.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0bb5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on review</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There shall be no administrative or judicial review under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ff">section 1395ff of this title</ref>, 1395<i>oo</i> of this title, or otherwise of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba0b0bb6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the establishment of a transition period under subsection (b)(1);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba0b0bb7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the definition and application of payment units under subsection (b)(2);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba0b0bb8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the computation of initial standard prospective payment amounts under subsection (b)(3)(A) (including the reduction described in clause (ii) of such subsection);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba0b0bb9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the establishment of the adjustment for outliers under subsection (b)(3)(C);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba0b0bba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the establishment of case mix and area wage adjustments under subsection (b)(4); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba0b0bbb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> the establishment of any adjustments for outliers under subsection (b)(5).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0bbc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Construction related to home health services</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0bbd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Telecommunications</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this section shall be construed as preventing a home health agency furnishing a home health unit of service for which payment is made under the prospective payment system established by this section for such units of service from furnishing services via a telecommunication system if such services—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba0b0bbe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> do not substitute for in-person home health services ordered as part of a plan of care certified by a physician <sup>2</sup> a nurse practitioner or clinical nurse specialist, or a physician assistant pursuant to section 1395f(a)(2)(C) or 1395n(a)(2)(A) of this title; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba0b0bbf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> are not considered a home health visit for purposes of eligibility or payment under this subchapter.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0b0bc0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction regarding requirement for certification</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this section shall be construed as waiving the requirement for a certification under section 1395f(a)(2)(C) or 1395n(a)(2)(A) of this title for the payment for home health services, whether or not furnished via a telecommunications system.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idba0b0bc1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, title XVIII, § 1895, as added <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tIV/s4603/a">Pub. L. 105–33, title IV, § 4603(a)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/467">111 Stat. 467</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dJ/tV/s5101/c/1">Pub. L. 105–277, div. J, title V, § 5101(c)(1)</ref>, (d)(2), <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-914">112 Stat. 2681–914</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/6/tIII/s302/b">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(6) [title III, §§ 302(b), 303(b), 306, 321(k)(19)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–359, 1501A–361, 1501A–362, 1501A–368; <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/6/tV/s501/a">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(6) [title V, §§ 501(a), (c)(1), 504]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2763">114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–529, 2763A–531; <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/tVII/s701">Pub. L. 108–173, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="2003-12-08">Dec. 8, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2334">117 Stat. 2334</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/tV/s5201/a">Pub. L. 109–171, title V, § 5201(a)</ref>, (c), <date date="2006-02-08">Feb. 8, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/46">120 Stat. 46</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tIII">Pub. L. 111–148, title III</ref>, §§ 3131(a)(1), (b), 3401(e), title X, §§ 10315(a), 10319(d), <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/427">124 Stat. 427</ref>, 428, 483, 944, 949; <ref href="/us/pl/113/185/s2/c/1">Pub. L. 113–185, § 2(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-10-06">Oct. 6, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1962">128 Stat. 1962</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/10/tIV/s411/c">Pub. L. 114–10, title IV, § 411(c)</ref>, <date date="2015-04-16">Apr. 16, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/161">129 Stat. 161</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/123/dE/tII/s50208/a/2">Pub. L. 115–123, div. E, title II, § 50208(a)(2)</ref>, title X, § 51001(a), title XII, § 53110, <date date="2018-02-09">Feb. 9, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/189">132 Stat. 189</ref>, 289, 304; <ref href="/us/pl/116/136/dA/tIII/s3708/d">Pub. L. 116–136, div. A, title III, § 3708(d)</ref>, <date date="2020-03-27">Mar. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/421">134 Stat. 421</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idba0b0bc2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idba0b0bc3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idba0b0bc4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 5201(d) of the Deficit Reduction Act of 2005, referred to in subsec. (b)(3)(B)(v)(I), is <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/tV/s5201/d">section 5201(d) of title V of Pub. L. 109–171</ref>, <date date="2006-02-08">Feb. 8, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/47">120 Stat. 47</ref>, which is not classified to the Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idba0b0bc5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/136/s3708/d/1">Pub. L. 116–136, § 3708(d)(1)</ref>, struck out “(provided under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395u/r">section 1395u(r) of this title</ref>)” after “unique identifier” and inserted “the nurse practitioner or clinical nurse specialist (as those terms are defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/aa/5">section 1395x(aa)(5) of this title</ref>), or the physician assistant (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/aa/5">section 1395x(aa)(5) of this title</ref>)” after “physician”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/116/136/s3708/d/2/A">Pub. L. 116–136, § 3708(d)(2)(A)</ref>, inserted “a nurse practitioner or clinical nurse specialist, or a physician assistant” after “physician”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/116/136/s3708/d/2/B">Pub. L. 116–136, § 3708(d)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “Rule of construction regarding requirement for certification” for “Physician certification” in heading and struck out “physician” before “certification” in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/123/s51001/a/1">Pub. L. 115–123, § 51001(a)(1)</ref>, inserted subpar. (A) designation and heading before “In defining” and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(A)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/115/123/s51001/a/2/A">Pub. L. 115–123, § 51001(a)(2)(A)</ref>, added cl. (iv).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/115/123/s53110/1">Pub. L. 115–123, § 53110(1)</ref>, inserted “and for 2020 shall be 1.5 percent” after “1 percent”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(vi)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/115/123/s53110/2">Pub. L. 115–123, § 53110(2)</ref>, inserted “and 2020” after “except 2018”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/115/123/s51001/a/2/B">Pub. L. 115–123, § 51001(a)(2)(B)</ref>, added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/115/123/s51001/a/3">Pub. L. 115–123, § 51001(a)(3)</ref>, inserted cl. (i) designation and heading before “The Secretary” and added cl. (ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/115/123/s50208/a/2">Pub. L. 115–123, § 50208(a)(2)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/114/10/s411/c/1">Pub. L. 114–10, § 411(c)(1)</ref>, inserted at end “Notwithstanding the previous sentence, the home health market basket percentage increase for 2018 shall be 1 percent.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(vi)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/114/10/s411/c/2">Pub. L. 114–10, § 411(c)(2)</ref>, inserted “(except 2018)” after “each subsequent year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(v)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/113/185/s2/c/1/A">Pub. L. 113–185, § 2(c)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “subclauses (II) and (IV)” for “subclause (II)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(v)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/113/185/s2/c/1/B">Pub. L. 113–185, § 2(c)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “Subject to subclause (V), for 2007” for “For 2007”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(v)(III). <ref href="/us/pl/113/185/s2/c/1/C">Pub. L. 113–185, § 2(c)(1)(C)</ref>, inserted “and subclause (IV)(aa)” after “subclause (II)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(v)(IV), (V). <ref href="/us/pl/113/185/s2/c/1/D">Pub. L. 113–185, § 2(c)(1)(D)</ref>, added subcls. (IV) and (V).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (b)(3)(A)(i)(III). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s3131/a/1/A">Pub. L. 111–148, § 3131(a)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “Subject to clause (iii), for periods” for “For periods”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(A)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s10315/a">Pub. L. 111–148, § 10315(a)</ref>, substituted “2014” for “2013” in heading and in subcl. (I), and “2017” for “2016” in subcl. (II).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s3131/a/1/B">Pub. L. 111–148, § 3131(a)(1)(B)</ref>, added cl. (iii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(ii)(V). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s3401/e/1">Pub. L. 111–148, § 3401(e)(1)</ref>, substituted “clauses (v) and (vi)” for “clause (v)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(vi). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s3401/e/2">Pub. L. 111–148, § 3401(e)(2)</ref>, added cl. (vi).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(vi)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s10319/d">Pub. L. 111–148, § 10319(d)</ref>, substituted “, 2012, and 2013” for “and 2012”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s3131/b/1">Pub. L. 111–148, § 3131(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “5 percent of the total payments estimated to be made based on the prospective payment system under this subsection for the period.” for “the aggregate increase in payments resulting from the application of paragraph (5) (relating to outliers).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s3131/b/2">Pub. L. 111–148, § 3131(b)(2)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A), inserted heading, substituted “Subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary” for “The Secretary” and “2.5 percent” for “5 percent”, and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(ii)(III). <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/s5201/a/1">Pub. L. 109–171, § 5201(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “all of 2005” for “each of 2005 and 2006”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(ii)(IV). <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/s5201/a/2">Pub. L. 109–171, § 5201(a)(2)</ref>, (4), added subcl. (IV). Former subcl. (IV) redesignated (V).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/109/171/s5201/a/3">Pub. L. 109–171, § 5201(a)(3)</ref>, struck out “2007 and” before “any subsequent year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(ii)(V). <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/s5201/a/3">Pub. L. 109–171, § 5201(a)(3)</ref>, (c)(1), redesignated subcl. (IV) as (V) and inserted “subject to clause (v),” after “subsequent year,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(v). <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/s5201/c/2">Pub. L. 109–171, § 5201(c)(2)</ref>, added cl. (v).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/s701/a/1">Pub. L. 108–173, § 701(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “fiscal year 2002 and for fiscal year 2003 and for each subsequent year (beginning with 2004)” for “each fiscal year (beginning with fiscal year 2002)” and inserted “or year” after “the fiscal year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(ii)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/s701/a/2/A">Pub. L. 108–173, § 701(a)(2)(A)</ref>, struck out “or” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(ii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/s701/b/1">Pub. L. 108–173, § 701(b)(1)</ref>, struck out “or” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/173/s701/a/2/D">Pub. L. 108–173, § 701(a)(2)(D)</ref>, added subcl. (II). Former subcl. (II) redesignated (III).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(ii)(III). <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/s701/b/4">Pub. L. 108–173, § 701(b)(4)</ref>, added subcl. (III). Former subcl. (III) redesignated (IV).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/173/s701/a/2/B">Pub. L. 108–173, § 701(a)(2)(B)</ref>, (C), redesignated subcl. (II) as (III) and substituted “2004 and any subsequent year” for “any subsequent fiscal year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(ii)(IV). <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/s701/b/2">Pub. L. 108–173, § 701(b)(2)</ref>, (3), redesignated subcl. (III) as (IV) and substituted “2007” for “2004”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/s701/a/3">Pub. L. 108–173, § 701(a)(3)</ref>, inserted “or year” after “fiscal year” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/s701/a/4">Pub. L. 108–173, § 701(a)(4)</ref>, inserted “or year” after “fiscal year” wherever appearing and “or years” after “fiscal years”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/s701/a/5">Pub. L. 108–173, § 701(a)(5)</ref>, inserted “or year” after “fiscal year”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (b)(3)(A)(i)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/6/tV/s501/a/3">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(6) [title V, § 501(a)(3)]</ref>, added subcl. (II). Former subcl. (II) redesignated (III).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(A)(i)(III). <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/6/tV/s501/a/1">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(6) [title V, § 501(a)(1), (2)]</ref>, redesignated subcl. (II) as (III) and substituted “described in subclause (II)” for “described in subclause (I)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/6/tV/s501/c/1">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(6) [title V, § 501(c)(1)]</ref>, added cl. (iv).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/6/tV/s504">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(6) [title V, § 504]</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/6/tIII/s321/k/19">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(6) [title III, § 321(k)(19)]</ref>, made technical amendment to reference in original act which appears in text as reference to <date date="1997-08-05">August 5, 1997</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/6/tIII/s302/b">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(6) [title III, § 302(b)]</ref>, amended heading and text of cl. (i) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Under such system the Secretary shall provide for computation of a standard prospective payment amount (or amounts). Such amount (or amounts) shall initially be based on the most current audited cost report data available to the Secretary and shall be computed in a manner so that the total amounts payable under the system for fiscal year 2001 shall be equal to the total amount that would have been made if the system had not been in effect but if the reduction in limits described in clause (ii) had been in effect. Such amount shall be standardized in a manner that eliminates the effect of variations in relative case mix and wage levels among different home health agencies in a budget neutral manner consistent with the case mix and wage level adjustments provided under paragraph (4)(A). Under the system, the Secretary may recognize regional differences or differences based upon whether or not the services or agency are in an urbanized area.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(A)(i)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/6/tIII/s303/b/1">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(6) [title III, § 303(b)(1)]</ref>, which directed that the second sentence of cl. (i) be amended in subcl. (I) by the insertion of “and if <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/v/1/L/ix">section 1395x(v)(1)(L)(ix) of this title</ref> had not been enacted” before semicolon, was executed by making the insertion before the period at end of subcl. (I) to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(A)(i)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/6/tIII/s303/b/2">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(6) [title III, § 303(b)(2)]</ref>, inserted “and if <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/v/1/L/ix">section 1395x(v)(1)(L)(ix) of this title</ref> had not been enacted” after “if the system had not been in effect”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(ii)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/s1000/a/6/tIII/s306">Pub. L. 106–113, § 1000(a)(6) [title III, § 306]</ref>, substituted “each of fiscal years 2002 and 2003” for “fiscal year 2002 or 2003”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s5101/c/1/A">Pub. L. 105–277, § 5101(c)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “for portions of cost reporting periods occurring on or after <date date="2000-10-01">October 1, 2000</date>” for “for cost reporting periods beginning on or after <date date="1999-10-01">October 1, 1999</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s5101/c/1/B/i">Pub. L. 105–277, § 5101(c)(1)(B)(i)</ref>, substituted “fiscal year 2001” for “fiscal year 2000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s5101/c/1/B/ii">Pub. L. 105–277, § 5101(c)(1)(B)(ii)</ref>, substituted “<date date="2000-09-30">September 30, 2000</date>” for “<date date="1999-09-30">September 30, 1999</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s5101/d/2/A">Pub. L. 105–277, § 5101(d)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “home health applicable increase percentage (as defined in clause (ii))” for “home health market basket percentage increase”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s5101/c/1/B/iii">Pub. L. 105–277, § 5101(c)(1)(B)(iii)</ref>, substituted “fiscal year 2002” for “fiscal year 2001”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(B)(ii), (iii). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s5101/d/2/B">Pub. L. 105–277, § 5101(d)(2)(B)</ref>, (C), added cl. (ii) and redesignated former cl. (ii) as (iii).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idba0b0bc6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idba0b0bc7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2020 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Secretary of Health and Human Services to prescribe regulations to apply the amendments made by <ref href="/us/pl/116/136">Pub. L. 116–136</ref> to items and services furnished, which shall become effective no later than 6 months after <date date="2020-03-27">Mar. 27, 2020</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/136/s3708/f">section 3708(f) of Pub. L. 116–136</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395f">section 1395f of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idba0b0bc8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2000 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/6/tV/s501/c/2">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(6) [title V, § 501(c)(2)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2763">114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–529, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/6/tV/s501/c/2">“The amendment made by paragraph (1) [amending this section] shall apply to episodes concluding on or after <date date="2001-10-01">October 1, 2001</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idba0b0bc9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1999 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 1000(a)(6) [title III, § 303(b)] of Pub. L.106–113 applicable to services furnished by home health agencies for cost reporting periods beginning on or after <date date="1999-10-01">Oct. 1, 1999</date>, see section 1000(a)(6) [title III, § 303(c)] of <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x">section 1395x of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 1000(a)(6) [title III, § 321(k)(19)] of <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref> effective as if included in the enactment of the Balanced Budget Act of 1997, <ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref>, except as otherwise provided, see section 1000(a)(6) [title III, § 321(m)] of <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395d">section 1395d of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idba0b0bca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tIV/s4603/d">Pub. L. 105–33, title IV, § 4603(d)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/471">111 Stat. 471</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dJ/tV/s5101/c/2">Pub. L. 105–277, div. J, title V, § 5101(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-914">112 Stat. 2681–914</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/277/dJ/tV/s5101/c/2">“Except as otherwise provided, the amendments made by this section [enacting this section and amending sections 1395f, 1395g, 1395k, 1395<i>l</i>, 1395u, and 1395y of this title] shall apply to portions of cost reporting periods occurring on or after <date date="2000-10-01">October 1, 2000</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba0d7bcb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Increasing Transparency for Home Health Payments Under the Medicare Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dFF/tIV/s4142">Pub. L. 117–328, div. FF, title IV, § 4142</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5929">136 Stat. 5929</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/328/dFF/tIV/s4142">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transparency</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In notice and comment rulemaking used to implement section 1895(b)(3)(D) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/D">42 U.S.C. 1395fff(b)(3)(D)</ref>[)], the Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the ‘Secretary’) shall, on the date of the notice of proposed rulemaking, make available through the internet website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Electronic data files showing the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services simulation of 60-day episodes under the home health prospective payment system in effect prior to the Patient Driven Groupings Model using data from 30-day periods paid under such Model, if such data are used in determining payment adjustments under clauses (ii) or (iii) of such section 1895(b)(3)(D).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> To the extent practicable, a description of actual behavior changes, as described in clause (i) of such section 1895(b)(3)(D), including behavior changes as a result of the implementation of sections 1895(b)(2)(B) and 1895(b)(4)(B) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/2/B">42 U.S.C. 1395fff(b)(2)(B)</ref> and 1395(b)(4)(B) [probably should be “1395fff(b)(4)(B)”]) that occurred in calendar years 2020 through 2026.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Engagement With Stakeholders.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this section [<date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>], the Secretary shall use an open door forum, a town hall meeting, a web-based forum, or other appropriate mechanism to receive input from home health stakeholders and interested parties on Medicare home health payment rate development, including the items described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) with respect to the home health prospective payment system rate for calendar year 2023.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement</inline>.—</heading><content>At least 30 days before the forum, meeting, or other mechanism referred to in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall make available through the internet website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services the items described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) with respect to the home health prospective payment system rate for calendar year 2023 as finalized in the final rule entitled ‘Medicare Program; Calendar Year [(CY)] 2023 Home Health Prospective Payment System Rate Update; Home Health Quality Reporting Program Requirements; Home Health Value-Based Purchasing Expanded Model Requirements; and Home Infusion Therapy Services Requirements’ published in the Federal Register on <date date="2022-11-04">November 4, 2022</date> (87 Fed. Reg. 66790).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Construction</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this section shall be construed to require any change in the methodology used by the Secretary to implement such section 1895(b)(3)(D), to restrict the Secretary’s discretion in establishing the methodology to implement such section, or to suggest that the Secretary’s promulgation of the methodology implementing such Calendar Year 2023 home health final rule was inadequate under Chapter 5 of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the ‘Administrative Procedures Act’ [probably should be “Administrative Procedure Act”]) or any other provision of law.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba0d7bcc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study and Report on the Development of Home Health Payment Revisions in Order To Ensure Access to Care and Payment for Severity of Illness</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tIII/s3131/d">Pub. L. 111–148, title III, § 3131(d)</ref>, title X, § 10315(b), <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/429">124 Stat. 429</ref>, 944, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/148/tIII/s3131/d">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the ‘Secretary’) shall conduct a study on home health agency costs involved with providing ongoing access to care to low-income Medicare beneficiaries or beneficiaries in medically underserved areas, and in treating beneficiaries with varying levels of severity of illness. In conducting the study, the Secretary may analyze items such as the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> Methods to potentially revise the home health prospective payment system under section 1895 of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff">42 U.S.C. 1395fff</ref>) to account for costs related to patient severity of illness or to improving beneficiary access to care, such as—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> payment adjustments for services that may involve additional or fewer resources;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> changes to reflect resources involved with providing home health services to low-income Medicare beneficiaries or Medicare beneficiaries residing in medically underserved areas;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> ways outlier payments might be revised to reflect costs of treating Medicare beneficiaries with high levels of severity of illness; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> other issues determined appropriate by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Operational issues involved with potential implementation of potential revisions to the home health payment system, including impacts for both home health agencies and administrative and systems issues for the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, and any possible payment vulnerabilities associated with implementing potential revisions.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Whether additional research might be needed.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Other items determined appropriate by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Considerations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In conducting the study under paragraph (1), the Secretary may consider whether patient severity of illness and access to care could be measured by factors, such as—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> population density and relative patient access to care;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> variations in service costs for providing care to individuals who are dually eligible under the Medicare and Medicaid programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the presence of severe or chronic diseases, which might be measured by multiple, discontinuous home health episodes;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> poverty status, such as evidenced by the receipt of Supplemental Security Income under title XVI of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1381">42 U.S.C. 1381</ref> et seq.]; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> other factors determined appropriate by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2014-03-01">March 1, 2014</date>, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the study conducted under paragraph (1), together with recommendations for such legislation and administrative action as the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consultations</inline>.—</heading><content>In conducting the study under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consult with appropriate stakeholders, such as groups representing home health agencies and groups representing Medicare beneficiaries.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Medicare demonstration project based on the results of the study.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to subparagraph (D), taking into account the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1), the Secretary may, as determined appropriate, provide for a demonstration project to test whether making payment adjustments for home health services under the Medicare program would substantially improve access to care for patients with high severity levels of illness or for low-income or underserved Medicare beneficiaries.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Waiving budget neutrality</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall not reduce the standard prospective payment amount (or amounts) under section 1895 of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff">42 U.S.C. 1395fff</ref>) applicable to home health services furnished during a period to offset any increase in payments during such period resulting from the application of the payment adjustments under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">No effect on subsequent periods</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A payment adjustment resulting from the application of subparagraph (A) for a period—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> shall not apply to payments for home health services under title XVIII [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395">42 U.S.C. 1395</ref> et seq.] after such period; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> shall not be taken into account in calculating the payment amounts applicable for such services after such period.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Duration</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Secretary determines it appropriate to conduct the demonstration project under this subsection, the Secretary shall conduct the project for a four year period beginning not later than <date date="2015-01-01">January 1, 2015</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="E">“(E)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall provide for the transfer from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund under section 1817 of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395i">42 U.S.C. 1395i</ref>) and the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund established under section 1841 of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395t">42 U.S.C. 1395t</ref>), in such proportion as the Secretary determines appropriate, of $500,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2015 through 2018. Such funds shall be made available for the study described in paragraph (1) and the design, implementation and evaluation of the demonstration described in this paragraph. Amounts available under this subparagraph shall be available until expended.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="F">“(F)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Evaluation and report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>If the Secretary determines it appropriate to conduct the demonstration project under this subsection, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> provide for an evaluation of the project; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> submit to Congress, by a date specified by the Secretary, a report on the project.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="G">“(G)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Administration</inline>.—</heading><content>Chapter 35 of title 44, United States Code, shall not apply with respect to this subsection.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba0d7bcd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Temporary Increase for Home Health Services Furnished in a Rural Area</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/173/tIV/s421">Pub. L. 108–173, title IV, § 421</ref>, <date date="2003-12-08">Dec. 8, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2283">117 Stat. 2283</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/tV/s5201/b">Pub. L. 109–171, title V, § 5201(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-02-08">Feb. 8, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/46">120 Stat. 46</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tIII/s3131/c">Pub. L. 111–148, title III, § 3131(c)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/428">124 Stat. 428</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/10/tII/s210">Pub. L. 114–10, title II, § 210</ref>, <date date="2015-04-16">Apr. 16, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/151">129 Stat. 151</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/123/dE/tII/s50208/a/1">Pub. L. 115–123, div. E, title II, § 50208(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-02-09">Feb. 9, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/188">132 Stat. 188</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dFF/tIV/s4137">Pub. L. 117–328, div. FF, title IV, § 4137</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5925">136 Stat. 5925</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/328/dFF/tIV/s4137">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>With respect to episodes and visits ending on or after <date date="2004-04-01">April 1, 2004</date>, and before <date date="2005-04-01">April 1, 2005</date>, episodes and visits beginning on or after <date date="2006-01-01">January 1, 2006</date>, and before <date date="2007-01-01">January 1, 2007</date>, and episodes and visits ending on or after <date date="2010-04-01">April 1, 2010</date>, and before <date date="2019-01-01">January 1, 2019</date>, in the case of home health services furnished in a rural area (as defined in section 1886(d)(2)(D) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ww/d/2/D">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(d)(2)(D)</ref>)), the Secretary [of Health and Human Services] shall increase the payment amount otherwise made under section 1895 of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff">42 U.S.C. 1395fff</ref>) for such services by 5 percent (or, in the case of episodes and visits ending on or after <date date="2010-04-01">April 1, 2010</date>, and before <date date="2019-01-01">January 1, 2019</date>, 3 percent).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Subsequent Temporary Increase.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall increase the payment amount otherwise made under such section 1895 for home health services furnished in a county (or equivalent area) in a rural area (as defined in such section 1886(d)(2)(D)) that, as determined by the Secretary—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> is in the highest quartile of all counties (or equivalent areas) based on the number of Medicare home health episodes furnished per 100 individuals who are entitled to, or enrolled for, benefits under part A of title XVIII of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395c">42 U.S.C. 1395c</ref> et seq.] or enrolled for benefits under part B of such title [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395j">42 U.S.C. 1395j</ref> et seq.] (but not enrolled in a plan under part C of such title [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395w–21">42 U.S.C. 1395w–21</ref> et seq.])—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> in the case of episodes and visits ending during 2019, by 1.5 percent; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> in the case of episodes and visits ending during 2020, by 0.5 percent;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> has a population density of 6 individuals or fewer per square mile of land area and is not described in subparagraph (A)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> in the case of episodes and visits ending during 2019, by 4 percent;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> in the case of episodes and visits ending during 2020, by 3 percent;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> in the case of episodes and visits ending during 2021, by 2 percent;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iv">“(iv)</num><content> in the case of episodes and visits ending during 2022, by 1 percent; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="v">“(v)</num><content> in the case of episodes and visits ending during 2023, by 1 percent; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> is not described in either subparagraph (A) or (B)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> in the case of episodes and visits ending during 2019, by 3 percent;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> in the case of episodes and visits ending during 2020, by 2 percent; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> in the case of episodes and visits ending during 2021, by 1 percent.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Rules for determinations.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">No switching</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this subsection, the determination by the Secretary as to which subparagraph of paragraph (1) applies to a county (or equivalent area) shall be made a single time and shall apply for the duration of the period to which this subsection applies.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Utilization</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In determining which counties (or equivalent areas) are in the highest quartile under paragraph (1)(A), the following rules shall apply:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> The Secretary shall use data from 2015.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> The Secretary shall exclude data from the territories (and the territories shall not be described in such paragraph).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> The Secretary may exclude data from counties (or equivalent areas) in rural areas with a low volume of home health episodes (and if data is so excluded with respect to a county (or equivalent area), such county (or equivalent area) shall not be described in such paragraph).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Population density</inline>.—</heading><content>In determining population density under paragraph (1)(B), the Secretary shall use data from the 2010 decennial Census.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitations on review</inline>.—</heading><content>There shall be no administrative or judicial review under section 1869 [probably means section 1869 of the Social Security Act, <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ff">42 U.S.C. 1395ff</ref>], section 1878 [probably means section 1878 of the Social Security Act, <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395">42 U.S.C. 1395</ref><i>oo</i>], or otherwise of determinations under paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Waiving Budget Neutrality</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall not reduce the standard prospective payment amount (or amounts) under section 1895 of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff">42 U.S.C. 1395fff</ref>) applicable to home health services furnished during a period to offset the increase in payments resulting from the application of subsection (a) or (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">No Effect on Subsequent Periods</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The payment increase provided under subsection (a) or (b) for a period under such subsection—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> shall not apply to episodes and visits ending after such period; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> shall not be taken into account in calculating the payment amounts applicable for episodes and visits occurring after such period.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba0d7bce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Demonstration Project for Medical Adult Day-Care Services</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/173/tVII/s703">Pub. L. 108–173, title VII, § 703</ref>, <date date="2003-12-08">Dec. 8, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2336">117 Stat. 2336</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/173/tVII/s703">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to the succeeding provisions of this section, the Secretary [of Health and Human Services] shall establish a demonstration project (in this section referred to as the ‘demonstration project’) under which the Secretary shall, as part of a plan of an episode of care for home health services established for a medicare beneficiary, permit a home health agency, directly or under arrangements with a medical adult day-care facility, to provide medical adult day-care services as a substitute for a portion of home health services that would otherwise be provided in the beneficiary’s home.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Payment.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to paragraph (2), the amount of payment for an episode of care for home health services, a portion of which consists of substitute medical adult day-care services, under the demonstration project shall be made at a rate equal to 95 percent of the amount that would otherwise apply for such home health services under section 1895 of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff">42 U.S.C. 1395fff</ref>). In no case may a home health agency, or a medical adult day-care facility under arrangements with a home health agency, separately charge a beneficiary for medical adult day-care services furnished under the plan of care.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Adjustment in case of overutilization of substitute adult day-care services to ensure budget neutrality</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall monitor the expenditures under the demonstration project and under title XVIII of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395">42 U.S.C. 1395</ref> et seq.] for home health services. If the Secretary estimates that the total expenditures under the demonstration project and under such title XVIII for home health services for a period determined by the Secretary exceed expenditures that would have been made under such title XVIII for home health services for such period if the demonstration project had not been conducted, the Secretary shall adjust the rate of payment to medical adult day-care facilities under paragraph (1) in order to eliminate such excess.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Demonstration Project Sites</inline>.—</heading><content>The demonstration project established under this section shall be conducted in not more than 5 sites in States selected by the Secretary that license or certify providers of services that furnish medical adult day-care services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Duration</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall conduct the demonstration project for a period of 3 years.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Voluntary Participation</inline>.—</heading><content>Participation of medicare beneficiaries in the demonstration project shall be voluntary. The total number of such beneficiaries that may participate in the project at any given time may not exceed 15,000.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Preference in Selecting Agencies</inline>.—</heading><content>In selecting home health agencies to participate under the demonstration project, the Secretary shall give preference to those agencies that are currently licensed or certified through common ownership and control to furnish medical adult day-care services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Waiver Authority</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary may waive such requirements of title XVIII of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395">42 U.S.C. 1395</ref> et seq.] as may be necessary for the purposes of carrying out the demonstration project, other than waiving the requirement that an individual be homebound in order to be eligible for benefits for home health services.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Evaluation and Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall conduct an evaluation of the clinical and cost-effectiveness of the demonstration project. Not later than 6 months after the completion of the project, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the evaluation, and shall include in the report the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> An analysis of the patient outcomes and costs of furnishing care to the medicare beneficiaries participating in the project as compared to such outcomes and costs to beneficiaries receiving only home health services for the same health conditions.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Such recommendations regarding the extension, expansion, or termination of the project as the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Home health agency</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘home health agency’ has the meaning given such term in section 1861(<i>o</i>) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x</ref>(<i>o</i>)).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Medical adult day-care facility</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘medical adult day-care facility’ means a facility that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> has been licensed or certified by a State to furnish medical adult day-care services in the State for a continuous 2-year period;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> is engaged in providing skilled nursing services and other therapeutic services directly or under arrangement with a home health agency;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> is licensed and certified by the State in which it operates or meets such standards established by the Secretary to assure quality of care and such other requirements as the Secretary finds necessary in the interest of the health and safety of individuals who are furnished services in the facility; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> provides medical adult day-care services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Medical adult day-care services</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘medical adult day-care services’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> home health service items and services described in paragraphs (1) through (7) of section 1861(m) [probably means section 1861(m) of the Social Security Act, <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/m">42 U.S.C. 1395x(m)</ref>] furnished in a medical adult day-care facility;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> a program of supervised activities furnished in a group setting in the facility that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> meet such criteria as the Secretary determines appropriate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> is designed to promote physical and mental health of the individuals; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> such other services as the Secretary may specify.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Medicare beneficiary</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘medicare beneficiary’ means an individual entitled to benefits under part A of this title [probably means part A of title XVIII of the Social Security Act, <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395c">42 U.S.C. 1395c</ref> et seq.], enrolled under part B of this title [probably means part B of title XVIII of the Social Security Act, <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395j">42 U.S.C. 1395j</ref> et seq.], or both.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba0d7bcf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Temporary Suspension of Oasis Requirement for Collection of Data on Non-Medicare and Non-Medicaid Patients</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/173/tVII/s704">Pub. L. 108–173, title VII, § 704</ref>, <date date="2003-12-08">Dec. 8, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2338">117 Stat. 2338</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/173/tVII/s704">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>During the period described in subsection (b), the Secretary [of Health and Human Services] may not require, under section 4602(e) of the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 (<ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Public Law 105–33</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/111/467">111 Stat. 467</ref>) [set out as a note under this section] or otherwise under OASIS, a home health agency to gather or submit information that relates to an individual who is not eligible for benefits under either title XVIII or title XIX of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395">42 U.S.C. 1395</ref> et seq., 1396 et seq.] (such information in this section referred to as ‘non-medicare/medicaid OASIS information’).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Period of Suspension</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The period described in this subsection—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> begins on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2003-12-08">Dec. 8, 2003</date>]; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> ends on the last day of the second month beginning after the date as of which the Secretary has published final regulations regarding the collection and use by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services of non-medicare/medicaid OASIS information following the submission of the report required under subsection (c).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall conduct a study on how non-medicare/medicaid OASIS information is and can be used by large home health agencies. Such study shall examine—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> whether there are unique benefits from the analysis of such information that cannot be derived from other information available to, or collected by, such agencies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the value of collecting such information by small home health agencies compared to the administrative burden related to such collection.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I31" class="indent1 firstIndent0">In conducting the study the Secretary shall obtain recommendations from quality assessment experts in the use of such information and the necessity of small, as well as large, home health agencies collecting such information.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the study conducted under paragraph (1) by not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2003-12-08">Dec. 8, 2003</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Construction</inline>.—</heading><content>Nothing in this section shall be construed as preventing home health agencies from collecting non-medicare/medicaid OASIS information for their own use.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba0d7bd0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">MedPAC Study on Medicare Margins of Home Health Agencies</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/173/tVII/s705">Pub. L. 108–173, title VII, § 705</ref>, <date date="2003-12-08">Dec. 8, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2339">117 Stat. 2339</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/173/tVII/s705">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study</inline>.—</heading><content>The Medicare Payment Advisory Commission shall conduct a study of payment margins of home health agencies under the home health prospective payment system under section 1895 of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff">42 U.S.C. 1395fff</ref>). Such study shall examine whether systematic differences in payment margins are related to differences in case mix (as measured by home health resource groups (HHRGs)) among such agencies. The study shall use the partial or full-year cost reports filed by home health agencies.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2003-12-08">Dec. 8, 2003</date>], the Commission shall submit to Congress a report on the study under subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba0d7bd1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Special Rule for Payment for Fiscal Year 2001 Based on Adjusted Prospective Payment Amounts</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/6/tV/s502/b">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(6) [title V, § 502(b)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2763">114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–530, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/6/tV/s502/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding the amendments made by subsection (a) [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x">section 1395x of this title</ref>], for purposes of making payments under section 1895(b) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b">42 U.S.C. 1395fff(b)</ref>) for home health services furnished during fiscal year 2001, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> with respect to episodes and visits ending on or after <date date="2000-10-01">October 1, 2000</date>, and before <date date="2001-04-01">April 1, 2001</date>, use the final standardized and budget neutral prospective payment amounts for 60-day episodes and standardized average per visit amounts for fiscal year 2001 as published by the Secretary in the Federal Register on <date date="2000-07-03">July 3, 2000</date> (65 Fed. Reg. 41128–41214); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> with respect to episodes and visits ending on or after <date date="2001-04-01">April 1, 2001</date>, and before <date date="2001-10-01">October 1, 2001</date>, use such amounts increased by 2.2 percent.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">No effect on other payments or determinations</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall not take the provisions of paragraph (1) into account for purposes of payments, determinations, or budget neutrality adjustments under section 1895 of the Social Security Act.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba0d7bd2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Temporary Two-Month Periodic Interim Payment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/6/tV/s503">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(6) [title V, § 503]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2763">114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–530, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/6/tV/s503">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding the amendments made by section 4603(b) of BBA [<ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref>, amending <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395g">section 1395g of this title</ref>] (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff">42 U.S.C. 1395fff</ref> note), in the case of a home health agency that was receiving periodic interim payments under section 1815(e)(2) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395g/e/2">42 U.S.C. 1395g(e)(2)</ref>) as of <date date="2000-09-30">September 30, 2000</date>, and that is not described in subsection (b), the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall, as soon as practicable, make a single periodic interim payment to such agency in an amount equal to four times the last full fortnightly periodic interim payment made to such agency under the payment system in effect prior to the implementation of the prospective payment system under section 1895(b) of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b">42 U.S.C. 1395fff(b)</ref>). Such amount of such periodic interim payment shall be included in the tentative settlement of the last cost report for the home health agency under the payment system in effect prior to the implementation of such prospective payment system, regardless of the ending date of such cost report.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exceptions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary shall not make an additional periodic interim payment under subsection (a) in the case of a home health agency (determined as of the day that such payment would otherwise be made) that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> notifies the Secretary that such agency does not want to receive such payment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> is not receiving payments pursuant to section 405.371 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> is excluded from the medicare program under title XI of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1301">42 U.S.C. 1301</ref> et seq.];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> no longer has a provider agreement under section 1866 of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395cc">42 U.S.C. 1395cc</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> is no longer in business; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> is subject to a court order providing for the withholding of medicare payments under title XVIII of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395">42 U.S.C. 1395</ref> et seq.].”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba0d7bd3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Temporary Increase for Home Health Services Furnished in a Rural Area</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/6/tV/s508">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(6) [title V, § 508]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2763">114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–533, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/6/tV/s508">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> 24<inline class="small-caps">-Month Increase Beginning April</inline> 1, 2001.—</heading><content>In the case of home health services furnished in a rural area (as defined in section 1886(d)(2)(D) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ww/d/2/D">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(d)(2)(D)</ref>)) on or after <date date="2001-04-01">April 1, 2001</date>, and before <date date="2003-04-01">April 1, 2003</date>, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall increase the payment amount otherwise made under section 1895 of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff">42 U.S.C. 1395fff</ref>) for such services by 10 percent.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Waiving Budget Neutrality</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall not reduce the standard prospective payment amount (or amounts) under section 1895 of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff">42 U.S.C. 1395fff</ref>) applicable to home health services furnished during a period to offset the increase in payments resulting from the application of subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba0d7bd4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Clarification of Application of Temporary Payment Increases for 2001</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/6/tV/s547/c">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(6) [title V, § 547(c)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2763">114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–553, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/6/tV/s547/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transitional allowance for full marketbasket [sic] increase</inline>.—</heading><content>The payment increase provided under section 502(b)(1)(B) [set out as a note above] shall not apply to episodes and visits ending after fiscal year 2001 and shall not be taken into account in calculating the payment amounts applicable for subsequent episodes and visits.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Temporary increase for rural home health services</inline>.—</heading><content>The payment increase provided under section 508(a) [set out as a note above] for the period beginning on <date date="2001-04-01">April 1, 2001</date>, and ending on <date date="2002-09-30">September 30, 2002</date>, shall not apply to episodes and visits ending after such period, and shall not be taken into account in calculating the payment amounts applicable for episodes and visits occurring after such period.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba0d7bd5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Adjustment To Reflect Administrative Costs Not Included in the Interim Payment System; GAO Report on Costs of Compliance With Oasis Data Collection Requirements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/6/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(6) [title III, § 301]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–358, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/6/tIII/s301">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Adjustment To Reflect Administrative Costs</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>In the case of a home health agency that furnishes home health services to a medicare beneficiary, for each such beneficiary to whom the agency furnished such services during the agency’s cost reporting period beginning in fiscal year 2000, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall pay the agency, in addition to any amount of payment made under section 1861(v)(1)(L) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/v/1/L">42 U.S.C. 1395x(v)(1)(L)</ref>) for the beneficiary and only for such cost reporting period, an aggregate amount of $10 to defray costs incurred by the agency attributable to data collection and reporting requirements under the Outcome and Assessment Information Set (OASIS) required by reason of section 4602(e) of BBA [the Balanced Budget Act of 1997, <ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref>] (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff">42 U.S.C. 1395fff</ref> note).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Payment schedule</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Midyear payment</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2000-04-01">April 1, 2000</date>, the Secretary shall pay to a home health agency an amount that the Secretary estimates to be 50 percent of the aggregate amount payable to the agency by reason of this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Upon settled cost report</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall pay the balance of amounts payable to an agency under this subsection on the date that the cost report submitted by the agency for the cost reporting period beginning in fiscal year 2000 is settled.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Payment from trust funds</inline>.—</heading><content>Payments under this subsection shall be made, in appropriate part as specified by the Secretary, from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund and from the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subsection:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Home health agency</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘home health agency’ has the meaning given that term under section 1861(<i>o</i>) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x</ref>(<i>o</i>)).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Home health services</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘home health services’ has the meaning given that term under section 1861(m) of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/m">42 U.S.C. 1395x(m)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Medicare beneficiary</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘medicare beneficiary’ means a beneficiary described in section 1861(v)(1)(L)(vi)(II) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/v/1/L/vi/II">42 U.S.C. 1395x(v)(1)(L)(vi)(II)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">GAO Report on Costs of Compliance With OASIS Data Collection Requirements.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to congress.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>], the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on the matters described in subparagraph (B) with respect to the data collection requirement of patients of such agencies under the Outcome and Assessment Information Set (OASIS) standard as part of the comprehensive assessment of patients.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Matters studied</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the matters described in this subparagraph include the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> An assessment of the costs incurred by medicare home health agencies in complying with such data collection requirement.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> An analysis of the effect of such data collection requirement on the privacy interests of patients from whom data is collected.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Audit</inline>.—</heading><content>The Comptroller General shall conduct an independent audit of the costs described in subparagraph (B)(i). Not later than 180 days after receipt of the report under subparagraph (A), the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report describing the Comptroller General’s findings with respect to such audit, and shall include comments on the report submitted to Congress by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under subparagraph (A).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this subsection:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Comprehensive assessment of patients</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘comprehensive assessment of patients’ means the rule published by the Health Care Financing Administration that requires, as a condition of participation in the medicare program, a home health agency to provide a patient-specific comprehensive assessment that accurately reflects the patient’s current status and that incorporates the Outcome and Assessment Information Set (OASIS).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Outcome and assessment information set</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Outcome and Assessment Information Set’ means the standard provided under the rule relating to data items that must be used in conducting a comprehensive assessment of patients.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba0d7bd6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report to Congress on Need for Reductions</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/6/tIII/s302/c">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(6) [title III, § 302(c)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–360, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/6/tV/s501/b">Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(6) [title V, § 501(b)]</ref>, <date date="2000-12-21">Dec. 21, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2763">114 Stat. 2763</ref>, 2763A–529, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/554/s1/a/6/tV/s501/b">“Not later than <date date="2002-04-01">April 1, 2002</date>, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report analyzing the need for the 15 percent reduction under subsection (b)(3)(A)(ii) of such section [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff/b/3/A/ii">42 U.S.C. 1395fff(b)(3)(A)(ii)</ref>], or for any reduction, in the computation of the base payment amounts under the prospective payment system for home health services established under such section.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba0d7bd7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study and Report to Congress Regarding Exemption of Rural Agencies and Populations From Inclusion in Home Health Prospective Payment System</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/6/tIII/s307">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(6) [title III, § 307]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–362, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/6/tIII/s307">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study</inline>.—</heading><content>The Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (referred to in this section as ‘MedPAC’) shall conduct a study to determine the feasibility and advisability of exempting home health services provided by a home health agency (or by others under arrangements with such agency) located in a rural area, or to an individual residing in a rural area, from payment under the prospective payment system for such services established by the Secretary of Health and Human Services in accordance with section 1895 of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395fff">42 U.S.C. 1395fff</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>], MedPAC shall submit a report to Congress on the study conducted under subsection (a), together with any recommendations for legislation that MedPAC determines to be appropriate as a result of such study.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba0d7bd8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Case Mix System Development</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tIV/s4602/d">Pub. L. 105–33, title IV, § 4602(d)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/467">111 Stat. 467</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/33/tIV/s4602/d">“The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall expand research on a prospective payment system for home health agencies under the medicare program that ties prospective payments to a unit of service, including an intensive effort to develop a reliable case mix adjuster that explains a significant amount of the variances in costs.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba0d7bd9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Case Mix System; Submission of Data</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tIV/s4602/e">Pub. L. 105–33, title IV, § 4602(e)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/467">111 Stat. 467</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/33/tIV/s4602/e">“Effective for cost reporting periods beginning on or after <date date="1997-10-01">October 1, 1997</date>, the Secretary of Health and Human Services may require all home health agencies to submit additional information that the Secretary considers necessary for the development of a reliable case mix system.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba0d7bda-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prospective Payment System Contingency</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tIV/s4603/e">Pub. L. 105–33, title IV, § 4603(e)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/471">111 Stat. 471</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dJ/tV/s5101/c/3">Pub. L. 105–277, div. J, title V, § 5101(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-914">112 Stat. 2681–914</ref>, provided that if the Secretary of Health and Human Services did not establish and implement the prospective payment system for home health services described in subsec. (b) of this section for portions of cost reporting periods described in <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s4603/d">section 4603(d) of Pub. L. 105–33</ref> (set out as a note above), for such portions the Secretary was to provide for a reduction by 15 percent in the cost limits and per beneficiary limits described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/v/1/L">section 1395x(v)(1)(L) of this title</ref>, as those limits would otherwise have been in effect on <date date="2000-09-30">Sept. 30, 2000</date>, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/6/tIII/s302/a">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(6) [title III, § 302(a)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–359.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba0d7bdb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Reports to Congress Regarding Home Health Cost Containment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tIV/s4616">Pub. L. 105–33, title IV, § 4616</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/475">111 Stat. 475</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/33/tIV/s4616">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Estimate</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="1997-10-01">October 1, 1997</date>, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to the Committees on Commerce and Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report that includes an estimate of the outlays that will be made under parts A and B of title XVIII of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395c">42 U.S.C. 1395c</ref> et seq., 1395j et seq.] for the provision of home health services during each of fiscal years 1998 through 2002.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than the end of each of years 1999 through 2002, the Secretary shall submit to such Committees a report that compares the actual outlays under such parts for such services during the fiscal year ending in the year, to the outlays estimated under subsection (a) for such fiscal year. If the Secretary finds that such actual outlays were greater than such estimated outlays for the fiscal year, the Secretary shall include in the report recommendations regarding beneficiary copayments for home health services provided under the medicare program or such other methods as will reduce the growth in outlays for home health services under the medicare program.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
