<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb89e34a9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i"><num value="1395i">§ 1395i.</num><heading> Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb89e34aa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Creation; deposits; transfers from Treasury</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is hereby created on the books of the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the “Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund” (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Trust Fund”). The Trust Fund shall consist of such gifts and bequests as may be made as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401/i/1">section 401(i)(1) of this title</ref>, and such amounts as may be deposited in, or appropriated to, such fund as provided in this part. There are hereby appropriated to the Trust Fund for the fiscal year ending <date date="1966-06-30">June 30, 1966</date>, and for each fiscal year thereafter, out of any moneys in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, amounts equivalent to 100 per centum of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb89e34ab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the taxes imposed by sections 3101(b) and 3111(b) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to wages reported to the Secretary of the Treasury or his delegate pursuant to subtitle F of such Code after <date date="1965-12-31">December 31, 1965</date>, as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury by applying the applicable rates of tax under such sections to such wages, which wages shall be certified by the Commissioner of Social Security on the basis of records of wages established and maintained by the Commissioner of Social Security in accordance with such reports; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8a0a5ac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the taxes imposed by section 1401(b) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to self-employment income reported to the Secretary of the Treasury or his delegate on tax returns under subtitle F of such Code, as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury by applying the applicable rate of tax under such section to such self-employment income, which self-employment income shall be certified by the Commissioner of Social Security on the basis of records of self-employment established and maintained by the Commissioner of Social Security in accordance with such returns.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The amounts appropriated by the preceding sentence shall be transferred from time to time from the general fund in the Treasury to the Trust Fund, such amounts to be determined on the basis of estimates by the Secretary of the Treasury of the taxes, specified in the preceding sentence, paid to or deposited into the Treasury; and proper adjustments shall be made in amounts subsequently transferred to the extent prior estimates were in excess of or were less than the taxes specified in such sentence.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a5ad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Board of Trustees; composition; meetings; duties</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With respect to the Trust Fund, there is hereby created a body to be known as the Board of Trustees of the Trust Fund (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Board of Trustees”) composed of the Commissioner of Social Security, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Labor, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services, all ex officio, and of two members of the public (both of whom may not be from the same political party), who shall be nominated by the President for a term of four years and subject to confirmation by the Senate. A member of the Board of Trustees serving as a member of the public and nominated and confirmed to fill a vacancy occurring during a term shall be nominated and confirmed only for the remainder of such term. An individual nominated and confirmed as a member of the public may serve in such position after the expiration of such member’s term until the earlier of the time at which the member’s successor takes office or the time at which a report of the Board is first issued under paragraph (2) after the expiration of the member’s term. The Secretary of the Treasury shall be the Managing Trustee of the Board of Trustees (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Managing Trustee”). The Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services shall serve as the Secretary of the Board of Trustees. The Board of Trustees shall meet not less frequently than once each calendar year. It shall be the duty of the Board of Trustees to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8a0a5ae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Hold the Trust Fund;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8a0a5af-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Report to the Congress not later than the first day of April of each year on the operation and status of the Trust Fund during the preceding fiscal year and on its expected operation and status during the current fiscal year and the next 2 fiscal years; Each report provided under paragraph (2) beginning with the report in 2005 shall include the information specified in section 801(a) of the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002769">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002769"><num>1</num> So in original. See 2003 Amendment note below.</note></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8a0a5b0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Report immediately to the Congress whenever the Board is of the opinion that the amount of the Trust Fund is unduly small; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8a0a5b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Review the general policies followed in managing the Trust Fund, and recommend changes in such policies, including necessary changes in the provisions of law which govern the way in which the Trust Fund is to be managed.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The report provided for in paragraph (2) shall include a statement of the assets of, and the disbursements made from, the Trust Fund during the preceding fiscal year, an estimate of the expected income to, and disbursements to be made from, the Trust Fund during the current fiscal year and each of the next 2 fiscal years, and a statement of the actuarial status of the Trust Fund. Such report shall also include an actuarial opinion by the Chief Actuary of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services certifying that the techniques and methodologies used are generally accepted within the actuarial profession and that the assumptions and cost estimates used are reasonable. Such report shall be printed as a House document of the session of the Congress to which the report is made. A person serving on the Board of Trustees shall not be considered to be a fiduciary and shall not be personally liable for actions taken in such capacity with respect to the Trust Fund.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a5b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Investment of Trust Fund by Managing Trustee</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be the duty of the Managing Trustee to invest such portion of the Trust Fund as is not, in his judgment, required to meet current withdrawals. Such investments may be made only in interest-bearing obligations of the United States or in obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by the United States. For such purpose such obligations may be acquired (1) on original issue at the issue price, or (2) by purchase of outstanding obligations at the market price. The purposes for which obligations of the United States may be issued under chapter 31 of title 31 are hereby extended to authorize the issuance at par of public-debt obligations for purchase by the Trust Fund. Such obligations issued for purchase by the Trust Fund shall have maturities fixed with due regard for the needs of the Trust Fund and shall bear interest at a rate equal to the average market yield (computed by the Managing Trustee on the basis of market quotations as of the end of the calendar month next preceding the date of such issue) on all marketable interest-bearing obligations of the United States then forming a part of the public debt which are not due or callable until after the expiration of 4 years from the end of such calendar month; except that where such average market yield is not a multiple of one-eighth of 1 per centum, the rate of interest on such obligations shall be the multiple of one-eighth of 1 per centum nearest such market yield. The Managing Trustee may purchase other interest-bearing obligations of the United States or obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by the United States, on original issue or at the market price, only where he determines that the purchase of such other obligations is in the public interest.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a5b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of Managing Trustee to sell obligations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any obligations acquired by the Trust Fund (except public-debt obligations issued exclusively to the Trust Fund) may be sold by the Managing Trustee at the market price, and such public-debt obligations may be redeemed at par plus accrued interest.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a5b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Interest on and proceeds from sale or redemption of obligations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in the Trust Fund shall be credited to and form a part of the Trust Fund.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a5b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment of estimated taxes</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a0a5b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Managing Trustee is directed to pay from time to time from the Trust Fund into the Treasury the amount estimated by him as taxes imposed under section 3101(b) which are subject to refund under section 6413(c) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to wages paid after <date date="1965-12-31">December 31, 1965</date>. Such taxes shall be determined on the basis of the records of wages established and maintained by the Commissioner of Social Security in accordance with the wages reported to the Secretary of the Treasury or his delegate pursuant to subtitle F of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and the Commissioner of Social Security shall furnish the Managing Trustee such information as may be required by the Managing Trustee for such purpose. The payments by the Managing Trustee shall be covered into the Treasury as repayments to the account for refunding internal revenue collections.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a0a5b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Repayments made under paragraph (1) shall not be available for expenditures but shall be carried to the surplus fund of the Treasury. If it subsequently appears that the estimates under such paragraph in any particular period were too high or too low, appropriate adjustments shall be made by the Managing Trustee in future payments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a5b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfers from other Funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There shall be transferred periodically (but not less often than once each fiscal year) to the Trust Fund from the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and from the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund amounts equivalent to the amounts not previously so transferred which the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall have certified as overpayments (other than amounts so certified to the Railroad Retirement Board) pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395gg/b">section 1395gg(b) of this title</ref>. There shall be transferred periodically (but not less often than once each fiscal year) to the Trust Fund from the Railroad Retirement Account amounts equivalent to the amounts not previously so transferred which the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall have certified as overpayments to the Railroad Retirement Board pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395gg/b">section 1395gg(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a5b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Payments from Trust Fund amounts certified by Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Managing Trustee shall also pay from time to time from the Trust Fund such amounts as the Secretary of Health and Human Services certifies are necessary to make the payments provided for by this part, and the payments with respect to administrative expenses in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401/g/1">section 401(g)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a5ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment of travel expenses for travel within United States; reconsideration interviews and proceedings before administrative law judges</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be made available for expenditure out of the Trust Fund such amounts as are required to pay travel expenses, either on an actual cost or commuted basis, to parties, their representatives, and all reasonably necessary witnesses for travel within the United States (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s410/i">section 410(i) of this title</ref>) to attend reconsideration interviews and proceedings before administrative law judges with respect to any determination under this subchapter. The amount available under the preceding sentence for payment for air travel by any person shall not exceed the coach fare for air travel between the points involved unless the use of first-class accommodations is required (as determined under regulations of the Secretary) because of such person’s health condition or the unavailability of alternative accommodations; and the amount available for payment for other travel by any person shall not exceed the cost of travel (between the points involved) by the most economical and expeditious means of transportation appropriate to such person’s health condition, as specified in such regulations. The amount available for payment under this subsection for travel by a representative to attend an administrative proceeding before an administrative law judge or other adjudicator shall not exceed the maximum amount allowable under this subsection for such travel originating within the geographic area of the office having jurisdiction over such proceeding.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a5bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Loans from other Funds; interest; repayment; report to Congress</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a0a5bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> If at any time prior to January 1988 the Managing Trustee determines that borrowing authorized under this subsection is appropriate in order to best meet the need for financing the benefit payments from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund, the Managing Trustee may, subject to paragraph (5), borrow such amounts as he determines to be appropriate from either the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund or the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund for transfer to and deposit in the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a0a5bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In any case where a loan has been made to the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund under paragraph (1), there shall be transferred on the last day of each month after such loan is made, from such Trust Fund to the lending Trust Fund, the total interest accrued to such day with respect to the unrepaid balance of such loan at a rate equal to the rate which the lending Trust Fund would earn on the amount involved if the loan were an investment under subsection (c) (even if such an investment would earn interest at a rate different than the rate earned by investments redeemed by the lending fund in order to make the loan).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a0a5be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/j/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a0a5bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/j/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> If in any month after a loan has been made to the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund under paragraph (1), the Managing Trustee determines that the assets of such Trust Fund are sufficient to permit repayment of all or part of any loans made to such Fund under paragraph (1), he shall make such repayments as he determines to be appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a0a5c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/j/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a0a5c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/j/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> If on the last day of any year after a loan has been made under paragraph (1) by the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund or the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund to the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund, the Managing Trustee determines that the Hospital Insurance Trust Fund ratio exceeds 15 percent, he shall transfer from such Trust Fund to the lending trust fund an amount that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8a0a5c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/j/3/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> together with any amounts transferred to another lending trust fund under this paragraph for such year, will reduce the Hospital Insurance Trust Fund ratio to 15 percent; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8a0a5c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/j/3/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> does not exceed the outstanding balance of such loan.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a0a5c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/j/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Amounts required to be transferred under clause (i) shall be transferred on the last day of the first month of the year succeeding the year in which the determination described in clause (i) is made.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a0a5c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/j/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this subparagraph, the term “Hospital Insurance Trust Fund ratio” means, with respect to any calendar year, the ratio of—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8a0a5c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/j/3/B/iii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the balance in the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund, as of the last day of such calendar year; to</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8a0a5c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/j/3/B/iii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the amount estimated by the Secretary to be the total amount to be paid from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund during the calendar year following such calendar year (other than payments of interest on, and repayments of, loans from the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund under paragraph (1)), and reducing the amount of any transfer to the Railroad Retirement Account by the amount of any transfers into such Trust Fund from the Railroad Retirement Account.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a0a5c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/j/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a0a5c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/j/3/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The full amount of all loans made under paragraph (1) (whether made before or after <date date="1983-01-01">January 1, 1983</date>) shall be repaid at the earliest feasible date and in any event no later than <date date="1989-12-31">December 31, 1989</date>.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a0a5ca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/j/3/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> For the period after <date date="1987-12-31">December 31, 1987</date> and before <date date="1990-01-01">January 1, 1990</date>, the Managing Trustee shall transfer each month from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund to any Trust Fund that is owed any amount by the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund on a loan made under paragraph (1), an amount not less than an amount equal to (I) the amount owed to such Trust Fund by the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund at the beginning of such month (plus the interest accrued on the outstanding balance of such loan during such month), divided by (II) the number of months elapsing after the preceding month and before January 1990. The Managing Trustee may, during this period, transfer larger amounts than prescribed by the preceding sentence.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a0a5cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/j/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The Board of Trustees shall make a timely report to the Congress of any amounts transferred (including interest payments) under this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a0a5cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/j/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a0a5cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/j/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> No amounts may be loaned by the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund or the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund under paragraph (1) during any month if the OASDI trust fund ratio for such month is less than 10 percent.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb8a0a5ce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/j/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> For purposes of this paragraph, the term “OASDI trust fund ratio” means, with respect to any month, the ratio of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8a0a5cf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/j/5/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the combined balance in the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund, reduced by the outstanding amount of any loan (including interest thereon) theretofore made to either such Trust Fund from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund under section 401(<i>l</i>) of this title, as of the last day of the second month preceding such month, to</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb8a0a5d0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/j/5/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the amount obtained by multiplying by twelve the total amount which (as estimated by the Secretary) will be paid from the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund during the month for which such ratio is to be determined for all purposes authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref> (other than payments of interest on, or repayments of, loans from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund under section 401(<i>l</i>) of this title), but excluding any transfer payments between such trust funds and reducing the amount of any transfers to the Railroad Retirement Account by the amount of any transfers into either such trust fund from that Account.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a5d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Health Care Fraud and Abuse Control Account</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a5d2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There is hereby established in the Trust Fund an expenditure account to be known as the “Health Care Fraud and Abuse Control Account” (in this subsection referred to as the “Account”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a5d3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Appropriated amounts to Trust Fund</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a5d4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">There are hereby appropriated to the Trust Fund—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a5d5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> such gifts and bequests as may be made as provided in subparagraph (B);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a5d6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> such amounts as may be deposited in the Trust Fund as provided in sections 242(b) and 249(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, and subchapter XI; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a5d7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> such amounts as are transferred to the Trust Fund under subparagraph (C).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a5d8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization to accept gifts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Trust Fund is authorized to accept on behalf of the United States money gifts and bequests made unconditionally to the Trust Fund, for the benefit of the Account or any activity financed through the Account.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a5d9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of amounts</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Managing Trustee shall transfer to the Trust Fund, under rules similar to the rules in section 9601 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, an amount equal to the sum of the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a5da-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Criminal fines recovered in cases involving a Federal health care offense (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s24/a">section 24(a) of title 18</ref>).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a5db-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> Civil monetary penalties and assessments imposed in health care cases, including amounts recovered under this subchapter and subchapters XI and XIX, and chapter 38 of title 31 (except as otherwise provided by law).</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a5dc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/2/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Amounts resulting from the forfeiture of property by reason of a Federal health care offense.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a5dd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/2/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> Penalties and damages obtained and otherwise creditable to miscellaneous receipts of the general fund of the Treasury obtained under sections 3729 through 3733 of title 31 (known as the False Claims Act), in cases involving claims related to the provision of health care items and services (other than funds awarded to a relator, for restitution or otherwise authorized by law).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a5de-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/2/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Application</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Nothing in subparagraph (C)(iii) shall be construed to limit the availability of recoveries and forfeitures obtained under title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1001">29 U.S.C. 1001</ref> et seq.] for the purpose of providing equitable or remedial relief for employee welfare benefit plans, and for participants and beneficiaries under such plans, as authorized under such title.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a5df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Appropriated amounts to Account for fraud and abuse control program, etc.</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a5e0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Departments of Health and Human Services and Justice</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a5e1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/A/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">There are hereby appropriated to the Account from the Trust Fund such sums as the Secretary and the Attorney General certify are necessary to carry out the purposes described in subparagraph (C), to be available without further appropriation until expended, in an amount not to exceed—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb8a0a5e2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> for fiscal year 1997, $104,000,000;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb8a0a5e3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> for each of the fiscal years 1998 through 2003, the limit for the preceding fiscal year, increased by 15 percent;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb8a0a5e4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/A/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> for each of fiscal years 2004, 2005, and 2006, the limit for fiscal year 2003; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb8a0a5e5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/A/i/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> for each fiscal year after fiscal year 2006, the limit under this clause for the preceding fiscal year, increased by the percentage increase in the consumer price index for all urban consumers (all items; United States city average) over the previous year.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a5e6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/A/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Medicare and medicaid activities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">For each fiscal year, of the amount appropriated in clause (i), the following amounts shall be available only for the purposes of the activities of the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services with respect to the programs under this subchapter and subchapter XIX—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb8a0a5e7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> for fiscal year 1997, not less than $60,000,000 and not more than $70,000,000;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb8a0a5e8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> for fiscal year 1998, not less than $80,000,000 and not more than $90,000,000;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb8a0a5e9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/A/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> for fiscal year 1999, not less than $90,000,000 and not more than $100,000,000;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb8a0a5ea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/A/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> for fiscal year 2000, not less than $110,000,000 and not more than $120,000,000;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb8a0a5eb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/A/ii/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> for fiscal year 2001, not less than $120,000,000 and not more than $130,000,000;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb8a0a5ec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/A/ii/VI"><num value="VI">(VI)</num><content> for fiscal year 2002, not less than $140,000,000 and not more than $150,000,000;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb8a0a5ed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/A/ii/VII"><num value="VII">(VII)</num><content> for each of fiscal years 2003, 2004, 2005, and 2006, not less than $150,000,000 and not more than $160,000,000;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb8a0a5ee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/A/ii/VIII"><num value="VIII">(VIII)</num><content> for fiscal year 2007, not less than $160,000,000, increased by the percentage increase in the consumer price index for all urban consumers (all items; United States city average) over the previous year; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb8a0a5ef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/A/ii/IX"><num value="IX">(IX)</num><content> for each fiscal year after fiscal year 2007, not less than the amount required under this clause for the preceding fiscal year, increased by the percentage increase in the consumer price index for all urban consumers (all items; United States city average) over the previous year.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a5f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal Bureau of Investigation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">There are hereby appropriated from the general fund of the United States Treasury and hereby appropriated to the Account for transfer to the Federal Bureau of Investigation to carry out the purposes described in subparagraph (C), to be available without further appropriation until expended—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a5f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> for fiscal year 1997, $47,000,000;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a5f2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> for fiscal year 1998, $56,000,000;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a5f3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> for fiscal year 1999, $66,000,000;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a5f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> for fiscal year 2000, $76,000,000;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a5f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> for fiscal year 2001, $88,000,000;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a5f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/B/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> for fiscal year 2002, $101,000,000;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a5f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/B/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> for each of fiscal years 2003, 2004, 2005, and 2006, $114,000,000; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a5f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/B/viii"><num value="viii">(viii)</num><content> for each fiscal year after fiscal year 2006, the amount to be appropriated under this subparagraph for the preceding fiscal year, increased by the percentage increase in the consumer price index for all urban consumers (all items; United States city average) over the previous year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a5f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The purposes described in this subparagraph are to cover the costs (including equipment, salaries and benefits, and travel and training) of the administration and operation of the health care fraud and abuse control program established under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–7c/a">section 1320a–7c(a) of this title</ref>, including the costs of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a5fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> prosecuting health care matters (through criminal, civil, and administrative proceedings);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a5fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> investigations;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a5fc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> financial and performance audits of health care programs and operations;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a5fd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> inspections and other evaluations; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a5fe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/3/C/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> provider and consumer education regarding compliance with the provisions of subchapter XI.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a5ff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Appropriated amounts to Account for Medicare Integrity Program</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a600-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">There are hereby appropriated to the Account from the Trust Fund for each fiscal year such amounts as are necessary for activities described in paragraph (3)(C) and to carry out the Medicare Integrity Program under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd">section 1395ddd of this title</ref>, subject to subparagraphs (B), (C), and (D) and to be available without further appropriation until expended.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a601-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Amounts specified</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (C), the amount appropriated under subparagraph (A) for a fiscal year is as follows:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a602-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> For fiscal year 1997, such amount shall be not less than $430,000,000 and not more than $440,000,000.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a603-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> For fiscal year 1998, such amount shall be not less than $490,000,000 and not more than $500,000,000.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a604-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/4/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> For fiscal year 1999, such amount shall be not less than $550,000,000 and not more than $560,000,000.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a605-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/4/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> For fiscal year 2000, such amount shall be not less than $620,000,000 and not more than $630,000,000.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a606-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/4/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> For fiscal year 2001, such amount shall be not less than $670,000,000 and not more than $680,000,000.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a607-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/4/B/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> For fiscal year 2002, such amount shall be not less than $690,000,000 and not more than $700,000,000.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a608-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/4/B/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> For each fiscal year after fiscal year 2002, such amount shall be not less than $710,000,000 and not more than $720,000,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a609-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/4/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustments</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The amount appropriated under subparagraph (A) for a fiscal year is increased as follows:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a60a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/4/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> For fiscal year 2006, $100,000,000.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a60b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/4/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> For each fiscal year after 2010, by the percentage increase in the consumer price index for all urban consumers (all items; United States city average) over the previous year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a60c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/4/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Expansion of the Medicare-Medicaid Data Match Program</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The amount appropriated under subparagraph (A) for a fiscal year is further increased as follows for purposes of carrying out <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/b/6">section 1395ddd(b)(6) of this title</ref> for the respective fiscal year:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a60d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/4/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> $12,000,000 for fiscal year 2006.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a60e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/4/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> $24,000,000 for fiscal year 2007.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a60f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/4/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> $36,000,000 for fiscal year 2008.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a610-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/4/D/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> $48,000,000 for fiscal year 2009.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a611-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/4/D/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> $60,000,000 for fiscal year 2010 and each fiscal year thereafter.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a612-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than January 1, the Secretary and the Attorney General shall submit jointly a report to Congress which identifies—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8a0a613-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the amounts appropriated to the Trust Fund for the previous fiscal year under paragraph (2)(A) and the source of such amounts; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8a0a614-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the amounts appropriated from the Trust Fund for such year under paragraph (3) and the justification for the expenditure of such amounts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a615-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> GAO report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than <date date="1998-06-01">June 1, 1998</date>, and January 1 of 2000, 2002, and 2004, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit a report to Congress which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8a0a616-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> identifies—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a617-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/6/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the amounts appropriated to the Trust Fund for the previous two fiscal years under paragraph (2)(A) and the source of such amounts; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a618-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/6/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the amounts appropriated from the Trust Fund for such fiscal years under paragraph (3) and the justification for the expenditure of such amounts;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8a0a619-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> identifies any expenditures from the Trust Fund with respect to activities not involving the program under this subchapter;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8a0a61a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/6/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> identifies any savings to the Trust Fund, and any other savings, resulting from expenditures from the Trust Fund; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb8a0a61b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/6/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> analyzes such other aspects of the operation of the Trust Fund as the Comptroller General of the United States considers appropriate.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a61c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional funding</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In addition to the funds otherwise appropriated to the Account from the Trust Fund under paragraphs (3) and (4) and for purposes described in paragraphs (3)(C) and (4)(A), there are hereby appropriated an additional $10,000,000 to such Account from such Trust Fund for each of fiscal years 2011 through 2020. The funds appropriated under this paragraph shall be allocated in the same proportion as the total funding appropriated with respect to paragraphs (3)(A) and (4)(A) was allocated with respect to fiscal year 2010, and shall be available without further appropriation until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a61d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional funding</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a61e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/8/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In addition to the funds otherwise appropriated to the Account from the Trust Fund under paragraphs (3)(C) and (4)(A) and for purposes described in paragraphs (3)(C) and (4)(A), there are hereby appropriated to such Account from such Trust Fund the following additional amounts:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a61f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/8/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> For fiscal year 2011, $95,000,000.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a620-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/8/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> For fiscal year 2012, $55,000,000.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a621-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/8/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> For each of fiscal years 2013 and 2014, $30,000,000.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb8a0a622-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/8/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> For each of fiscal years 2015 and 2016, $20,000,000.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb8a0a623-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/8/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Allocation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The funds appropriated under this paragraph shall be allocated in the same proportion as the total funding appropriated with respect to paragraphs (3)(A) and (4)(A) was allocated with respect to fiscal year 2010, and shall be available without further appropriation until expended.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb8a0a624-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, title XVIII, § 1817, as added <ref href="/us/pl/89/97/tI/s102/a">Pub. L. 89–97, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <date date="1965-07-30">July 30, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/299">79 Stat. 299</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/90/248/tI/s169/a">Pub. L. 90–248, title I, § 169(a)</ref>, <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/875">81 Stat. 875</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/603/tI/s132/d">Pub. L. 92–603, title I, § 132(d)</ref>, <date date="1972-10-30">Oct. 30, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1361">86 Stat. 1361</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/292/s5">Pub. L. 95–292, § 5</ref>, <date date="1978-06-13">June 13, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/315">92 Stat. 315</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/265/tIII/s310/c">Pub. L. 96–265, title III, § 310(c)</ref>, <date date="1980-06-09">June 9, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/460">94 Stat. 460</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/123/s1/b">Pub. L. 97–123, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/1659">95 Stat. 1659</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/21/tI">Pub. L. 98–21, title I</ref>, §§ 141(b), 142(b)(1), (2)(A), (3), (4), 154(b), title III, § 341(b), <date date="1983-04-20">Apr. 20, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/98">97 Stat. 98</ref>, 100, 101, 107, 135; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tIII">Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title III</ref>, §§ 2337(a), 2354(b)(2), title VI, § 2663(j)(2)(F)(i), <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1091">98 Stat. 1091</ref>, 1100, 1170; <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/tIX/s9213/b">Pub. L. 99–272, title IX, § 9213(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/180">100 Stat. 180</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s2">Pub. L. 99–514, § 2</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2095">100 Stat. 2095</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/360/tII/s212/c/3">Pub. L. 100–360, title II, § 212(c)(3)</ref>, <date date="1988-07-01">July 1, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/741">102 Stat. 741</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/tVIII/s8005/a">Pub. L. 100–647, title VIII, § 8005(a)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3781">102 Stat. 3781</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/234/tII/s202/a">Pub. L. 101–234, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-13">Dec. 13, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1981">103 Stat. 1981</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tV/s5106/c">Pub. L. 101–508, title V, § 5106(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-268">104 Stat. 1388–268</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/tI/s108/c/1">Pub. L. 103–296, title I, § 108(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-08-15">Aug. 15, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/1485">108 Stat. 1485</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/191/tII/s201/b">Pub. L. 104–191, title II, § 201(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-21">Aug. 21, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1993">110 Stat. 1993</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tIV/s4318">Pub. L. 105–33, title IV, § 4318</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/392">111 Stat. 392</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/6/tIII/s321/j/1">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(6) [title III, § 321(j)(1)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–366; <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/tVII/s736/a/5">Pub. L. 108–173, title VII, § 736(a)(5)</ref>, (6), title VIII, § 801(d)(1), title IX, § 900(e)(1)(D), <date date="2003-12-08">Dec. 8, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2355">117 Stat. 2355</ref>, 2359, 2371; <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/tV/s5204">Pub. L. 109–171, title V, § 5204</ref>, title VI, § 6034(d)(2), <date date="2006-02-08">Feb. 8, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/48">120 Stat. 48</ref>, 78; <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/dB/tIII/s303">Pub. L. 109–432, div. B, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2992">120 Stat. 2992</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tVI/s6402/i">Pub. L. 111–148, title VI, § 6402(i)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/760">124 Stat. 760</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/152/tI/s1303/a/1">Pub. L. 111–152, title I, § 1303(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-30">Mar. 30, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1057">124 Stat. 1057</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb8a0a625-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb8a0a626-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb8a0a627-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Internal Revenue Code of 1986, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1), (2), (f)(1), and (k)(2)(C), is classified generally to Title 26, Internal Revenue Code. Subtitle F of such Code appears at section 6001 et seq. of Title 26.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 801(a) of the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003, referred to in subsec. (b)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/s801/a">section 801(a) of Pub. L. 108–173</ref>, which is set out as a note under this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 242(b) and 249(b) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, referred to in subsec. (k)(2)(A)(ii), are sections 242(b) and 249(b) of <ref href="/us/pl/104/191">Pub. L. 104–191</ref>, which are set out as notes under this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (k)(2)(D), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/406">Pub. L. 93–406</ref>, <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/832">88 Stat. 832</ref>. Title I of the Act is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 1001 et seq.) of chapter 18 of Title 29, Labor. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1001">section 1001 of Title 29</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb8a0a628-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (k)(3)(A)(i)(III). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s6402/i/2/A/i">Pub. L. 111–148, § 6402(i)(2)(A)(i)</ref>, inserted “and” at the end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3)(A)(i)(IV). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s6402/i/2/A/ii">Pub. L. 111–148, § 6402(i)(2)(A)(ii)</ref>, substituted “for each fiscal year after fiscal year 2006” for “for each of fiscal years 2007, 2008, 2009, and 2010” and a period for “; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3)(A)(i)(V). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s6402/i/2/A/iii">Pub. L. 111–148, § 6402(i)(2)(A)(iii)</ref>, struck out subcl. (V) which read as follows: “for each fiscal year after fiscal year 2010, the limit under this clause for fiscal year 2010.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3)(A)(ii)(VIII). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s6402/i/2/B/i">Pub. L. 111–148, § 6402(i)(2)(B)(i)</ref>, inserted “and” at the end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3)(A)(ii)(IX). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s6402/i/2/B/ii">Pub. L. 111–148, § 6402(i)(2)(B)(ii)</ref>, substituted “for each fiscal year after fiscal year 2007” for “for each of fiscal years 2008, 2009, and 2010” and a period for “; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3)(A)(ii)(X). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s6402/i/2/B/iii">Pub. L. 111–148, § 6402(i)(2)(B)(iii)</ref>, struck out subcl. (X) which read as follows: “for each fiscal year after fiscal year 2010, not less than the amount required under this clause for fiscal year 2010.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3)(B)(vii). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s6402/i/2/C/i">Pub. L. 111–148, § 6402(i)(2)(C)(i)</ref>, inserted “and” at the end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3)(B)(viii). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s6402/i/2/C/ii">Pub. L. 111–148, § 6402(i)(2)(C)(ii)</ref>, substituted “for each fiscal year after fiscal year 2006” for “for each of fiscal years 2007, 2008, 2009, and 2010” and a period for “; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3)(B)(ix). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s6402/i/2/C/iii">Pub. L. 111–148, § 6402(i)(2)(C)(iii)</ref>, struck out cl. (ix) which read as follows: “for each fiscal year after fiscal year 2010, the amount to be appropriated under this subparagraph for fiscal year 2010.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/152/s1303/a/1/B">Pub. L. 111–152, § 1303(a)(1)(B)</ref>, inserted “for activities described in paragraph (3)(C) and” after “necessary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s6402/i/1/B">Pub. L. 111–148, § 6402(i)(1)(B)</ref>, inserted “until expended” after “appropriation”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(4)(C)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s6402/i/2/D">Pub. L. 111–148, § 6402(i)(2)(D)</ref>, added cl. (ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s6402/i/1/A">Pub. L. 111–148, § 6402(i)(1)(A)</ref>, added par. (7).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/111/152/s1303/a/1/A">Pub. L. 111–152, § 1303(a)(1)(A)</ref>, added par. (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (k)(3)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s303/a/1">Pub. L. 109–432, § 303(a)(1)</ref>, in introductory provisions inserted “until expended” after “without further appropriation”, in subcl. (II) struck out “and” at end, in subcl. (III) substituted “for each of fiscal years 2004, 2005, and 2006” for “for each fiscal year after fiscal year 2003” and semicolon for period at end, and added subcls. (IV) and (V).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3)(A)(ii)(VI) to (X). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s303/a/2">Pub. L. 109–432, § 303(a)(2)</ref>, in subcl. (VI) struck out “and” at end, in subcl. (VII) substituted “for each of fiscal years 2003, 2004, 2005, and 2006” for “for each fiscal year after fiscal year 2002” and semicolon for period at end, and added subcls. (VIII) to (X).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/s303/b">Pub. L. 109–432, § 303(b)</ref>, in introductory provisions inserted “until expended” after “without further appropriation”, in cl. (vi) struck out “and” at end, in cl. (vii) substituted “for each of fiscal years 2003, 2004, 2005, and 2006” for “for each fiscal year after fiscal year 2002” and semicolon for period at end, and added cls. (viii) and (ix).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/s6034/d/2/A">Pub. L. 109–171, § 6034(d)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “subparagraphs (B), (C), and (D)” for “subparagraph (B)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(4)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/s5204/1">Pub. L. 109–171, § 5204(1)</ref>, substituted “Subject to subparagraph (C), the amount” for “The amount” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(4)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/s5204/2">Pub. L. 109–171, § 5204(2)</ref>, added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(4)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/s6034/d/2/B">Pub. L. 109–171, § 6034(d)(2)(B)</ref>, added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/s900/e/1/D">Pub. L. 108–173, § 900(e)(1)(D)</ref>, in fifth sentence of introductory provisions, substituted “Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services” for “Health Care Financing Administration”, and, in second sentence of concluding provisions, substituted “Chief Actuary of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services” for “Chief Actuarial Officer of the Health Care Financing Administration”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/s801/d/1">Pub. L. 108–173, § 801(d)(1)</ref>, inserted at end “Each report provided under paragraph (2) beginning with the report in 2005 shall include the information specified in section 801(a) of the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3)(A)(i)(I). <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/s736/a/5/A">Pub. L. 108–173, § 736(a)(5)(A)</ref>, substituted semicolon for comma at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/s736/a/5/B">Pub. L. 108–173, § 736(a)(5)(B)</ref>, substituted “the programs under this subchapter and subchapter XIX” for “the Medicare and medicaid programs” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(6)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/s736/a/6">Pub. L. 108–173, § 736(a)(6)</ref>, substituted “program under this subchapter” for “Medicare program under this subchapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (k)(2)(C)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref> substituted “section 24(a)” for “section 982(a)(6)(B)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (k)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref> inserted “<date date="1998-06-01">June 1, 1998</date>, and” after “Not later than” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/104/191">Pub. L. 104–191</ref> added subsec. (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s108/c/1/A">Pub. L. 103–296, § 108(c)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “Commissioner of Social Security” for “Secretary of Health and Human Services” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s108/c/1/B">Pub. L. 103–296, § 108(c)(1)(B)</ref>, inserted “the Commissioner of Social Security,” after “composed of” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s108/c/1/C">Pub. L. 103–296, § 108(c)(1)(C)</ref>, substituted “Commissioner of Social Security” for “Secretary of Health and Human Services” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> inserted at end “The amount available for payment under this subsection for travel by a representative to attend an administrative proceeding before an administrative law judge or other adjudicator shall not exceed the maximum amount allowable under this subsection for such travel originating within the geographic area of the office having jurisdiction over such proceeding.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/101/234">Pub. L. 101–234</ref> repealed <ref href="/us/pl/100/360/s212/c/3">Pub. L. 100–360, § 212(c)(3)</ref>, and provided that the provisions of law amended or repealed by such section are restored or revised as if such section had not been enacted, see 1988 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/100/647">Pub. L. 100–647</ref> inserted after first sentence “A member of the Board of Trustees serving as a member of the public and nominated and confirmed to fill a vacancy occurring during a term shall be nominated and confirmed only for the remainder of such term. An individual nominated and confirmed as a member of the public may serve in such position after the expiration of such member’s term until the earlier of the time at which the member’s successor takes office or the time at which a report of the Board is first issued under paragraph (2) after the expiration of the member’s term.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/360">Pub. L. 100–360</ref> inserted after sixth sentence “Such report shall also identify (and treat separately) those outlays from the Trust Fund which are also outlays from the Medicare Catastrophic Coverage Account created under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395t–2">section 1395t–2 of this title</ref> and those outlays for which there are amounts transferred into the Federal Hospital Insurance Catastrophic Coverage Reserve Fund.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a)(1), (2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> substituted “Internal Revenue Code of 1986” for “Internal Revenue Code of 1954”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/99/272">Pub. L. 99–272</ref> struck out provision at end of penultimate sentence that certification shall not refer to economic assumptions underlying Trustee’s report.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> substituted “Internal Revenue Code of 1986” for “Internal Revenue Code of 1954” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2337/a">Pub. L. 98–369, § 2337(a)</ref>, in provisions following par. (2) substituted “from time to time” for “monthly on the first day of each calendar month”, “paid to or deposited into the Treasury” for “to be paid to or deposited into the Treasury during such month”, and struck out provision that all amounts transferred to the Trust Fund under the preceding sentence had to be invested by the Managing Trustee in the same manner and to the same extent as the other assets of the Trust Fund, and the Trust Fund had to pay interest to the general fund on the amount so transferred on the first day of any month at a rate (calculated on a daily basis, and applied against the difference between the amount so transferred on such first day and the amount which would have been transferred to the Trust Fund up to that day under the procedures in effect on <date date="1983-01-01">January 1, 1983</date>) equal to the rate earned by the investments of the Trust Fund in the same month under subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1), (2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2663/j/2/F/i">Pub. L. 98–369, § 2663(j)(2)(F)(i)</ref>, substituted “Health and Human Services” for “Health, Education, and Welfare” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2354/b/2">Pub. L. 98–369, § 2354(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “under chapter 31 of title 31” for “under the Second Liberty Bond Act, as amended”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (f)(1), (g), (h). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2663/j/2/F/i">Pub. L. 98–369, § 2663(j)(2)(F)(i)</ref>, substituted “Health and Human Services” for “Health, Education, and Welfare” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/98/21/s141/b/1/A">Pub. L. 98–21, § 141(b)(1)(A)</ref>, in provisions following par. (2) substituted “monthly on the first day of each calendar month” for “from time to time”, substituted “to be paid to or deposited into the Treasury during such month” for “paid to or deposited into the Treasury”, and inserted provision that all amounts transferred to the Trust Fund under existing provisions shall be invested by the Managing Trustee in the same manner and to the same extent as the other assets of the Trust Fund; and the Trust Fund shall pay interest to the general fund on the amount so transferred on the first day of any month at a rate (calculated on a daily basis, and applied against the difference between the amount so transferred on such first day and the amount which would have been transferred to the Trust Fund up to that day under the procedures in effect on <date date="1983-01-01">Jan. 1, 1983</date>) equal to the rate earned by the investments of the Trust Fund in the same month under subsection (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/21/s341/b/1">Pub. L. 98–21, § 341(b)(1)</ref>, substituted in provisions preceding par. (1) “Secretary of Health and Human Services, all ex officio, and of two members of the public (both of whom may not be from the same political party), who shall be nominated by the President for a term of four years and subject to confirmation by the Senate” for “Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, all ex officio”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/21/s154/b">Pub. L. 98–21, § 154(b)</ref>, inserted at end provision that the report referred to in par. (2) shall also include an actuarial opinion by the Chief Actuarial Officer of the Health Care Financing Administration certifying that the techniques and methodologies used are generally accepted within the actuarial profession and that the assumptions and cost estimates used are reasonable and provided further that the certification shall not refer to economic assumptions underlying the Trustee’s report.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/21/s341/b/2">Pub. L. 98–21, § 341(b)(2)</ref>, inserted at end provision that a person serving on the Board of Trustees shall not be considered to be a fiduciary and shall not be personally liable for actions taken in such capacity with respect to the Trust Fund.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/21/s142/b/1">Pub. L. 98–21, § 142(b)(1)</ref>, substituted reference to January 1988 for reference to January 1983 and inserted “, subject to paragraph (5),” after “may”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/21/s142/b/2/A">Pub. L. 98–21, § 142(b)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “on the last day of each month after such loan is made” for “from time to time”, substituted “the total interest accrued to such day” for “interest”, and inserted “(even if such an investment would earn interest at a rate different than the rate earned by investments redeemed by the lending fund in order to make the loan)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/98/21/s142/b/3">Pub. L. 98–21, § 142(b)(3)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A) and added subpars. (B) and (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/98/21/s142/b/4">Pub. L. 98–21, § 142(b)(4)</ref>, added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/97/123">Pub. L. 97–123</ref> added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/96/265">Pub. L. 96–265</ref> added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/95/292">Pub. L. 95–292</ref> substituted “Administrator of the Health Care Financing Administration” for “Commissioner of Social Security” in provisions preceding par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1972—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/92/603">Pub. L. 92–603</ref> inserted “such gifts and bequests as may be made as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401/i/1">section 401(i)(1) of this title</ref>, and” after “consist of” and before “such amounts” in provisions preceding par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/90/248">Pub. L. 90–248</ref> substituted “April” for “March”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb8a2f019-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8a2f01a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1999 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/6/tIII/s321/j/2">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(6) [title III, § 321(j)(2)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–366, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/6/tIII/s321/j/2">“The amendment made by this subsection [amending this section] shall take effect as if included in the amendment made by section 201 of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (<ref href="/us/pl/104/191">Public Law 104–191</ref>; <ref href="/us/stat/110/1992">110 Stat. 1992</ref>).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8a2f01b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/296">Pub. L. 103–296</ref> effective <date date="1995-03-31">Mar. 31, 1995</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/296/s110/a">section 110(a) of Pub. L. 103–296</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8a2f01c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> applicable with respect to determinations made on or after <date date="1991-07-01">July 1, 1991</date>, and to reimbursement for travel expenses incurred on or after <date date="1991-04-01">Apr. 1, 1991</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s5106/d">section 5106(d) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8a2f01d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1989 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/234">Pub. L. 101–234</ref> effective <date date="1990-01-01">Jan. 1, 1990</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/234/s202/b">section 202(b) of Pub. L. 100–234</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8a2f01e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/647">Pub. L. 100–647</ref> applicable to members of Board of Trustees of Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund serving on such Board as members of the public on or after <date date="1988-11-10">Nov. 10, 1988</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/647/s8005/b">section 8005(b) of Pub. L. 100–647</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8a2f01f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tIII/s2337/b">Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title III, § 2337(b)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1091">98 Stat. 1091</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tIII/s2337/b">“The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall become effective on the first day of the month following the month in which this Act is enacted [July 1984].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2354/b/2">section 2354(b)(2) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref> effective <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, but not to be construed as changing or affecting any right, liability, status, or interpretation which existed (under the provisions of law involved) before that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2354/e/1">section 2354(e)(1) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–1">section 1320a–1 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2663/j/2/F/i">section 2663(j)(2)(F)(i) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref> effective <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, but not to be construed as changing or affecting any right, liability, status, or interpretation which existed (under the provisions of law involved) before that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2664/b">section 2664(b) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8a2f020-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1983 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/21/s141/b">section 141(b) of Pub. L. 98–21</ref> effective on first day of month following April 1983, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/21/s141/c">section 141(c) of Pub. L. 98–21</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/98/21/tI/s142/b/2/B">Pub. L. 98–21, title I, § 142(b)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1983-04-20">Apr. 20, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/101">97 Stat. 101</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/98/21/tI/s142/b/2/B">“The amendment made by this paragraph [amending this section] shall apply with respect to months beginning more than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1983-04-20">Apr. 20, 1983</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by sections 154(b) and 341(b) of <ref href="/us/pl/98/21">Pub. L. 98–21</ref> effective <date date="1983-04-20">Apr. 20, 1983</date>, see sections 154(e) and 341(d) of <ref href="/us/pl/98/21">Pub. L. 98–21</ref>, set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8a2f021-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/123">Pub. L. 97–123</ref> effective <date date="1981-12-29">Dec. 29, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/123/s1/c">section 1(c) of Pub. L. 97–123</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8a2f022-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/292">Pub. L. 95–292</ref> effective with respect to services, supplies, and equipment furnished after the third calendar month beginning after <date date="1978-06-13">June 13, 1978</date>, except that provisions for the implementation of an incentive reimbursement system for dialysis services furnished in facilities and providers to become effective with respect to a facility’s or provider’s first accounting period beginning after the last day of the twelfth month following the month of June 1978, and except that provisions for reimbursement rates for home dialysis to become effective on <date date="1979-04-01">Apr. 1, 1979</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/292/s6">section 6 of Pub. L. 95–292</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s426">section 426 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb8a2f023-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1972 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/92/603">Pub. L. 92–603</ref> applicable with respect to gifts and bequests received after <date date="1972-10-30">Oct. 30, 1972</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/92/603/s132/f">section 132(f) of Pub. L. 92–603</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8a2f024-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Restoration of Medicare Trust Funds</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/173/tVII/s734">Pub. L. 108–173, title VII, § 734</ref>, <date date="2003-12-08">Dec. 8, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2352">117 Stat. 2352</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/173/tVII/s734">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Clerical error</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘clerical error’ means a failure that occurs on or after <date date="2001-04-15">April 15, 2001</date>, to have transferred the correct amount from the general fund of the Treasury to a Trust Fund.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Trust fund</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Trust Fund’ means the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund established under section 1817 of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395i">42 U.S.C. 1395i</ref>) and the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund established under section 1841 of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395t">42 U.S.C. 1395t</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Correction of Trust Fund Holdings.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of the Treasury shall take the actions described in paragraph (2) with respect to the Trust Fund with the goal being that, after such actions are taken, the holdings of the Trust Fund will replicate, to the extent practicable in the judgment of the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary [of Health and Human Services], the holdings that would have been held by the Trust Fund if the clerical error involved had not occurred.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Obligations issued and redeemed</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of the Treasury shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> issue to the Trust Fund obligations under chapter 31 of title 31, United States Code, that bear issue dates, interest rates, and maturity dates that are the same as those for the obligations that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> would have been issued to the Trust Fund if the clerical error involved had not occurred; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> were issued to the Trust Fund and were redeemed by reason of the clerical error involved; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> redeem from the Trust Fund obligations that would have been redeemed from the Trust Fund if the clerical error involved had not occurred.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Appropriation</inline>.—</heading><content>There is appropriated to the Trust Fund, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, an amount determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary, to be equal to the interest income lost by the Trust Fund through the date on which the appropriation is being made as a result of the clerical error involved.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Congressional Notice</inline>.—</heading><content>In the case of a clerical error that occurs after <date date="2001-04-15">April 15, 2001</date>, the Secretary of the Treasury, before taking action to correct the error under this section, shall notify the appropriate committees of Congress concerning such error and the actions to be taken under this section in response to such error.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deadline</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>With respect to the clerical error that occurred on <date date="2001-04-15">April 15, 2001</date>, not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2003-12-08">Dec. 8, 2003</date>]—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the Secretary of the Treasury shall take the actions under subsection (b)(1); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the appropriation under subsection (c) shall be made.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8a2f025-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Inclusion in Annual Report of Medicare Trustees of Information on Status of Medicare Trust Funds</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/173/tVIII/s801">Pub. L. 108–173, title VIII, § 801</ref>, <date date="2003-12-08">Dec. 8, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2357">117 Stat. 2357</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/173/tVIII/s801">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Determinations of Excess General Revenue Medicare Funding.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Board of Trustees of each medicare trust fund shall include in the annual reports submitted under subsection (b)(2) of sections 1817 and 1841 of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395i">42 U.S.C. 1395i</ref> and 1395t)—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the information described in subsection (b); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> a determination as to whether there is projected to be excess general revenue medicare funding (as defined in subsection (c)) for the fiscal year in which the report is submitted or for any of the succeeding 6 fiscal years.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Medicare funding warning</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105/h">section 1105(h) of title 31</ref>, United States Code, and this subtitle [subtitle A (§§ 801–804) of title VIII of <ref href="/us/pl/108/173">Pub. L. 108–173</ref>, amending this section, <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395t">section 1395t of this title</ref>, and <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105">section 1105 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance, and enacting provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105">section 1105 of Title 31</ref>], an affirmative determination under paragraph (1)(B) in 2 consecutive annual reports shall be treated as a medicare funding warning in the year in which the second such report is made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> 7-<inline class="small-caps">fiscal-year reporting period</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this subtitle, the term ‘7-fiscal-year reporting period’ means, with respect to a year in which an annual report described in paragraph (1) is made, the period of 7 consecutive fiscal years beginning with the fiscal year in which the report is submitted.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Information</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The information described in this subsection for an annual report in a year is as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Projections of growth of general revenue spending</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A statement of the general revenue medicare funding as a percentage of the total medicare outlays for each of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Each fiscal year within the 7-fiscal-year reporting period.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Previous fiscal years and as of 10, 50, and 75 years after such year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Comparison with other growth trends</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>A comparison of the trend of such percentages with the annual growth rate in the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> The gross domestic product.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Private health costs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> National health expenditures.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> Other appropriate measures.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Part d spending</inline>.—</heading><content>Expenditures, including trends in expenditures, under part D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395w–101">42 U.S.C. 1395w–101</ref> et seq.], as added by section 101.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Combined medicare trust fund analysis</inline>.—</heading><content>A financial analysis of the combined medicare trust funds if general revenue medicare funding were limited to the percentage specified in subsection (c)(1)(B) of total medicare outlays.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Excess general revenue medicare funding</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘excess general revenue medicare funding’ means, with respect to a fiscal year, that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> general revenue medicare funding (as defined in paragraph (2)), expressed as a percentage of total medicare outlays (as defined in paragraph (4)) for the fiscal year; exceeds</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> 45 percent.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">General revenue medicare funding</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘general revenue medicare funding’ means for a year—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the total medicare outlays (as defined in paragraph (4)) for the year; minus</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the dedicated medicare financing sources (as defined in paragraph (3)) for the year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Dedicated medicare financing sources</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘dedicated medicare financing sources’ means the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Hospital insurance tax</inline>.—</heading><content>Amounts appropriated to the Hospital Insurance Trust Fund under the third sentence of section 1817(a) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/a">42 U.S.C. 1395i(a)</ref>) and amounts transferred to such Trust Fund under section 7(c)(2) of the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 (<ref href="/us/usc/t45/s231f/c/2">45 U.S.C. 231f(c)(2)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Taxation of certain oasdi benefits</inline>.—</heading><content>Amounts appropriated to the Hospital Insurance Trust Fund under section 121(e)(1)(B) of the Social Security Amendments of 1983 (<ref href="/us/pl/98/21">Public Law 98–21</ref>) [set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>], as inserted by section 13215(c) of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993 (<ref href="/us/pl/103/66">Public Law 103–66</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State transfers</inline>.—</heading><content>The State share of amounts paid to the Federal Government by a State under section 1843 of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395v">42 U.S.C. 1395v</ref>) or pursuant to section 1935(c) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396u–5/c">42 U.S.C. 1396u–5(c)</ref>].</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Premiums</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The following premiums:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Part a</inline>.—</heading><content>Premiums paid by non-Federal sources under sections 1818 and section [sic] 1818A (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395i–2">42 U.S.C. 1395i–2</ref> and 1395i–2a) of such Act.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Part b</inline>.—</heading><content>Premiums paid by non-Federal sources under section 1839 of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395r">42 U.S.C. 1395r</ref>), including any adjustments in premiums under such section.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Part d</inline>.—</heading><content>Monthly beneficiary premiums paid under part D of title XVIII of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395w–101">42 U.S.C. 1395w–101</ref> et seq.], as added by section 101, and MA monthly prescription drug beneficiary premiums paid under part C of such title [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395w–21">42 U.S.C. 1395w–21</ref> et seq.] insofar as they are attributable to basic prescription drug coverage.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I31" class="indent1 firstIndent0">Premiums under clauses (ii) and (iii) shall be determined without regard to any reduction in such premiums attributable to a beneficiary rebate under section 1854(b)(1)(C) of such title [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395w–24/b/1/C">42 U.S.C. 1395w–24(b)(1)(C)</ref>], as amended by section 222(b)(1), and premiums under clause (iii) are deemed to include any amounts paid under section 1860D–13(b) of such title [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395w–113/b">42 U.S.C. 1395w–113(b)</ref>], as added by section 101.</continuation>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Gifts</inline>.—</heading><content>Amounts received by the medicare trust funds under section 201(i) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401/i">42 U.S.C. 401(i)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Total medicare outlays</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘total medicare outlays’ means total outlays from the medicare trust funds and shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> include payments made to plans under part C of title XVIII of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395w–21">42 U.S.C. 1395w–21</ref> et seq.] that are attributable to any rebates under section 1854(b)(1)(C) of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395w–24/b/1/C">42 U.S.C. 1395w–24(b)(1)(C)</ref>), as amended by section 222(b)(1);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> include administrative expenditures made in carrying out title XVIII of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395">42 U.S.C. 1395</ref> et seq.] and Federal outlays under section 1935(b) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396u–5/b">42 U.S.C. 1396u–5(b)</ref>], as added by section 103(a)(2); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> offset outlays by the amount of fraud and abuse collections insofar as they are applied or deposited into a medicare trust fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Medicare trust fund</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term ‘medicare trust fund’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund established under section 1817 of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395i">42 U.S.C. 1395i</ref>); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund established under section 1841 of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395t">42 U.S.C. 1395t</ref>), including the Medicare Prescription Drug Account under such Trust Fund.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Conforming Amendments.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Federal hospital insurance trust fund</inline> [Amended <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395i">section 1395i of this title</ref>].</heading><content />
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Federal supplementary medical insurance trust fund</inline> [Amended <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395t">section 1395t of this title</ref>].</heading><content />
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice of Medicare Funding Warning</inline>.—</heading><content>Whenever any report described in subsection (a) contains a determination that for any fiscal year within the 7-fiscal-year reporting period there will be excess general revenue medicare funding, Congress and the President should address the matter under existing rules and procedures.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8a2f026-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Criminal Fines Deposited in Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/191/tII/s242/b">Pub. L. 104–191, title II, § 242(b)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-21">Aug. 21, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2016">110 Stat. 2016</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/191/tII/s242/b">“The Secretary of the Treasury shall deposit into the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund pursuant to section 1817(k)(2)(C) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395i">42 U.S.C. 1395i</ref>) an amount equal to the criminal fines imposed under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s1347">section 1347 of title 18</ref>, United States Code (relating to health care fraud).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8a2f027-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Property Forfeited Deposited in Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/191/tII/s249/c">Pub. L. 104–191, title II, § 249(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-21">Aug. 21, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2020">110 Stat. 2020</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/191/tII/s249/c">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>After the payment of the costs of asset forfeiture has been made and after all restoration payments (if any) have been made, and notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of the Treasury shall deposit into the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund pursuant to section 1817(k)(2)(C) of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395i/k/2/C">42 U.S.C. 1395i(k)(2)(C)</ref>], as added by section 301(b), an amount equal to the net amount realized from the forfeiture of property by reason of a Federal health care offense pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s982/a/6">section 982(a)(6) of title 18</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Costs of asset forfeiture</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of paragraph (1), the term ‘payment of the costs of asset forfeiture’ means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><chapeau> the payment, at the discretion of the Attorney General, of any expenses necessary to seize, detain, inventory, safeguard, maintain, advertise, sell, or dispose of property under seizure, detention, or forfeited, or of any other necessary expenses incident to the seizure, detention, forfeiture, or disposal of such property, including payment for—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> contract services;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the employment of outside contractors to operate and manage properties or provide other specialized services necessary to dispose of such properties in an effort to maximize the return from such properties; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> reimbursement of any Federal, State, or local agency for any expenditures made to perform the functions described in this subparagraph;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> at the discretion of the Attorney General, the payment of awards for information or assistance leading to a civil or criminal forfeiture involving any Federal agency participating in the Health Care Fraud and Abuse Control Account;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> the compromise and payment of valid liens and mortgages against property that has been forfeited, subject to the discretion of the Attorney General to determine the validity of any such lien or mortgage and the amount of payment to be made, and the employment of attorneys and other personnel skilled in State real estate law as necessary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> payment authorized in connection with remission or mitigation procedures relating to property forfeited; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> the payment of State and local property taxes on forfeited real property that accrued between the date of the violation giving rise to the forfeiture and the date of the forfeiture order.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Restoration payment</inline>.—</heading><content>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if the Federal health care offense referred to in paragraph (1) resulted in a loss to an employee welfare benefit plan within the meaning of section 3(1) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1002/1">29 U.S.C. 1002(1)</ref>], the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer to such employee welfare benefit plan, from the amount realized from the forfeiture of property referred to in paragraph (1), an amount equal to such loss. For purposes of paragraph (1), the term ‘restoration payment’ means the amount transferred to an employee welfare benefit plan pursuant to this paragraph.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb8a2f028-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Due Date for 1983 Report on Operation and Status of Trust Fund</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Notwithstanding subsec. (b)(2) of this section, the annual report of the Board of Trustees of the Trust Fund required for calendar year 1983 under this section may be filed at any time not later than forty-five days after <date date="1983-04-20">Apr. 20, 1983</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/21/s154/d">section 154(d) of Pub. L. 98–21</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
