<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb9cd17ac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395vv"><num value="1395vv">§ 1395vv.</num><heading> Withholding payments from certain medicaid providers</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb9cd17ad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395vv/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustments by Secretary</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may adjust, in accordance with this section, payments under parts A and B to any institution which has in effect an agreement with the Secretary under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395cc">section 1395cc of this title</ref>, and any person who has accepted payment on the basis of an assignment under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395u/b/3/B/ii">section 1395u(b)(3)(B)(ii) of this title</ref>, where such institution or person—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9cd17ae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395vv/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> has (or previously had) in effect an agreement with a State agency to furnish medical care and services under a State plan approved under subchapter XIX, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9cd17af-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395vv/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> from which (or from whom) such State agency (A) has been unable to recover overpayments made under the State plan, or (B) has been unable to collect the information necessary to enable it to determine the amount (if any) of the overpayments made to such institution or person under the State plan.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb9cd17b0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395vv/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Implementing regulations; notice, opportunity to be heard, etc.</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall by regulation provide procedures for implementation of this section, which procedures shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9cd17b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395vv/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> assure that the authority under this section is exercised only on behalf of a State agency which demonstrates to the Secretary’s satisfaction that it has provided adequate notice of a determination or of a need for information, and an opportunity to appeal such determination or to provide such information,</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9cd17b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395vv/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> determine the amount of the payment to which the institution or person would otherwise be entitled under this subchapter which shall be treated as a setoff against overpayments under subchapter XIX, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9cd17b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395vv/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> assure the restoration to the institution or person of amounts withheld under this section which are ultimately determined to be in excess of overpayments under subchapter XIX and to which the institution or person would otherwise be entitled under this subchapter.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb9cd17b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395vv/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment to States of amounts recovered</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, from the trust funds established under sections 1395i and 1395t of this title, as appropriate, the Secretary shall pay to the appropriate State agency amounts recovered under this section to offset the State agency’s overpayment under subchapter XIX. Such payments shall be accounted for by the State agency as recoveries of overpayments under the State plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb9cd17b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, title XVIII, § 1885, as added <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXI/s2104">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXI, § 2104</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/788">95 Stat. 788</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
