<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb9cd178f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395uu"><num value="1395uu">§ 1395uu.</num><heading> Payments to promote closing or conversion of underutilized hospital facilities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb9cd1790-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395uu/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Transitional allowances; procedures applicable</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any hospital may file an application with the Secretary (in such form and including such data and information as the Secretary may require) for establishment of a transitional allowance under this subchapter with respect to the closing or conversion of an underutilized hospital facility. The Secretary also may establish procedures, consistent with this section, by which a hospital, before undergoing an actual closure or conversion of a hospital facility, can have a determination made as to whether or not it will be eligible for a transitional allowance under this section with respect to such closure or conversion.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb9cd1791-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395uu/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Allowable costs as transitional allowances; findings and determinations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Secretary finds, after consideration of an application under subsection (a), that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9cd1792-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395uu/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> the hospital’s closure or conversion—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9cd1793-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395uu/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is formally initiated after <date date="1981-09-30">September 30, 1981</date>,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9cd1794-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395uu/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is expected to benefit the program under this subchapter by (i) eliminating excess bed capacity, (ii) discontinuing an underutilized service for which there are adequate alternative sources, or (iii) substituting for the underutilized service some other service which is needed in the area, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9cd1795-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395uu/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> is consistent with the findings of an appropriate health planning agency and with any applicable State program for reduction in the number of hospital beds in the State, and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9cd1796-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395uu/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> in the case of a complete closure of a hospital—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9cd1797-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395uu/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the hospital is a private nonprofit hospital or a local governmental hospital, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9cd1798-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395uu/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the closure is not for replacement of the hospital,</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Secretary may include as an allowable cost in the hospital’s reasonable cost (for the purpose of making payments to the hospital under this subchapter) an amount (in this section referred to as a “transitional allowance”), as provided in subsection (c).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb9cd1799-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395uu/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Factors determinative of transitional allowance</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9cd179a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395uu/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Each transitional allowance established shall be reasonably related to the prior or pro­spective use of the facility involved under this subchapter and shall recognize—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9cd179b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395uu/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> in the case of a facility conversion or closure (other than a complete closure of a hospital)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9cd179c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395uu/c/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> in the case of a private nonprofit or local governmental hospital, that portion of the hospital’s costs attributable to capital assets of the facility which have been taken into account in determining reasonable cost for purposes of determining the amount of payment to the hospital under this subchapter, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9cd179d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395uu/c/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in the case of any hospital, transitional operating cost increases related to the conversion or closure to the extent that such operating costs exceed amounts ordinarily reimbursable under this subchapter; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9cd179e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395uu/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case of complete closure of a hospital, the outstanding portion of actual debt obligations previously recognized as reasonable for purposes of reimbursement under this subchapter, less any salvage value of the hospital.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9cd179f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395uu/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A transitional allowance shall be for a period (not to exceed 20 years) specified by the Secretary, except that, in the case of a complete closure described in paragraph (1)(B), the Secretary may provide for a lump-sum allowance where the Secretary determines that such a one-time allowance is more efficient and economical.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9cd17a0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395uu/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A transitional allowance shall take effect on a date established by the Secretary, but not earlier than the date of completion of the closure or conversion concerned.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb9cd17a1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395uu/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> A transitional allowance shall not be considered in applying the limits to costs recognized as reasonable pursuant to the third sentence of subparagraph (A) and subparagraph (L)(i) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/v/1">section 1395x(v)(1) of this title</ref>, or in determining whether the reasonable cost exceeds the customary charges for a service for purposes of determining the amount to be paid to a provider pursuant to sections 1395f(b) and 1395<i>l</i>(a)(2) of this title.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb9cd17a2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395uu/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Hearing to review determination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A hospital dissatisfied with a determination of the Secretary on its application under this section may obtain an informal or formal hearing, at the discretion of the Secretary, by filing (in such form and within such time period as the Secretary establishes) a request for such a hearing. The Secretary shall make a final determination on such application within 30 days after the last day of such hearing.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb9cd17a3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, title XVIII, § 1884, as added <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXI/s2101/a/s1">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXI, § 2101(a)[(1)]</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/785">95 Stat. 785</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/tI/s128/a/6">Pub. L. 97–248, title I, § 128(a)(6)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-03">Sept. 3, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/366">96 Stat. 366</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb9cd17a4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb9cd17a5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb9cd17a6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1982—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/248">Pub. L. 97–248</ref> redesignated second subsec. (c), relating to hearing to review determination, as subsec. (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb9cd17a7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb9cd17a8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1982 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/248">Pub. L. 97–248</ref> effective as if originally included as part of this section as this section was enacted by the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1981, <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/248/s128/e/2">section 128(e)(2) of Pub. L. 97–248</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x">section 1395x of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb9cd17a9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXI/s2101/c">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXI, § 2101(c)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/787">95 Stat. 787</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/35/tXXI/s2101/c">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [enacting this section and amending <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396b">section 1396b of this title</ref>] shall apply only to services furnished by a hospital during any accounting year beginning on or after <date date="1981-10-01">October 1, 1981</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb9cd17aa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Payments To Promote Closure and Conversion of Underutilized Hospital Facilities</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tIII/s2353">Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title III, § 2353</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1099">98 Stat. 1099</ref>, directed Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out a study and report to Congress prior to <date date="1985-03-31">Mar. 31, 1985</date>, on modifications required in this section in order to conform the closure and conversion program authorized in that section to the prospective payment system under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ww/d">section 1395ww(d) of this title</ref>, so as to provide assistance to hospitals which may have particular problems in converting facilities (or parts thereof) from acute care to less intensive care or in closing facilities (or parts thereof), such report to include recommendations as to how, and whether, implementation of this section as modified may result in reductions in total hospital inpatient costs and total expenditures under this subchapter, and prohibited from implementing this section prior to <date date="1985-03-31">Mar. 31, 1985</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb9cd17ab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Establishment and Evaluation of Transitional Allowances; Report and Recommendations to Congress</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXI/s2101/b">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXI, § 2101(b)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/786">95 Stat. 786</ref>, prohibited Secretary of Health and Human Services from establishing under this section transitional allowances with respect to more than 50 hospitals prior to <date date="1984-01-01">Jan. 1, 1984</date>, and directed Secretary to evaluate effectiveness of program of transitional allowances established under this section and, not later than <date date="1983-01-01">Jan. 1, 1983</date>, report to Congress on such evaluation and include in such report such recommendations for such legislative changes as deemed appropriate.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
