<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb9989b06-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd"><num value="1395dd">§ 1395dd.</num><heading> Examination and treatment for emergency medical conditions and women in labor</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb9989b07-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Medical screening requirement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of a hospital that has a hospital emergency department, if any individual (whether or not eligible for benefits under this subchapter) comes to the emergency department and a request is made on the individual’s behalf for examination or treatment for a medical condition, the hospital must provide for an appropriate medical screening examination within the capability of the hospital’s emergency department, including ancillary services routinely available to the emergency department, to determine whether or not an emergency medical condition (within the meaning of subsection (e)(1)) exists.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb9989b08-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Necessary stabilizing treatment for emergency medical conditions and labor</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb9989b09-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If any individual (whether or not eligible for benefits under this subchapter) comes to a hospital and the hospital determines that the individual has an emergency medical condition, the hospital must provide either—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9989b0a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> within the staff and facilities available at the hospital, for such further medical examination and such treatment as may be required to stabilize the medical condition, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9989b0b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> for transfer of the individual to another medical facility in accordance with subsection (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb9989b0c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Refusal to consent to treatment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A hospital is deemed to meet the requirement of paragraph (1)(A) with respect to an individual if the hospital offers the individual the further medical examination and treatment described in that paragraph and informs the individual (or a person acting on the individual’s behalf) of the risks and benefits to the individual of such examination and treatment, but the individual (or a person acting on the individual’s behalf) refuses to consent to the examination and treatment. The hospital shall take all reasonable steps to secure the individual’s (or person’s) written informed consent to refuse such examination and treatment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb9989b0d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Refusal to consent to transfer</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A hospital is deemed to meet the requirement of paragraph (1) with respect to an individual if the hospital offers to transfer the individual to another medical facility in accordance with subsection (c) and informs the individual (or a person acting on the individual’s behalf) of the risks and benefits to the individual of such transfer, but the individual (or a person acting on the individual’s behalf) refuses to consent to the transfer. The hospital shall take all reasonable steps to secure the individual’s (or person’s) written informed consent to refuse such transfer.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb9989b0e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Restricting transfers until individual stabilized</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb9989b0f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If an individual at a hospital has an emergency medical condition which has not been stabilized (within the meaning of subsection (e)(3)(B)), the hospital may not transfer the individual unless—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9989b10-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9989b11-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/c/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the individual (or a legally responsible person acting on the individual’s behalf) after being informed of the hospital’s obligations under this section and of the risk of transfer, in writing requests transfer to another medical facility,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9989b12-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/c/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> a physician (within the meaning of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/r/1">section 1395x(r)(1) of this title</ref>) has signed a certification that <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002918">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002918"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma.</note> based upon the information available at the time of transfer, the medical benefits reasonably expected from the provision of appropriate medical treatment at another medical facility outweigh the increased risks to the individual and, in the case of labor, to the unborn child from effecting the transfer, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9989b13-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/c/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> if a physician is not physically present in the emergency department at the time an individual is transferred, a qualified medical person (as defined by the Secretary in regulations) has signed a certification described in clause (ii) after a physician (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/r/1">section 1395x(r)(1) of this title</ref>), in consultation with the person, has made the determination described in such clause, and subsequently countersigns the certification; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9989b14-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the transfer is an appropriate transfer (within the meaning of paragraph (2)) to that facility.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">A certification described in clause (ii) or (iii) of subparagraph (A) shall include a summary of the risks and benefits upon which the certification is based.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb9989b15-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Appropriate transfer</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">An appropriate transfer to a medical facility is a transfer—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9989b16-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in which the transferring hospital provides the medical treatment within its capacity which minimizes the risks to the individual’s health and, in the case of a woman in labor, the health of the unborn child;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9989b17-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> in which the receiving facility—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9989b18-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/c/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> has available space and qualified personnel for the treatment of the individual, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9989b19-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/c/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> has agreed to accept transfer of the individual and to provide appropriate medical treatment;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9989b1a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> in which the transferring hospital sends to the receiving facility all medical records (or copies thereof), related to the emergency condition for which the individual has presented, available at the time of the transfer, including records related to the individual’s emergency medical condition, observations of signs or symptoms, preliminary diagnosis, treatment provided, results of any tests and the informed written consent or certification (or copy thereof) provided under paragraph (1)(A), and the name and address of any on-call physician (described in subsection (d)(1)(C)) who has refused or failed to appear within a reasonable time to provide necessary stabilizing treatment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9989b1b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/c/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> in which the transfer is effected through qualified personnel and transportation equipment, as required including the use of necessary and medically appropriate life support measures during the transfer; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9989b1c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/c/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> which meets such other requirements as the Secretary may find necessary in the interest of the health and safety of individuals transferred.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb9989b1d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb9989b1e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil money penalties</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9989b1f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> A participating hospital that negligently violates a requirement of this section is subject to a civil money penalty of not more than $50,000 (or not more than $25,000 in the case of a hospital with less than 100 beds) for each such violation. The provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–7a">section 1320a–7a of this title</ref> (other than subsections (a) and (b)) shall apply to a civil money penalty under this subparagraph in the same manner as such provisions apply with respect to a penalty or proceeding under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–7a/a">section 1320a–7a(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9989b20-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Subject to subparagraph (C), any physician who is responsible for the examination, treatment, or transfer of an individual in a participating hospital, including a physician on-call for the care of such an individual, and who negligently violates a requirement of this section, including a physician who—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9989b21-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/d/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> signs a certification under subsection (c)(1)(A) that the medical benefits reasonably to be expected from a transfer to another facility outweigh the risks associated with the transfer, if the physician knew or should have known that the benefits did not outweigh the risks, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9989b22-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/d/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> misrepresents an individual’s condition or other information, including a hospital’s obligations under this section,</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">is subject to a civil money penalty of not more than $50,000 for each such violation and, if the violation is gross and flagrant or is repeated, to exclusion from participation in this subchapter and State health care programs. The provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–7a">section 1320a–7a of this title</ref> (other than the first and second sentences of subsection (a) and subsection (b)) shall apply to a civil money penalty and exclusion under this subparagraph in the same manner as such provisions apply with respect to a penalty, exclusion, or proceeding under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–7a/a">section 1320a–7a(a) of this title</ref>.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9989b23-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> If, after an initial examination, a physician determines that the individual requires the services of a physician listed by the hospital on its list of on-call physicians (required to be maintained under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395cc/a/1/I">section 1395cc(a)(1)(I) of this title</ref>) and notifies the on-call physician and the on-call physician fails or refuses to appear within a reasonable period of time, and the physician orders the transfer of the individual because the physician determines that without the services of the on-call physician the benefits of transfer outweigh the risks of transfer, the physician authorizing the transfer shall not be subject to a penalty under subparagraph (B). However, the previous sentence shall not apply to the hospital or to the on-call physician who failed or refused to appear.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb9989b24-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Civil enforcement</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb9989b25-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/d/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Personal harm</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any individual who suffers personal harm as a direct result of a participating hospital’s violation of a requirement of this section may, in a civil action against the participating hospital, obtain those damages available for personal injury under the law of the State in which the hospital is located, and such equitable relief as is appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb9989b26-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/d/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Financial loss to other medical facility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any medical facility that suffers a financial loss as a direct result of a participating hospital’s violation of a requirement of this section may, in a civil action against the participating hospital, obtain those damages available for financial loss, under the law of the State in which the hospital is located, and such equitable relief as is appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb9989b27-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/d/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations on actions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">No action may be brought under this paragraph more than two years after the date of the violation with respect to which the action is brought.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb9989b28-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation with quality improvement organizations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In considering allegations of violations of the requirements of this section in imposing sanctions under paragraph (1) or in terminating a hospital’s participation under this subchapter, the Secretary shall request the appropriate quality improvement organization (with a contract under part B of subchapter XI) to assess whether the individual involved had an emergency medical condition which had not been stabilized, and provide a report on its findings. Except in the case in which a delay would jeopardize the health or safety of individuals, the Secretary shall request such a review before effecting a sanction under paragraph (1) and shall provide a period of at least 60 days for such review. Except in the case in which a delay would jeopardize the health or safety of individuals, the Secretary shall also request such a review before making a compliance determination as part of the process of terminating a hospital’s participation under this subchapter for violations related to the appropriateness of a medical screening examination, stabilizing treatment, or an appropriate transfer as required by this section, and shall provide a period of 5 days for such review. The Secretary shall provide a copy of the organization’s report to the hospital or physician consistent with confidentiality requirements imposed on the organization under such part B.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb9989b29-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice upon closing an investigation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish a procedure to notify hospitals and physicians when an investigation under this section is closed.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb9989b2a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9989b2b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The term “emergency medical condition” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9989b2c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> a medical condition manifesting itself by acute symptoms of sufficient severity (including severe pain) such that the absence of immediate medical attention could reasonably be expected to result in—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9989b2d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/e/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> placing the health of the individual (or, with respect to a pregnant woman, the health of the woman or her unborn child) in serious jeopardy,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9989b2e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/e/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> serious impairment to bodily functions, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9989b2f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/e/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> serious dysfunction of any bodily organ or part; or</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb9989b30-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> with respect to a pregnant woman who is having contractions—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9989b31-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/e/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> that there is inadequate time to effect a safe transfer to another hospital before delivery, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb9989b32-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/e/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> that transfer may pose a threat to the health or safety of the woman or the unborn child.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9989b33-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “participating hospital” means a hospital that has entered into a provider agreement under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395cc">section 1395cc of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9989b34-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9989b35-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The term “to stabilize” means, with respect to an emergency medical condition described in paragraph (1)(A), to provide such medical treatment of the condition as may be necessary to assure, within reasonable medical probability, that no material deterioration of the condition is likely to result from or occur during the transfer of the individual from a facility, or, with respect to an emergency medical condition described in paragraph (1)(B), to deliver (including the placenta).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9989b36-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The term “stabilized” means, with respect to an emergency medical condition described in paragraph (1)(A), that no material deterioration of the condition is likely, within reasonable medical probability, to result from or occur during the transfer of the individual from a facility, or, with respect to an emergency medical condition described in paragraph (1)(B), that the woman has delivered (including the placenta).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9989b37-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> The term “transfer” means the movement (including the discharge) of an individual outside a hospital’s facilities at the direction of any person employed by (or affiliated or associated, directly or indirectly, with) the hospital, but does not include such a movement of an individual who (A) has been declared dead, or (B) leaves the facility without the permission of any such person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb9989b38-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/e/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> The term “hospital” includes a critical access hospital (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/mm/1">section 1395x(mm)(1) of this title</ref>) and a rural emergency hospital (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/kkk/2">section 1395x(kkk)(2) of this title</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb9989b39-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Preemption</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The provisions of this section do not preempt any State or local law requirement, except to the extent that the requirement directly conflicts with a requirement of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb9989b3a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Nondiscrimination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A participating hospital that has specialized capabilities or facilities (such as burn units, shock-trauma units, neonatal intensive care units, or (with respect to rural areas) regional referral centers as identified by the Secretary in regulation) shall not refuse to accept an appropriate transfer of an individual who requires such specialized capabilities or facilities if the hospital has the capacity to treat the individual.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb9989b3b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> No delay in examination or treatment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A participating hospital may not delay provision of an appropriate medical screening examination required under subsection (a) or further medical examination and treatment required under subsection (b) in order to inquire about the individual’s method of payment or insurance status.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb9989b3c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Whistleblower protections</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A participating hospital may not penalize or take adverse action against a qualified medical person described in subsection (c)(1)(A)(iii) or a physician because the person or physician refuses to authorize the transfer of an individual with an emergency medical condition that has not been stabilized or against any hospital employee because the employee reports a violation of a requirement of this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb9989b3d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, title XVIII, § 1867, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/tIX/s9121/b">Pub. L. 99–272, title IX, § 9121(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/164">100 Stat. 164</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/99/509/tIX/s9307/c/4">Pub. L. 99–509, title IX, § 9307(c)(4)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-21">Oct. 21, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1996">100 Stat. 1996</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/tXVIII/s1895/b/4">Pub. L. 99–514, title XVIII, § 1895(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-22">Oct. 22, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/2933">100 Stat. 2933</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tIV/s4009/a/1">Pub. L. 100–203, title IV, § 4009(a)(1)</ref>, formerly § 4009(a)(1), (2), <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-56">101 Stat. 1330–56</ref>, 1330–57; <ref href="/us/pl/100/360/tIV/s411/b/8/A/i">Pub. L. 100–360, title IV, § 411(b)(8)(A)(i)</ref>, <date date="1988-07-01">July 1, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/772">102 Stat. 772</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/485/tVI/s608/d/18/E">Pub. L. 100–485, title VI, § 608(d)(18)(E)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-13">Oct. 13, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2419">102 Stat. 2419</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tVI">Pub. L. 101–239, title VI</ref>, §§ 6003(g)(3)(D)(xiv), 6211(a)–(h), <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2154">103 Stat. 2154</ref>, 2245–2248; <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tIV">Pub. L. 101–508, title IV</ref>, §§ 4008(b)(1)–(3)(A), 4207(a)(1)(A), (2), (3), (k)(3), formerly 4027(a)(1)(A), (2), (3), (k)(3), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-44">104 Stat. 1388–44</ref>, 1388–117, 1388–124, renumbered and amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/432/tI/s160/d/4">Pub. L. 103–432, title I, § 160(d)(4)</ref>, (5)(A), <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4444">108 Stat. 4444</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/tIV/s4201/c/1">Pub. L. 105–33, title IV, § 4201(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="1997-08-05">Aug. 5, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/373">111 Stat. 373</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/tVII/s736/a/14">Pub. L. 108–173, title VII, § 736(a)(14)</ref>, title IX, § 944(b), (c)(1), <date date="2003-12-08">Dec. 8, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2355">117 Stat. 2355</ref>, 2423; <ref href="/us/pl/112/40/tII/s261/a/3/A">Pub. L. 112–40, title II, § 261(a)(3)(A)</ref>, (E), <date date="2011-10-21">Oct. 21, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/423">125 Stat. 423</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dCC/tI/s125/b/2/B">Pub. L. 116–260, div. CC, title I, § 125(b)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2966">134 Stat. 2966</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb9989b3e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb9989b3f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idb9989b40-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 1395dd, <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531/tXVIII/s1867">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531, title XVIII, § 1867</ref>, as added <date date="1965-07-30">July 30, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/89/97/tI/s102/a">Pub. L. 89–97, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/329">79 Stat. 329</ref>; amended <date date="1968-01-02">Jan. 2, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/90/248/tI/s164/a">Pub. L. 90–248, title I, § 164(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/873">81 Stat. 873</ref>; <date date="1972-10-30">Oct. 30, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/92/603/tII/s288">Pub. L. 92–603, title II, § 288</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/1457">86 Stat. 1457</ref>, related to creation, composition, meetings, and functions of the Health Insurance Benefits Advisory Council and the appointment of a Chairman and members thereto, and qualifications, terms of office, compensation, and reimbursement of travel expenses of members, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tIII/s2349/a">Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title III, § 2349(a)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1097">98 Stat. 1097</ref>, eff. <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb9989b41-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsec. (e)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260">Pub. L. 116–260</ref> inserted “and a rural emergency hospital (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/kkk/2">section 1395x(kkk)(2) of this title</ref>)” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/112/40">Pub. L. 112–40</ref> substituted “quality improvement” for “peer review” in heading and for “utilization and quality control peer review” in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (d)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/s736/a/14/A">Pub. L. 108–173, § 736(a)(14)(A)</ref>, substituted “if the violation is” for “if the violation is is” in concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/s944/c/1">Pub. L. 108–173, § 944(c)(1)</ref>, inserted “or in terminating a hospital’s participation under this subchapter” after “in imposing sanctions under paragraph (1)” and inserted at end “Except in the case in which a delay would jeopardize the health or safety of individuals, the Secretary shall also request such a review before making a compliance determination as part of the process of terminating a hospital’s participation under this subchapter for violations related to the appropriateness of a medical screening examination, stabilizing treatment, or an appropriate transfer as required by this section, and shall provide a period of 5 days for such review. The Secretary shall provide a copy of the organization’s report to the hospital or physician consistent with confidentiality requirements imposed on the organization under such part B.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/s944/b">Pub. L. 108–173, § 944(b)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/s736/a/14/B">Pub. L. 108–173, § 736(a)(14)(B)</ref>, substituted “a pregnant woman” for “a pregnant women”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/s736/a/14/C">Pub. L. 108–173, § 736(a)(14)(C)</ref>, substituted “means a hospital” for “means hospital”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1997—Subsec. (e)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref> substituted “critical access” for “rural primary care”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/103/432/s160/d/5/A">Pub. L. 103–432, § 160(d)(5)(A)</ref>, made technical amendment to <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s4207/a/1/A">Pub. L. 101–508, § 4207(a)(1)(A)</ref>. See 1990 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (c)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s4008/b/3/A/iii">Pub. L. 101–508, § 4008(b)(3)(A)(iii)</ref>, substituted “subsection (d)(1)(C)” for “subsection (d)(2)(C)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s4008/b/3/A/i">Pub. L. 101–508, § 4008(b)(3)(A)(i)</ref>, (ii), redesignated par. (2) as (1) and struck out former par. (1) which read as follows: “If a hospital knowingly and willfully, or negligently, fails to meet the requirements of this section, such hospital is subject to—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) termination of its provider agreement under this subchapter in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395cc/b">section 1395cc(b) of this title</ref>, or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) at the option of the Secretary, suspension of such agreement for such period of time as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, upon reasonable notice to the hospital and to the public.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s4207/a/2">Pub. L. 101–508, § 4207(a)(2)</ref>, (3), formerly § 4027(a)(2), (3), as renumbered by <ref href="/us/pl/103/432/s160/d/4">Pub. L. 103–432, § 160(d)(4)</ref>, which directed amendment of par. (2)(B) by substituting “negligently” for “knowingly” and “is gross and flagrant or is repeated” for “knowing and willful or negligent”, was executed by making the substitutions in par. (1)(B) to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the intervening redesignation of par. (2) as (1) by <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s4008/b/3/A/ii">Pub. L. 101–508, § 4008(b)(3)(A)(ii)</ref>. See above.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s4008/b/3/A/ii">Pub. L. 101–508, § 4008(b)(3)(A)(ii)</ref>, redesignated par. (3) as (2). Former par. (2) redesignated (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s4008/b/1">Pub. L. 101–508, § 4008(b)(1)</ref>, (2), substituted “negligently” for “knowingly” and inserted “(or not more than $25,000 in the case of a hospital with less than 100 beds)” after “$50,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s4207/a/1/A">Pub. L. 101–508, § 4207(a)(1)(A)</ref>, formerly § 4027(a)(1)(A), as renumbered and amended by <ref href="/us/pl/103/432/s160/d/4">Pub. L. 103–432, § 160(d)(4)</ref>, (5)(A), added par. (3). Former par. (3) redesignated (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s4207/k/3">Pub. L. 101–508, § 4207(k)(3)</ref>, formerly § 4027(k)(3), as renumbered by <ref href="/us/pl/103/432/s160/d/4">Pub. L. 103–432, § 160(d)(4)</ref>, amended subsec. (i) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (i) read as follows: “A participating hospital may not penalize or take adverse action against a physician because the physician refuses to authorize the transfer of an individual with an emergency medical condition that has not been stabilized.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—<ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/h/2/A">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(h)(2)(A)</ref>, struck out “active” before “labor” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/h/2/B">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(h)(2)(B)</ref>, which directed the amendment of subsec. (a) by striking out “or to determine if the individual is in active labor (within the meaning of section (e)(2))” was executed by striking out “or to determine if the individual is in active labor (within the meaning of subsection (e)(2))” after “exists”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/a">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(a)</ref>, substituted “hospital’s emergency department, including ancillary services routinely available to the emergency department,” for “hospital’s emergency department”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/h/2/C">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(h)(2)(C)</ref>, struck out “active” before “labor” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/h/2/D/i">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(h)(2)(D)(i)</ref>, struck out “or is in active labor” after “emergency medical condition” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/h/2/D/ii">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(h)(2)(D)(ii)</ref>, struck out “or to provide for treatment of the labor” after “stabilize the medical condition”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/b/1">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “and informs the individual (or a person acting on the individual’s behalf) of the risks and benefits to the individual of such examination and treatment,” after “in that paragraph”, substituted “and treatment.” for “or treatment.”, and inserted at end “The hospital shall take all reasonable steps to secure the individual’s (or person’s) written informed consent to refuse such examination and treatment.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/b/2">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(b)(2)</ref>, inserted “and informs the individual (or a person acting on the individual’s behalf) of the risks and benefits to the individual of such transfer,” after “subsection (c)” and inserted at end “The hospital shall take all reasonable steps to secure the individual’s (or person’s) written informed consent to refuse such transfer.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/g/1/A">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(g)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “individual” for “patient” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/c/4">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(c)(4)</ref>, (g)(1)(B), (h)(2)(E), in introductory provisions, substituted “an individual” for “a patient”, “subsection (e)(3)(B))” for “subsection (e)(4)(B)) or is in active labor”, and “the individual” for “the patient”, and inserted at end “A certification described in clause (ii) or (iii) of subparagraph (A) shall include a summary of the risks and benefits upon which the certification is based.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/c/1">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(c)(1)</ref>, (g)(1)(B), substituted “the individual” for “the patient”, “the individual’s behalf” for “the patient’s behalf”, and “after being informed of the hospital’s obligations under this section and of the risk of transfer, in writing requests transfer to another medical facility” for “requests that the transfer be effected”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/c/2/B">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(c)(2)(B)</ref>, (3), (g)(1)(B), substituted “has signed a certification that based upon the information available at the time of transfer” for “, or other qualified medical personnel when a physician is not readily available in the emergency department, has signed a certification that, based upon the reasonable risks and benefits to the patient, and based upon the information available at the time” and “individual and, in the case of labor, to the unborn child” for “individual’s medical condition”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1)(A)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/c/2/A">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(c)(2)(A)</ref>, (C), (D), added cl. (iii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/c/5">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(c)(5)</ref>, added subpar. (A). Former subpar. (A) redesignated (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/c/5/A">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(c)(5)(A)</ref>, (g)(1)(B), redesignated subpar. (A) as (B) and substituted “the individual” for “the patient” in cls. (i) and (ii). Former subpar. (B) redesignated (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/c/5/A">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(c)(5)(A)</ref>, (d), redesignated subpar. (B) as (C) and substituted “sends to” for “provides” and “all medical records (or copies thereof), related to the emergency condition for which the individual has presented, available at the time of the transfer, including records related to the individual’s emergency medical condition, observations of signs or symptoms, preliminary diagnosis, treatment provided, results of any tests and the informed written consent or certification (or copy thereof) provided under paragraph (1)(A), and the name and address of any on-call physician (described in subsection (d)(2)(C)) who has refused or failed to appear within a reasonable time to provide necessary stabilizing treatment” for “with appropriate medical records (or copies thereof) of the examination and treatment effected at the transferring hospital”. Former subpar. (C) redesignated (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/c/5/A">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(c)(5)(A)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (C) as (D). Former subpar. (D) redesignated (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/c/5/A">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(c)(5)(A)</ref>, (g)(1)(B), redesignated subpar. (D) as (E) and substituted “individuals” for “patients”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/e/1">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(e)(1)</ref>, amended subpar. (B) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (B) read as follows: “The responsible physician in a participating hospital with respect to the hospital’s violation of a requirement of this subsection is subject to the sanctions described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395u/j/2">section 1395u(j)(2) of this title</ref>, except that, for purposes of this subparagraph, the civil money penalty with respect to each violation may not exceed $50,000, rather than $2,000.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/e/2">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(e)(2)</ref>, added subpar. (C) and struck out former subpar. (C) which read as follows: “As used in this paragraph, the term ‘responsible physician’ means, with respect to a hospital’s violation of a requirement of this section, a physician who—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) is employed by, or under contract with, the participating hospital, and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) acting as such an employee or under such a contract, has professional responsibility for the provision of examinations or treatments for the individual, or transfers of the individual, with respect to which the violation occurred.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/h/1/A">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(h)(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “means—” and subpars. (A) and (B) for “means a medical condition manifesting itself by acute symptoms of sufficient severity (including severe pain) such that the absence of immediate medical attention could reasonably be expected to result in—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) placing the patient’s health in serious jeopardy,</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) serious impairment to bodily functions, or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) serious dysfunction of any bodily organ or part.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/h/1/B">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(h)(1)(B)</ref>, (E), redesignated par. (3) as (2) and struck out former par. (2) which defined “active labor”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/h/1/E">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(h)(1)(E)</ref>, redesignated par. (4) as (3). Former par. (3) redesignated (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/h/1/E">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(h)(1)(E)</ref>, redesignated par. (5) as (4). Former par. (4) redesignated (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/h/1/C">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(h)(1)(C)</ref>, substituted “emergency medical condition described in paragraph (1)(A)” for “emergency medical condition”, “likely to result from or occur during” for “likely to result from”, and “from a facility, or, with respect to an emergency medical condition described in paragraph (1)(B), to deliver (including the placenta)” for “from a facility”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(4)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/h/1/D">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(h)(1)(D)</ref>, inserted “described in paragraph (1)(A)” after “emergency medical condition”, “or occur during” after “to result from”, and “, or, with respect to an emergency medical condition described in paragraph (1)(B), that the woman has delivered (including the placenta)” after “from a facility”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/h/1/E">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(h)(1)(E)</ref>, redesignated par. (6) as (5). Former par. (5) redesignated (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/g/2">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(g)(2)</ref>, substituted “an individual” for “a patient” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/h/1/E">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(h)(1)(E)</ref>, redesignated par. (6) as (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6003/g/3/D/xiv">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6003(g)(3)(D)(xiv)</ref>, added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (g) to (i). <ref href="/us/pl/101/239/s6211/f">Pub. L. 101–239, § 6211(f)</ref>, added subsecs. (g) to (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/360/s411/b/8/A/i">Pub. L. 100–360, § 411(b)(8)(A)(i)</ref>, amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/s4009/a/2">Pub. L. 100–203, § 4009(a)(2)</ref>, see 1987 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/360/s411/b/8/A/i">Pub. L. 100–360, § 411(b)(8)(A)(i)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/485/s608/d/18/E">Pub. L. 100–485, § 608(d)(18)(E)</ref>, amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/s4009/a/1">Pub. L. 100–203, § 4009(a)(1)</ref>, see 1987 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/s4009/a/2">Pub. L. 100–203, § 4009(a)(2)</ref>, which directed insertion of a provision related to imposing the sanction described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395u/j/2/A">section 1395u(j)(2)(A) of this title</ref>, was amended generally by <ref href="/us/pl/100/360/s411/b/8/A/i">Pub. L. 100–360, § 411(b)(8)(A)(i)</ref>, so that it does not amend par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/s4009/a/1">Pub. L. 100–203, § 4009(a)(1)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/360/s411/b/8/A/i">Pub. L. 100–360, § 411(b)(8)(A)(i)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/485/s608/d/18/E">Pub. L. 100–485, § 608(d)(18)(E)</ref>, substituted subpars. (A) and (B) for “In addition to the other grounds for imposition of a civil money penalty under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320a–7a/a">section 1320a–7a(a) of this title</ref>, a participating hospital that knowingly violates a requirement of this section and the responsible physician in the hospital with respect to such a violation are each subject, under that section, to a civil money penalty of not more than $25,000 for each such violation.”, designated second sentence as subpar. (C), substituted “this paragraph” for “the previous sentence”, and redesignated former subpars. (A) and (B) as cls. (i) and (ii), respectively, of subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (b)(2), (3). <ref href="/us/pl/99/509">Pub. L. 99–509</ref> struck out “legally responsible” after “individual (or a”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> struck out “and has, under the agreement, obligated itself to comply with the requirements of this section” after “<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395cc">section 1395cc of this title</ref>”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb99b0b42-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb99b0b43-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2020 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/116/260">Pub. L. 116–260</ref> applicable to items and services furnished on or after <date date="2023-01-01">Jan. 1, 2023</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s125/g">section 125(g) of Pub. L. 116–260</ref>, set out as a note under section 1395<i>l</i> of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb99b0b44-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2011 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/112/40">Pub. L. 112–40</ref> applicable to contracts entered into or renewed on or after <date date="2012-01-01">Jan. 1, 2012</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/112/40/s261/e">section 261(e) of Pub. L. 112–40</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320c">section 1320c of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb99b0b45-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2003 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/173/tIX/s944/c/2">Pub. L. 108–173, title IX, § 944(c)(2)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-08">Dec. 8, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2423">117 Stat. 2423</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/173/tIX/s944/c/2">“The amendments made by paragraph (1) [amending this section] shall apply to terminations of participation initiated on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2003-12-08">Dec. 8, 2003</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb99b0b46-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1997 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/33">Pub. L. 105–33</ref> applicable to services furnished on or after <date date="1997-10-01">Oct. 1, 1997</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/33/s4201/d">section 4201(d) of Pub. L. 105–33</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395f">section 1395f of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb99b0b47-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by section 4008(b)(1)–(3)(A) of <ref href="/us/pl/101/508">Pub. L. 101–508</ref> applicable to actions occurring on or after the first day of the sixth month beginning after <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s4008/b/4">section 4008(b)(4) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395cc">section 1395cc of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s4207/a/1/A">section 4207(a)(1)(A) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref> effective on the first day of the first month beginning more than 60 days after <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/101/508/s4207/a/1/C">section 4207(a)(1)(C) of Pub. L. 101–508</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320c–3">section 1320c–3 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tIV/s4207/a/4">Pub. L. 101–508, title IV, § 4207(a)(4)</ref>, formerly § 4027(a)(4), <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-118">104 Stat. 1388–118</ref>, as renumbered and amended by <ref href="/us/pl/103/432/tI/s160/d/4">Pub. L. 103–432, title I, § 160(d)(4)</ref>, (5)(B), <date date="1994-10-31">Oct. 31, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4444">108 Stat. 4444</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/432/tI/s160/d/4">“The amendments made by paragraphs (2) and (3) [amending this section] shall apply to actions occurring on or after the first day of the sixth month beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb99b0b48-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1989 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/239/tVI/s6211/i">Pub. L. 101–239, title VI, § 6211(i)</ref>, <date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2249">103 Stat. 2249</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/239/tVI/s6211/i">“The amendments made by this section [amending this section] shall take effect on the first day of the first month that begins more than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1989-12-19">Dec. 19, 1989</date>], without regard to whether regulations to carry out such amendments have been promulgated by such date.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb99b0b49-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/485">Pub. L. 100–485</ref> effective as if included in the enactment of the Medicare Catastrophic Coverage Act of 1988, <ref href="/us/pl/100/360">Pub. L. 100–360</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/485/s608/g/1">section 608(g)(1) of Pub. L. 100–485</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s704">section 704 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Except as specifically provided in <ref href="/us/pl/100/360/s411">section 411 of Pub. L. 100–360</ref>, amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/360">Pub. L. 100–360</ref>, as it relates to a provision in the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1987, <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref>, effective as if included in the enactment of that provision in <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/360/s411/a">section 411(a) of Pub. L. 100–360</ref>, set out as a Reference to OBRA; Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s106">section 106 of Title 1</ref>, General Provisions.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb99b0b4a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1987 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tIV/s4009/a/2">Pub. L. 100–203, title IV, § 4009(a)(2)</ref>, formerly § 4009(a)(3), <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-57">101 Stat. 1330–57</ref>, as redesignated by <ref href="/us/pl/100/360/tIV/s411/b/8/A/ii">Pub. L. 100–360, title IV, § 411(b)(8)(A)(ii)</ref>, <date date="1988-07-01">July 1, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/772">102 Stat. 772</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/360/tIV/s411/b/8/A/ii">“The amendments made by this subsection [amending this section] shall apply to actions occurring on or after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb99b0b4b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/514">Pub. L. 99–514</ref> effective, except as otherwise provided, as if included in enactment of the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985, <ref href="/us/pl/99/272">Pub. L. 99–272</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/99/514/s1895/e">section 1895(e) of Pub. L. 99–514</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s162">section 162 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb99b0b4c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/272/tIX/s9121/c">Pub. L. 99–272, title IX, § 9121(c)</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/167">100 Stat. 167</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/272/tIX/s9121/c">“The amendments made by this section [enacting this section and amending <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395cc">section 1395cc of this title</ref>] shall take effect on the first day of the first month that begins at least 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="shortTitle" id="idb99b0b4d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Short Title</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This section is popularly known as the Emergency Medical Treatment and Labor Act (EMTALA).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb99b0b4e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Emergency Medical Treatment and Labor Act (EMTALA) Technical Advisory Group</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/173/tIX/s945">Pub. L. 108–173, title IX, § 945</ref>, <date date="2003-12-08">Dec. 8, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2423">117 Stat. 2423</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/173/tIX/s945">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Establishment</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary [of Health and Human Services] shall establish a Technical Advisory Group (in this section referred to as the ‘Advisory Group’) to review issues related to the Emergency Medical Treatment and Labor Act (EMTALA) and its implementation. In this section, the term ‘EMTALA’ refers to the provisions of section 1867 of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd">42 U.S.C. 1395dd</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Membership</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Advisory Group shall be composed of 19 members, including the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services and the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services and of which—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> 4 shall be representatives of hospitals, including at least one public hospital, that have experience with the application of EMTALA and at least 2 of which have not been cited for EMTALA violations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> 7 shall be practicing physicians drawn from the fields of emergency medicine, cardiology or cardiothoracic surgery, orthopedic surgery, neurosurgery, pediatrics or a pediatric subspecialty, obstetrics-gynecology, and psychiatry, with not more than one physician from any particular field;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> 2 shall represent patients;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> 2 shall be staff involved in EMTALA investigations from different regional offices of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> 1 shall be from a State survey office involved in EMTALA investigations and 1 shall be from a peer review organization, both of whom shall be from areas other than the regions represented under paragraph (4).</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I33" class="indent0 firstIndent0">In selecting members described in paragraphs (1) through (3), the Secretary shall consider qualified individuals nominated by organizations representing providers and patients.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">General Responsibilities</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Advisory Group—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> shall review EMTALA regulations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> may provide advice and recommendations to the Secretary with respect to those regulations and their application to hospitals and physicians;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> shall solicit comments and recommendations from hospitals, physicians, and the public regarding the implementation of such regulations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> may disseminate information on the application of such regulations to hospitals, physicians, and the public.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Administrative Matters.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Chairperson</inline>.—</heading><content>The members of the Advisory Group shall elect a member to serve as chairperson of the Advisory Group for the life of the Advisory Group.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Meetings</inline>.—</heading><content>The Advisory Group shall first meet at the direction of the Secretary. The Advisory Group shall then meet twice per year and at such other times as the Advisory Group may provide.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination</inline>.—</heading><content>The Advisory Group shall terminate 30 months after the date of its first meeting.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Waiver of Administrative Limitation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall establish the Advisory Group notwithstanding any limitation that may apply to the number of advisory committees that may be established (within the Department of Health and Human Services or otherwise).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb99b0b4f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Federal Reimbursement of Emergency Health Services Furnished to Undocumented Aliens</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/173/tX/s1011">Pub. L. 108–173, title X, § 1011</ref>, <date date="2003-12-08">Dec. 8, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2432">117 Stat. 2432</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/173/tX/s1011">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Total Amount Available for Allotment.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, there are appropriated to the Secretary [of Health and Human Services] $250,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2005 through 2008 for the purpose of making allotments under this section for payments to eligible providers in States described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Availability</inline>.—</heading><content>Funds appropriated under paragraph (1) shall remain available until expended.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State Allotments.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Based on percentage of undocumented aliens.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Out of the amount appropriated under subsection (a) for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall use $167,000,000 of such amount to make allotments for such fiscal year in accordance with subparagraph (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Formula</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The amount of the allotment for payments to eligible providers in each State for a fiscal year shall be equal to the product of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the total amount available for allotments under this paragraph for the fiscal year; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the percentage of undocumented aliens residing in the State as compared to the total number of such aliens residing in all States, as determined by the Statistics Division of the Immigration and Naturalization Service, as of January 2003, based on the 2000 decennial census.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Based on number of undocumented alien apprehension states.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Out of the amount appropriated under subsection (a) for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall use $83,000,000 of such amount to make allotments, in addition to amounts allotted under paragraph (1), for such fiscal year for each of the 6 States with the highest number of undocumented alien apprehensions for such fiscal year.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Determination of allotments</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The amount of the allotment for each State described in subparagraph (A) for a fiscal year shall be equal to the product of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the total amount available for allotments under this paragraph for the fiscal year; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the percentage of undocumented alien apprehensions in the State in that fiscal year as compared to the total of such apprehensions for all such States for the preceding fiscal year.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Data</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this paragraph, the highest number of undocumented alien apprehensions for a fiscal year shall be based on the apprehension rates for the 4-consecutive-quarter period ending before the beginning of the fiscal year for which information is available for undocumented aliens in such States, as reported by the Department of Homeland Security.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Funds.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authority to make payments</inline>.—</heading><content>From the allotments made for a State under subsection (b) for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall pay the amount (subject to the total amount available from such allotments) determined under paragraph (2) directly to eligible providers located in the State for the provision of eligible services to aliens described in paragraph (5) to the extent that the eligible provider was not otherwise reimbursed (through insurance or otherwise) for such services during that fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Determination of payment amounts.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Subject to subparagraph (B), the payment amount determined under this paragraph shall be an amount determined by the Secretary that is equal to the lesser of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the amount that the provider demonstrates was incurred for the provision of such services; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> amounts determined under a methodology established by the Secretary for purposes of this subsection.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Pro-rata reduction</inline>.—</heading><content>If the amount of funds allotted to a State under subsection (b) for a fiscal year is insufficient to ensure that each eligible provider in that State receives the amount of payment calculated under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall reduce that amount of payment with respect to each eligible provider to ensure that the entire amount allotted to the State for that fiscal year is paid to such eligible providers.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Methodology</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In establishing a methodology under paragraph (2)(A)(ii), the Secretary—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> may establish different methodologies for types of eligible providers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> may base payments for hospital services on estimated hospital charges, adjusted to estimated cost, through the application of hospital-specific cost-to-charge ratios;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> shall provide for the election by a hospital to receive either payments to the hospital for—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> hospital and physician services; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> hospital services and for a portion of the on-call payments made by the hospital to physicians; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> shall make quarterly payments under this section to eligible providers.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I31" class="indent1 firstIndent0">If a hospital makes the election under subparagraph (C)(i), the hospital shall pass on payments for services of a physician to the physician and may not charge any administrative or other fee with respect to such payments.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on use of funds</inline>.—</heading><content>Payments made to eligible providers in a State from allotments made under subsection (b) for a fiscal year may only be used for costs incurred in providing eligible services to aliens described in paragraph (5).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Aliens described</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>For purposes of paragraphs (1) and (2), aliens described in this paragraph are any of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Undocumented aliens.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Aliens who have been paroled into the United States at a United States port of entry for the purpose of receiving eligible services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Mexican citizens permitted to enter the United States for not more than 72 hours under the authority of a biometric machine readable border crossing identification card (also referred to as a ‘laser visa’) issued in accordance with the requirements of regulations prescribed under section 101(a)(6) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1101/a/6">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(6)</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Applications; Advance Payments.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Deadline for establishment of application process.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2004-09-01">September 1, 2004</date>, the Secretary shall establish a process under which eligible providers located in a State may request payments under subsection (c).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inclusion of measures to combat fraud and abuse</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall include in the process established under subparagraph (A) measures to ensure that inappropriate, excessive, or fraudulent payments are not made from the allotments determined under subsection (b), including certification by the eligible provider of the veracity of the payment request.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Advance payment; retrospective adjustment</inline>.—</heading><content>The process established under paragraph (1) may provide for making payments under this section for each quarter of a fiscal year on the basis of advance estimates of expenditures submitted by applicants for such payments and such other investigation as the Secretary may find necessary, and for making reductions or increases in the payments as necessary to adjust for any overpayment or underpayment for prior quarters of such fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible provider</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘eligible provider’ means a hospital, physician, or provider of ambulance services (including an Indian Health Service facility whether operated by the Indian Health Service or by an Indian tribe or tribal organization).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligible services</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘eligible services’ means health care services required by the application of section 1867 of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd">42 U.S.C. 1395dd</ref>), and related hospital inpatient and outpatient services and ambulance services (as defined by the Secretary).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Hospital</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘hospital’ has the meaning given such term in section 1861(e) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/e">42 U.S.C. 1395x(e)</ref>), except that such term shall include a critical access hospital (as defined in section 1861(mm)(1) of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/mm/1">42 U.S.C. 1395x(mm)(1)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Physician</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘physician’ has the meaning given that term in section 1861(r) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/r">42 U.S.C. 1395x(r)</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Indian tribe; tribal organization</inline>.—</heading><content>The terms ‘Indian tribe’ and ‘tribal organization’ have the meanings given such terms in section 4 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s1603">25 U.S.C. 1603</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">State</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘State’ means the 50 States and the District of Columbia.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb99b0b50-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Inspector General Study of Prohibition on Hospital Employment of Physicians</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/508/tIV/s4008/c">Pub. L. 101–508, title IV, § 4008(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1388-44">104 Stat. 1388–44</ref>, directed Secretary of Health and Human Services (acting through Inspector General of Department of Health and Human Services) to conduct a study of the effect of State laws prohibiting the employment of physicians by hospitals on the availability and accessibility of trauma and emergency care services, and include in such study an analysis of the effect of such laws on the ability of hospitals to meet the requirements of section 1867 of the Social Security Act (this section) relating to the examination and treatment of individuals with an emergency medical condition and women in labor, with Secretary to submit a report to Congress on the study not later than 1 year after <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idb99b0b51-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idb99b0b52-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 13952. Protecting Vulnerable Newborn and Infant Children</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 13952, <date date="2020-09-25">Sept. 25, 2020</date>, 85 F.R. 62187, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Section</inline> 1. <i>Purpose</i>. Every infant born alive, no matter the circumstances of his or her birth, has the same dignity and the same rights as every other individual and is entitled to the same protections under Federal law. Such laws include the Emergency Medical Treatment and Labor Act (EMTALA), <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395dd">42 U.S.C. 1395dd</ref>, which guarantees, in hospitals that have an emergency department, each individual’s right to an appropriate medical screening examination and to either stabilizing treatment or an appropriate transfer. They also include section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act [of 1973] (Rehab Act), <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s794">29 U.S.C. 794</ref>, which prohibits discrimination against individuals with disabilities by programs and activities receiving Federal funding. In addition, the Born-Alive Infants Protection Act [of 2002], <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s8">1 U.S.C. 8</ref>, makes clear that all infants born alive are individuals for purposes of these and other Federal laws and are therefore afforded the same legal protections as any other person. Together, these laws help protect infants born alive from discrimination in the provision of medical treatment, including infants who require emergency medical treatment, who are premature, or who are born with disabilities. Such infants are entitled to meaningful and non-discriminatory access to medical examination and services, with the consent of a parent or guardian, when they present at hospitals receiving Federal funds.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Despite these laws, some hospitals refuse the required medical screening examination and stabilizing treatment or otherwise do not provide potentially lifesaving medical treatment to extremely premature or disabled infants, even when parents plead for such treatment. Hospitals might refuse to provide treatment to extremely premature infants—born alive before 24 weeks of gestation—because they believe these infants may not survive, may have to live with long-term disabilities, or may have a quality-of-life deemed to be inadequate. Active treatment of extremely premature infants has, however, been shown to improve their survival rates. And the denial of such treatment, or discouragement of parents from seeking such treatment for their children, devalues the lives of these children and may violate Federal law.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 2. <i>Policy</i>. It is the policy of the United States to recognize the human dignity and inherent worth of every newborn or other infant child, regardless of prematurity or disability, and to ensure for each child due protection under the law.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 3. (a) The Secretary of Health and Human Services (Secretary) shall ensure that individuals responsible for all programs and activities under his jurisdiction that receive Federal funding are aware of their obligations toward infants, including premature infants or infants with disabilities, who have an emergency medical condition in need of stabilizing treatment, under EMTALA and section 504 of the Rehab Act, as interpreted consistent with the Born-Alive Infants Protection Act. In particular, the Secretary shall ensure that individuals responsible for such programs and activities are aware that they are not excused from complying with these obligations, including the obligation to provide an appropriate medical screening examination and stabilizing treatment or transfer, when extremely premature infants are born alive or infants are born with disabilities. The Secretary shall also ensure that individuals responsible for such programs and activities are aware that they may not unlawfully discourage parents from seeking medical treatment for their infant child solely because of their infant child’s disability. The Secretary shall further ensure that individuals responsible for such programs and activities are aware of their obligations to provide stabilizing treatment that will allow the infant patients to be transferred to a more suitable facility if appropriate treatment is not possible at the initial location.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) The Secretary shall, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, ensure that Federal funding disbursed by the Department of Health and Human Services is expended in full compliance with EMTALA and section 504 of the Rehab Act, as interpreted consistent with the Born-Alive Infants Protection Act, as reflected in the policy set forth in section 2 of this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) The Secretary shall, as appropriate and to the fullest extent permitted by law, investigate complaints of violations of applicable Federal laws with respect to infants born alive, including infants who have an emergency medical condition in need of stabilizing treatment or infants with disabilities whose parents seek medical treatment for their infants. The Secretary shall also clarify, in an easily understandable format, the process by which parents and hospital staff may submit such complaints for investigation under applicable Federal laws.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) The Secretary shall take all appropriate enforcement action against individuals and organizations found through investigation to have violated applicable Federal laws, up to and including terminating Federal funding for non-compliant programs and activities.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) The Secretary shall, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, prioritize the allocation of Department of Health and Human Services discretionary grant funding and National Institutes of Health research dollars for programs and activities conducting research to develop treatments that may improve survival—especially survival without impairment—of infants born alive, including premature infants or infants with disabilities, who have an emergency medical condition in need of stabilizing treatment.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(d) The Secretary shall, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, prioritize the allocation of Department of Health and Human Services discretionary grant funding to programs and activities, including hospitals, that provide training to medical personnel regarding the provision of life-saving medical treatment to all infants born alive, including premature infants or infants with disabilities, who have an emergency medical condition in need of stabilizing treatment.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(e) The Secretary shall, as necessary and consistent with applicable law, issue such regulations or guidance as may be necessary to implement this order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><inline class="small-caps">Sec.</inline> 4. <i>General Provisions</i>. (a) Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(i) the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(ii) the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(b) This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">(c) This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>
<signature>
<name>Donald J. Trump.</name>
</signature>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
