<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idba06505c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd"><num value="1395ddd">§ 1395ddd.</num><heading> Medicare Integrity Program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idba06505d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of Program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is hereby established the Medicare Integrity Program (in this section referred to as the “Program”) under which the Secretary shall promote the integrity of the medicare program by entering into contracts in accordance with this section with eligible entities, or otherwise, to carry out the activities described in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idba06505e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Activities described</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The activities described in this subsection are as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba06505f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Review of activities of providers of services or other individuals and entities furnishing items and services for which payment may be made under this subchapter (including skilled nursing facilities and home health agencies), including medical and utilization review and fraud review (employing similar standards, processes, and technologies used by private health plans, including equipment and software technologies which surpass the capability of the equipment and technologies used in the review of claims under this subchapter as of <date date="1996-08-21">August 21, 1996</date>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba065060-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Audit of cost reports.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba065061-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Determinations as to whether payment should not be, or should not have been, made under this subchapter by reason of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395y/b">section 1395y(b) of this title</ref>, and recovery of payments that should not have been made.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba065062-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Education of providers of services, beneficiaries, and other persons with respect to payment integrity and benefit quality assurance issues.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba065063-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Developing (and periodically updating) a list of items of durable medical equipment in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395m/a/15">section 1395m(a)(15) of this title</ref> which are subject to prior authorization under such section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba065064-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> The Medicare-Medicaid Data Match Program in accordance with subsection (g).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idba065065-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility of entities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An entity is eligible to enter into a contract under the Program to carry out any of the activities described in subsection (b) if—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba065066-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the entity has demonstrated capability to carry out such activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba065067-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> in carrying out such activities, the entity agrees to cooperate with the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services, the Attorney General, and other law enforcement agencies, as appropriate, in the investigation and deterrence of fraud and abuse in relation to this subchapter and in other cases arising out of such activities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba065068-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the entity complies with such conflict of interest standards as are generally applicable to Federal acquisition and procurement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba065069-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the entity agrees to provide the Secretary and the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services with such performance statistics (including the number and amount of overpayments recovered, the number of fraud referrals, and the return on investment of such activities by the entity) as the Secretary or the Inspector General may request; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba06506a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the entity meets such other requirements as the Secretary may impose.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">In the case of the activity described in subsection (b)(5), an entity shall be deemed to be eligible to enter into a contract under the Program to carry out the activity if the entity is a carrier with a contract in effect under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395u">section 1395u of this title</ref>.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idba06506b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Process for entering into contracts</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall enter into contracts under the Program in accordance with such procedures as the Secretary shall by regulation establish, except that such procedures shall include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba06506c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Procedures for identifying, evaluating, and resolving organizational conflicts of interest that are generally applicable to Federal acquisition and procurement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba06506d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Competitive procedures to be used—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba06506e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> when entering into new contracts under this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba06506f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> when entering into contracts that may result in the elimination of responsibilities of an individual fiscal intermediary or carrier under section 202(b) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba065070-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> at any other time considered appropriate by the Secretary,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">except that the Secretary may continue to contract with entities that are carrying out the activities described in this section pursuant to agreements under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395h">section 1395h of this title</ref> or contracts under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395u">section 1395u of this title</ref> in effect on <date date="1996-08-21">August 21, 1996</date>.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba065071-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Procedures under which a contract under this section may be renewed without regard to any provision of law requiring competition if the contractor has met or exceeded the performance requirements established in the current contract.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary may enter into such contracts without regard to final rules having been promulgated.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idba065072-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on contractor liability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall by regulation provide for the limitation of a contractor’s liability for actions taken to carry out a contract under the Program, and such regulation shall, to the extent the Secretary finds appropriate, employ the same or comparable standards and other substantive and procedural provisions as are contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320c–6">section 1320c–6 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idba065073-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Recovery of overpayments</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba065074-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of repayment plans</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba065075-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the repayment, within 30 days by a provider of services or supplier, of an overpayment under this subchapter would constitute a hardship (as described in subparagraph (B)), subject to subparagraph (C), upon request of the provider of services or supplier the Secretary shall enter into a plan with the provider of services or supplier for the repayment (through offset or otherwise) of such overpayment over a period of at least 6 months but not longer than 3 years (or not longer than 5 years in the case of extreme hardship, as determined by the Secretary). Interest shall accrue on the balance through the period of repayment. Such plan shall meet terms and conditions determined to be appropriate by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba065076-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Hardship</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba065077-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/1/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the repayment of an overpayment (or overpayments) within 30 days is deemed to constitute a hardship if—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idba065078-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/1/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> in the case of a provider of services that files cost reports, the aggregate amount of the overpayments exceeds 10 percent of the amount paid under this subchapter to the provider of services for the cost reporting period covered by the most recently submitted cost report; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idba065079-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/1/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> in the case of another provider of services or supplier, the aggregate amount of the overpayments exceeds 10 percent of the amount paid under this subchapter to the provider of services or supplier for the previous calendar year.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba06507a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/1/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of application</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Secretary shall establish rules for the application of this subparagraph in the case of a provider of services or supplier that was not paid under this subchapter during the previous year or was paid under this subchapter only during a portion of that year.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba06507b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/1/B/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Treatment of previous overpayments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If a provider of services or supplier has entered into a repayment plan under subparagraph (A) with respect to a specific overpayment amount, such payment amount under the repayment plan shall not be taken into account under clause (i) with respect to subsequent overpayment amounts.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba06507c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/1/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Exceptions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idba06507d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the Secretary has reason to suspect that the provider of services or supplier may file for bankruptcy or otherwise cease to do business or discontinue participation in the program under this subchapter; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idba06507e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> there is an indication of fraud or abuse committed against the program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba06507f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/1/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Immediate collection if violation of repayment plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If a provider of services or supplier fails to make a payment in accordance with a repayment plan under this paragraph, the Secretary may immediately seek to offset or otherwise recover the total balance outstanding (including applicable interest) under the repayment plan.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba065080-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/1/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Relation to no fault provision</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed as affecting the application of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395gg/c">section 1395gg(c) of this title</ref> (relating to no adjustment in the cases of certain overpayments).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba065081-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on recoupment</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba065082-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of a provider of services or supplier that is determined to have received an overpayment under this subchapter and that seeks a reconsideration by a qualified independent contractor on such determination under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ff/b/1">section 1395ff(b)(1) of this title</ref>, the Secretary may not take any action (or authorize any other person, including any medicare contractor, as defined in subparagraph (C)) to recoup the overpayment until the date the decision on the reconsideration has been rendered. If the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ff/b/1">section 1395ff(b)(1) of this title</ref> (providing for such a reconsideration by a qualified independent contractor) are not in effect, in applying the previous sentence any reference to such a reconsideration shall be treated as a reference to a redetermination by the fiscal intermediary or carrier involved.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba065083-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Collection with interest</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Insofar as the determination on such appeal is against the provider of services or supplier, interest on the overpayment shall accrue on and after the date of the original notice of overpayment. Insofar as such determination against the provider of services or supplier is later reversed, the Secretary shall provide for repayment of the amount recouped plus interest at the same rate as would apply under the previous sentence for the period in which the amount was recouped.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba065084-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Medicare contractor defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of this subsection, the term “medicare contractor” has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395zz/g">section 1395zz(g) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba065085-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on use of extrapolation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A medicare contractor may not use extrapolation to determine overpayment amounts to be recovered by recoupment, offset, or otherwise unless the Secretary determines that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba065086-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> there is a sustained or high level of payment error; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba065087-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> documented educational intervention has failed to correct the payment error.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">There shall be no administrative or judicial review under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ff">section 1395ff of this title</ref>, section 1395<i>oo</i> of this title, or otherwise, of determinations by the Secretary of sustained or high levels of payment errors under this paragraph.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba065088-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Provision of supporting documentation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In the case of a provider of services or supplier with respect to which amounts were previously overpaid, a medicare contractor may request the periodic production of records or supporting documentation for a limited sample of submitted claims to ensure that the previous practice is not continuing.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba065089-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Consent settlement reforms</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba06508a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary may use a consent settlement (as defined in subparagraph (D)) to settle a projected overpayment.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba06508b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Opportunity to submit additional information before consent settlement offer</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Before offering a provider of services or supplier a consent settlement, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idba06508c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/5/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> communicate to the provider of services or supplier—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idba06508d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/5/B/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> that, based on a review of the medical records requested by the Secretary, a preliminary evaluation of those records indicates that there would be an overpayment;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idba06508e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/5/B/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the nature of the problems identified in such evaluation; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idba06508f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/5/B/i/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> the steps that the provider of services or supplier should take to address the problems; and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idba065090-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/5/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> provide for a 45-day period during which the provider of services or supplier may furnish additional information concerning the medical records for the claims that had been reviewed.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba065091-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/5/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Consent settlement offer</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall review any additional information furnished by the provider of services or supplier under subparagraph (B)(ii). Taking into consideration such information, the Secretary shall determine if there still appears to be an overpayment. If so, the Secretary—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idba065092-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/5/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> shall provide notice of such determination to the provider of services or supplier, including an explanation of the reason for such determination; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idba065093-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/5/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> in order to resolve the overpayment, may offer the provider of services or supplier—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idba065094-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/5/C/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the opportunity for a statistically valid random sample; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idba065095-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/5/C/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> a consent settlement.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">The opportunity provided under clause (ii)(I) does not waive any appeal rights with respect to the alleged overpayment involved.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba065096-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/5/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Consent settlement defined</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of this paragraph, the term “consent settlement” means an agreement between the Secretary and a provider of services or supplier whereby both parties agree to settle a projected overpayment based on less than a statistically valid sample of claims and the provider of services or supplier agrees not to appeal the claims involved.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba065097-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice of over-utilization of codes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish, in consultation with organizations representing the classes of providers of services and suppliers, a process under which the Secretary provides for notice to classes of providers of services and suppliers served by the contractor in cases in which the contractor has identified that particular billing codes may be overutilized by that class of providers of services or suppliers under the programs under this subchapter (or provisions of subchapter XI insofar as they relate to such programs).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba065098-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment audits</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba065099-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/7/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Written notice for post-payment audits</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (C), if a medicare contractor decides to conduct a post-payment audit of a provider of services or supplier under this subchapter, the contractor shall provide the provider of services or supplier with written notice (which may be in electronic form) of the intent to conduct such an audit.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba06509a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/7/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Explanation of findings for all audits</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subject to subparagraph (C), if a medicare contractor audits a provider of services or supplier under this subchapter, the contractor shall—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idba06509b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/7/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> give the provider of services or supplier a full review and explanation of the findings of the audit in a manner that is understandable to the provider of services or supplier and permits the development of an appropriate corrective action plan;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idba06509c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/7/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> inform the provider of services or supplier of the appeal rights under this subchapter as well as consent settlement options (which are at the discretion of the Secretary);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idba06509d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/7/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> give the provider of services or supplier an opportunity to provide additional information to the contractor; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idba06509e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/7/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> take into account information provided, on a timely basis, by the provider of services or supplier under clause (iii).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba06509f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/7/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Exception</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Subparagraphs (A) and (B) shall not apply if the provision of notice or findings would compromise pending law enforcement activities, whether civil or criminal, or reveal findings of law enforcement-related audits.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650a0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Standard methodology for probe sampling</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish a standard methodology for medicare contractors to use in selecting a sample of claims for review in the case of an abnormal billing pattern.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650a1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Medicare-Medicaid Data Match Program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650a2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Expansion of Program</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650a3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/g/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall enter into contracts with eligible entities or otherwise for the purpose of ensuring that, beginning with 2006, the Medicare-Medicaid Data Match Program (commonly referred to as the “Medi-Medi Program”) is conducted with respect to the program established under this subchapter and State Medicaid programs under subchapter XIX for the purpose of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idba0650a4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/g/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> identifying program vulnerabilities in the program established under this subchapter and the Medicaid program established under subchapter XIX through the use of computer algorithms to review claims data to look for payment anomalies (including billing or billing patterns identified with respect to provider, service, time, or patient that appear to be suspect or otherwise implausible);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idba0650a5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/g/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> working with States, the Attorney General, and the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services to coordinate appropriate actions to investigate and recover amounts with respect to suspect claims to protect the Federal and State share of expenditures under the Medicaid program under subchapter XIX, as well as the program established under this subchapter;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idba0650a6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/g/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> increasing the effectiveness and efficiency of both such programs through cost avoidance, savings, and recoupments of fraudulent, wasteful, or abusive expenditures; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idba0650a7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/g/1/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><chapeau> furthering the Secretary’s design, development, installation, or enhancement of an automated data system architecture—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idba0650a8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/g/1/A/iv/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> to collect, integrate, and assess data for purposes of program integrity, program oversight, and administration, including the Medi-Medi Program; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idba0650a9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/g/1/A/iv/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> that improves the coordination of requests for data from States.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650aa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/g/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Reporting requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall make available in a timely manner any data and statistical information collected by the Medi-Medi Program to the Attorney General, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services, and the States (including a Medicaid fraud and abuse control unit described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396b/q">section 1396b(q) of this title</ref>). Such information shall be disseminated no less frequently than quarterly.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650ab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Limited waiver authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall waive only such requirements of this section and of subchapters XI and XIX as are necessary to carry out paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650ac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/g/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Incentives for States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall study and, as appropriate, may specify incentives for States to work with the Secretary for the purposes described in paragraph (1)(A)(ii). The application of the previous sentence may include use of the waiver authority described in paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650ad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of recovery audit contractors</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650ae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Under the Program, the Secretary shall enter into contracts with recovery audit contractors in accordance with this subsection for the purpose of identifying underpayments and overpayments and recouping overpayments under this subchapter with respect to all services for which payment is made under this subchapter. Under the contracts—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba0650af-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> payment shall be made to such a contractor only from amounts recovered;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba0650b0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> from such amounts recovered, payment—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idba0650b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> shall be made on a contingent basis for collecting overpayments; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idba0650b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> may be made in such amounts as the Secretary may specify for identifying underpayments; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba0650b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the Secretary shall retain a portion of the amounts recovered which shall be available to the program management account of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services for purposes of activities conducted under the recovery audit program under this subsection.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Disposition of remaining recoveries</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The amounts recovered under such contracts that are not paid to the contractor under paragraph (1) or retained by the Secretary under paragraph (1)(C) or paragraph (10) shall be applied to reduce expenditures under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Nationwide coverage</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall enter into contracts under paragraph (1) in a manner so as to provide for activities in all States under such a contract by not later than <date date="2010-01-01">January 1, 2010</date> (not later than <date date="2010-12-31">December 31, 2010</date>, in the case of contracts relating to payments made under part C or D).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Audit and recovery periods</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each such contract shall provide that audit and recovery activities may be conducted during a fiscal year with respect to payments made under this subchapter—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba0650b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> during such fiscal year; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba0650b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> retrospectively (for a period of not more than 4 fiscal years prior to such fiscal year).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall waive such provisions of this subchapter as may be necessary to provide for payment of recovery audit contractors under this subsection in accordance with paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Qualifications of contractors</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/6/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary may not enter into a contract under paragraph (1) with a recovery audit contractor unless the contractor has staff that has the appropriate clinical knowledge of, and experience with, the payment rules and regulations under this subchapter or the contractor has, or will contract with, another entity that has such knowledgeable and experienced staff.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/6/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Ineligibility of certain contractors</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary may not enter into a contract under paragraph (1) with a recovery audit contractor to the extent the contractor is a fiscal intermediary under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395h">section 1395h of this title</ref>, a carrier under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395u">section 1395u of this title</ref>, or a medicare administrative contractor under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395kk–1">section 1395kk–1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/6/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Preference for entities with demonstrated proficiency</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In awarding contracts to recovery audit contractors under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall give preference to those risk entities that the Secretary determines have demonstrated more than 3 years direct management experience and a proficiency for cost control or recovery audits with private insurers, health care providers, health plans, under the Medicaid program under subchapter XIX, or under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Construction relating to conduct of investigation of fraud</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A recovery of an overpayment to a individual or entity by a recovery audit contractor under this subsection shall not be construed to prohibit the Secretary or the Attorney General from investigating and prosecuting, if appropriate, allegations of fraud or abuse arising from such overpayment.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall annually submit to Congress a report on the use of recovery audit contractors under this subsection. Each such report shall include information on the performance of such contractors in identifying underpayments and overpayments and recouping overpayments, including an evaluation of the comparative performance of such contractors and savings to the program under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Special rules relating to parts C and D</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall enter into contracts under paragraph (1) to require recovery audit contractors to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba0650c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/9/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> ensure that each MA plan under part C has an anti-fraud plan in effect and to review the effectiveness of each such anti-fraud plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba0650c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/9/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> ensure that each prescription drug plan under part D has an anti-fraud plan in effect and to review the effectiveness of each such anti-fraud plan;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba0650c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/9/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> examine claims for reinsurance payments under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395w–115/b">section 1395w–115(b) of this title</ref> to determine whether prescription drug plans submitting such claims incurred costs in excess of the allowable reinsurance costs permitted under paragraph (2) of that section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba0650c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/9/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> review estimates submitted by prescription drug plans by private plans with respect to the enrollment of high cost beneficiaries (as defined by the Secretary) and to compare such estimates with the numbers of such beneficiaries actually enrolled by such plans.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/10"><num value="10" class="bold">(10)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of certain recovered funds</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/10/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">After application of paragraph (1)(C), the Secretary shall retain a portion of the amounts recovered by recovery audit contractors for each year under this section which shall be available to the program management account of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services for purposes of, subject to subparagraph (B), carrying out sections 1395<i>l</i>(z),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002970">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002970"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> 1395m(<i>l</i>)(16), and 1395kk–1(a)(4)(G) of this title, carrying out section 514(b) of the Medicare Access and CHIP Reauthorization Act of 2015, and implementing strategies (such as claims processing edits) to help reduce the error rate of payments under this subchapter. The amounts retained under the preceding sentence shall not exceed an amount equal to 15 percent of the amounts recovered under this subsection, and shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/10/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Except for uses that support claims processing (including edits) or system functionality for detecting fraud, amounts retained under subparagraph (A) may not be used for technological-related infrastructure, capital investments, or information systems.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h/10/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> No reduction in payments to recovery audit contractors</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Nothing in subparagraph (A) shall reduce amounts available for payments to recovery audit contractors under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Evaluations and annual report</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650ca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/i/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Evaluations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall conduct evaluations of eligible entities which the Secretary contracts with under the Program not less frequently than every 3 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/i/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 180 days after the end of each fiscal year (beginning with fiscal year 2011), the Secretary shall submit a report to Congress which identifies—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba0650cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/i/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the use of funds, including funds transferred from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395i">section 1395i of this title</ref> and the Federal Supplementary Insurance Trust Fund under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395t">section 1395t of this title</ref>, to carry out this section; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba0650cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/i/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the effectiveness of the use of such funds.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650ce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Expanding activities of Medicare drug integrity contractors (MEDICs)</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650cf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/j/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Access to information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Under contracts entered into under this section with Medicare drug integrity contractors (including any successor entity to a Medicare drug integrity contractor), the Secretary shall authorize such contractors to directly accept prescription and necessary medical records from entities such as pharmacies, prescription drug plans, MA–PD plans, and physicians with respect to an individual in order for such contractors to provide information relevant to the determination of whether such individual is an at-risk beneficiary for prescription drug abuse, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395w–104/c/5/C">section 1395w–104(c)(5)(C) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650d0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/j/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement for acknowledgment of referrals</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If a PDP sponsor or MA organization refers information to a contractor described in paragraph (1) in order for such contractor to assist in the determination described in such paragraph, the contractor shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba0650d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/j/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> acknowledge to the sponsor or organization receipt of the referral; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba0650d2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/j/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case that any PDP sponsor or MA organization contacts the contractor requesting to know the determination by the contractor of whether or not an individual has been determined to be an individual described in such paragraph, shall <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002971">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002971"><num>2</num> So in original. The word “shall” probably should not appear.</note> inform such sponsor or organization of such determination on a date that is not later than 15 days after the date on which the sponsor or organization contacts the contractor.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650d3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/j/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Making data available to other entities</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650d4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/j/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For purposes of carrying out this subsection, subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall authorize MEDICs to respond to requests for information from PDP sponsors and MA organizations, State prescription drug monitoring programs, and other entities delegated by such sponsors or organizations using available programs and systems in the effort to prevent fraud, waste, and abuse.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba0650d5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/j/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> HIPAA compliant information only</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Information may only be disclosed by a MEDIC under subparagraph (A) if the disclosure of such information is permitted under the Federal regulations (concerning the privacy of individually identifiable health information) promulgated under section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320d–2">42 U.S.C. 1320d–2</ref> note).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idba0650d6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, title XVIII, § 1893, as added <ref href="/us/pl/104/191/tII/s202/a">Pub. L. 104–191, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-21">Aug. 21, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1996">110 Stat. 1996</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/tVII/s736/c/7">Pub. L. 108–173, title VII, § 736(c)(7)</ref>, title IX, § 935(a), <date date="2003-12-08">Dec. 8, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2356">117 Stat. 2356</ref>, 2407; <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/tVI/s6034/d/1">Pub. L. 109–171, title VI, § 6034(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="2006-02-08">Feb. 8, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/77">120 Stat. 77</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/432/dB/tIII/s302/a">Pub. L. 109–432, div. B, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2991">120 Stat. 2991</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tVI">Pub. L. 111–148, title VI</ref>, §§ 6402(j)(1), 6411(b), <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/762">124 Stat. 762</ref>, 775; <ref href="/us/pl/114/10/tV">Pub. L. 114–10, title V</ref>, §§ 505(b), 510, <date date="2015-04-16">Apr. 16, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/167">129 Stat. 167</ref>, 170; <ref href="/us/pl/114/115/s9/b">Pub. L. 114–115, § 9(b)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-28">Dec. 28, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/3135">129 Stat. 3135</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/198/tVII/s704/c/1">Pub. L. 114–198, title VII, § 704(c)(1)</ref>, <date date="2016-07-22">July 22, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/749">130 Stat. 749</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idba0650d7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idba0650d8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idba0650d9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 202(b) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, referred to in subsec. (d)(2)(B), is <ref href="/us/pl/104/191/s202/b">section 202(b) of Pub. L. 104–191</ref>, which amended sections 1395h and 1395u of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 1395<i>l</i>(z) of this title, referred to in subsec. (h)(10)(A), probably means the subsec. (z) of section 1395<i>l</i> of this title which relates to medical review of spinal subluxation services, was added by <ref href="/us/pl/114/10/tV/s514/a">Pub. L. 114–10, title V, § 514(a)</ref>, <date date="2015-04-16">Apr. 16, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/171">129 Stat. 171</ref>, and was redesignated subsec. (aa) by <ref href="/us/pl/115/271/tVI/s6083/b/1">Pub. L. 115–271, title VI, § 6083(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3994">132 Stat. 3994</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 514(b) of the Medicare Access and CHIP Reauthorization Act of 2015, referred to in subsec. (h)(10)(A), is <ref href="/us/pl/114/10/s514/b">section 514(b) of Pub. L. 114–10</ref>, which is set out as a note under section 1395<i>l</i> of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, referred to in subsec. (j)(3)(B), is <ref href="/us/pl/104/191/s264/c">section 264(c) of Pub. L. 104–191</ref>, title II, <date date="1996-08-21">Aug. 21, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2033">110 Stat. 2033</ref>, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320d–2">section 1320d–2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idba0650da-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/114/198">Pub. L. 114–198</ref> added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (g)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/114/115/s9/b/1">Pub. L. 114–115, § 9(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “or otherwise” after “eligible entities” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/114/115/s9/b/2">Pub. L. 114–115, § 9(b)(2)</ref>, inserted “to review claims data” after “algorithms” and substituted “provider, service, time, or patient” for “service, time, or patient”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1)(A)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/114/115/s9/b/3/A">Pub. L. 114–115, § 9(b)(3)(A)</ref>, inserted “to investigate and recover amounts with respect to suspect claims” after “appropriate actions”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1)(A)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/114/115/s9/b/3/B">Pub. L. 114–115, § 9(b)(3)(B)</ref>–(5), added cl. (iv).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/114/10/s510">Pub. L. 114–10, § 510</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/114/10/s505/b/1">Pub. L. 114–10, § 505(b)(1)</ref>, inserted “or paragraph (10)” after “paragraph (1)(C)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/114/10/s505/b/2">Pub. L. 114–10, § 505(b)(2)</ref>, added par. (10).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s6402/j/1/C">Pub. L. 111–148, § 6402(j)(1)(C)</ref>, inserted “, or otherwise,” after “entities”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s6402/j/1/A">Pub. L. 111–148, § 6402(j)(1)(A)</ref>, added par. (4) and redesignated former par. (4) as (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s6411/b/1">Pub. L. 111–148, § 6411(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “this subchapter” for “part A or B” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s6411/b/2">Pub. L. 111–148, § 6411(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “this subchapter” for “parts A and B”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s6411/b/3">Pub. L. 111–148, § 6411(b)(3)</ref>, inserted “(not later than <date date="2010-12-31">December 31, 2010</date>, in the case of contracts relating to payments made under part C or D)” after “2010”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s6411/b/4">Pub. L. 111–148, § 6411(b)(4)</ref>, substituted “this subchapter” for “part A or B” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s6411/b/5">Pub. L. 111–148, § 6411(b)(5)</ref>, added par. (9).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s6402/j/1/B">Pub. L. 111–148, § 6402(j)(1)(B)</ref>, added subsec. (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—Subsec. (b)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/s6034/d/1/A">Pub. L. 109–171, § 6034(d)(1)(A)</ref>, added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/109/171/s6034/d/1/B">Pub. L. 109–171, § 6034(d)(1)(B)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/109/432">Pub. L. 109–432</ref> added subsec. (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/s736/c/7">Pub. L. 108–173, § 736(c)(7)</ref>, substituted “medicare program” for “Medicare program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/108/173/s935/a">Pub. L. 108–173, § 935(a)</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idba0650db-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idba0650dc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2016 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/114/198">Pub. L. 114–198</ref> applicable to prescription drug plans (and MA–PD plans) for plan years beginning on or after <date date="2019-01-01">Jan. 1, 2019</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/198/s704/g/1">section 704(g)(1) of Pub. L. 114–198</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395w–101">section 1395w–101 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idba0650dd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2003 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/173/tIX/s935/b">Pub. L. 108–173, title IX, § 935(b)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-08">Dec. 8, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2411">117 Stat. 2411</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/173/tIX/s935/b">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of repayment plans</inline>.—</heading><content>Section 1893(f)(1) of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/1">42 U.S.C. 1395ddd(f)(1)</ref>], as added by subsection (a), shall apply to requests for repayment plans made after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2003-12-08">Dec. 8, 2003</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on recoupment</inline>.—</heading><content>Section 1893(f)(2) of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/2">42 U.S.C. 1395ddd(f)(2)</ref>], as added by subsection (a), shall apply to actions taken after the date of the enactment of this Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of extrapolation</inline>.—</heading><content>Section 1893(f)(3) of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/3">42 U.S.C. 1395ddd(f)(3)</ref>], as added by subsection (a), shall apply to statistically valid random samples initiated after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Provision of supporting documentation</inline>.—</heading><content>Section 1893(f)(4) of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/4">42 U.S.C. 1395ddd(f)(4)</ref>], as added by subsection (a), shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Consent settlement</inline>.—</heading><content>Section 1893(f)(5) of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/5">42 U.S.C. 1395ddd(f)(5)</ref>], as added by subsection (a), shall apply to consent settlements entered into after the date of the enactment of this Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice of overutilization</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary [of Health and Human Services] shall first establish the process for notice of overutilization of billing codes under section 1893A(f)(6) [1893(f)(6)] of the Social Security Act [probably means <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/6">42 U.S.C. 1395ddd(f)(6)</ref>], as added by subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="7">“(7)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Payment audits</inline>.—</heading><content>Section 1893A(f)(7) [1893(f)(7)] of the Social Security Act [probably means <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/7">42 U.S.C. 1395ddd(f)(7)</ref>], as added by subsection (a), shall apply to audits initiated after the date of the enactment of this Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="8">“(8)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Standard for abnormal billing patterns</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall first establish a standard methodology for selection of sample claims for abnormal billing patterns under section 1893(f)(8) of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/f/8">42 U.S.C. 1395ddd(f)(8)</ref>], as added by subsection (a).”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba0650de-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Improving the Sharing of Data Between the Federal Government and State Medicaid Programs</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/115/s9">Pub. L. 114–115, § 9</ref>, <date date="2015-12-28">Dec. 28, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/3135">129 Stat. 3135</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/115/s9">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the ‘Secretary’) shall establish a plan to encourage and facilitate the participation of States in the Medicare-Medicaid Data Match Program (commonly referred to as the ‘Medi-Medi Program’) under section 1893(g) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/g">42 U.S.C. 1395ddd(g)</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Program Revisions To Improve Medi-Medi Data Match Program Participation by States</inline>.—</heading><note topic="miscellaneous" id="idba0650df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<p>[Amended this section.]</p></note>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Providing States With Data on Improper Payments Made for Items or Services Provided to Dual Eligible Individuals.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall develop and implement a plan that allows each State agency responsible for administering a State plan for medical assistance under title XIX of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</ref> et seq.] access to relevant data on improper or fraudulent payments made under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395">42 U.S.C. 1395</ref> et seq.) for health care items or services provided to dual eligible individuals.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Dual eligible individual defined</inline>.—</heading><content>In this section, the term ‘dual eligible individual’ means an individual who is entitled to, or enrolled for, benefits under part A of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395c">42 U.S.C. 1395c</ref> et seq.), or enrolled for benefits under part B of title XVIII of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395j">42 U.S.C. 1395j</ref> et seq.), and is eligible for medical assistance under a State plan under title XIX of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</ref> et seq.) or under a waiver of such plan.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba0899d0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Extension of Two-Midnight Rule</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/93/tI/s111">Pub. L. 113–93, title I, § 111</ref>, <date date="2014-04-01">Apr. 1, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1044">128 Stat. 1044</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/114/10/tV/s521">Pub. L. 114–10, title V, § 521</ref>, <date date="2015-04-16">Apr. 16, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/176">129 Stat. 176</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/10/tV/s521">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Continuation of Certain Medical Review Activities</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Health and Human Services may continue medical review activities described in the notice entitled ‘Selecting Hospital Claims for Patient Status Reviews: Admissions On or After <date date="2013-10-01">October 1, 2013</date>’, posted on the Internet website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, through through [sic] the end of fiscal year 2015 for such additional hospital claims as the Secretary determines appropriate.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall not conduct patient status reviews (as described in such notice) on a post-payment review basis through recovery audit contractors under section 1893(h) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h">42 U.S.C. 1395ddd(h)</ref>) for inpatient claims with dates of admission <date date="2013-10-01">October 1, 2013</date>, through <date date="2015-09-30">September 30, 2015</date>, unless there is evidence of systematic gaming, fraud, abuse, or delays in the provision of care by a provider of services (as defined in section 1861(u) of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395x/u">42 U.S.C. 1395x(u)</ref>)).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Construction</inline>.—</heading><content>Except as provided in subsections (a) and (b), nothing in this section shall be construed as limiting the Secretary’s authority to pursue fraud and abuse activities under such section 1893(h) or otherwise.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba0899d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Access to Coordination of Benefits Contractor Database</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/432/dB/tIII/s302/b">Pub. L. 109–432, div. B, title III, § 302(b)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-20">Dec. 20, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2992">120 Stat. 2992</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/432/dB/tIII/s302/b">“The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall provide for access by recovery audit contractors conducting audit and recovery activities under section 1893(h) of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ddd/h">42 U.S.C. 1395ddd(h)</ref>], as added by subsection (a), to the database of the Coordination of Benefits Contractor of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services with respect to the audit and recovery periods described in paragraph (4) of such section 1893(h).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
