<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idba123727-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396"><num value="1396">§ 1396.</num><heading> Medicaid and CHIP Payment and Access Commission</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idba123728-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is hereby established the Medicaid and CHIP Payment and Access Commission (in this section referred to as “MACPAC”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idba123729-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba12372a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Review of access policies for all States and annual reports</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">MACPAC shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba12372b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> review policies of the Medicaid program established under this subchapter (in this section referred to as “Medicaid”) and the State Children’s Health Insurance Program established under subchapter XXI (in this section referred to as “CHIP”) affecting access to covered items and services, including topics described in paragraph (2);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba12372c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> make recommendations to Congress, the Secretary, and States concerning such access policies;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba12372d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> by not later than March 15 of each year (beginning with 2010), submit a report to Congress containing the results of such reviews and MACPAC’s recommendations concerning such policies; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba12372e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> by not later than June 15 of each year (beginning with 2010), submit a report to Congress containing an examination of issues affecting Medicaid and CHIP, including the implications of changes in health care delivery in the United States and in the market for health care services on such programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba12372f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Specific topics to be reviewed</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Specifically, MACPAC shall review and assess the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba123730-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Medicaid and CHIP payment policies</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Payment policies under Medicaid and CHIP, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idba123731-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the factors affecting expenditures for the efficient provision of items and services in different sectors, including the process for updating payments to medical, dental, and health professionals, hospitals, residential and long-term care providers, providers of home and community based services, Federally-qualified health centers and rural health clinics, managed care entities, and providers of other covered items and services;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idba123732-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> payment methodologies; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idba123733-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the relationship of such factors and methodologies to access and quality of care for Medicaid and CHIP beneficiaries (including how such factors and methodologies enable such beneficiaries to obtain the services for which they are eligible, affect provider supply, and affect providers that serve a disproportionate share of low-income and other vulnerable populations).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba123734-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility policies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Medicaid and CHIP eligibility policies, including a determination of the degree to which Federal and State policies provide health care coverage to needy populations.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba123735-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Enrollment and retention processes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Medicaid and CHIP enrollment and retention processes, including a determination of the degree to which Federal and State policies encourage the enrollment of individuals who are eligible for such programs and screen out individuals who are ineligible, while minimizing the share of program expenses devoted to such processes.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba123736-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/2/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Coverage policies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Medicaid and CHIP benefit and coverage policies, including a determination of the degree to which Federal and State policies provide access to the services enrollees require to improve and maintain their health and functional status.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba123737-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/2/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Quality of care</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Medicaid and CHIP policies as they relate to the quality of care provided under those programs, including a determination of the degree to which Federal and State policies achieve their stated goals and interact with similar goals established by other purchasers of health care services.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba123738-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/2/F"><num value="F" class="bold">(F)</num><heading class="bold"> Interaction of Medicaid and CHIP payment policies with health care delivery generally</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The effect of Medicaid and CHIP payment policies on access to items and services for children and other Medicaid and CHIP populations other than under this subchapter or subchapter XXI and the implications of changes in health care delivery in the United States and in the general market for health care items and services on Medicaid and CHIP.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba123739-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/2/G"><num value="G" class="bold">(G)</num><heading class="bold"> Interactions with Medicare and Medicaid</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Consistent with paragraph (11), the interaction of policies under Medicaid and the Medicare program under subchapter XVIII, including with respect to how such interactions affect access to services, payments, and dual eligible individuals.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba12373a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/2/H"><num value="H" class="bold">(H)</num><heading class="bold"> Other access policies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The effect of other Medicaid and CHIP policies on access to covered items and services, including policies relating to transportation and language barriers and preventive, acute, and long-term services and supports.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba12373b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Recommendations and reports of State-specific data</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">MACPAC shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba12373c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> review national and State-specific Medicaid and CHIP data; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba12373d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> submit reports and recommendations to Congress, the Secretary, and States based on such reviews.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba12373e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Creation of early-warning system</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">MACPAC shall create an early-warning system to identify provider shortage areas, as well as other factors that adversely affect, or have the potential to adversely affect, access to care by, or the health care status of, Medicaid and CHIP beneficiaries. MACPAC shall include in the annual report required under paragraph (1)(D) a description of all such areas or problems identified with respect to the period addressed in the report.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba12373f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Comments on certain secretarial reports and regulations</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba123740-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain secretarial reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the Secretary submits to Congress (or a committee of Congress) a report that is required by law and that relates to access policies, including with respect to payment policies, under Medicaid or CHIP, the Secretary shall transmit a copy of the report to MACPAC. MACPAC shall review the report and, not later than 6 months after the date of submittal of the Secretary’s report to Congress, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress and the Secretary written comments on such report. Such comments may include such recommendations as MACPAC deems appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba123741-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">MACPAC shall review Medicaid and CHIP regulations and may comment through submission of a report to the appropriate committees of Congress and the Secretary, on any such regulations that affect access, quality, or efficiency of health care.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba123742-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Agenda and additional reviews</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba123743-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/6/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">MACPAC shall consult periodically with the chairmen and ranking minority members of the appropriate committees of Congress regarding MACPAC’s agenda and progress towards achieving the agenda. MACPAC may conduct additional reviews, and submit additional reports to the appropriate committees of Congress, from time to time on such topics relating to the program under this subchapter or subchapter XXI as may be requested by such chairmen and members and as MACPAC deems appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba123744-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/6/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Review and reports regarding Medicaid DSH</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba123745-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/6/B/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">MACPAC shall review and submit an annual report to Congress on disproportionate share hospital payments under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396r–4">section 1396r–4 of this title</ref>. Each report shall include the information specified in clause (ii).</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba123746-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/6/B/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Required report information</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Each report required under this subparagraph shall include the following:</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idba123747-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/6/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> Data relating to changes in the number of uninsured individuals.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idba123748-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/6/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> Data relating to the amount and sources of hospitals’ uncompensated care costs, including the amount of such costs that are the result of providing unreimbursed or under-reimbursed services, charity care, or bad debt.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idba123749-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/6/B/ii/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> Data identifying hospitals with high levels of uncompensated care that also provide access to essential community services for low-income, uninsured, and vulnerable populations, such as graduate medical education, and the continuum of primary through quarternary care, including the provision of trauma care and public health services.</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idba12374a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/6/B/ii/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> State-specific analyses regarding the relationship between the most recent State DSH allotment and the projected State DSH allotment for the succeeding year and the data reported under subclauses (I), (II), and (III) for the State.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba12374b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/6/B/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Data</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary regularly shall provide MACPAC with the most recent State reports and most recent independent certified audits submitted under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396r–4/j">section 1396r–4(j) of this title</ref>, cost reports submitted under subchapter XVIII, and such other data as MACPAC may request for purposes of conducting the reviews and preparing and submitting the annual reports required under this subparagraph.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idba12374c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/6/B/iv"><num value="iv" class="bold">(iv)</num><heading class="bold"> Submission deadlines</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The first report required under this subparagraph shall be submitted to Congress not later than <date date="2016-02-01">February 1, 2016</date>. Subsequent reports shall be submitted as part of, or with, each annual report required under paragraph (1)(C) during the period of fiscal years 2017 through 2024.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba12374d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability of reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">MACPAC shall transmit to the Secretary a copy of each report submitted under this subsection and shall make such reports available to the public.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba12374e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Appropriate committee of Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For purposes of this section, the term “appropriate committees of Congress” means the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba12374f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Voting and reporting requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">With respect to each recommendation contained in a report submitted under paragraph (1), each member of MACPAC shall vote on the recommendation, and MACPAC shall include, by member, the results of that vote in the report containing the recommendation.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba123750-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/10"><num value="10" class="bold">(10)</num><heading class="bold"> Examination of budget consequences</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Before making any recommendations, MACPAC shall examine the budget consequences of such recommendations, directly or through consultation with appropriate expert entities, and shall submit with any recommendations, a report on the Federal and State-specific budget consequences of the recommendations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba123751-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/11"><num value="11" class="bold">(11)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation and coordination with MEDPAC</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba123752-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/11/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">MACPAC shall consult with the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (in this paragraph referred to as “MedPAC”) established under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395b–6">section 1395b–6 of this title</ref> in carrying out its duties under this section, as appropriate and particularly with respect to the issues specified in paragraph (2) as they relate to those Medicaid beneficiaries who are dually eligible for Medicaid and the Medicare program under subchapter XVIII, adult Medicaid beneficiaries (who are not dually eligible for Medicare), and beneficiaries under Medicare. Responsibility for analysis of and recommendations to change Medicare policy regarding Medicare beneficiaries, including Medicare beneficiaries who are dually eligible for Medicare and Medicaid, shall rest with MedPAC.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba123753-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/11/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Information sharing</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">MACPAC and MedPAC shall have access to deliberations and records of the other such entity, respectively, upon the request of the other such entity.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba123754-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/12"><num value="12" class="bold">(12)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation with States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">MACPAC shall regularly consult with States in carrying out its duties under this section, including with respect to developing processes for carrying out such duties, and shall ensure that input from States is taken into account and represented in MACPAC’s recommendations and reports.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba123755-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/13"><num value="13" class="bold">(13)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordinate and consult with the Federal Coordinated Health Care Office</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">MACPAC shall coordinate and consult with the Federal Coordinated Health Care Office established under section 2081 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002976">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002976"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act before making any recommendations regarding dual eligible individuals.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba123756-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/b/14"><num value="14" class="bold">(14)</num><heading class="bold"> Programmatic oversight vested in the Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">MACPAC’s authority to make recommendations in accordance with this section shall not affect, or be considered to duplicate, the Secretary’s authority to carry out Federal responsibilities with respect to Medicaid and CHIP.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idba123757-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Membership</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba123758-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Number and appointment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">MACPAC shall be composed of 17 members appointed by the Comptroller General of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba123759-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Qualifications</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba12375a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/c/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The membership of MACPAC shall include individuals who have had direct experience as enrollees or parents or caregivers of enrollees in Medicaid or CHIP and individuals with national recognition for their expertise in Federal safety net health programs, health finance and economics, actuarial science, health plans and integrated delivery systems, reimbursement for health care, health information technology, and other providers of health services, public health, and other related fields, who provide a mix of different professions, broad geographic representation, and a balance between urban and rural representation.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba12375b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/c/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Inclusion</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The membership of MACPAC shall include (but not be limited to) physicians, dentists, and other health professionals, employers, third-party payers, and individuals with expertise in the delivery of health services. Such membership shall also include representatives of children, pregnant women, the elderly, individuals with disabilities, caregivers, and dual eligible individuals, current or former representatives of State agencies responsible for administering Medicaid, and current or former representatives of State agencies responsible for administering CHIP.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba12375c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/c/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Majority nonproviders</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Individuals who are directly involved in the provision, or management of the delivery, of items and services covered under Medicaid or CHIP shall not constitute a majority of the membership of MACPAC.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba12375d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/c/2/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Ethical disclosure</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Comptroller General of the United States shall establish a system for public disclosure by members of MACPAC of financial and other potential conflicts of interest relating to such members. Members of MACPAC shall be treated as employees of Congress for purposes of applying subchapter I of chapter 131 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba12375e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Terms</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba12375f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/c/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The terms of members of MACPAC shall be for 3 years except that the Comptroller General of the United States shall designate staggered terms for the members first appointed.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba123760-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/c/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Vacancies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term for which the member’s predecessor was appointed shall be appointed only for the remainder of that term. A member may serve after the expiration of that member’s term until a successor has taken office. A vacancy in MACPAC shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba123761-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">While serving on the business of MACPAC (including travel time), a member of MACPAC shall be entitled to compensation at the per diem equivalent of the rate provided for level IV of the Executive Schedule under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5315">section 5315 of title 5</ref>; and while so serving away from home and the member’s regular place of business, a member may be allowed travel expenses, as authorized by the Chairman of MACPAC. Physicians serving as personnel of MACPAC may be provided a physician comparability allowance by MACPAC in the same manner as Government physicians may be provided such an allowance by an agency under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5948">section 5948 of title 5</ref>, and for such purpose subsection (i) of such section shall apply to MACPAC in the same manner as it applies to the Tennessee Valley Authority. For purposes of pay (other than pay of members of MACPAC) and employment benefits, rights, and privileges, all personnel of MACPAC shall be treated as if they were employees of the United States Senate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba14a862-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/c/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Chairman; Vice Chairman</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Comptroller General of the United States shall designate a member of MACPAC, at the time of appointment of the member <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002977">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002977"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma.</note> as Chairman and a member as Vice Chairman for that term of appointment, except that in the case of vacancy of the Chairmanship or Vice Chairmanship, the Comptroller General of the United States may designate another member for the remainder of that member’s term.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba14a863-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/c/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">MACPAC shall meet at the call of the Chairman.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idba14a864-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Director and staff; experts and consultants</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to such review as the Comptroller General of the United States deems necessary to assure the efficient administration of MACPAC, MACPAC may—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba14a865-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> employ and fix the compensation of an Executive Director (subject to the approval of the Comptroller General of the United States) and such other personnel as may be necessary to carry out its duties (without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba14a866-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> seek such assistance and support as may be required in the performance of its duties from appropriate Federal and State departments and agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba14a867-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> enter into contracts or make other arrangements, as may be necessary for the conduct of the work of MACPAC (without regard to <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba14a868-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> make advance, progress, and other payments which relate to the work of MACPAC;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba14a869-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> provide transportation and subsistence for persons serving without compensation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idba14a86a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> prescribe such rules and regulations as it deems necessary with respect to the internal organization and operation of MACPAC.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idba14a86b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Powers</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba14a86c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Obtaining official data</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">MACPAC may secure directly from any department or agency of the United States and, as a condition for receiving payments under sections 1396b(a) and 1397ee(a) of this title, from any State agency responsible for administering Medicaid or CHIP, information necessary to enable it to carry out this section. Upon request of the Chairman, the head of that department or agency shall furnish that information to MACPAC on an agreed upon schedule.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba14a86d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Data collection</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In order to carry out its functions, MACPAC shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba14a86e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> utilize existing information, both published and unpublished, where possible, collected and assessed either by its own staff or under other arrangements made in accordance with this section;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba14a86f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> carry out, or award grants or contracts for, original research and experimentation, where existing information is inadequate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idba14a870-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> adopt procedures allowing any interested party to submit information for MACPAC’s use in making reports and recommendations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba14a871-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Access of GAO to information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Comptroller General of the United States shall have unrestricted access to all deliberations, records, and nonproprietary data of MACPAC, immediately upon request.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba14a872-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/e/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Periodic audit</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">MACPAC shall be subject to periodic audit by the Comptroller General of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idba14a873-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Funding</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba14a874-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Request for appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">MACPAC shall submit requests for appropriations (other than for fiscal year 2010) in the same manner as the Comptroller General of the United States submits requests for appropriations, but amounts appropriated for MACPAC shall be separate from amounts appropriated for the Comptroller General of the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba14a875-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba14a876-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Funding for fiscal year 2010</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba14a877-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/f/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, there is appropriated to MACPAC to carry out the provisions of this section for fiscal year 2010, $9,000,000.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idba14a878-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/f/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Notwithstanding <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1397dd/a/13">section 1397dd(a)(13) of this title</ref>, from the amounts appropriated in such section for fiscal year 2010, $2,000,000 is hereby transferred and made available in such fiscal year to MACPAC to carry out the provisions of this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idba14a879-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1396/f/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Amounts made available under paragraphs (2) and (3) to MACPAC to carry out the provisions of this section shall remain available until expended.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idba14a87a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, title XIX, § 1900, as added <ref href="/us/pl/111/3/tV/s506/a">Pub. L. 111–3, title V, § 506(a)</ref>, <date date="2009-02-04">Feb. 4, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/91">123 Stat. 91</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tII/s2801/a">Pub. L. 111–148, title II, § 2801(a)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/328">124 Stat. 328</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/93/tII/s221/b">Pub. L. 113–93, title II, § 221(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-04-01">Apr. 1, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1076">128 Stat. 1076</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/286/s4/c/43">Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(c)(43)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4359">136 Stat. 4359</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idba14a87b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idba14a87c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idba14a87d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 2081 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(13), probably means <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s2602">section 2602 of Pub. L. 111–148</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/315">124 Stat. 315</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1315b">section 1315b of this title</ref>. <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s2602">Section 2602 of Pub. L. 111–148</ref> established the Federal Coordinated Health Care Office, and <ref href="/us/pl/111/148">Pub. L. 111–148</ref> does not contain a section 2081.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idba14a87e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (d)(3), “<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>” substituted for “section 3709 of the Revised Statutes (<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s5">41 U.S.C. 5</ref>)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s6/c">Pub. L. 111–350, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3854">124 Stat. 3854</ref>, which Act enacted Title 41, Public Contracts.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idba14a87f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 1396, <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531/tXIX/s1901">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531, title XIX, § 1901</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/89/97/tI/s121/a">Pub. L. 89–97, title I, § 121(a)</ref>, <date date="1965-07-30">July 30, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/343">79 Stat. 343</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/93/233/s13/a/1">Pub. L. 93–233, § 13(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1973-12-31">Dec. 31, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/960">87 Stat. 960</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tVI/s2663/j/3/C">Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title VI, § 2663(j)(3)(C)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1171">98 Stat. 1171</ref>, which related to appropriations, was transferred to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396–1">section 1396–1 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idba14a880-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (c)(2)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/117/286">Pub. L. 117–286</ref> substituted “subchapter I of chapter 131 of title 5.” for “title I of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (<ref href="/us/pl/95/521">Public Law 95–521</ref>).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (b)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/113/93">Pub. L. 113–93</ref> designated existing provisions as subpar. (A), inserted heading, and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s2801/a/1/A/i">Pub. L. 111–148, § 2801(a)(1)(A)(i)</ref>, inserted “for all States” before “and annual” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s2801/a/1/A/ii">Pub. L. 111–148, § 2801(a)(1)(A)(ii)</ref>, struck out “children’s” before “access”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s2801/a/1/A/iii">Pub. L. 111–148, § 2801(a)(1)(A)(iii)</ref>, inserted “, the Secretary, and States” after “Congress”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s2801/a/1/A/iv">Pub. L. 111–148, § 2801(a)(1)(A)(iv)</ref>, substituted “March 15” for “March 1”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s2801/a/1/A/v">Pub. L. 111–148, § 2801(a)(1)(A)(v)</ref>, substituted “June 15” for “June 1”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s2801/a/1/B/i/I">Pub. L. 111–148, § 2801(a)(1)(B)(i)(I)</ref>, inserted “the efficient provision of” after “expenditures for” and substituted “payments to medical, dental, and health professionals, hospitals, residential and long-term care providers, providers of home and community based services, Federally-qualified health centers and rural health clinics, managed care entities, and providers of other covered items and services” for “hospital, skilled nursing facility, physician, Federally-qualified health center, rural health center, and other fees”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(A)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s2801/a/1/B/i/II">Pub. L. 111–148, § 2801(a)(1)(B)(i)(II)</ref>, inserted “(including how such factors and methodologies enable such beneficiaries to obtain the services for which they are eligible, affect provider supply, and affect providers that serve a disproportionate share of low-income and other vulnerable populations)” after “CHIP beneficiaries”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(B) to (H). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s2801/a/1/B/ii">Pub. L. 111–148, § 2801(a)(1)(B)(ii)</ref>–(v), added subpars. (B) to (E) and (G), redesignated former subpars. (B) and (C) as (F) and (H), respectively, and, in subpar. (H), inserted “and preventive, acute, and long-term services and supports” after “barriers”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s2801/a/1/D">Pub. L. 111–148, § 2801(a)(1)(D)</ref>, added par. (3). Former par. (3) redesignated (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s2801/a/1/C">Pub. L. 111–148, § 2801(a)(1)(C)</ref>, (E), redesignated par. (3) as (4) and substituted “, as well as other factors that adversely affect, or have the potential to adversely affect, access to care by, or the health care status of, Medicaid and CHIP beneficiaries. MACPAC shall include in the annual report required under paragraph (1)(D) a description of all such areas or problems identified with respect to the period addressed in the report.” for “or any other problems that threaten access to care or the health care status of Medicaid and CHIP beneficiaries.” Former par. (4) redesignated (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s2801/a/1/C">Pub. L. 111–148, § 2801(a)(1)(C)</ref>, (F), redesignated par. (4) as (5), inserted “and regulations” after “reports” in heading, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A) and inserted heading, inserted “and the Secretary” after “appropriate committees of Congress” in subpar. (A), and added subpar. (B). Former par. (5) redesignated (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(6) to (10). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s2801/a/1/C">Pub. L. 111–148, § 2801(a)(1)(C)</ref>, (G), redesignated pars. (5) to (9) as (6) to (10), respectively, and inserted “, and shall submit with any recommendations, a report on the Federal and State-specific budget consequences of the recommendations” in par. (10) before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(11) to (14). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s2801/a/1/H">Pub. L. 111–148, § 2801(a)(1)(H)</ref>, added pars. (11) to (14).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2)(A), (B). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s2801/a/2/A">Pub. L. 111–148, § 2801(a)(2)(A)</ref>, added subpars. (A) and (B) and struck out former subpars. (A) and (B) which related to MACPAC membership qualifications.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s2801/a/3">Pub. L. 111–148, § 2801(a)(3)</ref>, inserted “and State” after “Federal”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s2801/a/4">Pub. L. 111–148, § 2801(a)(4)</ref>, inserted “and, as a condition for receiving payments under sections 1396b(a) and 1397ee(a) of this title, from any State agency responsible for administering Medicaid or CHIP,” after “United States”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s2801/a/5">Pub. L. 111–148, § 2801(a)(5)</ref>, substituted “Funding” for “Authorization of appropriations” in heading, inserted “(other than for fiscal year 2010)” before “in the same manner” in par. (1), and added pars. (3) and (4).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idba14a881-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idba14a882-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/3/s3">Pub. L. 111–3, § 3</ref>, <date date="2009-02-04">Feb. 4, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/10">123 Stat. 10</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/3/s3">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">General Effective Date</inline>.—</heading><content>Unless otherwise provided in this Act [enacting this section and sections 247d–9, 1320b–9a, 1396e–1, 1396w–2, and 1397kk to 1397mm of this title and <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s657p">section 657p of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade, transferring former <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396">section 1396 of this title</ref> to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396–1">section 1396–1 of this title</ref>, amending sections 300gg, 1308, 1320b–9, 1320b–9a, 1396a, 1396b, 1396r–1, 1396r–4, 1396u–7, 1397bb to 1397ee, and 1397gg to 1397jj of this title, <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1514">section 1514 of Title 19</ref>, Customs Duties, sections 5701 to 5703, 5712, 5713, 5721 to 5723, 5741, 6103, and 9801 of Title 26, Internal Revenue Code, and sections 1022, 1132, and 1181 of Title 29, Labor, enacting provisions set out as notes under this section and sections 1305, 1396a, 1396b, 1396d, 1396u–7, 1396u–8, 1396w–2, 1397bb to 1397ee, 1397gg, and 1397hh of this title, <ref href="/us/usc/t19/s1514">section 1514 of Title 19</ref>, sections 5701 to 5703, 5711, 5712, 6103, and 6655 of Title 26, and <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1181">section 1181 of Title 29</ref>, amending provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1397gg">section 1397gg of this title</ref>, and repealing provisions set out as notes under sections 1397aa and 1397ee of this title], subject to subsections (b) through (d), this Act (and the amendments made by this Act) shall take effect on <date date="2009-04-01">April 1, 2009</date>, and shall apply to child health assistance and medical assistance provided on or after that date.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Exception for State Legislation</inline>.—</heading><content>In the case of a State plan under title XIX [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</ref> et seq.] or State child health plan under [title] XXI [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1397aa">42 U.S.C. 1397aa</ref> et seq.] of the Social Security Act, which the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation in order for the respective plan to meet one or more additional requirements imposed by amendments made by this Act, the respective plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such title solely on the basis of its failure to meet such an additional requirement before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2009-02-04">Feb. 4, 2009</date>]. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of the session shall be considered to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Coordination of CHIP Funding for Fiscal Year</inline> 2009.—</heading><chapeau>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, insofar as funds have been appropriated under section 2104(a)(11), 2104(k), or 2104(<i>l</i>) of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1397dd/a/11">42 U.S.C. 1397dd(a)(11)</ref>, (k), (<i>l</i>)], as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/110/173/s201">section 201 of Public Law 110–173</ref>, to provide allotments to States under CHIP for fiscal year 2009—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> any amounts that are so appropriated that are not so allotted and obligated before <date date="2009-04-01">April 1, 2009</date> are rescinded; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> any amount provided for CHIP allotments to a State under this Act (and the amendments made by this Act) for such fiscal year shall be reduced by the amount of such appropriations so allotted and obligated before such date.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reliance on Law</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>With respect to amendments made by this Act (other than title VII) [enacting this section and sections 1320b–9a, 1396e–1, 1396w–2, and 1397kk to 1397mm of this title, amending sections 300gg, 1308, 1320b–9, 1320b–9a, 1396a, 1396b, 1396r–1, 1396r–4, 1396u–7, 1397bb to 1397ee, and 1397gg to 1397jj of this title, <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s9801">section 9801 of Title 26</ref>, Internal Revenue Code, and sections 1022, 1132, and 1181 of Title 29, Labor, amending provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1397gg">section 1397gg of this title</ref>, and repealing provisions set out as notes under sections 1397aa and 1397ee of this title] that become effective as of a date—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> such amendments are effective as of such date whether or not regulations implementing such amendments have been issued; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Federal financial participation for medical assistance or child health assistance furnished under title XIX or XXI, respectively, of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</ref> et seq., 1397aa et seq.] on or after such date by a State in good faith reliance on such amendments before the date of promulgation of final regulations, if any, to carry out such amendments (or before the date of guidance, if any, regarding the implementation of such amendments) shall not be denied on the basis of the State’s failure to comply with such regulations or guidance.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba14a883-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Application of Federal Acquisition Regulation to Contracts for Goods and Services</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/119/75/dB/tIV">Pub. L. 119–75, div. B, title IV</ref>, <date date="2026-02-03">Feb. 3, 2026</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/140/311">140 Stat. 311</ref>, provided in part: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/119/75/dB/tIV">“That in fiscal year 2026 and thereafter, for all contracts for goods and services to which the Medicaid and CHIP Payment and Access Commission is a party, the following Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR) clauses will apply: FAR 52.232–39 and FAR 52.233–4 (or a successor clause).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba14a884-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Think Differently Database</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/225">Pub. L. 118–225</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2817">138 Stat. 2817</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/225">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="1">“SECTION 1.</num><heading> SHORT TITLE.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“This Act may be cited as the ‘Think Differently Database Act’.</p>
</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="2">“SEC. 2.</num><heading> PROMOTING AWARENESS OF AVAILABLE RESOURCES FOR INDIVIDUALS WITH DISABILITIES.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>], the Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the ‘Secretary’) shall establish and update periodically a publicly available website to provide information with respect to resources and information for people with a disability and the caregivers and families of such people. Such website shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> information on eligibility to receive medical assistance under a State plan under the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</ref> et seq.) (or a waiver of such plan) based on a disability, including general information about eligibility under subclauses (XIII), (XV), (XVI), and (XIX) of section 1902(a)(10)(A)(ii) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396a/a/10/A/ii">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(10)(A)(ii)</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> which States offer eligibility under subclauses (XIII), (XV), (XVI), and (XIX) of section 1902(a)(10)(A)(ii) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396a/a/10/A/ii">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(10)(A)(ii)</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> each State’s specific eligibility requirements, if applicable, under subclauses (XIII), (XV), (XVI), and (XIX) of section 1902(a)(10)(A)(ii) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396a/a/10/A/ii">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(10)(A)(ii)</ref>);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> information about how to contact each State’s Medicaid office for information about Medicaid, including links and phone numbers for State contacts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> general information on Medicaid-covered long-term services and supports that may be available to individuals eligible for medical assistance under a State plan under the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</ref> et seq.) (or a waiver of such plan); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> where applicable, the average amount of time that individuals newly enrolled in a State’s waiver program for home and community-based services in the past 12 months were on the list of individuals waiting to enroll in such waiver program, in such a manner and process as described in section 441.311(d)(1)(iii) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Promotion</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall, as applicable and appropriate, identify and disseminate promotional activities to improve, among people with a disability and the caretakers and families of such people, the awareness of the resources included in the website established under subsection (a), such as through collaboration with the Social Security Administration during its annual updates to the Red Book.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Model</inline>.—</heading><content>In establishing the website under this section, the Secretary may use the website thinkdifferently.net as a model.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Nonapplication of Paperwork Reduction Act</inline>.—</heading><content>Chapter 35 of title 44, United States Code (commonly referred to as the ‘Paperwork Reduction Act of 1995’), shall not apply to the implementation of this section.”</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba14a885-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Purpose</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/3/s2">Pub. L. 111–3, § 2</ref>, <date date="2009-02-04">Feb. 4, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/10">123 Stat. 10</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/3/s2">“It is the purpose of this Act [see Effective Date note above] to provide dependable and stable funding for children’s health insurance under titles XXI and XIX of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1397aa">42 U.S.C. 1397aa</ref> et seq., 1396 et seq.] in order to enroll all six million uninsured children who are eligible, but not enrolled, for coverage today through such titles.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba14a886-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Model of Interstate Coordinated Enrollment and Coverage Process</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/3/tII/s213">Pub. L. 111–3, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="2009-02-04">Feb. 4, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/56">123 Stat. 56</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/3/tII/s213">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>In order to assure continuity of coverage of low-income children under the Medicaid program and the State Children’s Health Insurance Program (CHIP), not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2009-02-04">Feb. 4, 2009</date>], the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with State Medicaid and CHIP directors and organizations representing program beneficiaries, shall develop a model process for the coordination of the enrollment, retention, and coverage under such programs of children who, because of migration of families, emergency evacuations, natural or other disasters, public health emergencies, educational needs, or otherwise, frequently change their State of residency or otherwise are temporarily located outside of the State of their residency.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress</inline>.—</heading><content>After development of such model process, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress a report describing additional steps or authority needed to make further improvements to coordinate the enrollment, retention, and coverage under CHIP and Medicaid of children described in subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba14a887-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Improved Accessibility of Dental Provider Information to Enrollees Under Medicaid and CHIP</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/3/tV/s501/f">Pub. L. 111–3, title V, § 501(f)</ref>, <date date="2009-02-04">Feb. 4, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/88">123 Stat. 88</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/3/tV/s501/f">
<inline>“The Secretary [of Health and Human Services] shall—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> work with States, pediatric dentists, and other dental providers (including providers that are, or are affiliated with, a school of dentistry) to include, not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2009-02-04">Feb. 4, 2009</date>], on the Insure Kids Now website (http://www.insurekidsnow.gov/) and hotline (1–877–KIDS–NOW) (or on any successor websites or hotlines) a current and accurate list of all such dentists and providers within each State that provide dental services to children enrolled in the State plan (or waiver) under Medicaid or the State child health plan (or waiver) under CHIP, and shall ensure that such list is updated at least quarterly; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> work with States to include, not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, a description of the dental services provided under each State plan (or waiver) under Medicaid and each State child health plan (or waiver) under CHIP on such Insure Kids Now website, and shall ensure that such list is updated at least annually.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba14a888-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Deadline for Initial Appointments</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/3/tV/s506/b">Pub. L. 111–3, title V, § 506(b)</ref>, <date date="2009-02-04">Feb. 4, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/95">123 Stat. 95</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/3/tV/s506/b">“Not later than <date date="2010-01-01">January 1, 2010</date>, the Comptroller General of the United States shall appoint the initial members of the Medicaid and CHIP Payment and Access Commission established under section 1900 of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</ref>] (as added by subsection (a)).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba14a889-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Annual Report</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/3/tV/s506/c">Pub. L. 111–3, title V, § 506(c)</ref>, <date date="2009-02-04">Feb. 4, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/95">123 Stat. 95</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/3/tV/s506/c">“Not later than <date date="2010-01-01">January 1, 2010</date>, and annually thereafter, the Secretary [of Health and Human Services], in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Labor, and the States (as defined for purposes of Medicaid), shall submit an annual report to Congress on the financial status of, enrollment in, and spending trends for, Medicaid for the fiscal year ending on September 30 of the preceding year.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idba14a88a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">No Federal Funding for Illegal Aliens; Disallowance for Unauthorized Expenditures</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/3/tVI/s605">Pub. L. 111–3, title VI, § 605</ref>, <date date="2009-02-04">Feb. 4, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/100">123 Stat. 100</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tII/s2102/a/2">Pub. L. 111–148, title II, § 2102(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/288">124 Stat. 288</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/148/tII/s2102/a/2">“Nothing in this Act [see Effective Date note above] allows Federal payment for individuals who are not lawfully residing in the United States. Titles XI, XIX, and XXI of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1301">42 U.S.C. 1301</ref> et seq., 1396 et seq., 1397aa et seq.] provide for the disallowance of Federal financial participation for erroneous expenditures under Medicaid and under CHIP, respectively.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="idba14a88b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/111/3/s1/c">Pub. L. 111–3, § 1(c)</ref>, <date date="2009-02-04">Feb. 4, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/8">123 Stat. 8</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/3/s1/c">
<inline>“In this Act [see Effective Date note above]:</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> CHIP.—</heading><content>The term ‘CHIP’ means the State Children’s Health Insurance Program established under title XXI of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1397aa">42 U.S.C. 1397aa</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Medicaid</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Medicaid’ means the program for medical assistance established under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Secretary’ means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
