<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbaa85d60-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1397e"><num value="1397e">§ 1397e.</num><heading> Administrative and fiscal accountability</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbaa85d61-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1397e/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Reporting requirements; form, contents, etc.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each State shall prepare reports on its activities carried out with funds made available (or transferred for use) under this division. Reports shall be prepared annually, covering the most recently completed fiscal year, and shall be in such form and contain such information (including but not limited to the information specified in subsection (c)) as the State finds necessary to provide an accurate description of such activities, to secure a complete record of the purposes for which funds were spent, and to determine the extent to which funds were spent in a manner consistent with the reports required by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1397c">section 1397c of this title</ref>. The State shall make copies of the reports required by this section available for public inspection within the State and shall transmit a copy to the Secretary. Copies shall also be provided, upon request, to any interested public agency, and each such agency may provide its views on these reports to the Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbaa85d62-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1397e/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Audits; implementation, etc.</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each State shall, not less often than every two years, audit its expenditures from amounts received (or transferred for use) under this division. Such State audits shall be conducted by an entity independent of any agency administering activities funded under this division, in accordance with generally accepted auditing principles. Within 30 days following the completion of each audit, the State shall submit a copy of that audit to the legislature of the State and to the Secretary. Each State shall repay to the United States amounts ultimately found not to have been expended in accordance with this division, or the Secretary may offset such amounts against any other amount to which the State is or may become entitled under this division.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbaa85d63-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1397e/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> State reports on expenditure and use of social services funds</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each report prepared and transmitted by a State under subsection (a) shall set forth (with respect to the fiscal year covered by the report)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbaa85d64-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1397e/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the number of individuals who received services paid for in whole or in part with funds made available under this division, showing separately the number of children and the number of adults who received such services, and broken down in each case to reflect the types of services and circumstances involved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbaa85d65-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1397e/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the amount spent in providing each such type of service, showing separately for each type of service the amount spent per child recipient and the amount spent per adult recipient;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbaa85d66-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1397e/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the criteria applied in determining eligibility for services (such as income eligibility guidelines, sliding fee scales, the effect of public assistance benefits, and any requirements for enrollment in school or training programs); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbaa85d67-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1397e/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the methods by which services were provided, showing separately the services provided by public agencies and those provided by private agencies, and broken down in each case to reflect the types of services and circumstances involved.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Secretary shall establish uniform definitions of services for use by the States in preparing the information required by this subsection, and make such other provision as may be necessary or appropriate to assure that compliance with the requirements of this subsection will not be unduly burdensome on the States.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbaa85d68-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1397e/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional accounting requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For other provisions requiring States to account for Federal grants, see <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s6503">section 6503 of title 31</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbaa85d69-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, title XX, § 2006, as added <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXIII/s2352/a">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXIII, § 2352(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/870">95 Stat. 870</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/dB/tVI/s2663/h/2">Pub. L. 98–369, div. B, title VI, § 2663(h)(2)</ref>, <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1169">98 Stat. 1169</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/485/tVI/s607">Pub. L. 100–485, title VI, § 607</ref>, <date date="1988-10-13">Oct. 13, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2410">102 Stat. 2410</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tVI/s6703/d/1/B">Pub. L. 111–148, title VI, § 6703(d)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/803">124 Stat. 803</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbaa85d6a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbaa85d6b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idbaa85d6c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 1397e, <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531/tXX/s2006">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531, title XX, § 2006</ref>, as added <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/93/647/s2">Pub. L. 93–647, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2347">88 Stat. 2347</ref>, related to program evaluation and assistance, prior to the general revision of this subchapter by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2352/a">section 2352(a) of Pub. L. 97–35</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 1397e–1, <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531/tXX/s2007">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531, title XX, § 2007</ref>, as added <date date="1980-01-02">Jan. 2, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/96/178/s4/b">Pub. L. 96–178, § 4(b)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1296">93 Stat. 1296</ref>, related to child day care services, prior to the general revision of this subchapter by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2352/a">section 2352(a) of Pub. L. 97–35</ref>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1397f">section 1397f of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbaa85d6d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—<ref href="/us/pl/111/148">Pub. L. 111–148</ref>, which directed substitution of “this division” for “this subchapter” wherever appearing in subtitle 1 of title XX of act <date date="1935-08-14">Aug. 14, 1935</date>, was executed by making the substitution wherever appearing in this section, which is in subtitle A of title XX act <date date="1935-08-14">Aug. 14, 1935</date>, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/485/s607/1">Pub. L. 100–485, § 607(1)</ref>, substituted “Reports shall be prepared annually, covering the most recently completed fiscal year, and shall be in such form and contain such information (including but not limited to the information specified in subsection (c))” for “Reports shall be in such form, contain such information, and be of such frequency (but not less often than every two years)” in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/100/485/s607/3">Pub. L. 100–485, § 607(3)</ref>, added subsec. (c) and redesignated former subsec. (c) as (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s6503">section 6503 of title 31</ref>” for “section 202 of the Intergovernmental Cooperation Act of 1968 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4212">42 U.S.C. 4212</ref>)”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbaa85d6e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbaa85d6f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/369">Pub. L. 98–369</ref> effective <date date="1984-07-18">July 18, 1984</date>, but not to be construed as changing or affecting any right, liability, status, or interpretation which existed (under the provisions of law involved) before that date, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/369/s2664/b">section 2664(b) of Pub. L. 98–369</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s401">section 401 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
