<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbac50c3c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1406a"><num value="1406a">§ 1406a.</num><heading> Expenses of management and operation of transferred projects as nonadministrative; payment</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">On and after <date date="1939-05-10">May 10, 1939</date> all necessary expenses in connection with the management and operation of projects transferred to the Authority by Executive Order Numbered 7732 of <date date="1937-10-27">October 27, 1937</date>, as modified by Executive Order Numbered 7839 of <date date="1938-03-12">March 12, 1938</date>, may be considered as nonadministrative expenses, notwithstanding the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s712a">section 712a of title 15</ref>, and be paid from the rents received from each transferred project.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbac50c3d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1939-05-10/ch119/s1">May 10, 1939, ch. 119, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/53/690">53 Stat. 690</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbac50c3e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbac50c3f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbac50c40-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was not enacted as part of the United States Housing Act of 1937 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idbac50c41-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in <ref href="/us/act/1938-06-25/ch681/tI">act June 25, 1938, ch. 681, title I</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/52/1129">52 Stat. 1129</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbac50c42-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries; Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbac50c43-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Authority, meaning the United States Housing Authority, was consolidated with other agencies into the Housing and Home Finance Agency, and name of Authority changed to Public Housing Administration by Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1947, eff. <date date="1947-07-27">July 27, 1947</date>, 12 F.R. 4981, <ref href="/us/stat/61/954">61 Stat. 954</ref>, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees. Functions of Public Housing Administration and Housing and Home Finance Agency (of which Public Housing Administration was a constituent agency) and of heads thereof transferred to Secretary of Housing and Urban Development by <ref href="/us/pl/89/174/s5/a">Pub. L. 89–174, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1965-09-09">Sept. 9, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/669">79 Stat. 669</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3534/a">section 3534(a) of this title</ref>. Section 9(c) of such act, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3531">section 3531 of this title</ref>, provided that references to Housing and Home Finance Agency or to any agency or officer therein are to be deemed to mean Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and that Housing and Home Finance Agency and Public Housing Administration have lapsed.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Executive Order No. 7732, <date date="1937-10-27">Oct. 27, 1937</date>, 2 F.R. 2324, 44 C.F.R. 201.11, effective <date date="1937-11-01">Nov. 1, 1937</date>, transferred to the United States Housing Authority all right, interest, and title held by the Federal Emergency Administration of Public Works in any housing or slum-clearance projects constructed or in the process of construction on <date date="1937-09-01">Sept. 1, 1937</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
