<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbad363d5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1437b"><num value="1437b">§ 1437b.</num><heading> Loans and commitments to make loans for low-income housing projects</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbad363d6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1437b/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of Secretary; interest rates; repayment date; use as security for obligations of public housing agency</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may make loans or commitments to make loans to public housing agencies to help finance or refinance the development, acquisition, or operation of low-income housing projects by such agencies. Any contract for such loans and any amendment to a contract for such loans shall provide that such loans shall bear interest at a rate specified by the Secretary which shall not be less than a rate determined by the Secretary of the Treasury taking into consideration the current average market yield on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States with remaining periods to maturity comparable to the average maturities of such loans, plus one-eighth of 1 per centum. Such loans shall be secured in such manner and shall be repaid within such period not exceeding forty years, or not exceeding forty years from the date of the bonds evidencing the loan, as the Secretary may determine. The Secretary may require loans or commitments to make loans under this section to be pledged as security for obligations issued by a public housing agency in connection with a low-income housing project.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbad363d7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1437b/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Issuance of obligations by Secretary; limitation on amounts; forms and denominations; terms and conditions; purchase, establishment of maturities and rates of interest, and sale by Secretary of the Treasury</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may issue and have outstanding at any one time notes and other obligations for purchase by the Secretary of the Treasury in an amount which will not, unless authorized by the President, exceed $1,500,000,000. For the purpose of determining obligations incurred to make loans pursuant to this chapter against any limitation otherwise applicable with respect to such loans, the Secretary shall estimate the maximum amount to be loaned at any one time pursuant to loan agreements then outstanding with public housing agencies. Such notes or other obligations shall be in such forms and denominations and shall be subject to such terms and conditions as may be prescribed by the Secretary with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury. The notes or other obligations issued under this subsection shall have such maturities and bear such rate or rates of interest as shall be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury. The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized and directed to purchase any notes or other obligations of the Secretary issued hereunder and for such purpose is authorized to use as a public debt transaction the proceeds from the sale of any securities issued under chapter 31 of title 31, and the purposes for which securities may be issued under such chapter are extended to include any purchases of such obligations. The Secretary of the Treasury may at any time sell any of the notes or other obligations acquired by him under this section. All redemptions, purchases, and sales by the Secretary of the Treasury of such notes or other obligations shall be treated as public debt transactions of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbad363d8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1437b/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Public and Indian housing financing reforms</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbad363d9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1437b/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> At such times as the Secretary may determine, and in accordance with such accounting and other procedures as the Secretary may prescribe, each loan made by the Secretary under subsection (a) that has any principal amount outstanding or any interest amount outstanding or accrued shall be forgiven; and the terms and conditions of any contract, or any amendment to a contract, for such loan with respect to any promise to repay such principal and interest shall be canceled. Such cancellation shall not affect any other terms and conditions of such contract, which shall remain in effect as if the cancellation had not occurred. This paragraph shall not apply to any loan the repayment of which was not to be made using annual contributions, or to any loan all or part of the proceeds of which are due a public housing agency from contractors or others.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbad363da-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1437b/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbad363db-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1437b/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> On <date date="1986-04-07">April 7, 1986</date>, each note or other obligation issued by the Secretary to the Secretary of the Treasury pursuant to subsection (b), together with any promise to repay the principal and unpaid interest that has accrued on each note or obligation, shall be forgiven; and any other term or condition specified by each such obligation shall be canceled.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbad363dc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1437b/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> On <date date="1986-09-30">September 30, 1986</date>, and on any subsequent September 30, each such note or other obligation issued by the Secretary to the Secretary of the Treasury pursuant to subsection (b) during the fiscal year ending on such date, together with any promise to repay the principal and unpaid interest that has accrued on each note or obligation, shall be forgiven; and any other term or condition specified by each such obligation shall be canceled.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbad363dd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1437b/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Any amount of budget authority (and contract authority) that becomes available during any fiscal year as a result of the forgiveness of any loan, note, or obligation under this subsection shall be rescinded.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbad363de-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1937-09-01/ch896">Sept. 1, 1937, ch. 896</ref>, title I, § 4, as added <ref href="/us/pl/93/383/tII/s201/a">Pub. L. 93–383, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-08-22">Aug. 22, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/656">88 Stat. 656</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tIII/s322/c">Pub. L. 97–35, title III, § 322(c)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/402">95 Stat. 402</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/479/tII/s203/b/1">Pub. L. 98–479, title II, § 203(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1984-10-17">Oct. 17, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2229">98 Stat. 2229</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/tIII/s3004">Pub. L. 99–272, title III, § 3004</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/102">100 Stat. 102</ref>; renumbered title I, <ref href="/us/pl/100/358/s5">Pub. L. 100–358, § 5</ref>, <date date="1988-06-29">June 29, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/681">102 Stat. 681</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/625/tV/s572/2">Pub. L. 101–625, title V, § 572(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4236">104 Stat. 4236</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbad363df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbad363e0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idbad363e1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 4 of <ref href="/us/act/1937-09-01/ch896">act Sept. 1, 1937, ch. 896</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/50/889">50 Stat. 889</ref>, as amended, provided for assistance of officers, etc., of other agencies and transfer of property to the Authority and was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1404">section 1404 of this title</ref>, prior to the general revision of this chapter by <ref href="/us/pl/93/383">Pub. L. 93–383</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbad363e2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/625">Pub. L. 101–625</ref> substituted “low-income housing” for “lower income housing” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/99/272">Pub. L. 99–272</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/479">Pub. L. 98–479</ref> substituted “chapter 31 of title 31” for “the Second Liberty Bond Act, as amended” and “such chapter” for “such Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> substituted reference to lower income for reference to low-income in two places.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbad363e3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbad363e4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> effective <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s371">section 371 of Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s3701">section 3701 of Title 12</ref>, Banks and Banking.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbad363e5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Carryover of Amounts of Budget Authority; Availability as Appropriation of Funds for Grants</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/500/s101/g/tI">Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(g) [H.R. 5313, title I]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1783-242">100 Stat. 1783–242</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/99/591/s101/g/tI">Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(g) [H.R. 5313, title I]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3341-242">100 Stat. 3341–242</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s106">Pub. L. 100–202, § 106</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1329-433">101 Stat. 1329–433</ref>, provided in part: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/202/s106">“That the budget authority obligated under contracts for annual contributions shall be increased above amounts heretofore provided in appropriations Acts by $7,805,668,000: <i>Provided further</i>, That any part of the amount of the increase in budget authority provided for in the immediately foregoing proviso that is available under this Act for public housing development and acquisition costs or which is to be used for amendments for such costs, shall be available as an appropriation of funds, to remain available until expended, for grants, which are hereby authorized in lieu of loans under section 4(a) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437b">42 U.S.C. 1437b</ref>), and which the Secretary may make on substantially the same terms (except for repayment unless repayment is a properly imposed sanction) as those heretofore set forth in annual contributions contracts for loans and annual contributions: <i>Provided further</i>, That during 1987 and thereafter, any amounts of budget authority which are carried over from a prior year, or which are otherwise available for obligation, and which are available for public housing development and acquisition costs, together with any amounts of budget authority which are to be used for amendments for such costs, in accordance with any Act, shall also be made available as an appropriation of funds for grants, under the same terms as those applying under the immediately preceding proviso”.</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
