<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbb13c943-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1452c"><num value="1452c">§ 1452c.</num><heading> Nullification of right of redemption of single family mortgagors under rehabilitation loan program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb13c944-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1452c/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever with respect to a single family mortgage securing a loan under section 1452b <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003156">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003156"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development or its foreclosure agent forecloses in any Federal or State court or pursuant to a power of sale in a mortgage, the purchaser at the foreclosure sale shall be entitled to receive a conveyance of title to, and possession of, the property, subject to any interests senior to the interests of the Secretary. With respect to properties that are vacant and abandoned, notwithstanding any State law to the contrary, there shall be no right of redemption (including all instances any right to possession based upon any right of redemption) in the mortgagor or any other person subsequent to the foreclosure sale in connection with such single family mortgage. The appropriate State official or the trustee, as the case may be, shall execute and deliver a deed or other appropriate instrument conveying title to the purchaser at the foreclosure sale, consistent with applicable procedures in the jurisdiction and without regard to any such right of redemption.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb13c945-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1452c/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Foreclosure by others</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever with respect to a single family mortgage on a property that also has a single family mortgage securing a loan under section 1452b <sup>1</sup> of this title, a mortgagee forecloses in any Federal or State court or pursuant to a power of sale in a mortgage, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, if the Secretary is purchaser at the foreclosure sale, shall be entitled to receive a conveyance of title to, and possession of, the property, subject to the interests senior to the interests of the mortgagee. Notwithstanding any State law to the contrary, there shall be no right of redemption (including in all instances any right to possession based upon any right of redemption) if the mortgagor or any other person subsequent to the foreclosure sale to the Secretary in connection with a property that secured a single family mortgage for a loan under section 1452b <sup>1</sup> of this title. The appropriate State official or the trustee, as the case may be, shall execute and deliver a deed or other appropriate instrument conveying title to the Secretary, who is the purchaser at the foreclosure sale, consistent with applicable procedures in the jurisdiction and without regard to any such right of redemption.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb13c946-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1452c/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Verification of title</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The following actions shall be taken in order to verify title in the purchaser at the foreclosure sale:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb13c947-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1452c/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In the case of a judicial foreclosure in any Federal or State court, there shall be included in the petition and in the judgment of foreclosure a statement that the foreclosure is in accordance with this subsection and that there is no right of redemption in the mortgagor or any other person.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb13c948-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1452c/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> In the case of a foreclosure pursuant to a power of sale provision in the mortgage, the statement required in paragraph (1) shall be included in the advertisement of the sale and either in the recitals of the deed or other appropriate instrument conveying title to the purchaser at the foreclosure sale or in an affidavit or addendum to the deed.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb13c949-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1452c/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb13c94a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1452c/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The term “mortgage” means a deed of trust, mortgage, deed to secure debt, security agreement, or any other form of instrument under which any interest in property, real, personal, or mixed, or any interest in property, including leaseholds, life estates, reversionary interests, and any other estates under applicable State law, is conveyed in trust, mortgaged, encumbered, pledged, or otherwise rendered subject to a lien, for the purpose of securing the payment of money or the performance of an obligation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb13c94b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1452c/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The term “single family mortgage” means a mortgage that covers property that includes a 1- to 4-family residence.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbb13c94c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/101/235/tVII/s701">Pub. L. 101–235, title VII, § 701</ref>, <date date="1989-12-15">Dec. 15, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/2055">103 Stat. 2055</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbb13c94d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbb13c94e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbb13c94f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1452b">Section 1452b of this title</ref>, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/101/625/tII/s289/b/1">Pub. L. 101–625, title II, § 289(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-28">Nov. 28, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/4128">104 Stat. 4128</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbb13c950-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Department of Housing and Urban Development Reform Act of 1989, and not as part of the Housing Act of 1949 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
