<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbfd6331e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s14931"><num value="14931">§ 14931.</num><heading> Adoptions of children immigrating to the United States</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfd6331f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s14931/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Legal effect of certificates issued by the Secretary of State</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbfd63320-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s14931/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Issuance of certificates by the Secretary of State</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary of State shall, with respect to each Convention adoption, issue a certificate to the adoptive citizen parent domiciled in the United States that the adoption has been granted or, in the case of a prospective adoptive citizen parent, that legal custody of the child has been granted to the citizen parent for purposes of emigration and adoption, pursuant to the Convention and this chapter, if the Secretary of State—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbfd63321-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s14931/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> receives appropriate notification from the central authority of such child’s country of origin; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbfd63322-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s14931/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> has verified that the requirements of the Convention and this chapter have been met with respect to the adoption.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbfd63323-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s14931/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Legal effect of certificates</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If appended to an original adoption decree, the certificate described in paragraph (1) shall be treated by Federal and State agencies, courts, and other public and private persons and entities as conclusive evidence of the facts certified therein and shall constitute the certification required by <ref href="/us/usc/t8/s1154/d/2">section 1154(d)(2) of title 8</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfd63324-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s14931/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Legal effect of Convention adoption finalized in another Convention country</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A final adoption in another Convention country, certified by the Secretary of State pursuant to subsection (a) of this section or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s14932/c">section 14932(c) of this title</ref>, shall be recognized as a final valid adoption for purposes of all Federal, State, and local laws of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfd63325-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s14931/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Condition on finalization of Convention adoption by State court</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the case of a child who has entered the United States from another Convention country for the purpose of adoption, an order declaring the adoption final shall not be entered unless the Secretary of State has issued the certificate provided for in subsection (a) with respect to the adoption.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbfd63326-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/106/279/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 106–279, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="2000-10-06">Oct. 6, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/837">114 Stat. 837</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbfd63327-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbfd63328-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbfd63329-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/106/279">Pub. L. 106–279</ref>, <date date="2000-10-06">Oct. 6, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/825">114 Stat. 825</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s14901">section 14901 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbfd6332a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idbfd6332b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective upon entry into force for the United States of the Convention on Protection of Children and Co-operation in Respect of Intercountry Adoption, pursuant to Article 46(2)(a) of the Convention, with transition rule, see section 505(a)(2), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/106/279">Pub. L. 106–279</ref>, set out as an Effective Dates; Transition Rule note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s14901">section 14901 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
