<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbb305135-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1503"><num value="1503">§ 1503.</num><heading> Development of projects by Secretary; financial assistance to public housing agencies</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In any localities where the President determines that there is an acute shortage of housing which impedes the national defense program and that the necessary housing would not otherwise be provided when needed for persons engaged in national defense activities, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may undertake the development and administration of projects to assure the availability of dwellings in such localities for such persons and their families, or the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may extend financial assistance of public housing agencies for the development and administration of such projects. Such financial assistance to public housing agencies shall be extended (except as otherwise provided herein and not inconsistent herewith) under the provisions of, and in the same manner and forms as provided in, title I <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003175">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003175"><num>1</num> So in original. Reference should probably be to entire “United States Housing Act of 1937” because such Act is not divided into titles. See section 1437 et seq. of this title.</note> of the United States Housing Act of 1937, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437">42 U.S.C. 1437</ref> et seq.], with respect to other housing projects.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbb305136-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1940-06-28/ch440">June 28, 1940, ch. 440</ref>, title II, § 203, <ref href="/us/stat/54/683">54 Stat. 683</ref>; 1947 Reorg. Plan No. 3, § 4(a), eff. <date date="1947-07-27">July 27, 1947</date>, 12 F.R. 4981, <ref href="/us/stat/61/955">61 Stat. 955</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/174/s5/a">Pub. L. 89–174, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1965-09-09">Sept. 9, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/669">79 Stat. 669</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbb305137-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbb305138-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbb305139-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The United States Housing Act of 1937, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1937-09-01/ch896">act Sept. 1, 1937, ch. 896</ref>, as revised generally by <ref href="/us/pl/93/383/tII/s201/a">Pub. L. 93–383, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-08-22">Aug. 22, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/653">88 Stat. 653</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 8 (§ 1437 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437">section 1437 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbb30513a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbb30513b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions to Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1501">section 1501 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
