<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbb30513c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1504"><num value="1504">§ 1504.</num><heading> Rental rates; exemption from limitations of United States Housing Act of 1937</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any contract made for financial assistance under the United States Housing Act of 1937, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437">42 U.S.C. 1437</ref> et seq.], may be revised so as to provide that the project involved will be assisted for any of the purposes of this subchapter. The Department of the Navy or Army or the Air Force or the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, in the administration of any project developed for the purposes of this subchapter, shall fix rentals for persons engaged in national defense activities and their families which will be within their financial reach, and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, in any contract for financial assistance or any lease of such a project, shall require the fixing of such rentals. Projects developed by the Department of the Navy or Army or Air Force, or developed or assisted by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, for the purposes of this subchapter shall not be subject to the elimination requirements of sections 10(a) and 11(a) of said Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1410/a">42 U.S.C. 1410(a)</ref>, 1411(a)], or to any provisions of section 9 of said Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1409">42 U.S.C. 1409</ref>] which would require any part of the development cost thereof to be met in any manner other than from funds loaned or furnished by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development. Funds expended for the purposes of this subchapter shall be excluded in determining, for the purposes of section 21(d) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003176">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003176"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of said Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1421/d">42 U.S.C. 1421(d)</ref>], the amounts expended within each State. Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter or as may be inconsistent with this subchapter, all the provisions of title I <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003177">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003177"><num>2</num> So in original. Reference should probably be to entire “United States Housing Act of 1937” because such Act is not divided into titles. See section 1437 et seq. of this title.</note> of the United States Housing Act of 1937 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437">42 U.S.C. 1437</ref> et seq.] shall apply to this subchapter. During the period when the President determines that in any locality there is an acute need for housing to assure the availability of dwellings for persons engaged in national defense activities, dwellings in a project developed or assisted in said locality which are devoted to the purposes of providing housing for persons engaged in national defense activities shall not be subject to sections 2(1) and 2(2) of the United States Housing Act of 1937, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1402/1">42 U.S.C. 1402(1)</ref>, (2)], and during such period such projects shall be deemed projects of a low-rent character for the purposes of any of the applicable provisions in title I <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003177">2</ref> of the United States Housing Act of 1937.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbb30513d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1940-06-28/ch440">June 28, 1940, ch. 440</ref>, title II, § 204, <ref href="/us/stat/54/683">54 Stat. 683</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343">July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, §§ 205(a), 207(a), (f), <ref href="/us/stat/61/501-503">61 Stat. 501–503</ref>; 1947 Reorg. Plan No. 3, § 4(a), eff. <date date="1947-07-27">July 27, 1947</date>, 12 F.R. 4981, <ref href="/us/stat/61/955">61 Stat. 955</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/174/s5/a">Pub. L. 89–174, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1965-09-09">Sept. 9, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/669">79 Stat. 669</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbb30513e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbb30513f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbb305140-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The United States Housing Act of 1937, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1937-09-01/ch896">act Sept. 1, 1937, ch. 896</ref>, as revised generally by <ref href="/us/pl/93/383/tII/s201/a">Pub. L. 93–383, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-08-22">Aug. 22, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/653">88 Stat. 653</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 8 (§ 1437 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1437">section 1437 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 2, 9, 10(a), and 11(a) of the United States Housing Act of 1937, referred to in text, is a reference to sections of the Act prior to the general revision of the Act by <ref href="/us/pl/93/383">Pub. L. 93–383</ref>. The Act as so revised is classified to section 1437 et seq. of this title. Provisions of former sections 2, 9, and 10(a) are covered by sections 3, 4, and 5(a) of the Act which are classified to sections 1437a, 1437b, and 1437c(a) of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 21(d) of said Act, referred to in text, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/87/70/tII/s204/c">Pub. L. 87–70, title II, § 204(c)</ref>, <date date="1961-06-30">June 30, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/164">75 Stat. 164</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbb305141-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idbb305142-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Department of the Air Force inserted to conform to <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343/tII/s207/a">act July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II, § 207(a)</ref>, (f), <ref href="/us/stat/61/502">61 Stat. 502</ref>, 503, and Secretary of Defense Transfer Orders No. 14, eff. <date date="1948-07-01">July 1, 1948</date>, and No. 40 [App. B(124)], <date date="1949-07-22">July 22, 1949</date>. Department of War designated Department of the Army and title of Secretary of War changed to Secretary of the Army by <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343/tII/s205/a">act July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II, § 205(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/501">61 Stat. 501</ref>. Sections 205(a) and 207(a), (f) of act <date date="1947-07-26">July 26, 1947</date>, were repealed by <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041/s53">act Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, § 53</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/641">70A Stat. 641</ref>. <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041/s1">Act Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/1">70A Stat. 1</ref>, enacted “Title 10, Armed Forces”, which in sections 3010 to 3013 and 8010 to 8013 continued Departments of Army and Air Force under administrative supervision of Secretary of the Army and Secretary of the Air Force, respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbb305143-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions to Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1501">section 1501 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
