<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbfdd5f07-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s15062"><num value="15062">§ 15062.</num><heading> Grant awards</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfdd5f08-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s15062/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Existing Centers</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbfdd5f09-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s15062/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In awarding and distributing grant funds under section 15061(a)of this title for a fiscal year, the Secretary, subject to the availability of appropriations and the condition specified in subsection (d), shall award and distribute grant funds in equal amounts of $500,000 (adjusted in accordance with subsection (b)), to each Center that existed during the preceding fiscal year and that meets the requirements of this part, prior to making grants under subsection (c) or (d).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbfdd5f0a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s15062/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Reduction of award</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Notwithstanding paragraph (1), if the aggregate of the funds to be awarded to the Centers pursuant to paragraph (1) for any fiscal year exceeds the total amount appropriated under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s15066">section 15066 of this title</ref> for such fiscal year, the amount to be awarded to each Center for such fiscal year shall be proportionately reduced.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfdd5f0b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s15062/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Adjustments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to the availability of appropriations, for any fiscal year following a year in which each Center described in subsection (a) received a grant award of not less than $500,000 under subsection (a) (adjusted in accordance with this subsection), the Secretary shall adjust the awards to take into account the most recent percentage change in the Consumer Price Index published by the Secretary of Labor under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s720/c/1">section 720(c)(1) of title 29</ref> (if the percentage change indicates an increase), prior to making grants under subsection (c) or (d).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfdd5f0c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s15062/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> National training initiatives on critical and emerging needs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Subject to the availability of appropriations, for any fiscal year in which each Center described in subsection (a) receives a grant award of not less than $500,000, under subsection (a) (adjusted in accordance with subsection (b)), after making the grant awards, the Secretary shall make grants under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s15061/b">section 15061(b) of this title</ref> to Centers to pay for the Federal share of the cost of training initiatives related to the unmet needs of individuals with developmental disabilities and their families, as described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s15063/b">section 15063(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbfdd5f0d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s15062/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional grants</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For any fiscal year in which each Center described in subsection (a) receives a grant award of not less than $500,000 under subsection (a) (adjusted in accordance with subsection (b)), after making the grant awards, the Secretary may make grants under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s15061/a">section 15061(a) of this title</ref> for activities described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s15063/a">section 15063(a) of this title</ref> to additional Centers, or additional grants to Centers, for States or populations that are unserved or underserved by Centers due to such factors as—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfdd5f0e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s15062/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> population;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfdd5f0f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s15062/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a high concentration of rural or urban areas; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbfdd5f10-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s15062/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a high concentration of unserved or underserved populations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbfdd5f11-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/106/402/tI/s152">Pub. L. 106–402, title I, § 152</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1719">114 Stat. 1719</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
