<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbb305162-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1522"><num value="1522">§ 1522.</num><heading> Definitions; actions to recover developed property</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in subchapters II to VII of this chapter, (a) the term “persons engaged in national-defense activities” shall include (1) enlisted men in the naval or military services of the United States; (2) employees of the United States in the Departments of the Navy, Army, and Air Force assigned to duty at naval or military reservations, posts, or bases; (3) workers engaged or to be engaged in industries connected with and essential to the national defense; (4) officers of the Army, Air Force, and Marine Corps not above the grade of captain, and officers of the Navy and Coast Guard, not above the grade of lieutenant, senior grade, assigned to duty at naval or military reservations, posts, or bases, or to duty at defense industries: <i>Provided</i>, That any proceedings for the recovery of possession of any property or project developed or constructed under this subchapter shall be brought by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development in the courts of the States having jurisdiction of such causes and the laws of the States shall be applicable thereto; (b) the term “Federal agency” means any executive department or office (including the President), independent establishment, commission, board, bureau, division, or office in the executive branch of the United States Government, or other agency of the United States, including corporations in which the United States owns all or a majority of the stock, directly or indirectly.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbb305163-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1940-10-14/ch862">Oct. 14, 1940, ch. 862</ref>, title I, § 2, <ref href="/us/stat/54/1126">54 Stat. 1126</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1942-01-21/ch14/s2">Jan. 21, 1942, ch. 14, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/56/11">56 Stat. 11</ref>; Ex. Ord. No. 9070, § 1, eff. <date date="1942-02-24">Feb. 24, 1942</date>, 7 F.R. 1529; <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343">July 26, 1947, ch. 343</ref>, title II, §§ 205(a), 207(a), (f), <ref href="/us/stat/61/501-503">61 Stat. 501–503</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1950-04-20/ch94">Apr. 20, 1950, ch. 94</ref>, title II, § 204, <ref href="/us/stat/64/73">64 Stat. 73</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/174/s5/a">Pub. L. 89–174, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1965-09-09">Sept. 9, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/669">79 Stat. 669</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbb305164-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbb305165-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbb305166-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subchapter III of this chapter, referred to in text, was comprised of sections 1531 to 1536 of this title. Section 1532 was omitted from the Code pursuant to the time limitation set out in <ref href="/us/act/1952-07-03/ch570/s1/a/12">act July 3, 1952, ch. 570, § 1(a)(12)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/66/332">66 Stat. 332</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/act/1953-03-31/ch13/s1">act Mar. 31, 1953, ch. 13, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/18">67 Stat. 18</ref>. Sections 1531, 1533, and 1534 were omitted from the Code upon the termination of section 1532. Section 1535 was omitted from the Code as executed. Section 1536 was omitted from the Code as not having been repeated in subsequent appropriation acts.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subchapter VI of this chapter, referred to in text, was comprised of sections 1571 to 1576 of this title. Sections 1571 and 1573 have been omitted from the Code pursuant to the time limitation set out in <ref href="/us/act/1952-07-03/ch570/s1/a/12">act July 3, 1952, ch. 570, § 1(a)(12)</ref>, (21), <ref href="/us/stat/66/332">66 Stat. 332</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/act/1953-03-31/ch13/s1">act Mar. 31, 1953, ch. 13, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/18">67 Stat. 18</ref>. Sections 1572 and 1575 were omitted upon the termination of sections 1571 and 1573. Section 1574 was repealed by <ref href="/us/act/1951-10-31/ch654/s1/113">act Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 654, § 1(113)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/65/706">65 Stat. 706</ref>. Section 1576 was omitted from the Code as not having been repeated in subsequent appropriation acts.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbb305167-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1950—Act <date date="1950-04-20">Apr. 20, 1950</date>, substituted “Housing and Home Finance Administrator” for “National Housing Administrator”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1942—Act <date date="1942-01-21">Jan. 21, 1942</date>, inserted cl. (a)(4) and proviso.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbb305168-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idbb305169-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Department of the Air Force inserted on authority of <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343/tII/s207/a">act July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II, § 207(a)</ref>, (f), <ref href="/us/stat/61/502">61 Stat. 502</ref>, 503. Department of War designated Department of the Army and title of Secretary of War changed to Secretary of the Army by <ref href="/us/act/1947-07-26/ch343/tII/s205/a">act July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II, § 205(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/61/501">61 Stat. 501</ref>. Sections 205(a) and 207(a), (f) of act <date date="1947-07-26">July 26, 1947</date>, were repealed by <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041/s53">act Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, § 53</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/641">70A Stat. 641</ref>. <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-10/ch1041/s1">Act Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70A/1">70A Stat. 1</ref>, enacted “Title 10, Armed Forces”, which in sections 3010 to 3013 and 8010 to 8013 continued Departments of the Army and Air Force under administrative supervision of Secretary of the Army and Secretary of the Air Force, respectively.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbb30516a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of Housing and Home Finance Agency transferred to Secretary of Housing and Urban Development by <ref href="/us/pl/89/174/s5/a">Pub. L. 89–174, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1965-09-09">Sept. 9, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/669">79 Stat. 669</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3534/a">section 3534(a) of this title</ref>. Section 9(c) of such act, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3531">section 3531 of this title</ref>, provided that references to Housing and Home Finance Agency or to any agency or officer therein are to be deemed to mean Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and that Housing and Home Finance Agency has lapsed.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbb30516b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbb30516c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of Federal Works Administrator relating to defense housing consolidated with other agencies into National Housing Agency during World War II by Ex. Ord. No. 9070.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
