<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbb350c28-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1584"><num value="1584">§ 1584.</num><heading> Removal of all dwelling structures on land under Secretary’s control; temporary housing exempted; preference in fulfilling vacancies</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With respect to temporary housing remaining under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development on land under his control, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall (1) permit vacancies, occurring or continuing after <date date="1953-07-01">July 1, 1953</date>, to be filled only by transfer of tenants of other accommodations in the same locality being removed as required by subchapters II to VII of this chapter; (2) notify, on or before <date date="1954-03-31">March 31, 1954</date>, all tenants to vacate the premises prior to <date date="1954-07-01">July 1, 1954</date>; (3) promptly after <date date="1954-07-01">July 1, 1954</date>, cause actions to be instituted to evict any tenants still remaining; and (4) remove (by demolition or otherwise) all dwelling structures as soon as practicable after they become vacant: <i>Provided</i>, That in any case where a request for relinquishment or transfer has been filed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1581">section 1581 of this title</ref> and where under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1581/c">section 1581(c) of this title</ref> the date for compliance with all conditions to the relinquishment or transfer shall have been extended, each of the foregoing dates shall be extended for a period of time equal to the period of the extension under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1581/c">section 1581(c) of this title</ref>: <i>And provided further</i>, That nothing heretofore in this section shall apply (1) to any temporary housing in any municipality in which the total number of persons, who on <date date="1948-12-31">December 31, 1948</date>, were living in temporary family accommodations provided by the United States or any agency thereof since <date date="1939-09-08">September 8, 1939</date>, exceeds 30 per centum of the total population of such municipality as shown by the 1940 census, nor (2) to any temporary housing as to which the local governing body has adopted a resolution as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1582/c">section 1582(c) of this title</ref>, nor (3) to any temporary housing for which a request has been submitted in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1581/b">section 1581(b) of this title</ref>, but which has not been relinquished or transferred solely because the applicant has been unable to obtain from the landowner the right to possession of the land on reasonable terms as determined by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development: <i>Provided</i>, That, in filling vacancies in such housing, the preferences set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1581/d/1">section 1581(d)(1) of this title</ref> shall be applicable and that families within such preference classes shall be eligible for admission to such housing, nor (4) to any temporary housing in which accommodations have been reserved, prior to the enactment of this section, for veterans attending an educational institution if (i) such institution certifies that the accommodations are urgently needed for such veterans and submits facts showing, to the satisfaction of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, that all reasonable efforts have been made by the institution to find other accommodations for them and (ii) such institution agrees to reimburse the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development for any financial loss to the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development in the operation of the accommodations after <date date="1951-06-30">June 30, 1951</date>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbb350c29-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1940-10-14/ch862">Oct. 14, 1940, ch. 862</ref>, title VI, § 604, as added <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-28/ch688/s7">June 28, 1948, ch. 688, § 7</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/act/1950-04-20/ch94">Apr. 20, 1950, ch. 94</ref>, title II, § 201, <ref href="/us/stat/64/59">64 Stat. 59</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/act/1951-06-30/ch197">June 30, 1951, ch. 197</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/65/110">65 Stat. 110</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1951-09-01/ch378">Sept. 1, 1951, ch. 378</ref>, title VI, § 603(a), <ref href="/us/stat/65/314">65 Stat. 314</ref>; Ex. Ord. No. 10284, §§ 3–5, eff. <date date="1951-09-04">Sept. 4, 1951</date>, 16 F.R. 8971; Ex. Ord. No. 10339, eff. <date date="1952-04-07">Apr. 7, 1952</date>, 17 F.R. 3012; <ref href="/us/pl/89/174/s5/a">Pub. L. 89–174, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1965-09-09">Sept. 9, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/669">79 Stat. 669</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbb350c2a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbb350c2b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbb350c2c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subchapters III and VI of this chapter, referred to in text, were comprised of sections 1531 to 1536 and 1571 to 1576, respectively, of this title and have been omitted from the Code. For further details, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1522">section 1522 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbb350c2d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1951—Act <date date="1951-09-01">Sept. 1, 1951</date>, repealed former fourth and fifth provisos which related to adjustments in rentals that might be set for Government-owned temporary housing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act <date date="1951-06-30">June 30, 1951</date>, substituted “<date date="1951-08-15">August 15, 1951</date>” for “<date date="1951-07-01">July 1, 1951</date>”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbb350c2e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbb350c2f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions to Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1581">section 1581 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbb350c30-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idbb350c31-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 10284</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 10284, <date date="1951-09-04">Sept. 4, 1951</date>, extended time for filling vacancies from <date date="1951-08-15">Aug. 15, 1951</date>, to <date date="1952-07-01">July 1, 1952</date>, for notices to vacate premises from <date date="1952-03-31">Mar. 31, 1952</date>, to <date date="1953-03-31">Mar. 31, 1953</date>, for time of vacating from <date date="1952-07-01">July 1, 1952</date>, to <date date="1953-07-01">July 1, 1953</date>, and for eviction from <date date="1952-07-01">July 1, 1952</date>, to <date date="1953-07-01">July 1, 1953</date>. See note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1589a">section 1589a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idbb350c32-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 10339</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 10339, <date date="1952-04-07">Apr. 7, 1952</date>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1589a">section 1589a of this title</ref>, extended time for filling vacancies from <date date="1952-07-01">July 1, 1952</date>, to <date date="1953-07-01">July 1, 1953</date>, for notices to vacate premises from <date date="1953-03-31">Mar. 31, 1953</date>, to <date date="1954-03-31">Mar. 31, 1954</date>, for time of vacating from <date date="1953-07-01">July 1, 1953</date>, to <date date="1954-07-01">July 1, 1954</date>, and for eviction from <date date="1953-07-01">July 1, 1953</date>, to <date date="1954-07-01">July 1, 1954</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
