<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbb39eed0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1591c"><num value="1591c">§ 1591c.</num><heading> Expiration date; exception</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After <date date="1953-06-30">June 30, 1953</date>, no construction of permanent housing may be begun under subchapter IX of this chapter. After <date date="1954-07-31">July 31, 1954</date>, (a) no mortgage may be insured under title IX of the National Housing Act, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1750">12 U.S.C. 1750</ref> et seq.] (except (i) pursuant to a commitment to insure issued on or before such date or (ii) after <date date="1954-07-31">July 31, 1954</date>, and until <date date="1955-08-01">August 1, 1955</date>, during such period, or for such project or projects, as the President may designate hereunder or (iii) pursuant to a commitment to insure issued pursuant to the preceding clause (ii)), (b) no agreement may be made to extend assistance for the provision of community facilities or services under subchapter IX of this chapter, and no construction of temporary housing or community facilities by the United States may be begun under such subchapter, except after <date date="1954-07-31">July 31, 1954</date>, and until <date date="1955-08-01">August 1, 1955</date>, during such period, or for such project or projects, as the President may designate hereunder: <i>Provided</i>, That to the extent necessary to assure the adequate completion of any facilities for which prior agreements have been made under subchapter IX, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may, at any time after <date date="1954-07-31">July 31, 1954</date>, enter into amendatory agreements under such subchapter involving the expenditure of additional Federal funds within the balance available therefor on or before such date, (c) no loan may be made or obligations purchased by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701g–1">section 1701g–1 of title 12</ref> (except pursuant to a commitment issued on or before <date date="1953-06-30">June 30, 1953</date>, or to refinance an existing loan or existing obligations held under such section by said Secretary on <date date="1953-06-30">June 30, 1953</date>).</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbb39eed1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1951-09-01/ch378">Sept. 1, 1951, ch. 378</ref>, title I, § 104, <ref href="/us/stat/65/295">65 Stat. 295</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1953-06-30/ch170/s16">June 30, 1953, ch. 170, § 16</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/125">67 Stat. 125</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1954-06-29/ch410/s3">June 29, 1954, ch. 410, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/320">68 Stat. 320</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-02/ch649">Aug. 2, 1954, ch. 649</ref>, title I, § 129, <ref href="/us/stat/68/609">68 Stat. 609</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1955-06-30/ch251/s2">June 30, 1955, ch. 251, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/69/225">69 Stat. 225</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1955-08-11/ch783">Aug. 11, 1955, ch. 783</ref>, title I, § 105, <ref href="/us/stat/69/637">69 Stat. 637</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/174/s5/a">Pub. L. 89–174, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1965-09-09">Sept. 9, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/669">79 Stat. 669</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbb39eed2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbb39eed3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbb39eed4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Housing Act, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-27/ch847">act June 27, 1934, ch. 847</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/1246">48 Stat. 1246</ref>. Title IX of the National Housing Act is title IX of <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-27/ch847">act June 27, 1934, ch. 847</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/act/1951-09-01/ch378/tII/s201">act Sept. 1, 1951, ch. 378, title II, § 201</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/65/295">65 Stat. 295</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter X (§ 1750 et seq.) of chapter 13 of Title 12, Banks and Banking. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701">section 1701 of Title 12</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1701g–1">Section 1701g–1 of title 12</ref>, referred to in text, has been omitted from the Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbb39eed5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1955—Act <date date="1955-08-11">Aug. 11, 1955</date>, inserted item (iii) in cl. (a).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act <date date="1955-06-30">June 30, 1955</date>, substituted “<date date="1955-08-01">August 1, 1955</date>” for “<date date="1955-07-01">July 1, 1955</date>” in two places in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1954—Act <date date="1954-08-02">Aug. 2, 1954</date>, gave President standby authority to use mortgage insurance authority under title IX of the National Housing Act and the provisions in subchapter IX of this chapter for Federal aid in providing defense housing and community facilities and services in critical defense areas, in substitution for provisions under which authority for new projects under these two programs would have expired on <date date="1954-06-30">June 30, 1954</date>, and authorized the Housing and Home Finance Administrator to enter into amendatory agreements after <date date="1954-06-30">June 30, 1954</date>, to provide additional Federal assistance with respect to defense community facilities undertaken on or before such date where he finds it necessary to do so to assure the adequate completion of such facilities.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act <date date="1954-06-29">June 29, 1954</date>, substituted “<date date="1954-07-31">July 31, 1954</date>” for “<date date="1954-06-30">June 30, 1954</date>” at beginning of second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1953—Act <date date="1953-06-30">June 30, 1953</date>, inserted sentence prohibiting the beginning of permanent housing construction under subchapter IX of this chapter, after <date date="1953-06-30">June 30, 1953</date>; substituted “<date date="1954-06-30">June 30, 1954</date>” for “<date date="1953-06-30">June 30, 1953</date>” at beginning of present second sentence and “temporary housing” for “housing” in cl. (b) of present second sentence; struck a former cl. (c) out of existing second sentence which provided that (after <date date="1953-06-30">June 30, 1953</date>) no land might be acquired by the Housing and Home Finance Administrator under subchapter X of this chapter; and redesignated cl. (d) as (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbb39eed6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbb39eed7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions to Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1581">section 1581 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
