<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbb39eec8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1591b"><num value="1591b">§ 1591b.</num><heading> Community facilities or services by local agencies</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In order to assure that community facilities or services required in connection with national defense activities shall, wherever possible, be provided by the appropriate local agencies with local funds, in any area which the President, pursuant to the authority contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1591">section 1591 of this title</ref>, has declared to be a critical defense housing area—</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbb39eec9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1591b/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Certification of necessity for loan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">no loan shall be made pursuant to subchapter IX of this chapter for the provision of community facilities or equipment therefor required in connection with national defense activities in such area unless the chief executive officer of the appropriate political subdivision certifies, and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development finds, that such facilities or equipment could not otherwise be provided when needed;</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbb39eeca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1591b/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Certification of necessity for grants or other payments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">no grant or other payment shall be made pursuant to subchapter IX of this chapter for the provision, or for the operation and maintenance, of community facilities or equipment therefor, or for the provision of community services, required in connection with national defense activities in such area unless the chief executive officer of the appropriate political subdivision certifies, and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development finds, that such community facilities or services cannot otherwise be provided when needed, or operated and maintained, as the case may be, without the imposition of an increased excessive tax burden or an unusual or excessive increase in the debt limit of the appropriate local agency; and</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbb39eecb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1591b/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Maintenance and operation of facilities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">no community facilities or services shall be provided, and no community facilities shall be maintained and operated, by the United States directly except where the appropriate local agency is demonstrably unable to provide such facilities and services, or to maintain or operate such community facilities and services adequately with its own personnel, with loans, grants, or payments authorized to be made pursuant to subchapter IX of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this section, the term “chief executive officer of the appropriate political subdivision” shall mean appropriate principal executive officer or governing body having primary responsibility with respect to the community facility or service involved, but shall not, in any case, mean any public housing authority, or its governing body, or any of its officers, acting in such capacity.</continuation>
<sourceCredit id="idbb39eecc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1951-09-01/ch378">Sept. 1, 1951, ch. 378</ref>, title I, § 103, <ref href="/us/stat/65/294">65 Stat. 294</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/174/s5/a">Pub. L. 89–174, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1965-09-09">Sept. 9, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/669">79 Stat. 669</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbb39eecd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbb39eece-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbb39eecf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions to Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1581">section 1581 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
