<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbb3c3839-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1592n"><num value="1592n">§ 1592n.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this subchapter, the following terms shall have the meanings respectively ascribed to them below, and, unless the context clearly indicates otherwise, shall include the plural as well as the singular number:</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb3c383a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1592n/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> “State” shall mean the several States, the District of Columbia, and Territories, and possessions of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb3c383b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1592n/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> “Federal agency” shall mean any executive department or officer (including the President), independent establishment, commission, board, bureau, division, or office in the executive branch of the United States Government, or other agency of the United States, including corporations in which the United States owns all or a majority of the stock, directly or indirectly.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb3c383c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1592n/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> “Community facility” shall mean waterworks, sewers, sewage, garbage and refuse disposal facilities, police and fire protection facilities, public sanitary facilities, works for treatment and purification of water, libraries, hospitals and other places for the care of the sick, recreational facilities, streets and roads, and day-care centers.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb3c383d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1592n/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> “Community service” shall mean the maintenance and operation of facilities for health, refuse disposal, sewage treatment, recreation, water purification, and day-care centers, and the provision of fire-protection.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb3c383e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1592n/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> “National defense” shall mean (1) the operations and activities of the armed forces, the Atomic Energy Commission, or any other Government department or agency directly or indirectly and substantially concerned with the national defense, (2) other operations and activities directly or indirectly and substantially concerned with the operations and activities of the armed forces and the Atomic Energy Commission, (3) activities in connection with the Mutual Defense Assistance Act of 1949, as amended, or (4) the provision of community facilities or services necessary to the health, safety, or public welfare of the inhabitants of a town or community which has been relocated as a result of the acquisition (through eminent domain or purchase in lieu thereof) of its former site by or on behalf of the Atomic Energy Commission for national-defense activities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb3c383f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1592n/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> “Nonprofit agency” shall mean any agency no part of the net earnings of which inures to the benefit of any private stockholder or individual.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb3c3840-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1592n/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> “Project” shall mean housing or community facilities acquired, developed, or constructed with financial assistance pursuant to this subchapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb3c3841-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1592n/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content> “Veteran” shall mean a person, or the family of a person, who has served in the active military or naval service of the United States at any time (i) on or after <date date="1940-09-16">September 16, 1940</date>, and prior to <date date="1947-07-26">July 26, 1947</date>, (ii) on or after <date date="1917-04-06">April 6, 1917</date>, and prior to <date date="1918-11-11">November 11, 1918</date>, or (iii) on or after <date date="1950-06-27">June 27, 1950</date>, and prior to such date thereafter as shall be determined by the President, and who shall have been discharged or released therefrom under conditions other than dishonorable or who shall be still serving therein. The term shall also include the family of a person who served in the active military or naval service of the United States within any such period and who shall have died of causes determined by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to have been service-connected.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbb3c3842-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1951-09-01/ch378">Sept. 1, 1951, ch. 378</ref>, title III, § 315, <ref href="/us/stat/65/309">65 Stat. 309</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1953-06-30/ch170/s18">June 30, 1953, ch. 170, § 18</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/67/126">67 Stat. 126</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/54/s13/q/7/B">Pub. L. 102–54, § 13(q)(7)(B)</ref>, <date date="1991-06-13">June 13, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/281">105 Stat. 281</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbb3c3843-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbb3c3844-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbb3c3845-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Mutual Defense Assistance Act of 1949, referred to in subsec. (e), is <ref href="/us/act/1949-10-06/ch626">act Oct. 6, 1949, ch. 626</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/714">63 Stat. 714</ref>, which was classified generally to chapter 20 (§ 1571 et seq.) of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse, prior to its repeal by <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-26/ch937/tV/s542/a/5">act Aug. 26, 1954, ch. 937, title V, § 542(a)(5)</ref>, (9) to (11), <ref href="/us/stat/68/861">68 Stat. 861</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbb3c3846-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1991—Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/102/54">Pub. L. 102–54</ref> substituted “Secretary of Veterans Affairs” for “Veterans’ Administration”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1953—Subsec. (e)(4). Act <date date="1953-06-30">June 30, 1953</date>, added cl. (4).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbb3c3847-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbb3c3848-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Atomic Energy Commission abolished and functions transferred by sections 5814 and 5841 of this title. See, also, Transfer of Functions notes set out under those sections.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
