<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbb3c385b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1593e"><num value="1593e">§ 1593e.</num><heading> Housing of persons displaced by acquisition of property for defense installations or industries</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon a finding by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development that the acquisition of any real property for a defense installation or industry has resulted, or will result, in the displacement of persons from their homes on such property, he may (notwithstanding any other provision of this or any other law) issue regulations pursuant to which such persons may be permitted to occupy or purchase housing for which credit restrictions established pursuant to the Defense Production Act of 1950 [<ref href="/us/usc/t50/s4501">50 U.S.C. 4501</ref> et seq.] have been relaxed or housing which has been provided or assisted under the provisions of this Act (including amendments to other Acts provided herein), subject to any conditions or requirements that he determines necessary for purposes of national defense.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbb3c385c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1951-09-01/ch378">Sept. 1, 1951, ch. 378</ref>, title VI, § 611, <ref href="/us/stat/65/316">65 Stat. 316</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/174/s5/a">Pub. L. 89–174, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1965-09-09">Sept. 9, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/669">79 Stat. 669</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbb3c385d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbb3c385e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbb3c385f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Defense Production Act of 1950, referred to in text, is <ref href="/us/act/1950-09-08/ch932">act Sept. 8, 1950, ch. 932</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/798">64 Stat. 798</ref>, which is classified to chapter 55 (§ 4501 et seq.) of Title 50, War and National Defense. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act and herein, referred to in text, mean <ref href="/us/act/1951-09-01/ch378">act Sept. 1, 1951, ch. 378</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/65/293">65 Stat. 293</ref>, known as the Defense Housing and Community Facilities and Services Act of 1951. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1951 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1501">section 1501 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbb3c3860-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbb3c3861-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of functions to Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1581">section 1581 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
