<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc00d2137-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317"><num value="16317">§ 16317.</num><heading> Systems biology program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d2138-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d2139-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish a research, development, and demonstration program in microbial and plant systems biology, protein science, computational biology, and environmental science to support the energy, national security, and environmental missions of the Department.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d213a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Grants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The program shall support individual researchers and multidisciplinary teams of researchers through competitive, merit-reviewed grants.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d213b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall consult with other Federal agencies that conduct genetic and protein research.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d213c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Goals</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The program shall have the goal of developing technologies and methods based on the biological functions of genomes, microbes, and plants that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc00d213d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> can facilitate the production of fuels, including hydrogen in sustainable production systems that reduce greenhouse gas emissions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc00d213e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> convert carbon dioxide to organic carbon;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc00d213f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> detoxify soils and water, including at facilities of the Department, contaminated with heavy metals and radiological materials;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc00d2140-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> develop cellulosic and other feedstocks that are less resource and land intensive and that promote sustainable use of resources, including soil, water, energy, forests, and land, and ensure protection of air, water, and soil quality; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc00d2141-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> address other Department missions as identified by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d2142-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Plan</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d2143-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Development of plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date>, the Secretary shall prepare and transmit to Congress a research plan describing how the program authorized pursuant to this section will be undertaken to accomplish the program goals established in subsection (b).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d2144-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Review of plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall contract with the National Academy of Sciences to review the research plan developed under this subsection. The Secretary shall transmit the review to Congress not later than 18 months after transmittal of the research plan under paragraph (1), along with the Secretary’s response to the recommendations contained in the review.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d2145-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> User facilities and ancillary equipment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Within the funds authorized to be appropriated pursuant to this part, amounts shall be available for projects to develop, plan, construct, acquire, or operate special equipment, instrumentation, or facilities, including user facilities at National Laboratories, for researchers conducting research, development, demonstration, and commercial application in systems biology and proteomics and associated biological disciplines.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d2146-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition on biomedical and human cell and human subject research</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d2147-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> No biomedical research</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In carrying out the program under this section, the Secretary shall not conduct biomedical research.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d2148-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Nothing in this section shall authorize the Secretary to conduct any research or demonstrations—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc00d2149-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> on human cells or human subjects; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc00d214a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> designed to have direct application with respect to human cells or human subjects.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d214b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Bioenergy research centers</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d214c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In carrying out the program under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s18644/a">section 18644(a) of this title</ref>, the Director shall support up to 6 bioenergy research centers to conduct fundamental research in plant and microbial systems biology, biological imaging and analysis, and genomics, and to accelerate advanced research and development of advanced biofuels, bioenergy or biobased materials, chemicals, and products that are produced from a variety of regionally diverse feedstocks, and to facilitate the translation of research results to industry. The activities of the centers authorized under this subsection may include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc00d214d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> accelerating the domestication of bioenergy-relevant plants, microbes, and associated microbial communities to enable high-impact, value-added coproduct development at multiple points in the bioenergy supply chain;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc00d214e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> developing the science and technological advances to ensure process sustainability is considered in the creation of advanced biofuels and bioproducts from lignocellulosic biomass; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc00d214f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> using the latest tools in genomics, molecular biology, catalysis science, chemical engineering, systems biology, and computational and robotics technologies to sustainably produce and transform biomass into advanced biofuels and bioproducts.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d2150-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Selection and duration</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d2151-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A center established under paragraph (1) shall be selected on a competitive, merit-reviewed basis for a period of not more than 5 years, subject to the availability of appropriations, beginning on the date of establishment of that center.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d2152-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Applications</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Director shall consider applications from National Laboratories, multi-institutional collaborations, and other appropriate entities.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d2153-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Existing centers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A center already in existence on <date date="2022-08-09">August 9, 2022</date>, may continue to receive support for a period of not more than 5 years beginning on the date of establishment of that center.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d2154-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/2/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> New centers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Director shall select any new center pursuant to paragraph (1) on a competitive, merit-reviewed basis, with special consideration for applications from an institution of higher education (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">section 1001 of title 20</ref>) that is located in an eligible jurisdiction (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s13503/b/3/A">section 13503(b)(3)(A) of this title</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d2155-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Renewal</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">After the end of the applicable period described in paragraph (2), the Director may renew support for a center for a period of not more than 5 years on a merit-reviewed basis. For a center in operation for 10 years after its previous selection on a competitive, merit-reviewed basis, the Director may renew support for the center on a competitive, merit-reviewed basis for a period of not more than 5 years, and may subsequently provide an additional renewal on a merit-reviewed basis for a period of not more than 5 years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d2156-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Activities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Centers shall undertake research activities to accelerate the production of advanced biofuels and bioproducts from biomass resources by identifying the most suitable species of plants for use as energy crops; and improving methods of breeding, propagation, planting, producing, harvesting, storage and processing. Activities may include the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc00d2157-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> Research activities to increase sustainability, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc00d2158-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> advancing knowledge of how bioenergy crop interactions with biotic and abiotic environmental factors influence crop growth, yield, and quality;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc00d2159-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> identifying the most impactful research areas that address the economics of advanced biofuels and bioproducts production; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc00d215a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/4/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> utilizing multiscale modeling to advance predictive understanding of advanced biofuel cropping ecosystems.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc00d215b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> Research activities to further feedstock development, including lignocellulosic, algal, gaseous wastes including carbon oxides and methane, and direct air capture of single carbon gases via plants and microbes, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc00d215c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> developing genetic and genomic tools, high-throughput analytical tools, and biosystems design approaches to enhance bioenergy feedstocks and their associated microbiomes;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc00d215d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> conducting field testing of new potential bioenergy feedstock crops under environmentally benign and geographically diverse conditions to assess viability and robustness; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc00d215e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/4/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> developing quantitative models informed by experimentation to predict how bioenergy feedstocks perform under diverse conditions.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc00d215f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> Research activities to improve lignocellulosic deconstruction and separation methods, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc00d2160-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/4/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> developing feedstock-agnostic deconstruction processes capable of efficiently fractionating biomass into targeted output streams;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc00d2161-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/4/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> gaining a detailed understanding of plant cell wall biosynthesis, composition, structure, and properties during deconstruction; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc00d2162-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/4/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> improving enzymes and approaches for biomass breakdown and cellulose, hemicellulose, and lignin processing.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc00d2163-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/4/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> Research activities to improve the feedstock conversion process for advanced biofuels and bioproducts, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc00d2164-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/4/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> developing high-throughput methods to screen or select high-performance microbial strains and communities to improve product formation rates, yields, and selectivity;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc00d2165-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/4/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> establishing a broad set of platform microorganisms and microbial communities suitable for metabolic engineering to produce advanced biofuels and bioproducts and high-throughput methods for experimental validation of gene function;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc00d2166-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/4/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> developing techniques to enhance microbial robustness for tolerating toxins to improve advanced biofuel and bioproduct yields and to gain a better understanding of the cellular and molecular bases of tolerance for major chemical classes of inhibitors found in these processes;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc00d2167-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/4/D/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> advancing technologies for the use of batch, continuous, and consolidated bioprocessing;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc00d2168-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/4/D/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> identifying, creating, and optimizing microbial and chemical pathways to produce promising, atom-economical intermediates and final bioproducts from biomass with considerations given to environmentally benign processes;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc00d2169-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/4/D/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> developing high-throughput, real-time, in situ analytical techniques to understand and characterize the pre- and post-bioproduct separation streams in detail;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc00d216a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/4/D/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> creating methodologies for efficiently identifying viable target molecules, identifying high-value bioproducts in existing biomass streams, and utilizing current byproduct streams;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc00d216b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/4/D/viii"><num value="viii">(viii)</num><content> identifying and improving plant feedstocks with enhanced extractable levels of desired bioproducts or bioproduct precursors, including lignin streams; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc00d216c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/4/D/ix"><num value="ix">(ix)</num><content> developing integrated biological and chemical catalytic approaches to valorize and produce a diverse portfolio of advanced biofuels and bioproducts.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d216d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Industry partnerships</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Centers shall establish industry partnerships to translate research results to commercial applications.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d216e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In coordination with the Bioenergy Technologies Office of the Department, the Secretary shall support interdisciplinary research activities to improve the capacity, efficiency, resilience, security, reliability, and affordability, of the production and use of advanced biofuels and bioproducts, as well as activities to enable positive impacts and avoid the potential negative impacts that the production and use of advanced biofuels and bioproducts may have on ecosystems, people, and historically marginalized communities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d216f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Funding</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Of the funds authorized to be appropriated under subsection (k) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s18644">section 18644 of this title</ref> for a fiscal year, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this subsection $30,000,000 per center established under paragraph (1) for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d2170-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In this subsection:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d2171-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/8/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Advanced biofuel</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “advanced biofuel” has the meaning given the term in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8101">section 8101 of title 7</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d2172-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/8/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Bioenergy</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “bioenergy” means energy derived from biofuels.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d2173-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/8/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Biomass</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “biomass” has the meaning given the term in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s15852/b">section 15852(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idc00d2174-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16317/f/8/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Bioproduct</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The term “bioproduct” has the meaning given the term “biobased product” in <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8101">section 8101 of title 7</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc00d2175-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/109/58/tIX/s977">Pub. L. 109–58, title IX, § 977</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/903">119 Stat. 903</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/tII">Pub. L. 110–140, title II</ref>, §§ 232(a), 233, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1537">121 Stat. 1537</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/167/dB/tI/s10103/e">Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title I, § 10103(e)</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/1430">136 Stat. 1430</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc00d2176-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc00d2177-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc00d2178-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This part, referred to in subsec. (d), was in the original “this subtitle”, meaning subtitle G (§§ 971–984A) of title IX of <ref href="/us/pl/109/58">Pub. L. 109–58</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/898">119 Stat. 898</ref>, which enacted this part and amended <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s5523">section 5523 of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of subtitle G to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc00d2179-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/117/167">Pub. L. 117–167</ref> added subsec. (f) and struck out former subsec. (f) which related to establishment of at least 7 bioenergy research centers to carry out the program under subsec. (a) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/s232/a/1">Pub. L. 110–140, § 232(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “computational biology, and environmental science” for “and computational biology”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/s232/a/2/A">Pub. L. 110–140, § 232(a)(2)(A)</ref>, inserted “in sustainable production systems that reduce greenhouse gas emissions” after “hydrogen”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/s232/a/2/B">Pub. L. 110–140, § 232(a)(2)(B)</ref>–(D), added par. (4) and redesignated former par. (4) as (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/s233">Pub. L. 110–140, § 233</ref>, added subsec. (f).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc00d217a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idc00d217b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2007 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/110/140">Pub. L. 110–140</ref> effective on the date that is 1 day after <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/s1601">section 1601 of Pub. L. 110–140</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1824">section 1824 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
