<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc00f6b6b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16359"><num value="16359">§ 16359.</num><heading> Competitive award of management contracts</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">None of the funds authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary by this subchapter may be used to award a management and operating contract for a National Laboratory (excluding those named in subparagraphs (G), (H), (N), and (O) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s15801/3">section 15801(3) of this title</ref>), unless such contract is competitively awarded, or the Secretary grants, on a case-by-case basis, a waiver. The Secretary may not delegate the authority to grant such a waiver and shall submit to Congress a report notifying it of the waiver, and setting forth the reasons for the waiver, at least 60 days prior to the date of the award of such contract.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idc00f6b6c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/109/58/tIX/s995">Pub. L. 109–58, title IX, § 995</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/914">119 Stat. 914</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc00f6b6d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc00f6b6e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc00f6b6f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subchapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this title”, meaning title IX of <ref href="/us/pl/109/58">Pub. L. 109–58</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/856">119 Stat. 856</ref>, which enacted this subchapter, amended sections 8101 and 8102 of Title 7, Agriculture, and <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s5523">section 5523 of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade, enacted provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s15801">section 15801 of this title</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8102">section 8102 of Title 7</ref>, and <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s2001">section 2001 of Title 30</ref>, Mineral Lands and Mining, and amended provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s8101">section 8101 of Title 7</ref> and <ref href="/us/usc/t30/s1902">section 1902 of Title 30</ref>. For complete classification of title IX to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s15801">section 15801 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
