<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc0169697-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16452"><num value="16452">§ 16452.</num><heading> Federal access to books and records</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc0169698-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16452/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each holding company and each associate company thereof shall maintain, and shall make available to the Commission, such books, accounts, memoranda, and other records as the Commission determines are relevant to costs incurred by a public utility or natural gas company that is an associate company of such holding company and necessary or appropriate for the protection of utility customers with respect to jurisdictional rates.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc0169699-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16452/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Affiliate companies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each affiliate of a holding company or of any subsidiary company of a holding company shall maintain, and shall make available to the Commission, such books, accounts, memoranda, and other records with respect to any transaction with another affiliate, as the Commission determines are relevant to costs incurred by a public utility or natural gas company that is an associate company of such holding company and necessary or appropriate for the protection of utility customers with respect to jurisdictional rates.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc016969a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16452/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Holding company systems</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission may examine the books, accounts, memoranda, and other records of any company in a holding company system, or any affiliate thereof, as the Commission determines are relevant to costs incurred by a public utility or natural gas company within such holding company system and necessary or appropriate for the protection of utility customers with respect to jurisdictional rates.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc016969b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s16452/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Confidentiality</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No member, officer, or employee of the Commission shall divulge any fact or information that may come to his or her knowledge during the course of examination of books, accounts, memoranda, or other records as provided in this section, except as may be directed by the Commission or by a court of competent jurisdiction.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc016969c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/109/58/tXII/s1264">Pub. L. 109–58, title XII, § 1264</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/974">119 Stat. 974</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
