<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbb3ea9ee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1652"><num value="1652">§ 1652.</num><heading> Computation of benefits; application to aliens and nonnationals</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb3ea9ef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1652/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The minimum limit on weekly compensation for disability, established by <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s906/b">section 906(b) of title 33</ref>, and the minimum limit on the average weekly wages on which death benefits are to be computed, established by <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s909/e">section 909(e) of title 33</ref>, shall not apply in computing compensation and death benefits under this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb3ea9f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1652/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Compensation for permanent total or permanent partial disability under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s908/c/21">section 908(c)(21) of title 33</ref>, or for death under this chapter to aliens and nonnationals of the United States not residents of the United States or Canada shall be in the same amount as provided for residents, except that dependents in any foreign country shall be limited to surviving wife and child or children, or if there be no surviving wife or child or children, to surviving father or mother whom the employee has supported, either wholly or in part, for the period of one year immediately prior to the date of the injury, and except that the Secretary of Labor may, at his option or upon the application of the insurance carrier shall, commute all future installments of compensation to be paid to such aliens or nonnationals of the United States by paying or causing to be paid to them one-half of the commuted amount of such future installments of compensation as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbb3ea9f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1941-08-16/ch357/s2">Aug. 16, 1941, ch. 357, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/55/623">55 Stat. 623</ref>; 1946 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 3, eff. <date date="1946-07-16">July 16, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 7873, <ref href="/us/stat/60/1095">60 Stat. 1095</ref>; 1950 Reorg. Plan No. 19, § 1, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3178, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1271">64 Stat. 1271</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/426/s27/d/2">Pub. L. 98–426, § 27(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1984-09-28">Sept. 28, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/1654">98 Stat. 1654</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbb3ea9f2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbb3ea9f3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbb3ea9f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsecs. (a), (b). <ref href="/us/pl/98/426">Pub. L. 98–426</ref> substituted references to sections of the Longshore and Harbor Workers’ Compensation Act for sections of the Longshoremen’s and Harbor Workers’ Compensation Act, which references have been translated to sections of title 33, thus requiring no change in text.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbb3ea9f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbb3ea9f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1984 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/98/426">Pub. L. 98–426</ref> effective <date date="1984-09-28">Sept. 28, 1984</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/98/426/s28/e/1">section 28(e)(1) of Pub. L. 98–426</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s901">section 901 of Title 33</ref>, Navigation and Navigable Waters.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbb3ea9f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbb3ea9f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Labor” and “Secretary” substituted for “Federal Security Administrator” and “Administrator”, respectively, in subsec. (b), pursuant to Reorg. Plan No. 19 of 1950, § 1, eff. <date date="1950-05-24">May 24, 1950</date>, 15 F.R. 3178, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1271">64 Stat. 1271</ref>, which transferred functions of Federal Security Administrator to Secretary of Labor.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Previously, “Federal Security Administrator” and “Administrator” substituted for “United States Employees’ Compensation Commission” and “Commission” pursuant to Reorg. Plan No. 2 of 1946, § 3, eff. <date date="1946-07-16">July 16, 1946</date>, 11 F.R. 7873, <ref href="/us/stat/60/1095">60 Stat. 1095</ref>, which abolished United States Employees’ Compensation Commission and transferred its functions to Federal Security Administrator.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
