<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc03a72a7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s17382"><num value="17382">§ 17382.</num><heading> Smart grid system report</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary of the Office of Electricity Delivery and Energy Reliability (referred to in this section as the “OEDER”) and through the Smart Grid Task Force established in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s17383">section 17383 of this title</ref>, shall, after consulting with any interested individual or entity as appropriate, no later than 1 year after <date date="2007-12-19">December 19, 2007</date>, and every 2 years thereafter, report to Congress concerning the status of smart grid deployments nationwide and any regulatory or government barriers to continued deployment. The report shall provide the current status and prospects of smart grid development, including information on technology penetration, communications network capabilities, costs, and obstacles. It may include recommendations for State and Federal policies or actions helpful to facilitate the transition to a smart grid. To the extent appropriate, it should take a regional perspective. In preparing this report, the Secretary shall solicit advice and contributions from the Smart Grid Advisory Committee created in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s17383">section 17383 of this title</ref>; from other involved Federal agencies including but not limited to the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (“Commission”), the National Institute of Standards and Technology (“Institute”), and the Department of Homeland Security; and from other stakeholder groups not already represented on the Smart Grid Advisory Committee.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idc03a72a8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/110/140/tXIII/s1302">Pub. L. 110–140, title XIII, § 1302</ref>, <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1784">121 Stat. 1784</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc03a72a9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc03a72aa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idc03a72ab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="2007-12-19">December 19, 2007</date>, referred to in text, was in the original “enactment” and was translated as meaning the date of enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/110/140">Pub. L. 110–140</ref> to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc03a72ac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idc03a72ad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective on the date that is 1 day after <date date="2007-12-19">Dec. 19, 2007</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/110/140/s1601">section 1601 of Pub. L. 110–140</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s1824">section 1824 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
