<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbb4a907f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1757"><num value="1757">§ 1757.</num><heading> State disbursement to schools</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb4a9080-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1757/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Disbursement by State educational agency</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Funds paid to any State during any fiscal year pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1753">section 1753 of this title</ref> shall be disbursed by the State educational agency, in accordance with such agreements approved by the Secretary, as may be entered into by such State agency and the schools in the State, to those schools in the State which the State educational agency, taking into account need and attendance, determines are eligible to participate in the school lunch program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb4a9081-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1757/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Permanent, amendable agreements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The agreements described in subsection (a) shall be permanent agreements that may be amended as necessary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb4a9082-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1757/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Suspension or termination of agreements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The State educational agency may suspend or terminate any such agreement in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb4a9083-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1757/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Use of funds paid to States may include, in addition to the purchase price of agricultural commodities and other foods, the cost of processing, distributing, transporting, storing or handling thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb4a9084-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1757/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In no event shall such disbursement for food to any school for any fiscal year exceed an amount determined by multiplying the number of lunches served in the school in the school lunch program under this chapter during such year by the maximum per meal reimbursement rate for the State, for the type of lunch served, as prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb4a9085-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1757/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Increase in meal reimbursement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In any fiscal year in which the national average payment per lunch determined under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1753">section 1753 of this title</ref> is increased above the amount prescribed in the previous fiscal year, the maximum per meal reimbursement rate, for the type of lunch served, shall be increased by a like amount.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb4a9086-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1757/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> In advance or as reimbursement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Lunch assistance disbursements to schools under this section and under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1759a">section 1759a of this title</ref> may be made in advance or by way of reimbursement in accordance with procedures prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbb4a9087-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-06-04/ch281/s8">June 4, 1946, ch. 281, § 8</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/232">60 Stat. 232</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/433/s8">Pub. L. 92–433, § 8</ref>, <date date="1972-09-26">Sept. 26, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/729">86 Stat. 729</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/150/s2/b">Pub. L. 93–150, § 2(b)</ref>, <date date="1973-11-07">Nov. 7, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/560">87 Stat. 560</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/166/s3">Pub. L. 95–166, § 3</ref>, <date date="1977-11-10">Nov. 10, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1332">91 Stat. 1332</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/627/s10/d/1">Pub. L. 95–627, § 10(d)(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3624">92 Stat. 3624</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tVIII/s819/d">Pub. L. 97–35, title VIII, § 819(d)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/533">95 Stat. 533</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/147/tII/s201">Pub. L. 101–147, title II, § 201</ref>, title III, §§ 304, 312(1), <date date="1989-11-10">Nov. 10, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/908">103 Stat. 908</ref>, 914, 916; <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/tVII/s701/a">Pub. L. 104–193, title VII, § 701(a)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2287">110 Stat. 2287</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbb4a9088-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbb4a9089-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbb4a908a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—<ref href="/us/pl/104/193">Pub. L. 104–193</ref> designated first and second sentences as subsecs. (a) and (b), respectively, substituted “in subsection (a)” for “in the preceding sentence” in subsec. (b), designated third sentence as subsec. (c) and substituted “The State educational agency may” for “Nothing in the preceding sentence shall be construed to limit the ability of the State educational agency to”, struck out fourth and fifth sentences, designated sixth sentence as subsec. (d) and substituted “Use of funds paid to States” for “Such food costs”, and designated seventh to ninth sentences as subsecs. (e) to (g), respectively. Prior to amendment, fourth and fifth sentences read as follows: “Such disbursement to any school shall be made only for the purpose of assisting it to obtain agricultural commodities and other foods for consumption by children in the school lunch program. The terms ‘child’ and ‘children’ as used in this chapter shall be deemed to include individuals regardless of age who are determined by the State educational agency, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary, to have 1 or more mental or physical handicaps and who are attending any child care institution as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1766">section 1766 of this title</ref> or any nonresidential public or nonprofit private school of high school grade or under for the purpose of participating in a school program established for individuals with mental or physical handicaps: <i>Provided</i>, That no institution that is not otherwise eligible to participate in the program under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1766">section 1766 of this title</ref> shall be deemed so eligible because of this sentence.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—<ref href="/us/pl/101/147/s312/1">Pub. L. 101–147, § 312(1)</ref>, substituted “school lunch” for “school-lunch” in three places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/147/s304">Pub. L. 101–147, § 304</ref>, which directed the amendment of subsec. (d) by substituting “individuals” for “persons”, “to have 1 or more mental or physical handicaps” for “to be mentally or physically handicapped”, and “for individuals with mental or physical handicaps” for “for mentally or physically handicapped”, was executed by making the substitutions in the undesignated text before the proviso as the probable intent of Congress because the section contains no subsection designations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/147/s201">Pub. L. 101–147, § 201</ref>, inserted after first sentence “The agreements described in the preceding sentence shall be permanent agreements that may be amended as necessary. Nothing in the preceding sentence shall be construed to limit the ability of the State educational agency to suspend or terminate any such agreement in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—<ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> substituted references to per meal reimbursement rate, for references to Federal food-cost contribution rate wherever appearing, and struck out reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1754">section 1754 of this title</ref>, and food service equipment assistance.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—<ref href="/us/pl/95/627">Pub. L. 95–627</ref> inserted provision relating to definition of “child” and “children”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—<ref href="/us/pl/95/166">Pub. L. 95–166</ref> substituted “food service equipment assistance” for “nonfood assistance”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—<ref href="/us/pl/93/150">Pub. L. 93–150</ref> provided that in any fiscal year in which the national average payment per lunch determined under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1753">section 1753 of this title</ref> is increased above the amount prescribed in the previous fiscal year, the maximum Federal food-cost contribution rate, for the type of lunch served, shall be increased by a like amount.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1972—<ref href="/us/pl/92/433">Pub. L. 92–433</ref> substituted provision that disbursement to schools be made for the purpose of assisting them to finance the costs of agricultural commodities, for provision that such disbursement be made for the purpose of reimbursing them for such costs and inserted provision that lunch assistance disbursements to schools under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1759a">section 1759a of this title</ref> may be made in advance or by way of reimbursement according to procedure prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbb4a908b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbb4a908c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> effective <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s820/a/4">section 820(a)(4) of Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1753">section 1753 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbb4a908d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/627">Pub. L. 95–627</ref> effective <date date="1978-10-01">Oct. 1, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/627/s14">section 14 of Pub. L. 95–627</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1755">section 1755 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
