<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbb6e450d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773"><num value="1773">§ 1773.</num><heading> School breakfast program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb6e450e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment; authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to enable the Secretary to carry out a program to assist the States and the Department of Defense through grants-in-aid and other means to initiate, maintain, or expand nonprofit breakfast programs in all schools which make application for assistance and agree to carry out a nonprofit breakfast program in accordance with this chapter. Appropriations and expenditures for this chapter shall be considered Health and Human Services functions for budget purposes rather than functions of Agriculture.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb6e450f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Breakfast assistance payments to State educational agencies; calculation; national average payments for breakfasts, free breakfasts and reduced price breakfasts; maximum price for reduced cost breakfasts; minimum daily nutrition requirements criteria; additional payments for severe need schools; maximum severe need payments</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb6e4510-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb6e4511-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb6e4512-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/b/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall make breakfast assistance payments to each State educational agency each fiscal year, at such times as the Secretary may determine, from the sums appropriated for such purpose, in an amount equal to the product obtained by multiplying—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb6e4513-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/b/1/A/i/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the number of breakfasts served during such fiscal year to children in schools in such States which participate in the school breakfast program under agreements with such State educational agency; by</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb6e4514-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/b/1/A/i/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the national average breakfast payment for free breakfasts, for reduced price breakfasts, or for breakfasts served to children not eligible for free or reduced price meals, as appropriate, as prescribed in clause (B) of this paragraph.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb6e4515-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/b/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The agreements described in clause (i)(I) shall be permanent agreements that may be amended as necessary. Nothing in the preceding sentence shall be construed to limit the ability of the State educational agency to suspend or terminate any such agreement in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb6e4516-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The national average payment for each free breakfast shall be 57 cents (as adjusted pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1759a/a">section 1759a(a) of this title</ref>). The national average payment for each reduced price breakfast shall be one-half of the national average payment for each free breakfast, except that in no case shall the difference between the amount of the national average payment for a free breakfast and the national average payment for a reduced price breakfast exceed 30 cents. The national average payment for each breakfast served to a child not eligible for free or reduced price meals shall be 8.25 cents (as adjusted pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1759a/a">section 1759a(a) of this title</ref>).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb6e4517-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> No school which receives breakfast assistance payments under this section may charge a price of more than 30 cents for a reduced price breakfast.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb6e4518-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> No breakfast assistance payment may be made under this subsection for any breakfast served by a school unless such breakfast consists of a combination of foods which meet the minimum nutritional requirements prescribed by the Secretary under subsection (e) of this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb6e4519-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Free and reduced price policy statement</inline>.—</heading><content>After the initial submission, a local educational agency shall not be required to submit a free and reduced price policy statement to a State educational agency under this chapter unless there is a substantive change in the free and reduced price policy of the local educational agency. A routine change in the policy of a local educational agency, such as an annual adjustment of the income eligibility guidelines for free and reduced price meals, shall not be sufficient cause for requiring the local educational agency to submit a policy statement.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb6e451a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb6e451b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary shall make additional payments for breakfasts served to children qualifying for a free or reduced price meal at schools that are in severe need.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb6e451c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> The maximum payment for each such free breakfast shall be the higher of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb6e451d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/b/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the national average payment established by the Secretary for free breakfasts plus 10 cents, or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb6e451e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/b/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> 45 cents (as adjusted pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1759a/a/3/B">section 1759a(a)(3)(B) of this title</ref>).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb6e451f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The maximum payment for each such reduced price breakfast shall be thirty cents less than the maximum payment for each free breakfast as determined under clause (B) of this paragraph.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb6e4520-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary shall increase by 6 cents the annually adjusted payment for each breakfast served under this chapter and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1766">section 1766 of this title</ref>. These funds shall be used to assist States, to the extent feasible, in improving the nutritional quality of the breakfasts.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb6e4521-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, whenever stocks of agricultural commodities are acquired by the Secretary or the Commodity Credit Corporation and are not likely to be sold by the Secretary or the Commodity Credit Corporation or otherwise used in programs of commodity sale or distribution, the Secretary shall make such commodities available to school food authorities and eligible institutions serving breakfasts under this chapter in a quantity equal in value to not less than 3 cents for each breakfast served under this chapter and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1766">section 1766 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb6e4522-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Expenditures of funds from State and local sources for the maintenance of the breakfast program shall not be diminished as a result of funds or commodities received under paragraph (3) or (4).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb6e4523-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Disbursement of apportioned funds by State; preference for schools in poor economic areas, for students traveling long distances daily, and for schools for improvement of nutrition and dietary practices of children of working mothers and from low-income families</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Funds apportioned and paid to any State for the purpose of this section shall be disbursed by the State educational agency to schools selected by the State educational agency to assist such schools in operating a breakfast program and for the purpose of subsection (d). Disbursement to schools shall be made at such rates per meal or on such other basis as the Secretary shall prescribe. In selecting schools for participation, the State educational agency shall, to the extent practicable, give first consideration to those schools drawing attendance from areas in which poor economic conditions exist, to those schools in which a substantial proportion of the children enrolled must travel long distances daily, and to those schools in which there is a special need for improving the nutrition and dietary practices of children of working mothers and children from low-income families. Breakfast assistance disbursements to schools under this section may be made in advance or by way of reimbursement in accordance with procedures prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb6e4524-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Severe need assistance</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbb6e4525-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each State educational agency shall provide additional assistance to schools in severe need, which shall include only those schools (having a breakfast program or desiring to initiate a breakfast program) in which—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbb6e4526-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> during the most recent second preceding school year for which lunches were served, 40 percent or more of the lunches served to students at the school were served free or at a reduced price; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbb6e4527-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case of a school in which lunches were not served during the most recent second preceding school year, the Secretary otherwise determines that the requirements of subparagraph (A) would have been met.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbb6e4528-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A school, on the submission of appropriate documentation about the need circumstances in that school and the eligibility of the school for additional assistance, shall be entitled to receive the meal reimbursement rate specified in subsection (b)(2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb6e4529-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Nutritional requirements; service free or at reduced price; compliance assistance</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb6e452a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb6e452b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Breakfasts served by schools participating in the school breakfast program under this section shall consist of a combination of foods and shall meet the minimum nutritional requirements prescribed by the Secretary on the basis of tested nutritional research, except that the minimum nutritional requirements shall be measured by not less than the weekly average of the nutrient content of school breakfasts. Such breakfasts shall be served free or at a reduced price to children in school under the same terms and conditions as are set forth with respect to the service of lunches free or at a reduced price in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1758">section 1758 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb6e452c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The Secretary shall provide through State educational agencies technical assistance and training, including technical assistance and training in the preparation of foods high in complex carbohydrates and lower-fat versions of foods commonly used in the school breakfast program established under this section, to schools participating in the school breakfast program to assist the schools in complying with the nutritional requirements prescribed by the Secretary pursuant to subparagraph (A) and in providing appropriate meals to children with medically certified special dietary needs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb6e452d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1773/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> At the option of a local school food authority, a student in a school under the authority that participates in the school breakfast program under this chapter may be allowed to refuse not more than one item of a breakfast that the student does not intend to consume. A refusal of an offered food item shall not affect the full charge to the student for a breakfast meeting the requirements of this section or the amount of payments made under this chapter to a school for the breakfast.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbb6e452e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/642/s4">Pub. L. 89–642, § 4</ref>, <date date="1966-10-11">Oct. 11, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/886">80 Stat. 886</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/302/s5">Pub. L. 90–302, § 5</ref>, <date date="1968-05-08">May 8, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/119">82 Stat. 119</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/248">Pub. L. 91–248</ref>, §§ 6(d), 10, <date date="1970-05-14">May 14, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/210">84 Stat. 210</ref>, 214; <ref href="/us/pl/92/32">Pub. L. 92–32</ref>, §§ 2–5, <date date="1971-06-30">June 30, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/85">85 Stat. 85</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/433/s3">Pub. L. 92–433, § 3</ref>, <date date="1972-09-26">Sept. 26, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/724">86 Stat. 724</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/150/s4">Pub. L. 93–150, § 4</ref>, <date date="1973-11-07">Nov. 7, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/562">87 Stat. 562</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/105">Pub. L. 94–105</ref>, §§ 2, 3, 15(b), 17(a), <date date="1975-10-07">Oct. 7, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/511">89 Stat. 511</ref>, 522, 525; <ref href="/us/pl/95/166/s12">Pub. L. 95–166, § 12</ref>, <date date="1977-11-10">Nov. 10, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1337">91 Stat. 1337</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/561/tXIV/s1408/b/1">Pub. L. 95–561, title XIV, § 1408(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-01">Nov. 1, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/2368">92 Stat. 2368</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/627/s6/c">Pub. L. 95–627, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3620">92 Stat. 3620</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tVIII">Pub. L. 97–35, title VIII</ref>, §§ 801(c), 817(d), 819(b), <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/522">95 Stat. 522</ref>, 532, 533; <ref href="/us/pl/99/500/tIII">Pub. L. 99–500, title III</ref>, §§ 330(a), 331, 372(b)(1), <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1783-363">100 Stat. 1783–363</ref>, 1783–369, and <ref href="/us/pl/99/591/tIII">Pub. L. 99–591, title III</ref>, §§ 330(a), 331, 372(b)(1), <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3341-366">100 Stat. 3341–366</ref>, 3341–372; <ref href="/us/pl/99/661/dD/tII">Pub. L. 99–661, div. D, title II</ref>, §§ 4210(a), 4211, title V, § 4502(b)(1), <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/4074">100 Stat. 4074</ref>, 4080; <ref href="/us/pl/100/435/tII/s210">Pub. L. 100–435, title II, § 210</ref>, <date date="1988-09-19">Sept. 19, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1657">102 Stat. 1657</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/147/tI/s121">Pub. L. 101–147, title I, § 121</ref>, title II, § 212(a)(1), (2)(A), (b), title III, § 322, <date date="1989-11-10">Nov. 10, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/891">103 Stat. 891</ref>, 912, 916; <ref href="/us/pl/103/448/tII/s201">Pub. L. 103–448, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4734">108 Stat. 4734</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/tVII">Pub. L. 104–193, title VII</ref>, §§ 722–723(b)(1), <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2301">110 Stat. 2301</ref>, 2302; <ref href="/us/pl/105/336/tI/s103/b/2">Pub. L. 105–336, title I, § 103(b)(2)</ref>, title II, § 201, <date date="1998-10-31">Oct. 31, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3146">112 Stat. 3146</ref>, 3158; <ref href="/us/pl/106/78/tVII/s752/b/16">Pub. L. 106–78, title VII, § 752(b)(16)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-22">Oct. 22, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1170">113 Stat. 1170</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/265/tI/s108/c">Pub. L. 108–265, title I, § 108(c)</ref>, title II, § 201, <date date="2004-06-30">June 30, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/746">118 Stat. 746</ref>, 768.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbb6e452f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbb6e4530-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbb6e4531-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/591">Pub. L. 99–591</ref> is a corrected version of <ref href="/us/pl/99/500">Pub. L. 99–500</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbb6e4532-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (b)(1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/108/265/s108/c">Pub. L. 108–265, § 108(c)</ref>, substituted “local educational agency” for “school food authority” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/108/265/s201">Pub. L. 108–265, § 201</ref>, added subsec. (d) and struck out former subsec. (d), which authorized severe need assistance to schools in which the service of breakfasts is required by State law and to schools in which 40 percent or more of lunches were served free or at a reduced price during the most recent second preceding school year, and entitled such schools to receive the lesser of 100 percent of the operating costs of the breakfast program or the meal reimbursement rate specified in subsec. (b)(2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsecs. (b), (e)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/106/78">Pub. L. 106–78</ref> made technical amendment to references in original act which appear in text as references to sections 1758, 1759a, and 1766 of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/105/336/s201">Pub. L. 105–336, § 201</ref>, struck out “and to carry out the provisions of subsection (g) of this section” before period at end of first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/105/336/s103/b/2/A">Pub. L. 105–336, § 103(b)(2)(A)</ref>, struck out “adjusted to the nearest one-fourth cent,” after “payment for each free breakfast,” in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/105/336/s103/b/2/B">Pub. L. 105–336, § 103(b)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “(as adjusted pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1759a/a/3/B">section 1759a(a)(3)(B) of this title</ref>).” for “, which shall be adjusted on an annual basis each July 1 to the nearest one-fourth cent in accordance with changes in the series for food away from home of the Consumer Price Index published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor for the most recent twelve-month period for which such data are available, except that the initial such adjustment shall be made on <date date="1978-01-01">January 1, 1978</date>, and shall reflect the change in the series of food away from home during the period <date date="1976-11-01">November 1, 1976</date>, to <date date="1977-10-31">October 31, 1977</date>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (b)(1)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/s722">Pub. L. 104–193, § 722</ref>, added subpar. (E).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/s723/a">Pub. L. 104–193, § 723(a)</ref>, struck out at end “The Secretary shall provide through State educational agencies additional technical assistance to schools that are having difficulty maintaining compliance with the requirements.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (f), (g). <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/s723/b/1">Pub. L. 104–193, § 723(b)(1)</ref>, struck out subsec. (f) relating to expansion of program and subsec. (g) relating to startup and expansion costs.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/448/s201/a">Pub. L. 103–448, § 201(a)</ref>, (b), designated existing provisions as subpar. (A), inserted “, except that the minimum nutritional requirements shall be measured by not less than the weekly average of the nutrient content of school breakfasts” before period at end, and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/103/448/s201/c">Pub. L. 103–448, § 201(c)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A) and added subpars. (B) and (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/103/448/s201/d">Pub. L. 103–448, § 201(d)</ref>, amended heading and text of subsec. (g) generally. Prior to amendment, text required the Secretary to pay State educational agencies to assist eligible schools in initiating a school breakfast program, set forth a plan by which certain State educational agencies competing for startup cost payments were to be given preference, provided that breakfast program maintenance funds were not to be diminished by these payments, defined “eligible school”, and directed Secretary to report to Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/147/s121/1">Pub. L. 101–147, § 121(1)</ref>, inserted before period at end of first sentence “and to carry out the provisions of subsection (g) of this section”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/101/147/s322/1">Pub. L. 101–147, § 322(1)</ref>, substituted “reduced price” for “reduced-price” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/101/147/s212/b">Pub. L. 101–147, § 212(b)</ref>, designated existing provisions as cl. (i), redesignated former cls. (i) and (ii) as subcls. (I) and (II), respectively, of cl. (i), and added cl. (ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/101/147/s322/2">Pub. L. 101–147, § 322(2)</ref>, made technical amendment to reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1766">section 1766 of this title</ref> involving underlying provisions of original act and requiring no change in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3) to (5). <ref href="/us/pl/101/147/s212/a/1">Pub. L. 101–147, § 212(a)(1)</ref>, (2)(A), amended subsec. (b)(3) to (5), as amended identically by <ref href="/us/pl/99/591/s330/a">Pub. L. 99–591, § 330(a)</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/99/661/s4210/a">Pub. L. 99–661, § 4210(a)</ref>, and as further amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/435/s210">Pub. L. 100–435, § 210</ref>, to read as if only the amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/99/661">Pub. L. 99–661</ref> was enacted, and further amended subsec. (b)(3) identically to the amendment that was made by <ref href="/us/pl/100/435">Pub. L. 100–435</ref>, resulting in no change in text, see 1986 and 1988 Amendment notes below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/101/147/s322/1">Pub. L. 101–147, § 322(1)</ref>, substituted “reduced price” for “reduced-price”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/101/147/s121/2">Pub. L. 101–147, § 121(2)</ref>, inserted “Expansion of program” as heading, designated existing provisions as par. (1), struck out at end “Within 4 months after <date date="1975-10-07">October 7, 1975</date>, the Secretary shall report to the committees of jurisdiction in the Congress his plans and those of the cooperating State agencies to bring about the needed expansion in the school breakfast program.”, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/101/147/s121/3">Pub. L. 101–147, § 121(3)</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/435">Pub. L. 100–435</ref> substituted “6” for “3”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/500">Pub. L. 99–500</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/99/591/s372/b/1">Pub. L. 99–591, § 372(b)(1)</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/99/661/s4502/b/1">Pub. L. 99–661, § 4502(b)(1)</ref>, amended subsec. (a) identically, substituting “Health and Human Services” for “Health, Education, and Welfare”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3) to (5). <ref href="/us/pl/99/500">Pub. L. 99–500</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/99/591/s330/a">Pub. L. 99–591, § 330(a)</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/99/661/s4210/a">Pub. L. 99–661, § 4210(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (b) identically, adding pars. (3) to (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/99/500">Pub. L. 99–500</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/99/591/s331">Pub. L. 99–591, § 331</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/99/661/s4211">Pub. L. 99–661, § 4211</ref>, amended subsec. (e) identically, designating existing provisions as par. (1) and adding par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s801/c/1">Pub. L. 97–35, § 801(c)(1)</ref>, (2), in par. (1) substituted provisions respecting calculation, amount, limitations, etc., for breakfast assistance payments to State educational agencies for provisions respecting apportionment, calculation, etc., for payments beginning with fiscal year ending <date date="1973-06-30">June 30, 1973</date>, and in par. (2) substituted provisions respecting annual adjustments, for provisions respecting semiannual adjustments and substituted “thirty” for “five”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s819/b">Pub. L. 97–35, § 819(b)</ref>, struck out “financing the costs of” after “such schools in”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s801/c/3/A">Pub. L. 97–35, § 801(c)(3)(A)</ref>, substituted provisions limiting additional assistance requirements to schools in severe need for provisions setting forth requirements for eligibility standards for providing additional assistance to schools in severe need.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s817/d">Pub. L. 97–35, § 817(d)</ref>, redesignated former subsec. (g) as (f). Former subsec. (f), which related to nonprofit private schools, was struck out.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s817/d">Pub. L. 97–35, § 817(d)</ref>, redesignated former subsec. (g) as (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/561">Pub. L. 95–561</ref> inserted provision relating to applicability to programs of the Department of Defense.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/627">Pub. L. 95–627</ref> specified which schools could be considered to be in severe need.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/95/166/s12/1">Pub. L. 95–166, § 12(1)</ref>, (2), designated existing provisions as par. (1) and struck out provision for payment of up to 45 cents for breakfasts served to children qualifying for a free breakfast in cases of severe need, which is now covered in par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/95/166/s12/3">Pub. L. 95–166, § 12(3)</ref>, added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/166/s12/4">Pub. L. 95–166, § 12(4)</ref>, substituted requirement that the Secretary establish eligibility standards for providing additional assistance to schools in severe need for prior requirement that the State educational agency require applicant schools to provide justification of the need for such assistance; required the eligibility standards to be submitted to the Secretary for approval and to be included in the State plan of child nutrition operations and submission of appropriate documentation about the need circumstances in the school and the school’s eligibility for additional assistance; and authorized payment of the lesser of 100 percent of the operating costs or the meal reimbursement rate, previously limited to the 100 percent payment.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/105/s2">Pub. L. 94–105, § 2</ref>, struck out “for the fiscal years ending <date date="1973-06-30">June 30, 1973</date>, <date date="1974-06-30">June 30, 1974</date>, and <date date="1975-06-30">June 30, 1975</date>,” after “such sums as are necessary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/94/105/s15/b">Pub. L. 94–105, § 15(b)</ref>, substituted “American Samoa, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands” for “and American Samoa” wherever appearing in cl. (1) of first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/94/105/s17/a">Pub. L. 94–105, § 17(a)</ref>, substituted “directly to the schools (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1784/c">section 1784(c) of this title</ref> which are private and nonprofit as defined in the last sentence of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1784/c">section 1784(c) of this title</ref>)” for “directly to the nonprofit private schools”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/94/105/s3">Pub. L. 94–105, § 3</ref>, added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/93/150/s4/c">Pub. L. 93–150, § 4(c)</ref>, prescribed a minimum payment of 8 cents as the national average payment for all breakfasts served to eligible children, inserted provision for minimum payment of 15 cents for each reduced-price breakfast and for minimum payment of 20 cents for each free breakfast, and authorized, in cases of severe need, a payment of up to 45 cents for each breakfast served to children qualifying for a free breakfast.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/93/150/s4/a">Pub. L. 93–150, § 4(a)</ref>, (b), substituted in first sentence “State educational agency to assist such schools in financing the costs of operating a breakfast program” for “State educational agency, to assist such schools in financing the cost of obtaining agricultural and other foods for consumption by needy children in a breakfast program” and struck out second sentence which provided that “Such food costs may include, in addition to the purchase price, the cost of processing, distributing, transporting, storing, and handling.”, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1972—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/92/433/s3/a">Pub. L. 92–433, § 3(a)</ref>, substituted authorization of appropriation of such sums as are necessary for fiscal years ending <date date="1973-06-30">June 30, 1973</date>, <date date="1974-06-30">June 30, 1974</date>, and <date date="1975-06-30">June 30, 1975</date>, for provisions authorizing appropriation of amounts not exceeding $25,000,000 for fiscal years 1972 and 1973 and made amounts available to schools making applications for assistance and agreeing to carry out a nonprofit breakfast program in accordance with this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/92/433/s3/b">Pub. L. 92–433, § 3(b)</ref>, made existing apportionment formula applicable to fiscal year ending <date date="1973-06-30">June 30, 1973</date> and added new formula for fiscal years beginning with fiscal year ending <date date="1974-06-30">June 30, 1974</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/92/433/s3/c">Pub. L. 92–433, § 3(c)</ref>, inserted provision that breakfast assistance disbursements to schools may be made in advance or by way of reimbursement in accordance with procedure prescribed by the Secretary.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/92/433/s3/d">Pub. L. 92–433, § 3(d)</ref>, substituted provisions that breakfasts be served free or at reduced cost under same terms and conditions as set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1758">section 1758 of this title</ref> for provisions relating to determination by local school authorities of the inability of children to pay full cost, criteria for such determination, income poverty guidelines, affidavit of household’s annual income, eligibility of nonprofit private schools for funds, and prohibition of discrimination on account of inability to pay.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/92/433/s3/e">Pub. L. 92–433, § 3(e)</ref>, substituted provisions that for fiscal year ending <date date="1973-06-30">June 30, 1973</date>, withholding and disbursement to nonprofit private schools will be effected as before and that commencing with the next fiscal year, the Secretary would directly make payments to the nonprofit private schools participating in the breakfast program under agreement with the Secretary for provisions that such withholding and disbursement be effected in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1759">section 1759 of this title</ref> with some exceptions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1971—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/92/32/s2">Pub. L. 92–32, § 2</ref>, authorized appropriations of 25 million dollars for fiscal years 1972, and 1973, and struck out provision for appropriation of 6.5, 10, and 25 million dollars for fiscal years, 1969, 1970, and 1971, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/92/32/s3">Pub. L. 92–32, § 3</ref>, substituted “assist such schools in financing the cost” for “reimburse such schools for the cost” and provided for preference of schools for improvement of nutrition and dietary practices of children of working mothers and from low-income families.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/92/32/s4">Pub. L. 92–32, § 4</ref>, increased financial assistance from “80” to “100” per centum.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/92/32/s5">Pub. L. 92–32, § 5</ref>, substituted provisions relating to criteria for determination of eligible children, income poverty guidelines, priority of neediest children, affidavit of household’s annual income, and certification of availability of funds for nonprofit private schools, for former provision for determination of eligible children on basis of consultations of local school authorities with public welfare and health agencies.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/91/248/s10">Pub. L. 91–248, § 10</ref>, substituted “$25,000,000” for “$12,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/91/248/s6/d">Pub. L. 91–248, § 6(d)</ref>, provided that there be no overt identification of those children who receive free and reduced price meals.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/90/302">Pub. L. 90–302</ref> provided authorization to appropriate $6,500,000 for fiscal year 1969, not to exceed $10,000,000 for fiscal year 1970, and not to exceed $12,000,000 for fiscal year 1971, struck out references to authorization for fiscal years 1967 and 1968 and to pilot programs conducted on a nonpartisan basis, and added provision that appropriations and expenditures for this chapter be considered Health, Education, and Welfare functions for budget purposes rather than functions of Agriculture.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbb6e4533-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbb6e4534-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2004 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/265/s108/c">section 108(c) of Pub. L. 108–265</ref> effective <date date="2004-06-30">June 30, 2004</date>, and amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/265/s201">section 201 of Pub. L. 108–265</ref> effective <date date="2004-07-01">July 1, 2004</date>, see section 502(a), (b)(1) of <ref href="/us/pl/108/265">Pub. L. 108–265</ref>, as amended, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1754">section 1754 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbb6e4535-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/336">Pub. L. 105–336</ref> effective <date date="1998-10-01">Oct. 1, 1998</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/336/s401">section 401 of Pub. L. 105–336</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1755">section 1755 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbb6e4536-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1996 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/104/193/tVII/s723/b/2">Pub. L. 104–193, title VII, § 723(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2302">110 Stat. 2302</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/104/193/tVII/s723/b/2">“The amendments made by paragraph (1) [amending this section] shall become effective on <date date="1996-10-01">October 1, 1996</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbb6e4537-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1994 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/103/448">Pub. L. 103–448</ref> effective <date date="1994-10-01">Oct. 1, 1994</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/448/s401">section 401 of Pub. L. 103–448</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1755">section 1755 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbb6e4538-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1989 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/147/tII/s212/a/2/B">Pub. L. 101–147, title II, § 212(a)(2)(B)</ref>, <date date="1989-11-10">Nov. 10, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/912">103 Stat. 912</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/147/tII/s212/a/2/B">“The amendments made by subparagraph (A) [amending this section] shall take effect as if such amendments had been effective on <date date="1989-07-01">July 1, 1989</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbb6e4539-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/435">Pub. L. 100–435</ref> to be effective and implemented on <date date="1989-07-01">July 1, 1989</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/435/s701/b/4">section 701(b)(4) of Pub. L. 100–435</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s2012">section 2012 of Title 7</ref>, Agriculture.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbb6e453a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/661/dD/tII/s4210/a">Pub. L. 99–661, div. D, title II, § 4210(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/4074">100 Stat. 4074</ref>, provided that the amendment made by that section is effective <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/500/tIII/s330/a">Pub. L. 99–500, title III, § 330(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1783-363">100 Stat. 1783–363</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/99/591/tIII/s330/a">Pub. L. 99–591, title III, § 330(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3341-366">100 Stat. 3341–366</ref>, provided that the amendment made by each such section is effective <date date="1987-07-01">July 1, 1987</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbb6e453b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s801/c">section 801(c) of Pub. L. 97–35</ref> effective <date date="1981-09-01">Sept. 1, 1981</date>, and amendment by sections 817 and 819 of <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> effective <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>, see section 820(1)(A), (4) of <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1753">section 1753 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbb6e453c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/627">Pub. L. 95–627</ref> effective <date date="1978-10-01">Oct. 1, 1978</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/627/s14">section 14 of Pub. L. 95–627</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1755">section 1755 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/561">Pub. L. 95–561</ref> effective <date date="1978-10-01">Oct. 1, 1978</date>, and no provision therein to be construed as impairing or preventing the taking effect of any other Act providing for the transfer of functions described therein to an executive department having responsibility for education, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/561/s1415">section 1415 of Pub. L. 95–561</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s921">section 921 of Title 20</ref>, Education.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbb6e453d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Review of Best Practices in the Breakfast Program</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/265/tII/s206">Pub. L. 108–265, title II, § 206</ref>, <date date="2004-06-30">June 30, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/787">118 Stat. 787</ref>, directed the Secretary of Agriculture to enter into an agreement with a research organization to collect and disseminate a review of best practices to assist school food authorities in addressing existing impediments at the State and local level that hinder the growth of the school breakfast program and, not later than 1 year after <date date="2004-06-30">June 30, 2004</date>, to make the review available to school food authorities via the Internet and to transmit it to congressional committees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbb6e453e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Consolidation of School Lunch Program and School Breakfast Program Into Comprehensive Meal Program</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For provisions directing Secretary of Agriculture to consolidate school breakfast program under this section and school lunch program under chapter 13 (§ 1751 et seq.) of this title into comprehensive meal program, see <ref href="/us/pl/103/448/s301">section 301 of Pub. L. 103–448</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1751">section 1751 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbb6e453f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Adjustments in Maximum Breakfast Payments for Fiscal Year Ending <date date="1981-09-30">September 30, 1981</date></heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/499/tII/s210">Pub. L. 96–499, title II, § 210</ref>, <date date="1980-12-05">Dec. 5, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/2602">94 Stat. 2602</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/499/tII/s210">
<inline>“Notwithstanding section 4(b)(2)(B)(ii) of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 [subsec. (b)(2)(B)(ii) of this section], in determining the maximum payment for free breakfasts under such section for the fiscal year ending <date date="1981-09-30">September 30, 1981</date>—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> no adjustment under such section shall be made on January 1 of such fiscal year; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the adjustment under such section required to be made on July 1 of such fiscal year shall be computed to the nearest one-fourth cent based on changes, measured over the preceding twelve-month period for which data are available, in the series for food away from home of the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers, published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics, Department of Labor.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbb6e4540-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Alternate Foods</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/627/s6/d">Pub. L. 95–627, § 6(d)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/3621">93 Stat. 3621</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/627/s6/d">“The Secretary shall not limit or prohibit, during the school year 1978–79, the use of formulated grain-fruit products currently approved for use in the school breakfast program. The Secretary shall consult experts in child nutrition, industry representatives, and school food service personnel and school administrators (including personnel and administrators in school systems using such products) with respect to the continued use of formulated grain-fruit products in the school breakfast program, and shall also take into account the findings and recommendations in the report on this subject of the General Accounting Office [now Government Accountability Office]. The Secretary shall not promulgate a final rule disapproving the use of such products in the school breakfast program beyond the 1978–79 school year until the Secretary has notified the appropriate committees of Congress, and such rule shall not take effect until sixty days after such notification.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbb6e4541-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report to Congress of Needs for Additional Funds for School Breakfast and Nonfood Assistance Programs, Fiscal Year Ending <date date="1972-06-30">June 30, 1972</date></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/92/153/s3">Pub. L. 92–153, § 3</ref>, <date date="1971-11-05">Nov. 5, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/420">85 Stat. 420</ref>, provided that the Secretary of Agriculture determine immediately upon enactment of this resolution (<date date="1971-11-05">Nov. 5, 1971</date>) and report to Congress the needs for additional funds to carry out the school breakfast and nonfood assistance programs during the fiscal year ending <date date="1972-06-30">June 30, 1972</date>, at levels permitting expansion of the school breakfast and school lunch programs to all schools desiring such programs as rapidly as practicable.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbb6e4542-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Funds to Schools in Need of Additional Assistance in School Breakfast Program</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/92/153/s7">Pub. L. 92–153, § 7</ref>, <date date="1971-11-05">Nov. 5, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/420">85 Stat. 420</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/92/153/s7">“In addition to any other authority given to the Secretary he is hereby authorized to transfer funds from <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-24/s32">section 32 of the Act of August 24, 1935</ref> [<ref href="/us/usc/t7/s612c">section 612c of Title 7</ref>, Agriculture], for the purpose of assisting schools which demonstrate a need for additional funds in the school breakfast program.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbb6e4543-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Direct Distribution Programs for Diet of Needy Children Suffering From General and Continued Hunger; Additional Funds</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Additional funds for direct distribution programs for diet of needy children suffering from general and continued hunger and payment of administrative costs of State or local welfare agency carrying out such programs, see <ref href="/us/pl/92/32/s6">section 6 of Pub. L. 92–32</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t7/s612c">section 612c of Title 7</ref>, Agriculture.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
