<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbb73271c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1785"><num value="1785">§ 1785.</num><heading> Accounts and records; availability for inspection; authority to settle, adjust, or waive claims</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb73271d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1785/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> States, State educational agencies, schools, and nonprofit institutions participating in programs under this chapter shall keep such accounts and records as may be necessary to enable the Secretary to determine whether there has been compliance with this chapter and the regulations hereunder. Such accounts and records shall be available at any reasonable time for inspection and audit by representatives of the Secretary and shall be preserved for such period of time, not in excess of three years, as the Secretary determines is necessary.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb73271e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1785/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> With regard to any claim arising under this chapter or under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1751">42 U.S.C. 1751</ref> et seq.], the Secretary shall have the authority to determine the amount of, to settle and to adjust any such claim, and to compromise or deny such claim or any part thereof. The Secretary shall also have the authority to waive such claims if the Secretary determines that to do so would serve the purposes of either this chapter or the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act. Nothing contained in this subsection shall be construed to diminish the authority of the Attorney General of the United States under <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s516">section 516 of title 28</ref> to conduct litigation on behalf of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbb73271f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/642/s16">Pub. L. 89–642, § 16</ref>, <date date="1966-10-11">Oct. 11, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/890">80 Stat. 890</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tVIII/s816">Pub. L. 97–35, title VIII, § 816</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/531">95 Stat. 531</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/193/tVII/s728">Pub. L. 104–193, title VII, § 728</ref>, <date date="1996-08-22">Aug. 22, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2302">110 Stat. 2302</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/78/tVII/s752/b/16">Pub. L. 106–78, title VII, § 752(b)(16)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-22">Oct. 22, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1170">113 Stat. 1170</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbb732720-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbb732721-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbb732722-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/act/1946-06-04/ch281">act June 4, 1946, ch. 281</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/230">60 Stat. 230</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 13 (§ 1751 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1751">section 1751 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbb732723-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/106/78">Pub. L. 106–78</ref> substituted “Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act” for “National School Lunch Act” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/193">Pub. L. 104–193</ref> substituted “be available at any reasonable time” for “at all times be available”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—<ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbb732724-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbb732725-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref> effective <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, see section 820(a)(7)(C), of <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1753">section 1753 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbb732726-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study of Cost Accounting Requirements</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Secretary prohibited from delaying or withholding or causing any State to delay or withhold payments for reimbursement of per meal costs on the basis of noncompliance with full cost accounting procedure unless and until the Secretary has studied additional personnel and training needs of States, local school districts and schools resulting from imposition of requirement to implement full cost accounting procedures, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/105/s21">section 21 of Pub. L. 94–105</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1760">section 1760 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
