<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc03f2de1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s17938"><num value="17938">§ 17938.</num><heading> Business associate contracts required for certain entities</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each organization, with respect to a covered entity, that provides data transmission of protected health information to such entity (or its business associate) and that requires access on a routine basis to such protected health information, such as a Health Information Exchange Organization, Regional Health Information Organization, E-prescribing Gateway, or each vendor that contracts with a covered entity to allow that covered entity to offer a personal health record to patients as part of its electronic health record, is required to enter into a written contract (or other written arrangement) described in section 164.502(e)(2) of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations and a written contract (or other arrangement) described in section 164.308(b) of such title, with such entity and shall be treated as a business associate of the covered entity for purposes of the provisions of this subchapter and subparts C and E of part 164 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations, as such provisions are in effect as of <date date="2009-02-17">February 17, 2009</date>.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idc03f2de2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/111/5/dA/tXIII/s13408">Pub. L. 111–5, div. A, title XIII, § 13408</ref>, <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/271">123 Stat. 271</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc03f2de3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc03f2de4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc03f2de5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subchapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this subtitle”, meaning subtitle D (§ 13400 et seq.) of title XIII of div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/111/5">Pub. L. 111–5</ref>, <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/258">123 Stat. 258</ref>, which is classified principally to this subchapter. For complete classification of subtitle D to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idc03f2de6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idc03f2de7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective 12 months after <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, except as otherwise specifically provided, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/5/s13423">section 13423 of Pub. L. 111–5</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s17931">section 17931 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
