<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc0419f14-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s17951"><num value="17951">§ 17951.</num><heading> Relationship to other laws</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc0419f15-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s17951/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Application of HIPAA State preemption</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Section 1178 of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320d–7">42 U.S.C. 1320d–7</ref>) shall apply to a provision or requirement under this subchapter in the same manner that such section applies to a provision or requirement under part C of title XI of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320d">42 U.S.C. 1320d</ref> et seq.] or a standard or implementation specification adopted or established under sections 1172 through 1174 of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320d–1">42 U.S.C. 1320d–1</ref> to 1320d–3].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc0419f16-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s17951/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The standards governing the privacy and security of individually identifiable health information promulgated by the Secretary under sections 262(a) and 264 of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 shall remain in effect to the extent that they are consistent with this subchapter. The Secretary shall by rule amend such Federal regulations as required to make such regulations consistent with this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc0419f17-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s17951/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this subchapter shall constitute a waiver of any privilege otherwise applicable to an individual with respect to the protected health information of such individual.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc0419f18-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/111/5/dA/tXIII/s13421">Pub. L. 111–5, div. A, title XIII, § 13421</ref>, <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/276">123 Stat. 276</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc0419f19-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc0419f1a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc0419f1b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This subchapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this subtitle”, meaning subtitle D (§ 13400 et seq.) of title XIII of div. A of <ref href="/us/pl/111/5">Pub. L. 111–5</ref>, <date date="2009-02-17">Feb. 17, 2009</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/123/258">123 Stat. 258</ref>, which is classified principally to this subchapter. For complete classification of subtitle D to the Code, see Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Social Security Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/620">49 Stat. 620</ref>. Part C of title XI of the Act is classified generally to part C (§ 1320d et seq.) of subchapter XI of chapter 7 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1305">section 1305 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/pl/104/191">Pub. L. 104–191</ref>, <date date="1996-08-21">Aug. 21, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1936">110 Stat. 1936</ref>. Section 262(a) of the Act enacted sections 1320d to 1320d–8 of this title. Section 264 of the Act is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1320d–2">section 1320d–2 of this title</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1996 Amendments note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">section 201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
