<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc04b1545-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051"><num value="18051">§ 18051.</num><heading> State flexibility to establish basic health programs for low-income individuals not eligible for medicaid</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc04b1546-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc04b1547-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish a basic health program meeting the requirements of this section under which a State may enter into contracts to offer 1 or more standard health plans providing at least the essential health benefits described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s18022/b">section 18022(b) of this title</ref> to eligible individuals in lieu of offering such individuals coverage through an Exchange.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc04b1548-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Certifications as to benefit coverage and costs</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Such program shall provide that a State may not establish a basic health program under this section unless the State establishes to the satisfaction of the Secretary, and the Secretary certifies, that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc04b1549-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> in the case of an eligible individual enrolled in a standard health plan offered through the program, the State provides—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc04b154a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/a/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> that the amount of the monthly premium an eligible individual is required to pay for coverage under the standard health plan for the individual and the individual’s dependents does not exceed the amount of the monthly premium that the eligible individual would have been required to pay (in the rating area in which the individual resides) if the individual had enrolled in the applicable second lowest cost silver plan (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s36B/b/3/B">section 36B(b)(3)(B) of title 26</ref>) offered to the individual through an Exchange; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc04b154b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/a/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> that the cost-sharing an eligible individual is required to pay under the standard health plan does not exceed—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idc04b154c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/a/2/A/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> the cost-sharing required under a platinum plan in the case of an eligible individual with household income not in excess of 150 percent of the poverty line for the size of the family involved; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idc04b154d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/a/2/A/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> the cost-sharing required under a gold plan in the case of an eligible individual not described in subclause (I); and</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc04b154e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the benefits provided under the standard health plans offered through the program cover at least the essential health benefits described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s18022/b">section 18022(b) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">For purposes of subparagraph (A)(i), the amount of the monthly premium an individual is required to pay under either the standard health plan or the applicable second lowest cost silver plan shall be determined after reduction for any premium tax credits and cost-sharing reductions allowable with respect to either plan.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc04b154f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Standard health plan</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “standard heath <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004316">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn004316"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “health”.</note> plan” means a health benefits plan that the State contracts with under this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc04b1550-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> under which the only individuals eligible to enroll are eligible individuals;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc04b1551-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> that provides at least the essential health benefits described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s18022/b">section 18022(b) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc04b1552-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> in the case of a plan that provides health insurance coverage offered by a health insurance issuer, that has a medical loss ratio of at least 85 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc04b1553-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Contracting process</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc04b1554-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A State basic health program shall establish a competitive process for entering into contracts with standard health plans under subsection (a), including negotiation of premiums and cost-sharing and negotiation of benefits in addition to the essential health benefits described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s18022/b">section 18022(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc04b1555-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Specific items to be considered</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A State shall, as part of its competitive process under paragraph (1), include at least the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idc04b1556-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/c/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Innovation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Negotiation with offerors of a standard health plan for the inclusion of innovative features in the plan, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc04b1557-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/c/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> care coordination and care management for enrollees, especially for those with chronic health conditions;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc04b1558-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/c/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> incentives for use of preventive services; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc04b1559-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/c/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the establishment of relationships between providers and patients that maximize patient involvement in health care decision-making, including providing incentives for appropriate utilization under the plan.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idc04b155a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/c/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Health and resource differences</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Consideration of, and the making of suitable allowances for, differences in health care needs of enrollees and differences in local availability of, and access to, health care providers. Nothing in this subparagraph shall be construed as allowing discrimination on the basis of pre-existing conditions or other health status-related factors.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idc04b155b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/c/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Managed care</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Contracting with managed care systems, or with systems that offer as many of the attributes of managed care as are feasible in the local health care market.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idc04b155c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/c/2/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Performance measures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Establishing specific performance measures and standards for issuers of standard health plans that focus on quality of care and improved health outcomes, requiring such plans to report to the State with respect to the measures and standards, and making the performance and quality information available to enrollees in a useful form.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc04b155d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Enhanced availability</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idc04b155e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/c/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Multiple plans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A State shall, to the maximum extent feasible, seek to make multiple standard health plans available to eligible individuals within a State to ensure individuals have a choice of such plans.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idc04b155f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/c/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Regional compacts</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A State may negotiate a regional compact with other States to include coverage of eligible individuals in all such States in agreements with issuers of standard health plans.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc04b1560-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination with other State programs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A State shall seek to coordinate the administration of, and provision of benefits under, its program under this section with the State medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</ref> et seq.], the State child health plan under title XXI of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1397aa">42 U.S.C. 1397aa</ref> et seq.], and other State-administered health programs to maximize the efficiency of such programs and to improve the continuity of care.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc04d8561-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of funds to States</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc04d8562-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Secretary determines that a State electing the application of this section meets the requirements of the program established under subsection (a), the Secretary shall transfer to the State for each fiscal year for which 1 or more standard health plans are operating within the State the amount determined under paragraph (3).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc04d8563-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A State shall establish a trust for the deposit of the amounts received under paragraph (1) and amounts in the trust fund shall only be used to reduce the premiums and cost-sharing of, or to provide additional benefits for, eligible individuals enrolled in standard health plans within the State. Amounts in the trust fund, and expenditures of such amounts, shall not be included in determining the amount of any non-Federal funds for purposes of meeting any matching or expenditure requirement of any federally-funded program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc04d8564-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount of payment</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idc04d8565-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/d/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretarial determination</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idc04d8566-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/d/3/A/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The amount determined under this paragraph for any fiscal year is the amount the Secretary determines is equal to 95 percent of the premium tax credits under <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s36B">section 36B of title 26</ref>, and the cost-sharing reductions under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s18071">section 18071 of this title</ref>, that would have been provided for the fiscal year to eligible individuals enrolled in standard health plans in the State if such eligible individuals were allowed to enroll in qualified health plans through an Exchange established under this subchapter.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idc04d8567-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/d/3/A/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Specific requirements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Secretary shall make the determination under clause (i) on a per enrollee basis and shall take into account all relevant factors necessary to determine the value of the premium tax credits and cost-sharing reductions that would have been provided to eligible individuals described in clause (i), including the age and income of the enrollee, whether the enrollment is for self-only or family coverage, geographic differences in average spending for health care across rating areas, the health status of the enrollee for purposes of determining risk adjustment payments and reinsurance payments that would have been made if the enrollee had enrolled in a qualified health plan through an Exchange, and whether any reconciliation of the credit or cost-sharing reductions would have occurred if the enrollee had been so enrolled. This determination shall take into consideration the experience of other States with respect to participation in an Exchange and such credits and reductions provided to residents of the other States, with a special focus on enrollees with income below 200 percent of poverty.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idc04d8568-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/d/3/A/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> Certification</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The Chief Actuary of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, in consultation with the Office of Tax Analysis of the Department of the Treasury, shall certify whether the methodology used to make determinations under this subparagraph, and such determinations, meet the requirements of clause (ii). Such certifications shall be based on sufficient data from the State and from comparable States about their experience with programs created by this Act.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idc04d8569-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/d/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Corrections</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall adjust the payment for any fiscal year to reflect any error in the determinations under subparagraph (A) for any preceding fiscal year.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc04d856a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Application of special rules</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s18023">section 18023 of this title</ref> shall apply to a State basic health program, and to standard health plans offered through such program, in the same manner as such rules apply to qualified health plans.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc04d856b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible individual</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc04d856c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In this section, the term “eligible individual” means, with respect to any State, an individual—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc04d856d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/e/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> who a <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004317">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn004317"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be preceded by “is”.</note> resident of the State who is not eligible to enroll in the State’s medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</ref> et seq.] for benefits that at a minimum consist of the essential health benefits described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s18022/b">section 18022(b) of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc04d856e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/e/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> whose household income exceeds 133 percent but does not exceed 200 percent of the poverty line for the size of the family involved, or, in the case of an alien lawfully present in the United States, whose income is not greater than 133 percent of the poverty line for the size of the family involved but who is not eligible for the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act by reason of such alien status;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc04d856f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/e/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> who is not eligible for minimum essential coverage (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s5000A/f">section 5000A(f) of title 26</ref>) or is eligible for an employer-sponsored plan that is not affordable coverage (as determined under section 5000A(e)(2) of such title); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc04d8570-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/e/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> who has not attained age 65 as of the beginning of the plan year.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">Such term shall not include any individual who is not a qualified individual under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s18032">section 18032 of this title</ref> who is eligible to be covered by a qualified health plan offered through an Exchange.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc04d8571-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible individuals may not use Exchange</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">An eligible individual shall not be treated as a qualified individual under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s18032">section 18032 of this title</ref> eligible for enrollment in a qualified health plan offered through an Exchange established under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s18031">section 18031 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc04d8572-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretarial oversight</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall each year conduct a review of each State program to ensure compliance with the requirements of this section, including ensuring that the State program meets—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc04d8573-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> eligibility verification requirements for participation in the program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc04d8574-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the requirements for use of Federal funds received by the program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc04d8575-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the quality and performance standards under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc04d8576-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Standard health plan offerors</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A State may provide that persons eligible to offer standard health plans under a basic health program established under this section may include a licensed health maintenance organization, a licensed health insurance insurer, or a network of health care providers established to offer services under the program.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc04d8577-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18051/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any term used in this section which is also used in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s36B">section 36B of title 26</ref> shall have the meaning given such term by such section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc04d8578-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tI/s1331">Pub. L. 111–148, title I, § 1331</ref>, title X, § 10104(<i>o</i>), <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/199">124 Stat. 199</ref>, 902.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc04d8579-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc04d857a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc04d857b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Social Security Act, referred to in subsecs. (c)(4) and (e)(1)(A), (B), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/620">49 Stat. 620</ref>. Titles XIX and XXI of the Act are classified generally to subchapters XIX (§ 1396 et seq.) and XXI (§ 1397aa et seq.), respectively, of chapter 7 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1305">section 1305 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (d)(3)(A)(iii), is <ref href="/us/pl/111/148">Pub. L. 111–148</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/119">124 Stat. 119</ref>, known as the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s18001">section 18001 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idc04d857c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (d)(3)(A)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s10104">Pub. L. 111–148, § 10104</ref>(<i>o</i>)(1), substituted “95 percent” for “85 percent”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s10104">Pub. L. 111–148, § 10104</ref>(<i>o</i>)(2), inserted “, or, in the case of an alien lawfully present in the United States, whose income is not greater than 133 percent of the poverty line for the size of the family involved but who is not eligible for the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act by reason of such alien status” before semicolon at end.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
