<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc04d8632-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18063"><num value="18063">§ 18063.</num><heading> Risk adjustment</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc04d8633-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18063/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc04d8634-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18063/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Low actuarial risk plans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Using the criteria and methods developed under subsection (b), each State shall assess a charge on health plans and health insurance issuers (with respect to health insurance coverage) described in subsection (c) if the actuarial risk of the enrollees of such plans or coverage for a year is less than the average actuarial risk of all enrollees in all plans or coverage in such State for such year that are not self-insured group health plans (which are subject to the provisions of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [<ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1001">29 U.S.C. 1001</ref> et seq.]).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc04d8635-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18063/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> High actuarial risk plans</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Using the criteria and methods developed under subsection (b), each State shall provide a payment to health plans and health insurance issuers (with respect to health insurance coverage) described in subsection (c) if the actuarial risk of the enrollees of such plans or coverage for a year is greater than the average actuarial risk of all enrollees in all plans and coverage in such State for such year that are not self-insured group health plans (which are subject to the provisions of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc04d8636-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18063/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Criteria and methods</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with States, shall establish criteria and methods to be used in carrying out the risk adjustment activities under this section. The Secretary may utilize criteria and methods similar to the criteria and methods utilized under part C or D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395w–21">42 U.S.C. 1395w–21</ref> et seq., 1395w–101 et seq.]. Such criteria and methods shall be included in the standards and requirements the Secretary prescribes under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s18041">section 18041 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc04d8637-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18063/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Scope</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A health plan or a health insurance issuer is described in this subsection if such health plan or health insurance issuer provides coverage in the individual or small group market within the State. This subsection shall not apply to a grandfathered health plan or the issuer of a grandfathered health plan with respect to that plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc04d8638-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tI/s1343">Pub. L. 111–148, title I, § 1343</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/212">124 Stat. 212</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc04d8639-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc04d863a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc04d863b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, referred to in subsec. (a), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/406">Pub. L. 93–406</ref>, <date date="1974-09-02">Sept. 2, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/829">88 Stat. 829</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 18 (§ 1001 et seq.) of Title 29, Labor. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t29/s1001">section 1001 of Title 29</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Social Security Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/620">49 Stat. 620</ref>. Parts C and D of title XVIII of the Act are classified generally to parts C (§ 1395w–21 et seq.) and D (§ 1395w–101 et seq.), respectively, of subchapter XVIII of chapter 7 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1305">section 1305 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
