<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbb9491ed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862r–1"><num value="1862r–1">§ 1862r–1.</num><heading> Dyslexia</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb9491ee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862r–1/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Consistent with subsection (c), the National Science Foundation shall support multi-directorate, merit-reviewed, and competitively awarded research on the science of specific learning disability, including dyslexia, such as research on the early identification of children and students with dyslexia, professional development for teachers and administrators of students with dyslexia, curricula and educational tools needed for children with dyslexia, and implementation and scaling of successful models of dyslexia intervention. Research supported under this subsection shall be conducted with the goal of practical application.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb9491ef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862r–1/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Awards</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To promote development of early career researchers, in awarding funds under subsection (a) the National Science Foundation shall prioritize applications for funding submitted by early career researchers.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb9491f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862r–1/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To prevent unnecessary duplication of research, activities under this this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1862r">section 1862r of this title</ref> shall be coordinated with similar activities supported by other Federal agencies, including research funded by the Institute of Education Sciences and the National Institutes of Health.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb9491f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862r–1/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Funding</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The National Science Foundation shall devote not less than $5,000,000 to research described in subsection (a), which shall include not less than $2,500,000 for research on the science of dyslexia, for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021, subject to the availability of appropriations, to come from amounts made available for the Research and Related Activities account or the Education and Human Resources Directorate under subsection (e). This section shall be carried out using funds otherwise appropriated by law after <date date="2016-02-18">February 18, 2016</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb9491f2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862r–1/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For each of fiscal years 2016 through 2021, there are authorized out of funds appropriated to the National Science Foundation, $5,000,000 to carry out the activities described in subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbb9491f3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/114/124/s4">Pub. L. 114–124, § 4</ref>, <date date="2016-02-18">Feb. 18, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/120">130 Stat. 120</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbb9491f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbb9491f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbb9491f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Research Excellence and Advancements for Dyslexia Act or READ Act, and not as part of the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbb9491f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="idbb9491f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definition of Specific Learning Disability</heading>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/114/124/s5">Pub. L. 114–124, § 5</ref>, <date date="2016-02-18">Feb. 18, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/121">130 Stat. 121</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/124/s5">
<inline>“In this Act [see Short Title of 2016 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1861">section 1861 of this title</ref>], the term ‘specific learning disability’—</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> means a disorder in 1 or more of the basic psychological processes involved in understanding or in using language, spoken or written, which disorder may manifest itself in the imperfect ability to listen, think, speak, read, write, spell, or do mathematical calculations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> includes such conditions as perceptual disabilities, brain injury, minimal brain dysfunction, dyslexia, and developmental aphasia; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> does not include a learning problem that is primarily the result of visual, hearing, or motor disabilities, of intellectual disability, of emotional disturbance, or of environmental, cultural, or economic disadvantage.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
