<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbb9220ac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862p–3"><num value="1862p–3">§ 1862p–3.</num><heading> Sustainable chemistry basic research</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director shall establish a Green Chemistry Basic Research program to award competitive, merit-based grants to support research into green and sustainable chemistry which will lead to clean, safe, and economical alternatives to traditional chemical products and practices. The research program shall provide sustained support for green chemistry research, education, and technology transfer through—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb9220ad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862p–3/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> merit-reviewed competitive grants to individual investigators and teams of investigators, including, to the extent practicable, young investigators, for research;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb9220ae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862p–3/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> grants to fund collaborative research partnerships among universities, industry, and nonprofit organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb9220af-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862p–3/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> symposia, forums, and conferences to increase outreach, collaboration, and dissemination of green chemistry advances and practices; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb9220b0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862p–3/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> education, training, and retraining of undergraduate and graduate students and professional chemists and chemical engineers, including through partnerships with industry, in green chemistry science and engineering.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idbb9220b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/111/358/tV/s509">Pub. L. 111–358, title V, § 509</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4009">124 Stat. 4009</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbb9220b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbb9220b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbb9220b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the America COMPETES Reauthorization Act of 2010, also known as the America Creating Opportunities to Meaningfully Promote Excellence in Technology, Education, and Science Reauthorization Act of 2010, and also as part of the National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2010, and not as part of the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbb9220b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbb9220b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Coordination of Sustainable Chemistry Research and Development</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/329/tI/s114">Pub. L. 114–329, title I, § 114</ref>, <date date="2017-01-06">Jan. 6, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/2993">130 Stat. 2993</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/329/tI/s114">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Importance of Sustainable Chemistry</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the science of chemistry is vital to improving the quality of human life and plays an important role in addressing critical global challenges, including water quality, energy, health care, and agriculture;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> sustainable chemistry can reduce risks to human health and the environment, reduce waste, improve pollution prevention, promote safe and efficient manufacturing, and promote efficient use of resources in developing new materials, processes, and technologies that support viable long-term solutions to a significant number of challenges;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> sustainable chemistry can stimulate innovation, encourage new and creative approaches to problems, create jobs, and save money; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> a coordinated effort on sustainable chemistry will allow for a greater return on research investment in this area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sustainable Chemistry Basic Research</inline>.—</heading><content>Subject to the availability of appropriated funds, the Director of the [National Science] Foundation may continue to carry out the Sustainable Chemistry Basic Research program authorized under section 509 of the National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2010 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1862p–3">42 U.S.C. 1862p–3</ref>).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="idbb9220b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definitions of terms used in this section, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/358/s502">section 502 of Pub. L. 111–358</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1862p">section 1862p of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
