<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbb88837a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862k"><num value="1862k">§ 1862k.</num><heading> Findings; core strategies</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb88837b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862k/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Findings</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Congress finds the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb88837c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862k/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The United States depends upon its scientific and technological capabilities to preserve the military and economic security of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb88837d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862k/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> America’s leadership in the global marketplace is dependent upon a strong commitment to education, basic research, and development.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb88837e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862k/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A nation that is not technologically literate cannot compete in the emerging global economy.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb88837f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862k/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> A coordinated commitment to mathematics and science instruction at all levels of education is a necessary component of successful efforts to produce technologically literate citizens.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb888380-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862k/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Professional development is a necessary component of efforts to produce system-wide improvements in mathematics, engineering, and science education in secondary, elementary, and postsecondary settings.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb888381-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862k/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb888382-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862k/a/6/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The mission of the National Science Foundation is to provide Federal support for basic scientific and engineering research, and to be a primary contributor to mathematics, science, and engineering education at academic institutions in the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb888383-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862k/a/6/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> In accordance with such mission, the long-term goals of the National Science Foundation include providing leadership to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbb888384-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862k/a/6/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> enable the United States to maintain a position of world leadership in all aspects of science, mathematics, engineering, and technology;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbb888385-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862k/a/6/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> promote the discovery, integration, dissemination, and application of new knowledge in service to society; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbb888386-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862k/a/6/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> achieve excellence in United States science, mathematics, engineering, and technology education at all levels.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb888387-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862k/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Core strategies</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out activities designed to achieve the goals described in subsection (a), the Foundation shall use the following core strategies:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb888388-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862k/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Develop intellectual capital, both people and ideas, with particular emphasis on groups and regions that traditionally have not participated fully in science, mathematics, and engineering.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb888389-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862k/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Strengthen the scientific infrastructure by investing in facilities planning and modernization, instrument acquisition, instrument design and development, and shared-use research platforms.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb88838a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862k/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Integrate research and education through activities that emphasize and strengthen the natural connections between learning and inquiry.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbb88838b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1862k/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Promote partnerships with industry, elementary and secondary schools, community colleges, colleges and universities, other agencies, State and local governments, and other institutions involved in science, mathematics, and engineering to enhance the delivery of math and science education and improve the technological literacy of the citizens of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbb88838c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/105/207/tI/s101">Pub. L. 105–207, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1998-07-29">July 29, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/869">112 Stat. 869</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbb88838d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbb88838e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbb88838f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 1998, and not as part of the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbb888390-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbb888391-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Indirect Costs</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/207/tII/s203">Pub. L. 105–207, title II, § 203</ref>, <date date="1998-07-29">July 29, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/875">112 Stat. 875</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/207/tII/s203">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Matching Funds</inline>.—</heading><content>Matching funds required pursuant to section 204(a)(2)(C) of the Academic Research Facilities Modernization Act of 1988 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1862c/a/2/C">42 U.S.C. 1862c(a)(2)(C)</ref>) shall not be considered facilities costs for purposes of determining indirect cost rates under Office of Management and Budget Circular A–21.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in consultation with other Federal agencies the Director deems appropriate, shall prepare a report—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> analyzing the Federal indirect cost reimbursement rates (as the term is defined in Office of Management and Budget Circular A–21) paid to universities in comparison with Federal indirect cost reimbursement rates paid to other entities, such as industry, government laboratories, research hospitals, and nonprofit institutions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> analyzing the distribution of the Federal indirect cost reimbursement rates by category (such as administration, facilities, utilities, and libraries), and by the type of entity; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> determining what factors, including the type of research, influence the distribution;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><chapeau> analyzing the impact, if any, that changes in Office of Management and Budget Circular A–21 have had on—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the Federal indirect cost reimbursement rates, the rate of change of the Federal indirect cost reimbursement rates, the distribution by category of the Federal indirect cost reimbursement rates, and the distribution by type of entity of the Federal indirect cost reimbursement rates; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> the Federal indirect cost reimbursement (as calculated in accordance with Office of Management and Budget Circular A–21), the rate of change of the Federal indirect cost reimbursement, the distribution by category of the Federal indirect cost reimbursement, and the distribution by type of entity of the Federal indirect cost reimbursement;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="D">“(D)</num><content> analyzing the impact, if any, of Federal and State law on the Federal indirect cost reimbursement rates;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="E">“(E)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> analyzing options to reduce or control the rate of growth of the Federal indirect cost reimbursement rates, including options such as benchmarking of facilities and equipment cost, elimination of cost studies, mandated percentage reductions in the Federal indirect cost reimbursement; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> assessing the benefits and burdens of the options to the Federal Government, research institutions, and researchers; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="F">“(F)</num><chapeau> analyzing options for creating a database—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> for tracking the Federal indirect cost reimbursement rates and the Federal indirect cost reimbursement; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> for analyzing the impact that changes in policies with respect to Federal indirect cost reimbursement will have on the Federal Government, researchers, and research institutions.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to congress</inline>.—</heading><content>The report prepared under paragraph (1) shall be submitted to Congress not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-07-29">July 29, 1998</date>].”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbb888392-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Notice; Enhancement of Science and Mathematics Programs</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/207/tII">Pub. L. 105–207, title II</ref>, §§ 205, 206, <date date="1998-07-29">July 29, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/876">112 Stat. 876</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/105/207/tII">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="205">“SEC. 205.</num><heading> NOTICE.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice of Reprogramming</inline>.—</heading><content>If any funds appropriated pursuant to the amendments made by this Act [See Short Title of 1998 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1861">section 1861 of this title</ref>] are subject to a reprogramming action that requires notice to be provided to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives, notice of that action shall concurrently be provided to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, the Committee on Labor and Human Resources [now Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions] of the Senate, and the Committee on Science [now Committee on Science, Space, and Technology] of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Notice of Reorganization</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 15 days before any major reorganization of any program, project, or activity of the National Science Foundation, the Director of the National Science Foundation shall provide notice to the Committees on Science [now Science, Space, and Technology] and Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Commerce, Science and Transportation, Labor and Human Resources [now Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions] of the Senate, and Appropriations of the Senate.</content>
</subsection>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I580467"><num value="206">“SEC. 206.</num><heading> ENHANCEMENT OF SCIENCE AND MATHEMATICS PROGRAMS.</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Educationally useful federal equipment</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘educationally useful Federal equipment’ means computers and related peripheral tools and research equipment that is appropriate for use in schools.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">School</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘school’ means a public or private educational institution that serves any of the grades of kindergarten through grade 12.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Sense of the Congress.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>It is the sense of the Congress that the Director should, to the greatest extent practicable and in a manner consistent with applicable Federal law (including Executive Order No. 12999 [<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s549">40 U.S.C. 549</ref> note]), donate educationally useful Federal equipment to schools in order to enhance the science and mathematics programs of those schools.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Reports.—</inline></heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-07-29">July 29, 1998</date>], and annually thereafter, the Director shall prepare and submit to the President a report that meets the requirements of this paragraph. The President shall submit that report to Congress at the same time as the President submits a budget request to Congress under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105/a">section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, United States Code.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Contents of report</inline>.—</heading><content>The report prepared by the Director under this paragraph shall describe any donations of educationally useful Federal equipment to schools made during the period covered by the report.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="idbb888393-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/105/207/s2">Pub. L. 105–207, § 2</ref>, <date date="1998-07-29">July 29, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/869">112 Stat. 869</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/107/368/s14/b/3">Pub. L. 107–368, § 14(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="2002-12-19">Dec. 19, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/3057">116 Stat. 3057</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/368/s14/b/3">
<inline>“In this Act [see Short Title of 1998 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1861">section 1861 of this title</ref>]:</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Director</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Director’ means the Director of the National Science Foundation established under section 2 of the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1861">42 U.S.C. 1861</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Foundation</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Foundation’ means the National Science Foundation established under section 2 of the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1861">42 U.S.C. 1861</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Full life-cycle cost</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘full life-cycle cost’ means all costs of planning, development, procurement, construction, operations and support, and shut-down costs, without regard to funding source and without regard to what entity manages the project or facility involved.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Board</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Board’ means the National Science Board established under section 2 of the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1861">42 U.S.C. 1861</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">United states</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘United States’ means the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">National research facility</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘national research facility’ means a research facility funded by the Foundation which is available, subject to appropriate policies allocating access, for use by all scientists and engineers affiliated with research institutions located in the United States.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
