<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbb994cd2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1869"><num value="1869">§ 1869.</num><heading> Scholarships and graduate fellowships</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb994cd3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1869/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Foundation is authorized to award scholarships and graduate fellowships for study and research in the sciences or in engineering at appropriate nonprofit American or nonprofit foreign institutions selected by the recipient of such aid, for stated periods of time. Persons shall be selected for such scholarships and fellowships from among citizens, nationals or lawfully admitted permanent resident aliens of the United States, and such selections shall be made solely on the basis of ability; but in any case in which two or more applicants for scholarships or fellowships, as the case may be, are deemed by the Foundation to be possessed of substantially equal ability, and there are not sufficient scholarships or fellowships, as the case may be, available to grant one to each of such applicants, the available scholarship or scholarships or fellowship or fellowships shall be awarded to the applicants in such manner as will tend to result in a wide distribution of scholarships and fellowships throughout the United States and as will address national workforce demand in critical STEM fields. Nothing contained in this chapter shall prohibit the Foundation from refusing or revoking a scholarship or fellowship award, in whole or in part, in the case of any applicant or recipient, if the Board is of the opinion that such award is not in the best interests of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb994cd4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1869/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director shall establish for each year the amount to be awarded for scholarships and fellowships under this section for that year. Each such scholarship and fellowship shall include a cost of education allowance of at least $16,000, subject to any restrictions on the use of cost of education allowance as determined by the Director.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbb994cd5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1869/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Outreach</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director shall ensure program outreach to recruit fellowship applicants from fields of study that are in areas of critical national need from all regions of the country, and from historically underrepresented populations in STEM.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbb994cd6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1950-05-10/ch171/s10">May 10, 1950, ch. 171, § 10</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/152">64 Stat. 152</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/232/s5">Pub. L. 86–232, § 5</ref>, <date date="1959-09-08">Sept. 8, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/468">73 Stat. 468</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/550">Pub. L. 86–550</ref>, <date date="1960-06-29">June 29, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/256">74 Stat. 256</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/835/s2">Pub. L. 87–835, § 2</ref>, <date date="1962-10-16">Oct. 16, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/1070">76 Stat. 1070</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/407/s8">Pub. L. 90–407, § 8</ref>, <date date="1968-07-18">July 18, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/364">82 Stat. 364</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/159/tI/s110/a/13">Pub. L. 99–159, title I, § 110(a)(13)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-22">Nov. 22, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/891">99 Stat. 891</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/383/s7/c">Pub. L. 99–383, § 7(c)</ref>, <date date="1986-08-21">Aug. 21, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/814">100 Stat. 814</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/589/tIII/s302/c">Pub. L. 101–589, title III, § 302(c)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2895">104 Stat. 2895</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/358/tV/s510/d">Pub. L. 111–358, title V, § 510(d)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4010">124 Stat. 4010</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/167/dB/tIII/s10313/b/2">Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title III, § 10313(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/1524">136 Stat. 1524</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbb994cd7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbb994cd8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbb994cd9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/117/167/s10313/b/2/A">Pub. L. 117–167, § 10313(b)(2)(A)</ref>, inserted “and as will address national workforce demand in critical STEM fields” after “throughout the United States”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/117/167/s10313/b/2/B">Pub. L. 117–167, § 10313(b)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “of at least $16,000” for “of $12,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/117/167/s10313/b/2/C">Pub. L. 117–167, § 10313(b)(2)(C)</ref>, added subsec. (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—<ref href="/us/pl/111/358">Pub. L. 111–358</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), inserted heading, and added subsec. (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—<ref href="/us/pl/101/589">Pub. L. 101–589</ref> substituted “, nationals or lawfully admitted permanent resident aliens” for “or nationals” in second sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—<ref href="/us/pl/99/383">Pub. L. 99–383</ref> struck out “, within the limits of funds made available specifically for such purpose pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1875">section 1875 of this title</ref>,” after “The Foundation is authorized to award”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—<ref href="/us/pl/99/159">Pub. L. 99–159</ref> substituted “study and research in the sciences or in engineering” for “scientific study or scientific work in the mathematical, physical, medical, biological, engineering, social, and other sciences”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—<ref href="/us/pl/90/407">Pub. L. 90–407</ref> inserted social sciences to the enumerated list of sciences, and substituted “throughout the United States” for “among the States, Territories, possessions, and the District of Columbia”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—<ref href="/us/pl/87/835">Pub. L. 87–835</ref> authorized the Foundation to refuse or revoke a scholarship or fellowship award if they believe such award is not in the best interests of the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1960—<ref href="/us/pl/86/550">Pub. L. 86–550</ref> authorized the selection of nationals for scholarships and fellowships.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1959—<ref href="/us/pl/86/232">Pub. L. 86–232</ref> substituted “appropriate” for “accredited” and struck out “of higher education” after “foreign institutions”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbb994cda-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbb994cdb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Graduate Student Support</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/358/tV/s510/a">Pub. L. 111–358, title V, § 510(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4010">124 Stat. 4010</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/358/tV/s510/a">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Finding</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Congress finds that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the Integrative Graduate Education and Research Traineeship program is an important program for training the next generation of scientists and engineers in team-based interdisciplinary research and problem solving, and for providing them with the many additional skills, such as communication skills, needed to thrive in diverse STEM careers; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> the Integrative Graduate Education and Research Traineeship program is no less valuable to the preparation and support of graduate students than the Foundation’s Graduate Research Fellowship program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Equal Treatment of IGERT and GRF</inline>.—</heading><content>Beginning in fiscal year 2011, the Director shall increase or, if necessary, decrease funding for the Foundation’s Integrative Graduate Education and Research Traineeship program (or any program by which it is replaced) at least at the same rate as it increases or decreases funding for the Graduate Research Fellowship program.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of terms used in section 510(a), (b) of <ref href="/us/pl/111/358">Pub. L. 111–358</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/111/358/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 111–358</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6621">section 6621 of this title</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/111/358/s502">section 502 of Pub. L. 111–358</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1862p">section 1862p of this title</ref>.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbb994cdc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Continuation of Existing Offices, Procedures, and Organization of the National Science Foundation</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/90/407">Pub. L. 90–407</ref> intended to continue in effect the existing offices, procedures, and organization of the Foundation, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/407/s16">section 16 of Pub. L. 90–407</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1862">section 1862 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
