<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbb994d26-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1872"><num value="1872">§ 1872.</num><heading> International cooperation and coordination with foreign policy</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb994d27-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1872/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The Foundation is authorized to cooperate in any international scientific or engineering activities consistent with the purposes of this chapter and to expend for such international scientific or engineering activities such sums within the limit of appropriated funds as the Foundation may deem desirable. The Director may defray the expenses of representatives of Government agencies and other organizations and of individual scientists or engineers to accredited international scientific or engineering congresses and meetings whenever he deem <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003223">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003223"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “deems”.</note> it necessary in the promotion of the objectives of this chapter. In this connection, with the approval of the Secretary of State, the Foundation may undertake programs granting fellowships to, or making other similar arrangements with, foreign nationals for study and research in the sciences or in engineering in the United States without regard to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1869">section 1869 of this title</ref> or the affidavit of allegiance to the United States required by section 1874(d)(2) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003224">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003224"><num>2</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb9b9618-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1872/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb9b9619-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1872/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The authority to enter into contracts or other arrangements with organizations or individuals in foreign countries and with agencies of foreign countries, as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1870/c">section 1870(c) of this title</ref>, and the authority to cooperate in international scientific or engineering activities as provided in subsection (a) of this section, shall be exercised only with the approval of the Secretary of State, to the end that such authority shall be exercised in such manner as is consistent with the foreign policy objectives of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbb9b961a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1872/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If, in the exercise of the authority referred to in paragraph (1) of this subsection, negotiation with foreign countries or agencies thereof becomes necessary, such negotiation shall be carried on by the Secretary of State in consultation with the Director.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbb9b961b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1950-05-10/ch171/s13">May 10, 1950, ch. 171, § 13</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/154">64 Stat. 154</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/232/s7">Pub. L. 86–232, § 7</ref>, <date date="1959-09-08">Sept. 8, 1959</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/73/468">73 Stat. 468</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/407/s10">Pub. L. 90–407, § 10</ref>, <date date="1968-07-18">July 18, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/365">82 Stat. 365</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/159/tI/s110/a/16">Pub. L. 99–159, title I, § 110(a)(16)</ref>, (17), <date date="1985-11-22">Nov. 22, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/891">99 Stat. 891</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbb9b961c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbb9b961d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbb9b961e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1874/d/2">Section 1874(d)(2) of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (a), was redesignated section 1874(c)(2) by <ref href="/us/pl/96/516/s21/b/2">Pub. L. 96–516, § 21(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1980-12-12">Dec. 12, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/3010">94 Stat. 3010</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbb9b961f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/159/s110/a/16">Pub. L. 99–159, § 110(a)(16)</ref>, inserted “or engineering” after “scientific” the first three places appearing and “or engineers” after “scientists” and substituted “study and research in the sciences or in engineering” for “scientific study or scientific work”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/159/s110/a/17">Pub. L. 99–159, § 110(a)(17)</ref>, inserted reference to engineering.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/90/407">Pub. L. 90–407</ref> struck out “, with the approval of the Board,” after “The Director”, and substituted “section 15(d)(2) of this Act” for “section 16(d)(2) of this Act”, which resulted in no change in text because, for purposes of classification, provision was translated as “<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1874/d/2">section 1874(d)(2) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1959—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/86/232">Pub. L. 86–232</ref> authorized the Foundation, with approval of the Secretary of State, to cooperate in scientific activities rather than scientific research activities, and to grant fellowships or make other arrangements with foreign nationals for scientific study or scientific work in the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/86/232">Pub. L. 86–232</ref> struck out “research” from phrase “scientific research activities”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbb9b9620-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbb9b9621-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Continuation of Existing Offices, Procedures, and Organization of the National Science Foundation</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/90/407">Pub. L. 90–407</ref> intended to continue in effect the existing offices, procedures, and organization of the Foundation, see <ref href="/us/pl/90/407/s16">section 16 of Pub. L. 90–407</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1862">section 1862 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
