<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc0713b11-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18937"><num value="18937">§ 18937.</num><heading> Artificial intelligence</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director shall continue to support the development of artificial intelligence and data science, and carry out the activities of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 authorized in division E of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</ref>), including through—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc0713b12-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18937/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> expanding the Institute’s capabilities, including scientific staff and research infrastructure;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc0713b13-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18937/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> supporting measurement research and development for advanced computer chips and hardware designed for artificial intelligence systems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc0713b14-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18937/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> supporting the development of technical standards and guidelines that promote safe and trustworthy artificial intelligence systems, such as enhancing the accuracy, explainability, privacy, reliability, robustness, safety, security, and mitigation of harmful bias in artificial intelligence systems;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc0713b15-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18937/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> creating a framework for managing risks associated with artificial intelligence systems; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc0713b16-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18937/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> developing and publishing cybersecurity tools, encryption methods, and best practices for artificial intelligence and data science.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idc0713b17-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/117/167/dB/tII/s10232/a">Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title II, § 10232(a)</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/1484">136 Stat. 1484</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc0713b18-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc0713b19-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idc0713b1a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020, referred to in introductory provisions of subsec. (a), is div. E of <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/4523">134 Stat. 4523</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 119 of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of div. E to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s9401">section 9401 of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Division E of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021, referred to in introductory provisions of subsec. (a), is div. E of <ref href="/us/pl/116/283">Pub. L. 116–283</ref>, <date date="2021-01-01">Jan. 1, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/3388">134 Stat. 3388</ref>, also known as the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
