<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc0713b37-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951"><num value="18951">§ 18951.</num><heading> International standards development</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc0713b38-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Sense of Congress</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the sense of Congress that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc0713b39-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the principles of openness, transparency, due process, balance of interests, appeals, and consensus in the development of international standards are critical;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc0713b3a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> voluntary consensus standards, developed through an industry-led process, serve as the cornerstone of the United States standardization system and have become the basis of a sound national economy and the key to global market access;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc0713b3b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> strengthening the unique United States public-private partnerships approach to standards development is critical to United States economic competitiveness; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc0713b3c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the United States Government should ensure cooperation and coordination across Federal agencies to partner with and support private sector stakeholders to continue to shape international dialogues in regard to standards development for emerging technologies.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc0713b3d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> International standards engagement</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc0713b3e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director shall lead information exchange and coordination among Federal agencies and communication from Federal agencies to the private sector of the United States to ensure effective Federal engagement in the development and use of international technical standards.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc0713b3f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">To support private sector-led engagement and ensure effective Federal engagement in the development and use of international technical standards, the Director shall consider—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc0713b40-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the role and needs of the Federal Government with respect to international technical standards;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc0713b41-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> organizations developing international technical standards of interest to the United States, United States representation and influence in these organizations, and key contributors for technical and leadership expertise in these organizations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc0713b42-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> support for persons with domain subject matter expertise, especially from small businesses located in the United States, to influence and engage in technical standards leadership positions, working groups and meetings;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc0713b43-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> opportunities for partnerships for supporting international technical standards from across the Federal Government, Federally funded research and development centers, university-affiliated research centers, institutions of higher education, industry, industry associations, nonprofit organizations, and other key contributors;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc0713b44-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/b/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> support for activities to encourage the adoption of technical standards developed in the United States to be adopted by international standards organizations; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc0713b45-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/b/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> other activities determined by the Director to be necessary to support United States participation in international standards development, economic competitiveness, and national security in the development and use of international technical standards.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc0713b46-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Capacity building guidance</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director shall support education and workforce development efforts to promote United States participation in international standards organizations. The Director shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc0713b47-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> identify and create, as appropriate, technical standards education and training resources for interested businesses, industry associations, academia, nonprofit organizations, Federal agencies, and other relevant standards contributors, including activities targeted at integrating standards content into undergraduate and graduate curricula in science, engineering, business, public policy, and law;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc0713b48-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> conduct outreach, including to private sector leaders, to support engagement by more United States stakeholders in international technical standards development; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc0713b49-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> other activities determined necessary by the Director to support increased engagement, influence, and leadership of United States organizations in the development of international technical standards.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc0713b4a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Capacity building pilot program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc0713b4b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director, in coordination with the Director of the National Science Foundation, and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, as appropriate, shall establish or enter into cooperative agreements with appropriate nongovernmental organizations to establish a 5-year pilot program to award grants, on a merit-reviewed, competitive basis, to private sector entities, institutions of higher education, or nonprofit institutions based in the United States to support increased participation and leadership by small business and academic interests in international standards organizations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc0713b4c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Grants awarded to eligible entities under this subsection may be used to cover reasonable costs, up to a specified ceiling set by the Director, of activities to support increased engagement and leadership of eligible entity employees in international standards organizations, which may include costs associated with—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc0713b4d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> travel;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc0713b4e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> education and training;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc0713b4f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> dues or fees related to participation in technical standards development activities; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc0713b50-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> other such costs that the Director determines may reasonably support participation of the eligible entity in international standards organizations.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc0713b51-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Award criteria</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director shall ensure that award decisions made under this subsection take into account the extent to which the eligible entity—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc0713b52-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> employs full-time an individual or individuals who demonstrate deep technical standards expertise;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc0713b53-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> employs full-time an individual or individuals who demonstrate knowledge with the processes of the standards development organization in which the eligible entity intends to engage using grant funds;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc0713b54-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> proposes a feasible set of standard deliverables to be completed over the period of the grant;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc0713b55-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> explains how the eligible entity will fund additional standards-related activities necessary to achieve the deliverables referred to in subparagraph (C) if the grant funds are insufficient to cover all costs of such activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc0713b56-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> commits personnel with appropriate expertise to regularly engage in relevant international organizations responsible for developing technical standards over the period of the grant; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc0713b57-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d/3/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> identifies a clearly defined current or anticipated market need or gap that would be addressed by their standards development proposal.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc0713b58-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A small business concern (as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s632">section 632 of title 15</ref> based in the United States, an institution of higher education, or a nonprofit institution (as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s3703">section 3703 of title 15</ref>) shall be eligible to receive grants under this program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc0713b59-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Guidance on application and award process</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director shall develop, and periodically update, guidance, including eligibility, applicant disclosure requirements, grant amount and duration, the merit review process, priority areas for standards development, and any additional requirements for how grants are awarded under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc0713b5a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Merit review process</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director shall ensure that grants under this subsection are awarded based on a competitive, merit review process including the use of merit review panels that may include experts from both government, the private sector, and, as appropriate, academic, nonprofit, or other organizations as the Director determines appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc0713b5b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In carrying out the pilot program established under this subsection, the Director shall consult with other Federal agencies, private sector organizations, institutions of higher education, and nonprofit organizations to help inform the pilot program, including the guidance developed under paragraph (5).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc0713b5c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director shall brief Congress after the second year of the pilot program and each year following that includes the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc0713b5d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> An assessment of the effectiveness of the pilot program for improving the participation of United States small businesses, United States institutions of higher education, or other nonprofit research institutions in international standards organizations, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc0713b5e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d/8/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the type of activities supported, including leadership roles;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc0713b5f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d/8/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the international standards organizations participated in; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idc0713b60-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d/8/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the technical areas covered by the activities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc0713b61-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18951/d/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> If determined effective, a plan for permanent implementation of the pilot program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc0713b62-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/117/167/dB/tII/s10245">Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title II, § 10245</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/1488">136 Stat. 1488</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
