<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc073acc8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18996"><num value="18996">§ 18996.</num><heading> Cybersecurity workforce data initiative</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director, acting through the National Center for Science and Engineering Statistics established in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1862p">section 1862p of this title</ref> and in coordination with the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology and other appropriate Federal statistical agencies, shall establish a cybersecurity workforce data initiative that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc073acc9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18996/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> assesses the feasibility of providing nationally representative estimates and statistical information on the cybersecurity workforce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc073acca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18996/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> utilizes the National Initiative for Cybersecurity Education (NICE) Cybersecurity Workforce Framework (NIST Special Publication 800–181), or other frameworks, as appropriate, to enable a consistent measurement of the cybersecurity workforce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc073accb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18996/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> utilizes and complements existing data on employer requirements and unfilled positions in the cybersecurity workforce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc073accc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18996/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> consults key stakeholders and the broader community of practice in cybersecurity workforce development to determine data requirements needed to strengthen the cybersecurity workforce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc073accd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18996/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> evaluates existing Federal survey data for information pertinent to developing national estimates of the cybersecurity workforce;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc073acce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18996/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> evaluates administrative data and other supplementary data sources, as available, to describe and measure the cybersecurity workforce; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc073accf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s18996/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> collects statistical data, to the greatest extent practicable, on credential attainment and employment outcomes information for the cybersecurity workforce.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idc075f4c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/117/167/dB/tIII/s10317">Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title III, § 10317</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/1531">136 Stat. 1531</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
