<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idc081dcd1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181"><num value="19181">§ 19181.</num><heading> Agency responsibilities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc081dcd2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In consultation with outside stakeholders and the heads of Federal research agencies and the Interagency Working Group on Inclusion in STEM, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall develop a uniform set of policy guidelines for Federal research agencies to carry out a sustained program of outreach activities to increase clarity, transparency, and accountability for Federal research agency investments in STEM education and research activities at HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs, including such institutions in rural areas.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc081dcd3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Outreach activities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In developing policy guidelines under subsection (a) the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall include guidelines that require each Federal research agency—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc081dcd4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> to designate a liaison for HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs responsible for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc081dcd5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> enhancing direct communication with HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs to increase the Federal research agency’s understanding of the capacity and needs of such institutions and to raise awareness of available Federal funding opportunities at such institutions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc081dcd6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> coordinating programs, activities, and initiatives while accounting for the capacity and needs of HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc081dcd7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> tracking Federal research agency investments in and engagement with HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc081dcd8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> reporting progress toward increasing participation of HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs in award programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc081dcd9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to the extent practicable, to produce an annual summary of funding opportunities and proposal deadlines targeted at HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs, including for grants, contracts, subcontracts, and cooperative agreements;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc081dcda-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> to the extent practicable, identifying in annual budget requests potential areas for collaboration with HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs in the relevant fiscal year, including relating to potential meetings and workshops;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc081dcdb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> to investigate proposal structures that support broader participation by emerging research institutions, including HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc081dcdc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> to conduct on-site reviews of research facilities at HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs, as practicable, and make recommendations regarding strategies for becoming more competitive in research;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc081dcdd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> to hold geographically accessible or virtual workshops on research priorities of the Federal research agency and on how to write competitive award proposals and how to bolster award management capacity for the entire award lifecycle, from application to completion;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc081dcde-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> to ensure opportunities for HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs to directly communicate with Federal research agency officials responsible for managing competitive award programs in order to receive feedback on research ideas and proposals, including guidance on the Federal research agency’s merit review process; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idc081dcdf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><chapeau> to foster mutually beneficial public-private collaboration among Federal research agencies, industry, Federal laboratories, academia, and nonprofit organizations to—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc081dce0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/b/8/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> identify alternative sources of funding for STEM education and research at HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc081dce1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/b/8/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> provide access to high-quality, relevant research experiences for students and faculty of HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc081dce2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/b/8/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> expand the professional networks of students and faculty of HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc081dce3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/b/8/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> broaden STEM educational opportunities for students and faculty of HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc081dce4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/b/8/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> support the transition of students of HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs into the STEM workforce; <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn004398">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn004398"><num>1</num> So in original. The semicolon probably should be a period.</note></content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc081dce5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Strategic plan</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc081dce6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than one year after <date date="2022-08-09">August 9, 2022</date>, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in collaboration with the head of each Federal research agency, shall submit to Congress a report containing a strategic plan which reflects the plans of each Federal research agency to increase the capacity of HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs to compete effectively for grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements and to encourage HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs to participate in Federal programs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idc081dce7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Considerations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In developing a strategic plan under paragraph (1), the Director and the head of each Federal research agency shall consider the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc081dce8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Issuing new or expanding existing funding opportunities targeted to HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc081dce9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Modifying existing research and development program solicitations to incentivize effective partnerships with HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc081dcea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/c/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Offering planning grants for HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs to develop or equip grant offices with the requisite depth of knowledge to submit competitive grant proposals and manage awarded grants.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc081dceb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/c/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Offering additional training programs, including individualized and timely guidance to grant officers, faculty, and postdoctoral researchers at HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs to ensure their understanding of the requirements for an effective grant proposal.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idc081dcec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/c/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> Other approaches for making current competitive funding models more accessible for underresourced HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idc081dced-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s19181/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Report on policy guidelines</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than two years after <date date="2022-08-09">August 9, 2022</date>, and every five years thereafter, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall report to Congress on the implementation by Federal research agencies of the policy guidelines developed under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idc081dcee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/117/167/dB/tV/s10522">Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title V, § 10522</ref>, <date date="2022-08-09">Aug. 9, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/1620">136 Stat. 1620</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idc081dcef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idc081dcf0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idc081dcf1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of <ref href="/us/pl/117/167/s10522">section 10522 of Pub. L. 117–167</ref>. Subsec. (e) of <ref href="/us/pl/117/167/s10522">section 10522 of Pub. L. 117–167</ref> amended <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s6621">section 6621 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
