<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbba532f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962a–3"><num value="1962a–3">§ 1962a–3.</num><heading> Review of river basin commission plans; report to President and Congress</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon receipt of a plan or revision thereof from any river basin commission under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1962b–3/3">section 1962b–3(3) of this title</ref>, the Council shall review the plan or revision with special regard to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbba532f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962a–3/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the efficacy of such plan or revision in achieving optimum use of the water and related land resources in the area involved;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbba532f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962a–3/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the effect of the plan on the achievement of other programs for the development of agricultural, urban, energy, industrial, recreational, fish and wildlife, and other resources of the entire Nation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbba532f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962a–3/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the contributions which such plan or revision will make in obtaining the Nation’s economic and social goals.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Based on such review the Council shall—</continuation>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbba532fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962a–3/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> formulate such recommendations as it deems desirable in the national interest; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbba532fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962a–3/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> transmit its recommendations, together with the plan or revision of the river basin commission and the views, comments, and recommendations with respect to such plan or revision submitted by any Federal agency, Governor, interstate commission, or United States section of an international commission, to the President for his review and transmittal to the Congress with his recommendations in regard to authorization of Federal projects.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbba532fc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/80/tI/s104">Pub. L. 89–80, title I, § 104</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/245">79 Stat. 245</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbba532fd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbba532fe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idbba532ff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Ex. Ord. No. 11747. Delegation of Presidential Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 11747, eff. <date date="1973-11-07">Nov. 7, 1973</date>, 38 F.R. 30993, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 12608, <date date="1987-09-09">Sept. 9, 1987</date>, 52 F.R. 34617, provided:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">By virtue of the authority vested in me by <ref href="/us/usc/t3/s301">section 301 of title 3</ref> of the United States Code, and as President of the United States, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Chairman of the Water Resources Council is designated and empowered to exercise, without the approval, ratification, or other action of the President, the approval function for standards and procedures vested in the President by section 103 of the Water Resources Planning Act, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1962a–2">42 U.S.C. 1962a–2</ref>).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
