<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbba5336e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962c–2"><num value="1962c–2">§ 1962c–2.</num><heading> State programs; approval by Council; submission; requirements; notice and hearing prior to disapproval</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Council shall approve any program for comprehensive water and related land resources planning which is submitted by a State, if such program—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbba7a46f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962c–2/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> provides for comprehensive planning with respect to intrastate or interstate water resources, or both, in such State to meet the needs for water and water-related activities taking into account prospective demands for all purposes served through or affected by water and related land resources development, with adequate provision for coordination with all Federal, State, and local agencies, and nongovernmental entities having responsibilities in affected fields;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbba7a470-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962c–2/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> provides, where comprehensive statewide development planning is being carried on with or without assistance under section 701 of the Housing Act of 1954 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003227">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003227"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> or under chapter 2003 of title 54, for full coordination between comprehensive water resources planning and other statewide planning programs and for assurances that such water resources planning will be in conformity with the general development policy in such State;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbba7a471-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962c–2/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> designates a State agency (hereinafter referred to as the “State agency”) to administer the program;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbba7a472-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962c–2/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> provides that the State agency will make such reports in such form and containing such information as the Council from time to time reasonably requires to carry out its functions under this subchapter;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbba7a473-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962c–2/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> sets forth the procedure to be followed in carrying out the State program and in administering such program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbba7a474-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962c–2/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> provides such accounting, budgeting, and other fiscal methods and procedures as are necessary for keeping appropriate accountability of the funds and for the proper and efficient administration of the program.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The Council shall not disapprove any program without first giving reasonable notice and opportunity for hearing to the State agency administering such program.</continuation>
<sourceCredit id="idbba7a475-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/80/tIII/s303">Pub. L. 89–80, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/252">79 Stat. 252</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/287/s5/k/1">Pub. L. 113–287, § 5(k)(1)</ref>, <date date="2014-12-19">Dec. 19, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/3269">128 Stat. 3269</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbba7a476-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbba7a477-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbba7a478-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 701 of the Housing Act of 1954, referred to in par. (2), is section 701 of <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-02/ch649">act Aug. 2, 1954, ch. 649</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/640">68 Stat. 640</ref>, which was classified to section 461 of former Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, and was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tIII/s313/b">Pub. L. 97–35, title III, § 313(b)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/398">95 Stat. 398</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbba7a479-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Par. (2). <ref href="/us/pl/113/287">Pub. L. 113–287</ref> substituted “chapter 2003 of title 54” for “the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
