<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbba7a47e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962c–4"><num value="1962c–4">§ 1962c–4.</num><heading> Payments to States; computation of amount</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The method of computing and paying amounts pursuant to this subchapter shall be as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbba7a47f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962c–4/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Council shall, prior to the beginning of each calendar quarter or other period prescribed by it, estimate the amount to be paid to each State under the provisions of this subchapter for such period, such estimate to be based on such records of the State and information furnished by it, and such other investigation, as the Council may find necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbba7a480-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962c–4/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Council shall pay to the State, from the allotment available therefor, the amount so estimated by it for any period, reduced or increased, as the case may be, by any sum (not previously adjusted under this paragraph) by which it finds that its estimate of the amount to be paid such State for any prior period under this subchapter was greater or less than the amount which should have been paid to such State for such prior period under this subchapter. Such payments shall be made through the disbursing facilities of the Treasury Department, at such times and in such installments as the Council may determine.</content>
</paragraph>
<sourceCredit id="idbba7a481-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/80/tIII/s305">Pub. L. 89–80, title III, § 305</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/253">79 Stat. 253</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
