<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbba7a4c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b"><num value="1962d–5b">§ 1962d–5b.</num><heading> Written agreement requirement for water resources projects</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Cooperation of non-Federal interest</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">After <date date="1970-12-31">December 31, 1970</date>, the construction of any water resources project, or an acceptable separable element thereof, by the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, or by a non-Federal interest where such interest will be reimbursed for such construction under any provision of law, shall not be commenced until each non-Federal interest has entered into a written partnership agreement with the Secretary (or, where appropriate, the district engineer for the district in which the project will be carried out) under which each party agrees to carry out its responsibilities and requirements for implementation or construction of the project or the appropriate element of the project, as the case may be; except that no such agreement shall be required if the Secretary determines that the administrative costs associated with negotiating, executing, or administering the agreement would exceed the amount of the contribution required from the non-Federal interest and are less than $25,000.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Liquidated damages</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A partnership agreement described in paragraph (1) may include a provision for liquidated damages in the event of a failure of one or more parties to perform.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Obligation of future appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In any partnership agreement described in paragraph (1) and entered into by a State, or a body politic of the State which derives its powers from the State constitution, or a governmental entity created by the State legislature, the agreement may reflect that it does not obligate future appropriations for such performance and payment when obligating future appropriations would be inconsistent with constitutional or statutory limitations of the State or a political subdivision of the State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Credit for in-kind contributions</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A partnership agreement described in paragraph (1) may provide with respect to a project that the Secretary shall credit toward the non-Federal share of the cost of the project, including a project implemented without specific authorization in law or a project under an environmental infrastructure assistance program, the value of in-kind contributions made by the non-Federal interest, including—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbba7a4c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the costs of planning (including data collection), design, management, mitigation, construction, and construction services that are provided by the non-Federal interest for implementation of the project;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbba7a4c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the value of materials or services provided before execution of the partnership agreement, including efforts on constructed elements incorporated into the project; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbba7a4ca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the value of materials and services provided after execution of the partnership agreement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Condition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary may credit an in-kind contribution under subparagraph (A) only if the Secretary determines that the material or service provided as an in-kind contribution is integral to the project.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Work performed before partnership agreement</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/C/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Construction</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4ce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/C/i/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">In any case in which the non-Federal interest is to receive credit under subparagraph (A) for the cost of construction carried out by the non-Federal interest before execution of a partnership agreement and that construction has not been carried out as of <date date="2007-11-08">November 8, 2007</date>, the Secretary and the non-Federal interest shall enter into an agreement under which the non-Federal interest shall carry out such work and shall do so prior to the non-Federal interest initiating construction or issuing a written notice to proceed for the construction.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4cf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/C/i/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">Construction that is carried out after the execution of an agreement to carry out work described in subclause (I) and any design activities that are required for that construction, even if the design activity is carried out prior to the execution of the agreement to carry out work, shall be eligible for credit.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4d0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/C/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Planning</heading><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/C/ii/I"><num value="I" class="bold">(I)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">In any case in which the non-Federal interest is to receive credit under subparagraph (A) for the cost of planning carried out by the non-Federal interest before execution of a feasibility cost-sharing agreement, the Secretary and the non-Federal interest shall enter into an agreement under which the non-Federal interest shall carry out such work and shall do so prior to the non-Federal interest initiating that planning.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I72" class="indent6 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4d2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/C/ii/II"><num value="II" class="bold">(II)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4">Planning that is carried out by the non-Federal interest after the execution of an agreement to carry out work described in subclause (I) shall be eligible for credit.</p>
</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4d3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Credit authorized under this paragraph for a project—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbba7a4d4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/D/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> shall not exceed the non-Federal share of the cost of the project;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbba7a4d5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/D/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> shall not alter any other requirement that a non-Federal interest provide lands, easements, relocations, rights-of-way, or areas for disposal of dredged material for the project;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbba7a4d6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/D/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> shall not alter any requirement that a non-Federal interest pay a portion of the costs of construction of the project under sections 2211(a)(2) and 2213(a)(1)(A) of title 33; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbba7a4d7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/D/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> shall not exceed the actual and reasonable costs of the materials, services, or other things provided by the non-Federal interest, as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4d8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Analysis of costs and benefits</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the evaluation of the costs and benefits of a project, the Secretary shall not consider construction carried out by a non-Federal interest under this subsection as part of the future without project condition.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4d9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/F"><num value="F" class="bold">(F)</num><heading class="bold"> Transfer of credit between separable elements of a project</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Credit for in-kind contributions provided by a non-Federal interest that are in excess of the non-Federal cost share for an authorized separable element of a project may be applied toward the non-Federal cost share for a different authorized separable element of the same project.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4da-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/G"><num value="G" class="bold">(G)</num><heading class="bold"> Application of credit</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4db-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/G/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">To the extent that credit for in-kind contributions, as limited by subparagraph (D), and credit for required land, easements, rights-of-way, dredged material disposal areas, and relocations provided by the non-Federal interest exceed the non-Federal share of the cost of construction of a project other than a navigation project, the Secretary, subject to the availability of funds, shall enter into a reimbursement agreement with the non-Federal interest, which shall be in addition to a partnership agreement under subparagraph (A), to reimburse the difference to the non-Federal interest.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4dc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/G/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Priority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">If appropriated funds are insufficient to cover the full cost of all requested reimbursement agreements under clause (i), the Secretary shall enter into reimbursement agreements in the order in which requests for such agreements are received.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4dd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/H"><num value="H" class="bold">(H)</num><heading class="bold"> Applicability</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4de-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/H/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">This paragraph shall apply to water resources projects authorized after <date date="1986-11-16">November 16, 1986</date>, including projects initiated after <date date="1986-11-16">November 16, 1986</date>, without specific authorization in law, and to water resources projects authorized prior to <date date="1986-11-17">November 17, 1986</date>, if correction of design deficiencies is necessary.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4/H/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization as addition to other authorizations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The authority of the Secretary to provide credit for in-kind contributions pursuant to this paragraph shall be in addition to any other authorization to provide credit for in-kind contributions and shall not be construed as a limitation on such other authorization. The Secretary shall apply the provisions of this paragraph, in lieu of provisions under other crediting authority, only if so requested by the non-Federal interest.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4e0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition of non-Federal interest</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The term “non-Federal interest” means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbba7a4e1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a legally constituted public body (including an Indian tribe and a tribal organization (as those terms are defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5304">section 5304 of title 25</ref>)) and an inter-tribal consortium (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s3202">section 3202 of title 25</ref>); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbba7a4e2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a nonprofit entity with the consent of the affected local government,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">that has full authority and capability to perform the terms of its agreement and to pay damages, if necessary, in the event of failure to perform.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4e3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Enforcement; jurisdiction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Every agreement entered into pursuant to this section shall be enforcible in the appropriate district court of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4e4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Nonperformance of terms of agreement by non-Federal interest; notice; reasonable opportunity for performance; performance by Chief of Engineers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After commencement of construction of a project, the Chief of Engineers may undertake performance of those items of cooperation necessary to the functioning of the project for its purposes, if he has first notified the non-Federal interest of its failure to perform the terms of its agreement and has given such interest a reasonable time after such notification to so perform.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4e5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Delegation of authority</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than <date date="2008-06-30">June 30, 2008</date>, the Secretary shall issue policies and guidelines for partnership agreements that delegate to the district engineers, at a minimum—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbba7a4e6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the authority to approve any policy in a partnership agreement that has appeared in an agreement previously approved by the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbba7a4e7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the authority to approve any policy in a partnership agreement the specific terms of which are dictated by law or by a final feasibility study, final environmental impact statement, or other final decision document for a water resources project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbba7a4e8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the authority to approve any partnership agreement that complies with the policies and guidelines issued by the Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbba7a4e9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the authority to sign any partnership agreement for any water resources project unless, within 30 days of the date of authorization of the project, the Secretary notifies the district engineer in which the project will be carried out that the Secretary wishes to retain the prerogative to sign the partnership agreement for that project.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4ea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2007-11-08">November 8, 2007</date>, and every year thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report detailing the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbba7a4eb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The number of partnership agreements signed by district engineers and the number of partnership agreements signed by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbba7a4ec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> For any partnership agreement signed by the Secretary, an explanation of why delegation to the district engineer was not appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4ed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Public availability</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 120 days after <date date="2007-11-08">November 8, 2007</date>, the Chief of Engineers shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbba7a4ee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> ensure that each district engineer has made available to the public, including on the Internet, all partnership agreements entered into under this section within the preceding 10 years and all partnership agreements for water resources projects currently being carried out in that district; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbba7a4ef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> make each partnership agreement entered into after <date date="2007-11-08">November 8, 2007</date>, available to the public, including on the Internet, not later than 7 days after the date on which such agreement is entered into.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbba7a4f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section shall not apply to any project the construction of which was commenced before <date date="1972-01-01">January 1, 1972</date>, or to the assurances for future demands required by the Water Supply Act of 1958, as amended [<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s390b">43 U.S.C. 390b</ref>].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbba7a4f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/91/611/tII/s221">Pub. L. 91–611, title II, § 221</ref>, <date date="1970-12-31">Dec. 31, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1831">84 Stat. 1831</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/222/s4">Pub. L. 92–222, § 4</ref>, <date date="1971-12-23">Dec. 23, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/799">85 Stat. 799</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/662/tIX/s912/a">Pub. L. 99–662, title IX, § 912(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/4189">100 Stat. 4189</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dA/tX/s1064/d">Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1064(d)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/445">110 Stat. 445</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/303/tII/s220">Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 220</ref>, <date date="1996-10-12">Oct. 12, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3696">110 Stat. 3696</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/541/tII/s201">Pub. L. 106–541, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="2000-12-11">Dec. 11, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2587">114 Stat. 2587</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/114/tII/s2003/a">Pub. L. 110–114, title II, § 2003(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2007-11-08">Nov. 8, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1067">121 Stat. 1067</ref>, 1069; <ref href="/us/pl/113/121/tI/s1018/a">Pub. L. 113–121, title I, § 1018(a)</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1224">128 Stat. 1224</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/322/tI/s1131">Pub. L. 114–322, title I, § 1131</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1653">130 Stat. 1653</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/270/tI/s1155/b">Pub. L. 115–270, title I, § 1155(b)</ref>, <date date="2018-10-23">Oct. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3793">132 Stat. 3793</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/272/dA/tI/s1137">Pub. L. 118–272, div. A, title I, § 1137</ref>, <date date="2025-01-04">Jan. 4, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/3025">138 Stat. 3025</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbba7a4f2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbba7a4f3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbba7a4f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Water Supply Act of 1958, as amended, referred to in subsec. (h), is <ref href="/us/pl/85/500/tIII/s301">Pub. L. 85–500, title III, § 301</ref>, <date date="1958-07-03">July 3, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/319">72 Stat. 319</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s390b">section 390b of Title 43</ref>, Public Lands.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbba7a4f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Flood Control Act of 1970, and not as part of the Water Resources Planning Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbba7a4f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/118/272">Pub. L. 118–272</ref> inserted “and an inter-tribal consortium (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s3202">section 3202 of title 25</ref>)” after “<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5304">section 5304 of title 25</ref>))”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/115/270">Pub. L. 115–270</ref> substituted “(including an Indian tribe and a tribal organization (as those terms are defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5304">section 5304 of title 25</ref>)); or” for “(including a federally recognized Indian tribe and, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1602">section 1602 of title 43</ref>, a Native village, Regional Corporation, and Village Corporation); or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/114/322">Pub. L. 114–322</ref> inserted “and, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1602">section 1602 of title 43</ref>, a Native village, Regional Corporation, and Village Corporation” after “Indian tribe”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (a)(4)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/113/121/s1018/a/1">Pub. L. 113–121, § 1018(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “or a project under an environmental infrastructure assistance program” after “law” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/113/121/s1018/a/2">Pub. L. 113–121, § 1018(a)(2)</ref>, added text of subpar. (C) and struck out text of former subpar. (C) which read as follows: “In any case in which the non-Federal interest is to receive credit under subparagraph (A)(ii) for the cost of work carried out by the non-Federal interest and such work has not been carried out as of <date date="2007-11-08">November 8, 2007</date>, the Secretary and the non-Federal interest shall enter into an agreement under which the non-Federal interest shall carry out such work, and only work carried out following the execution of the agreement shall be eligible for credit.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4)(D)(iii). <ref href="/us/pl/113/121/s1018/a/3">Pub. L. 113–121, § 1018(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “sections 2211(a)(2) and 2213(a)(1)(A) of title 33” for “sections 2211 and 2213 of title 33”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4)(E) to (H). <ref href="/us/pl/113/121/s1018/a/4">Pub. L. 113–121, § 1018(a)(4)</ref>, (5), added subpars. (E) to (G) and redesignated former subpar. (E) as (H).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4)(H)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/113/121/s1018/a/6/A">Pub. L. 113–121, § 1018(a)(6)(A)</ref>, inserted “, and to water resources projects authorized prior to <date date="1986-11-17">November 17, 1986</date>, if correction of design deficiencies is necessary” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(4)(H)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/113/121/s1018/a/6/B">Pub. L. 113–121, § 1018(a)(6)(B)</ref>, added cl. (ii) and struck out former cl. (ii). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “In any case in which a specific provision of law provides for a non-Federal interest to receive credit toward the non-Federal share of the cost of a study for, or construction or operation and maintenance of, a water resources project, the specific provision of law shall apply instead of this paragraph.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—<ref href="/us/pl/110/114/s2003/a/1">Pub. L. 110–114, § 2003(a)(1)</ref>, inserted section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/110/114/s2003/a/2">Pub. L. 110–114, § 2003(a)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (a) and struck out former subsec. (a), which read as follows: “After <date date="1970-12-31">December 31, 1970</date>, the construction of any water resources project, or an acceptable separable element thereof, by the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, or by a non-Federal interest where such interest will be reimbursed for such construction under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5a">section 1962d–5a of this title</ref> or under any other provision of law, shall not be commenced until each non-Federal interest has entered into a written agreement with the Secretary of the Army to furnish its required cooperation for the project or the appropriate element of the project, as the case may be; except that no such agreement shall be required if the Secretary determines that the administrative costs associated with negotiating, executing, or administering the agreement would exceed the amount of the contribution required from the non-Federal interest and are less than $25,000. In any such agreement entered into by a State, or a body politic of the State which derives its powers from the State constitution, or a governmental entity created by the State legislature, the agreement may reflect that it does not obligate future appropriations for such performance and payment when obligating future appropriations would be inconsistent with constitutional or statutory limitations of the State or a political subdivision of the State.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/110/114/s2003/b">Pub. L. 110–114, § 2003(b)</ref>, inserted heading and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “A non-Federal interest shall be a legally constituted public body with full authority and capability to perform the terms of its agreement and to pay damages, if necessary, in the event of failure to perform.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e) to (h). <ref href="/us/pl/110/114/s2003/c">Pub. L. 110–114, § 2003(c)</ref>, added subsecs. (e) to (g) and redesignated former subsec. (e) as (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/106/541">Pub. L. 106–541</ref> in last sentence, struck out “State legislative” after “obligate future”, substituted “constitutional” for “State constitutional”, and inserted “of the State or a political subdivision of the State” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/104/303">Pub. L. 104–303</ref>, in first sentence, inserted before period at end “; except that no such agreement shall be required if the Secretary determines that the administrative costs associated with negotiating, executing, or administering the agreement would exceed the amount of the contribution required from the non-Federal interest and are less than $25,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (e), (f). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106">Pub. L. 104–106</ref> redesignated subsec. (f) as (e) and struck out former subsec. (e) which read as follows: “The Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, shall maintain a continuing inventory of agreements and the status of their performance, and shall report thereon annually to the Congress.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/99/662">Pub. L. 99–662</ref> inserted “, or an acceptable separable element thereof,”, “or the appropriate element of the project, as the case may be”, and “In any such agreement entered into by a State, or a body politic of the State which derives its powers from the State constitution, or a governmental entity created by the State legislature, the agreement may reflect that it does not obligate future State legislative appropriations for such performance and payment when obligating future appropriations would be inconsistent with State constitutional or statutory limitations.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1971—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/92/222">Pub. L. 92–222</ref> made provisions of section inapplicable to the assurances for future demands required by the Water Supply Act of 1958, as amended.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbba7a4f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbba7a4f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2014 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/121/tI/s1018/c">Pub. L. 113–121, title I, § 1018(c)</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1226">128 Stat. 1226</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/121/tI/s1018/c">“The amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) [amending this section and provisions set out as a note under this section] take effect on <date date="2007-11-08">November 8, 2007</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbba7a4f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2007 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/114/tII/s2003/e">Pub. L. 110–114, title II, § 2003(e)</ref>, <date date="2007-11-08">Nov. 8, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1070">121 Stat. 1070</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/113/121/tI/s1018/b">Pub. L. 113–121, title I, § 1018(b)</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1225">128 Stat. 1225</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/121/tI/s1018/b">“The amendments made by subsections (a), (b), and (d) [amending this section and provisions set out as a note under this section] only apply to partnership agreements entered into after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2007-11-08">Nov. 8, 2007</date>]; except that, at the request of a non-Federal interest for a project, the district engineer for the district in which the project is located may amend a project partnership agreement entered into on or before such date and under which construction on the project, or construction of design deficiency corrections on the project, has not been initiated, or under which construction of the project has not been completed and the work to be performed by the non-Federal interests has not been carried out and is creditable only toward any remaining non-Federal cost share, as of such date of enactment for the purpose of incorporating such amendments.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbba7a4fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Local Government Water Management Plans</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/270/tI/s1164">Pub. L. 115–270, title I, § 1164</ref>, <date date="2018-10-23">Oct. 23, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/3797">132 Stat. 3797</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/270/tI/s1164">“With the consent of the non-Federal interest for a feasibility study for a water resources development project, the Secretary [of the Army] may enter into a written agreement under section 221(a) of the Flood Control Act of 1970 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a">42 U.S.C. 1962d–5b(a)</ref>], with a unit of local government in the watershed that has adopted a local or regional water management plan, to allow the unit of local government to participate in the feasibility study to determine if there is an opportunity to include additional feasible elements in the project in order to help achieve the purposes identified in the local or regional water management plan.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbba7a4fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Water Supply Conservation</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/322/tI/s1116">Pub. L. 114–322, title I, § 1116</ref>, <date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1639">130 Stat. 1639</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dH/tLXXXI/s8107">Pub. L. 117–263, div. H, title LXXXI, § 8107</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3700">136 Stat. 3700</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dH/tLXXXI/s8107">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In a State in which a drought emergency has been declared or was in effect for any portion of any 2 consecutive or nonconsecutive years during the 10-year period preceding a request from a non-Federal interest for assistance under this section, the Secretary [of the Army] is authorized—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> to conduct an evaluation for purposes of approving water supply conservation measures that are consistent with the authorized purposes of water resources development projects under the jurisdiction of the Secretary; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> to enter into written agreements pursuant to section 221 of the Flood Control Act of 1970 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b">42 U.S.C. 1962d–5b</ref>) with non-Federal interests to carry out the conservation measures approved by such evaluations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Eligibility</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Water supply conservation measures evaluated under subsection (a) may include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Stormwater capture.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Releases for ground water replenishment or aquifer storage and recovery.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Releases to augment water supply at another Federal or non-Federal storage facility.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Other conservation measures that enhance usage of a Corps of Engineers project for water supply, including measures utilizing a natural feature or nature-based feature (as those terms are defined in section 1184(a) [<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s2289a/a">33 U.S.C. 2289a(a)</ref>]) to reduce drought risk.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Costs</inline>.—</heading><content>A non-Federal interest shall pay only the separable costs associated with the evaluation, implementation, operation, and maintenance of an approved water supply conservation measure, which payments may be accepted and expended by the Corps of Engineers to cover such costs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Statutory Construction</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Nothing in this section may be construed to modify or alter the obligations of a non-Federal interest under existing or future agreements for—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> water supply storage pursuant to section 301 of the Water Supply Act of 1958 (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s390b">43 U.S.C. 390b</ref>); or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> surplus water use pursuant to <ref href="/us/act/1944-12-22/s6">section 6 of the Act of December 22, 1944</ref> (<ref href="/us/stat/58/890">58 Stat. 890</ref>, chapter 665; <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s708">33 U.S.C. 708</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitations</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Nothing in this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> affects, modifies, or changes the authorized purposes of a Corps of Engineers project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> affects existing Corps of Engineers authorities, including its authorities with respect to navigation, flood damage reduction, and environmental protection and restoration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> affects the Corps of Engineers ability to provide for temporary deviations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> affects the application of a cost-sharing requirement under section 101, 102, or 103 of the Water Resources Development Act of 1986 (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s2211">33 U.S.C. 2211</ref>, 2212, and 2213);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> supersedes or modifies any written agreement between the Federal Government and a non-Federal interest that is in effect on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2016-12-16">Dec. 16, 2016</date>];</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> supersedes or modifies any amendment to an existing multistate water control plan, including those water control plans along the Missouri River and those water control plans in the Apalachicola-Chattahoochee-Flint and Alabama-Coosa-Tallapoosa basins;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> affects any water right in existence on the date of enactment of this Act; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> preempts or affects any State water law ot interstate compact governing water.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbba9edec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Guidelines</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/121/tI/s1018/d">Pub. L. 113–121, title I, § 1018(d)</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1226">128 Stat. 1226</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/121/tI/s1018/d">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>], the Secretary [of the Army] shall update any guidance or regulations for carrying out section 221(a)(4) of the Flood Control Act of 1970 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4">42 U.S.C. 1962d–5b(a)(4)</ref>) (as amended by subsection (a)) that are in existence on the date of enactment of this Act or issue new guidelines, as determined to be appropriate by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Inclusions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Any guidance, regulations, or guidelines updated or issued under paragraph (1) shall include, at a minimum—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the milestone for executing an in-kind memorandum of understanding for construction by a non-Federal interest;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> criteria and procedures for evaluating a request to execute an in-kind memorandum of understanding for construction by a non-Federal interest that is earlier than the milestone under subparagraph (A) for that execution; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> criteria and procedures for determining whether work carried out by a non-Federal interest is integral to a project.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Public and stakeholder participation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Before issuing any new or revised guidance, regulations, or guidelines or any subsequent updates to those documents, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> consult with affected non-Federal interests;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> publish the proposed guidelines developed under this subsection in the Federal Register; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> provide the public with an opportunity to comment on the proposed guidelines.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbba9eded-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Other Credit</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/121/tI/s1018/e">Pub. L. 113–121, title I, § 1018(e)</ref>, <date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1226">128 Stat. 1226</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/121/tI/s1018/e">“Nothing in section 221(a)(4) of the Flood Control Act of 1970 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b/a/4">42 U.S.C. 1962d–5b(a)(4)</ref>) (as amended by subsection (a)) affects any eligibility for credit under section 104 of the Water Resources Development [Act] of 1986 (<ref href="/us/usc/t33/s2214">33 U.S.C. 2214</ref>) that was approved by the Secretary [of the Army] prior to the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2014-06-10">June 10, 2014</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbba9edee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Partnership and Cooperation Agreements; References</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/114/tII/s2003/f">Pub. L. 110–114, title II, § 2003(f)</ref>, <date date="2007-11-08">Nov. 8, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1070">121 Stat. 1070</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/114/tII/s2003/f">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>A goal of agreements entered into under section 221 of the Flood Control Act of 1970 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1962d–5b">42 U.S.C. 1962d–5b</ref>) shall be to further partnership and cooperation, and the agreements shall be referred to as ‘partnership agreements’.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">References to cooperation agreements</inline>.—</heading><content>Any reference in a law, regulation, document, or other paper of the United States to a ‘cooperation agreement’ or ‘project cooperation agreement’ shall be deemed to be a reference to a ‘partnership agreement’ or a ‘project partnership agreement’, respectively.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">References to partnership agreements</inline>.—</heading><content>Any reference to a ‘partnership agreement’ or ‘project partnership agreement’ in this Act [see Short Title of 2007 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s2201">section 2201 of Title 33</ref>, Navigation and Navigable Waters] (other than this section) shall be deemed to be a reference to a ‘cooperation agreement’ or a ‘project cooperation agreement’, respectively.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbba9edef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Compliance With Cooperation Requirements for Non-Federal Interests in Water Resources Projects</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/662/tIX/s912/b">Pub. L. 99–662, title IX, § 912(b)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/4190">100 Stat. 4190</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/110/114/tII/s2003/d">Pub. L. 110–114, title II, § 2003(d)</ref>, <date date="2007-11-08">Nov. 8, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/121/1070">121 Stat. 1070</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/114/tII/s2003/d">
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The Secretary may require compliance with any requirements pertaining to cooperation by non-Federal interests in carrying out any water resources project authorized before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1986-11-17">Nov. 17, 1986</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Whenever on the basis of any information available to the Secretary, the Secretary finds that any non-Federal interest is not providing cooperation required under subsection (a) [amending this section], the Secretary may issue an order requiring such non-Federal interest to provide such cooperation.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> Non-Federal interests shall be liable for interest on any payments required pursuant to section 221 of the Flood Control Act of 1970 [this section] that may fall delinquent. The interest rate to be charged on any such delinquent payment shall be at a rate, to be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, equal to 150 percent of the average bond equivalent rate of the thirteen-week Treasury bills auctioned immediately prior to the date on which such payment became delinquent, or auctioned immediately prior to the beginning of each additional three-month period if the period of delinquency exceeds three months.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The Secretary may request the Attorney General to bring a civil action for appropriate relief, including permanent or temporary injunction, for payment of damages or, for any violation of an order issued under this section, to recover any cost incurred by the Secretary in undertaking performance of any item of cooperation under section 221(d) of the Flood Control Act of 1970 [subsec. (d) of this section], or to collect interest for which a non-Federal interest is liable under paragraph (3). Any action under this subsection may be brought in the district court of the United States for the district in which the defendant is located or resides, or is doing business, and such court shall have jurisdiction to restrain such violation, to require compliance, to require payment of any damages, and to require payment of any costs incurred by the Secretary in undertaking performance of any such item.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> The Secretary is authorized to determine that no funds appropriated for operation and maintenance, including operation and maintenance of the project for flood control, Mississippi River and Tributaries, are to be used for the particular benefit of projects within the jurisdiction of any non-Federal interest when such non-Federal interest is in arrears for more than twenty-four months in the payment of charges due under an agreement entered into with the United States pursuant to section 221 of the Flood Control Act of 1970 (<ref href="/us/pl/91/611">Public Law 91–611</ref>) [this section].”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
