<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbba53300-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962a–4"><num value="1962a–4">§ 1962a–4.</num><heading> Administrative provisions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbba53301-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962a–4/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Hearings, proceedings, evidence, reports; office space; use of mails; personnel; consultants; motor vehicles; necessary expenses; other powers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this chapter, the Council may: (1) hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, receive such evidence, and print or otherwise reproduce and distribute so much of its proceedings and reports thereon as it may deem advisable; (2) acquire, furnish, and equip such office space as is necessary; (3) use the United States mails in the same manner and upon the same conditions as other departments and agencies of the United States; (4) employ and fix the compensation of such personnel as it deems advisable, in accordance with the civil service laws and chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5; (5) procure services as authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3109">section 3109 of title 5</ref>, at rates not in excess of the daily equivalent of the rate prescribed for grade GS–18 under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5332">section 5332 of title 5</ref> in the case of individual experts or consultants; (6) purchase, hire, operate, and maintain passenger motor vehicles; and (7) incur such necessary expenses and exercise such other powers as are consistent with and reasonably required to perform its functions under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbba53302-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962a–4/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Oaths</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any member of the Council is authorized to administer oaths when it is determined by a majority of the Council that testimony shall be taken or evidence received under oath.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbba53303-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962a–4/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Records; public inspection</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To the extent permitted by law, all appropriate records and papers of the Council may be made available for public inspection during ordinary office hours.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbba53304-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962a–4/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Information and personnel from other Federal agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon request of the Council, the head of any Federal department or agency is authorized (1) to furnish to the Council such information as may be necessary for carrying out its functions and as may be available to or procurable by such department or agency, and (2) to detail to temporary duty with such Council on a reimbursable basis such personnel within his administrative jurisdiction as it may need or believe to be useful for carrying out its functions, each such detail to be without loss of seniority, pay, or other employee status.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbba53305-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1962a–4/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Responsibility for personnel and funds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Council shall be responsible for (1) the appointment and supervision of personnel, (2) the assignment of duties and responsibilities among such personnel, and (3) the use and expenditures of funds.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbba53306-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/89/80/tI/s105">Pub. L. 89–80, title I, § 105</ref>, <date date="1965-07-22">July 22, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/246">79 Stat. 246</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/112/s1/b">Pub. L. 94–112, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1975-10-16">Oct. 16, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/575">89 Stat. 575</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbba53307-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbba53308-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbba53309-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (a), “chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5” substituted for “Classification Act of 1949, as amended” and “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s3109">section 3109 of title 5</ref>” substituted for “<ref href="/us/act/1946-08-02/s15">section 15 of the Act of August 2, 1946</ref> (<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s55a">5 U.S.C. 55a</ref>)”, on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/89/554/s7/b">Pub. L. 89–554, § 7(b)</ref>, <date date="1966-09-06">Sept. 6, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/631">80 Stat. 631</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbba5330a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (a)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/94/112">Pub. L. 94–112</ref> substituted “not in excess of the daily equivalent of the rate prescribed for grade GS–18 under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5332">section 5332 of title 5</ref> in the case of individual experts or consultants” for “not to exceed $100 per diem for individuals”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbba5330b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbba5330c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Other Laws to GS–16, 17, or 18 Pay Rates</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References in laws to the rates of pay for GS–16, 17, or 18, or to maximum rates of pay under the General Schedule, to be considered references to rates payable under specified sections of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, see section 529 [title I, § 101(c)(1)] of <ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref>, set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5376">section 5376 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
