<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbbb38b67-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a"><num value="1996a">§ 1996a.</num><heading> Traditional Indian religious use of peyote</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbb38b68-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Congressional findings and declarations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress finds and declares that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbb38b69-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> for many Indian people, the traditional ceremonial use of the peyote cactus as a religious sacrament has for centuries been integral to a way of life, and significant in perpetuating Indian tribes and cultures;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbb38b6a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> since 1965, this ceremonial use of peyote by Indians has been protected by Federal regulation;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbb38b6b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> while at least 28 States have enacted laws which are similar to, or are in conformance with, the Federal regulation which protects the ceremonial use of peyote by Indian religious practitioners, 22 States have not done so, and this lack of uniformity has created hardship for Indian people who participate in such religious ceremonies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbb38b6c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the Supreme Court of the United States, in the case of Employment Division v. Smith, 494 U.S. 872 (1990), held that the First Amendment does not protect Indian practitioners who use peyote in Indian religious ceremonies, and also raised uncertainty whether this religious practice would be protected under the compelling State interest standard; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbb38b6d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the lack of adequate and clear legal protection for the religious use of peyote by Indians may serve to stigmatize and marginalize Indian tribes and cultures, and increase the risk that they will be exposed to discriminatory treatment.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbb38b6e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Use, possession, or transportation of peyote</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbb38b6f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the use, possession, or transportation of peyote by an Indian for bona fide traditional ceremonial purposes in connection with the practice of a traditional Indian religion is lawful, and shall not be prohibited by the United States or any State. No Indian shall be penalized or discriminated against on the basis of such use, possession or transportation, including, but not limited to, denial of otherwise applicable benefits under public assistance programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbb38b70-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> This section does not prohibit such reasonable regulation and registration by the Drug Enforcement Administration of those persons who cultivate, harvest, or distribute peyote as may be consistent with the purposes of this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1996">section 1996 of this title</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbb38b71-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> This section does not prohibit application of the provisions of section 481.111(a) of Vernon’s Texas Health and Safety Code Annotated, in effect on <date date="1994-10-06">October 6, 1994</date>, insofar as those provisions pertain to the cultivation, harvest, and distribution of peyote.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbb38b72-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Nothing in this section shall prohibit any Federal department or agency, in carrying out its statutory responsibilities and functions, from promulgating regulations establishing reasonable limitations on the use or ingestion of peyote prior to or during the performance of duties by sworn law enforcement officers or personnel directly involved in public transportation or any other safety-sensitive positions where the performance of such duties may be adversely affected by such use or ingestion. Such regulations shall be adopted only after consultation with representatives of traditional Indian religions for which the sacramental use of peyote is integral to their practice. Any regulation promulgated pursuant to this section shall be subject to the balancing test set forth in section 3 of the Religious Freedom Restoration Act (<ref href="/us/pl/103/141">Public Law 103–141</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000bb–1">42 U.S.C. 2000bb–1</ref>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbb38b73-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> This section shall not be construed as requiring prison authorities to permit, nor shall it be construed to prohibit prison authorities from permitting, access to peyote by Indians while incarcerated within Federal or State prison facilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbb38b74-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Subject to the provisions of the Religious Freedom Restoration Act (<ref href="/us/pl/103/141">Public Law 103–141</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000bb–1">42 U.S.C. 2000bb–1</ref>) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000bb">42 U.S.C. 2000bb</ref> et seq.], this section shall not be construed to prohibit States from enacting or enforcing reasonable traffic safety laws or regulations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbb38b75-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Subject to the provisions of the Religious Freedom Restoration Act (<ref href="/us/pl/103/141">Public Law 103–141</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000bb–1">42 U.S.C. 2000bb–1</ref>), this section does not prohibit the Secretary of Defense from promulgating regulations establishing reasonable limitations on the use, possession, transportation, or distribution of peyote to promote military readiness, safety, or compliance with international law or laws of other countries. Such regulations shall be adopted only after consultation with representatives of traditional Indian religions for which the sacramental use of peyote is integral to their practice.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbb38b76-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For purposes of this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbb38b77-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the term “Indian” means a member of an Indian tribe;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbb38b78-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the term “Indian tribe” means any tribe, band, nation, pueblo, or other organized group or community of Indians, including any Alaska Native village (as defined in, or established pursuant to, the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">43 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.)), which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbb38b79-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> the term “Indian religion” means any religion—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbbb38b7a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> which is practiced by Indians, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbbb38b7b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the origin and interpretation of which is from within a traditional Indian culture or community; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbb38b7c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the term “State” means any State of the United States, and any political subdivision thereof.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbb38b7d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Protection of rights of Indians and Indian tribes</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed as abrogating, diminishing, or otherwise affecting—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbb38b7e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the inherent rights of any Indian tribe;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbb38b7f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the rights, express or implicit, of any Indian tribe which exist under treaties, Executive orders, and laws of the United States;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbb38b80-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the inherent right of Indians to practice their religions; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbb38b81-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s1996a/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the right of Indians to practice their religions under any Federal or State law.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbbb38b82-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/341/s3">Pub. L. 95–341, § 3</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/103/344/s2">Pub. L. 103–344, § 2</ref>, <date date="1994-10-06">Oct. 6, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3125">108 Stat. 3125</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbbb38b83-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbbb38b84-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbbb38b85-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Religious Freedom Restoration Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(6), (7), probably means the Religious Freedom Restoration Act of 1993, <ref href="/us/pl/103/141">Pub. L. 103–141</ref>, <date date="1993-11-16">Nov. 16, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1488">107 Stat. 1488</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 21B (§ 2000bb et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000bb">section 2000bb of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act, referred to in subsec. (c)(2), is <ref href="/us/pl/92/203">Pub. L. 92–203</ref>, <date date="1971-12-18">Dec. 18, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/688">85 Stat. 688</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 33 (§ 1601 et seq.) of Title 43, Public Lands. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1601">section 1601 of Title 43</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
