<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbbc69e8e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000aa–6"><num value="2000aa–6">§ 2000aa–6.</num><heading> Civil actions by aggrieved persons</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbc69e8f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000aa–6/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Right of action</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A person aggrieved by a search for or seizure of materials in violation of this chapter shall have a civil cause of action for damages for such search or seizure—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbc69e90-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000aa–6/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> against the United States, against a State which has waived its sovereign immunity under the Constitution to a claim for damages resulting from a violation of this chapter, or against any other governmental unit, all of which shall be liable for violations of this chapter by their officers or employees while acting within the scope or under color of their office or employment; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbc69e91-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000aa–6/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> against an officer or employee of a State who has violated this chapter while acting within the scope or under color of his office or employment, if such State has not waived its sovereign immunity as provided in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbc69e92-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000aa–6/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Good faith defense</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be a complete defense to a civil action brought under paragraph (2) of subsection (a) that the officer or employee had a reasonable good faith belief in the lawfulness of his conduct.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbc69e93-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000aa–6/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Official immunity</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The United States, a State, or any other governmental unit liable for violations of this chapter under subsection (a)(1), may not assert as a defense to a claim arising under this chapter the immunity of the officer or employee whose violation is complained of or his reasonable good faith belief in the lawfulness of his conduct, except that such a defense may be asserted if the violation complained of is that of a judicial officer.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbc69e94-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000aa–6/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Exclusive nature of remedy</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The remedy provided by subsection (a)(1) against the United States, a State, or any other governmental unit is exclusive of any other civil action or proceeding for conduct constituting a violation of this chapter, against the officer or employee whose violation gave rise to the claim, or against the estate of such officer or employee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbc69e95-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000aa–6/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Admissibility of evidence</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Evidence otherwise admissible in a proceeding shall not be excluded on the basis of a violation of this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbc69e96-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000aa–6/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Damages; costs and attorneys’ fees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A person having a cause of action under this section shall be entitled to recover actual damages but not less than liquidated damages of $1,000, and such reasonable attorneys’ fees and other litigation costs reasonably incurred as the court, in its discretion, may award: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the United States, a State, or any other governmental unit shall not be liable for interest prior to judgment.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbc69e97-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000aa–6/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Attorney General; claims settlement; regulations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Attorney General may settle a claim for damages brought against the United States under this section, and shall promulgate regulations to provide for the commencement of an administrative inquiry following a determination of a violation of this chapter by an officer or employee of the United States and for the imposition of administrative sanctions against such officer or employee, if warranted.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbc69e98-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000aa–6/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Jurisdiction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The district courts shall have original jurisdiction of all civil actions arising under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbbc69e99-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/440/tI/s106">Pub. L. 96–440, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="1980-10-13">Oct. 13, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1880">94 Stat. 1880</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbbc69e9a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbbc69e9b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idbbc69e9c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1981-01-01">Jan. 1, 1981</date>, except that insofar as such provisions are applicable to a State or any governmental unit other than the United States, the section is effective one year from <date date="1980-10-13">Oct. 13, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/440/s108">section 108 of Pub. L. 96–440</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000aa">section 2000aa of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
