<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbbc69e9d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000aa–7"><num value="2000aa–7">§ 2000aa–7.</num><heading> Definitions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbc69e9e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000aa–7/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> “Documentary materials”, as used in this chapter, means materials upon which information is recorded, and includes, but is not limited to, written or printed materials, photographs, motion picture films, negatives, video tapes, audio tapes, and other mechanically, magentically <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003240">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003240"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “magnetically”.</note> or electronically recorded cards, tapes, or discs, but does not include contraband or the fruits of a crime or things otherwise criminally possessed, or property designed or intended for use, or which is or has been used as, the means of committing a criminal offense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbc69e9f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000aa–7/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> “Work product materials”, as used in this chapter, means materials, other than contraband or the fruits of a crime or things otherwise criminally possessed, or property designed or intended for use, or which is or has been used, as the means of committing a criminal offense, and—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbc69ea0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000aa–7/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> in anticipation of communicating such materials to the public, are prepared, produced, authored, or created, whether by the person in possession of the materials or by any other person;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbc69ea1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000aa–7/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> are possessed for the purposes of communicating such materials to the public; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbc69ea2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000aa–7/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> include mental impressions, conclusions, opinions, or theories of the person who prepared, produced, authored, or created such material.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbc69ea3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000aa–7/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> “Any other governmental unit”, as used in this chapter, includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, any territory or possession of the United States, and any local government, unit of local government, or any unit of State government.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbbc69ea4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/96/440/tI/s107">Pub. L. 96–440, title I, § 107</ref>, <date date="1980-10-13">Oct. 13, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1881">94 Stat. 1881</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbbc69ea5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbbc69ea6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idbbc69ea7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1981-01-01">Jan. 1, 1981</date>, except that insofar as such provisions are applicable to a State or any governmental unit other than the United States, the section is effective one year from <date date="1980-10-13">Oct. 13, 1980</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/96/440/s108">section 108 of Pub. L. 96–440</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000aa">section 2000aa of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
