<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbbc8e7f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000cc–2"><num value="2000cc–2">§ 2000cc–2.</num><heading> Judicial relief</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbc8e7f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000cc–2/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Cause of action</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A person may assert a violation of this chapter as a claim or defense in a judicial proceeding and obtain appropriate relief against a government. Standing to assert a claim or defense under this section shall be governed by the general rules of standing under article III of the Constitution.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbc8e7f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000cc–2/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Burden of persuasion</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If a plaintiff produces prima facie evidence to support a claim alleging a violation of the Free Exercise Clause or a violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000cc">section 2000cc of this title</ref>, the government shall bear the burden of persuasion on any element of the claim, except that the plaintiff shall bear the burden of persuasion on whether the law (including a regulation) or government practice that is challenged by the claim substantially burdens the plaintiff’s exercise of religion.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbc8e7f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000cc–2/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Full faith and credit</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Adjudication of a claim of a violation of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000cc">section 2000cc of this title</ref> in a non-Federal forum shall not be entitled to full faith and credit in a Federal court unless the claimant had a full and fair adjudication of that claim in the non-Federal forum.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbc8e7f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000cc–2/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Omitted</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbc8e7f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000cc–2/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Prisoners</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to amend or repeal the Prison Litigation Reform Act of 1995 (including provisions of law amended by that Act).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbc8e7fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000cc–2/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of United States to enforce this chapter</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The United States may bring an action for injunctive or declaratory relief to enforce compliance with this chapter. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to deny, impair, or otherwise affect any right or authority of the Attorney General, the United States, or any agency, officer, or employee of the United States, acting under any law other than this subsection, to institute or intervene in any proceeding.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbc8e7fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2000cc–2/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the only jurisdictional basis for applying a provision of this chapter is a claim that a substantial burden by a government on religious exercise affects, or that removal of that substantial burden would affect, commerce with foreign nations, among the several States, or with Indian tribes, the provision shall not apply if the government demonstrates that all substantial burdens on, or the removal of all substantial burdens from, similar religious exercise throughout the Nation would not lead in the aggregate to a substantial effect on commerce with foreign nations, among the several States, or with Indian tribes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbbc8e7fc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/106/274/s4">Pub. L. 106–274, § 4</ref>, <date date="2000-09-22">Sept. 22, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/804">114 Stat. 804</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbbc8e7fd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbbc8e7fe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbbc8e7ff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/106/274">Pub. L. 106–274</ref>, <date date="2000-09-22">Sept. 22, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/803">114 Stat. 803</ref>, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2000cc">section 2000cc of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Prison Litigation Reform Act of 1995, referred to in subsec. (e), is <ref href="/us/pl/104/134/tI/s101/a/tVIII">Pub. L. 104–134, title I, § 101(a) [title VIII]</ref>, <date date="1996-04-26">Apr. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1321">110 Stat. 1321</ref>, 1321–66. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1996 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t18/s3601">section 3601 of Title 18</ref>, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbbc8e800-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is comprised of <ref href="/us/pl/106/274/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 106–274</ref>. Subsec. (d) of <ref href="/us/pl/106/274/s4">section 4 of Pub. L. 106–274</ref> amended <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1988/b">section 1988(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
