<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbbd284d2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2002"><num value="2002">§ 2002.</num><heading> Transfer of hospitals and facilities to State or private institutions; conditions and restrictions; failure to meet requirements</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Whenever the health needs of the Indians can be better met thereby, the Secretary of Health and Human Services is authorized in his discretion to enter into contracts with any State, Territory, or political subdivision thereof, or any private nonprofit corporation, agency or institution providing for the transfer by the United States Public Health Service of Indian hospitals or health facilities, including initial operating equipment and supplies.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It shall be a condition of such transfer that all facilities transferred shall be available to meet the health needs of the Indians and that such health needs shall be given priority over those of the non-Indian population. No hospital or health facility that has been constructed or maintained for a specific tribe of Indians, or for a specific group of tribes, shall be transferred by the Secretary of Health and Human Services to a non-Indian entity or organization under this subchapter unless such action has been approved by the governing body of the tribe, or by the governing bodies of a majority of the tribes, for which such hospital or health facility has been constructed or maintained: <i>Provided</i>, That if, following such transfer by the United States Public Health Service, the Secretary of Health and Human Services finds the hospital or health facility transferred under this section is not thereafter serving the need of the Indians, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall notify those charged with management thereof, setting forth needed improvements, and in the event such improvements are not made within a time to be specified, shall immediately assume management and operation of such hospital or health facility.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbbd284d3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1954-08-05/ch658/s2">Aug. 5, 1954, ch. 658, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/674">68 Stat. 674</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/tV/s509/b">Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/695">93 Stat. 695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbbd284d4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbbd284d5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idbbd284d6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Health and Human Services” substituted in text for “Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare” pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/s509/b">section 509(b) of Pub. L. 96–88</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s3508/b">section 3508(b) of Title 20</ref>, Education.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idbbd284d7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1959-07-01">July 1, 1959</date>, see section 6 of act <date date="1954-08-05">Aug. 5, 1954</date>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2001">section 2001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbbd284d8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbbd284d9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of Public Health Service, Surgeon General of Public Health Service, and all other officers and employees of Public Health Service, and functions of all agencies of or in Public Health Service transferred to Secretary of Health, Education and Welfare by Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1966, eff. <date date="1966-06-25">June 25, 1966</date>, 31 F.R. 8855, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1610">80 Stat. 1610</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s202">section 202 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
