<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbbd28517-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2005e"><num value="2005e">§ 2005e.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As used in this subchapter:</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd28518-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2005e/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> “Hospital” includes diagnostic or treatment centers and general hospitals, and related facilities, such as laboratories, outpatient departments, nurses’ home and training facilities, and central service facilities operated in connection with hospitals, but does not include any hospital furnishing primarily domiciliary care;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd28519-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2005e/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> “Diagnostic or treatment center” means a facility for the diagnosis or diagnosis and treatment of ambulatory patients—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbd2851a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2005e/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> which is operated in connection with a hospital, or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbd2851b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2005e/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> in which patient care is under the professional supervision of persons licensed to practice medicine or surgery in the State, or, in the case of dental diagnosis or treatment, under the professional supervision of persons licensed to practice dentistry in the State.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd2851c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2005e/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> “Nonprofit” means owned or operated by one or more corporations or associations no part of the net earnings of which inures, or may lawfully inure, to the benefit of any private shareholder or individual.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd2851d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2005e/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> “Construction” means construction of new buildings, expansion, remodeling, and alteration of existing buildings, and initial equipment of any such buildings (including medical transportation facilities), including architects and engineering fees, but excluding legal fees, the cost of off-site improvements and the cost of the acquisition of land.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbbd2851e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/85/151/s6">Pub. L. 85–151, § 6</ref>, <date date="1957-08-16">Aug. 16, 1957</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/71/371">71 Stat. 371</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
