<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbbd4cf2f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2012"><num value="2012">§ 2012.</num><heading> Congressional findings</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Congress of the United States makes the following findings concerning the development, use, and control of atomic energy:</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf30-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2012/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The development, utilization, and control of atomic energy for military and for all other purposes are vital to the common defense and security.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf31-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2012/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/88/489/s1">Pub. L. 88–489, § 1</ref>, <date date="1964-08-26">Aug. 26, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/602">78 Stat. 602</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf32-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2012/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The processing and utilization of source, byproduct, and special nuclear material affect interstate and foreign commerce and must be regulated in the national interest.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf33-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2012/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> The processing and utilization of source, byproduct, and special nuclear material must be regulated in the national interest and in order to provide for the common defense and security and to protect the health and safety of the public.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf34-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2012/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><content> Source and special nuclear material, production facilities, and utilization facilities are affected with the public interest, and regulation by the United States of the production and utilization of atomic energy and of the facilities used in connection therewith is necessary in the national interest to assure the common defense and security and to protect the health and safety of the public.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf35-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2012/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> The necessity for protection against possible interstate damage occurring from the operation of facilities for the production or utilization of source or special nuclear material places the operation of those facilities in interstate commerce for the purposes of this chapter.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf36-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2012/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> Funds of the United States may be provided for the development and use of atomic energy under conditions which will provide for the common defense and security and promote the general welfare.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf37-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2012/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/88/489/s2">Pub. L. 88–489, § 2</ref>, <date date="1964-08-26">Aug. 26, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/602">78 Stat. 602</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf38-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2012/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> In order to protect the public and to encourage the development of the atomic energy industry, in the interest of the general welfare and of the common defense and security, the United States may make funds available for a portion of the damages suffered by the public from nuclear incidents, and may limit the liability of those persons liable for such losses.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbbd4cf39-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, title I, § 2, as added <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-30/ch1073/s1">Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/921">68 Stat. 921</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/85/256/s1">Pub. L. 85–256, § 1</ref>, <date date="1957-09-02">Sept. 2, 1957</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/71/576">71 Stat. 576</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/489">Pub. L. 88–489</ref>, §§ 1, 2, <date date="1964-08-26">Aug. 26, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/602">78 Stat. 602</ref>; renumbered title I, <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tIX/s902/a/8">Pub. L. 102–486, title IX, § 902(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2944">106 Stat. 2944</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbbd4cf3a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbbd4cf3b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbbd4cf3c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (f), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-30/ch1073/s1">act Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/919">68 Stat. 919</ref>, known as the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2011">section 2011 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idbbd4cf3d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 2 of <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/756">60 Stat. 756</ref>, which related to establishment of Atomic Energy Commission, its membership, tenure, compensation, and appointment of certain officers and committees, was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1802">section 1802 of this title</ref>, prior to the general amendment of act <date date="1946-08-01">Aug. 1, 1946</date>, by act <date date="1954-08-30">Aug. 30, 1954</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbbd4cf3e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1964—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/88/489/s1">Pub. L. 88–489, § 1</ref>, struck out subsec. (b) which found that use of United States property by others must be regulated in national interest and in order to provide for common defense and security and to protect health and safety of public.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/88/489/s2">Pub. L. 88–489, § 2</ref>, struck out subsec. (h) which found it essential to common defense and security that title to all special nuclear material be in United States while such special nuclear material is within United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1957—Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/85/256">Pub. L. 85–256</ref> added subsec. (i).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbbd4cf3f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbd4cf40-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Control and Regulation Powers of United States and of Atomic Energy Commission Unaffected by Private Ownership of Special Nuclear Materials</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/88/489/s20">Pub. L. 88–489, § 20</ref>, <date date="1964-08-26">Aug. 26, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/607">78 Stat. 607</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/88/489/s20">“Nothing in this Act [amending this section and sections 2013, 2073 to 2078, 2135, 2153, 2201, 2233 and 2234 of this title, repealing <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2072">section 2072 of this title</ref>, and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2072">section 2072 of this title</ref>] shall be deemed to diminish existing authority of the United States, or of the Atomic Energy Commission under the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, as amended [this chapter], to regulate source, byproduct, and special nuclear material and production and utilization facilities, or to control such materials and facilities exported from the United States by imposition of governmental guarantees and security safeguards with respect thereto, in order to assure the common defense and security and to protect the health and safety of the public, or to reduce the responsibility of the Atomic Energy Commission to achieve such objectives.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
