<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbbd4cf4e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014"><num value="2014">§ 2014.</num><heading> Definitions</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The intent of Congress in the definitions as given in this section should be construed from the words or phrases used in the definitions. As used in this chapter:</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf4f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> The term “agency of the United States” means the executive branch of the United States, or any Government agency, or the legislative branch of the United States, or any agency, committee, commission, office, or other establishment in the legislative branch, or the judicial branch of the United States, or any office, agency, committee, commission, or other establishment in the judicial branch.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf50-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The term “agreement for cooperation” means any agreement with another nation or regional defense organization authorized or permitted by sections 2074, 2077, 2094, 2112, 2121(c), 2133, 2134, or 2164 of this title, and made pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153">section 2153 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf51-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The term “atomic energy” means all forms of energy released in the course of nuclear fission or nuclear transformation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf52-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/d"><num value="d">(d)</num><content> The term “atomic weapon” means any device utilizing atomic energy, exclusive of the means for transporting or propelling the device (where such means is a separable and divisible part of the device), the principal purpose of which is for use as, or for development of, a weapon, a weapon prototype, or a weapon test device.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf53-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/e"><num value="e">(e)</num><chapeau> The term “byproduct material” means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbd4cf54-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> any radioactive material (except special nuclear material) yielded in or made radioactive by exposure to the radiation incident to the process of producing or utilizing special nuclear material;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbd4cf55-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the tailings or wastes produced by the extraction or concentration of uranium or thorium from any ore processed primarily for its source material content;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbd4cf56-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbd4cf57-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> any discrete source of radium-226 that is produced, extracted, or converted after extraction, before, on, or after <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date>, for use for a commercial, medical, or research activity; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbd4cf58-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> any material that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbbd4cf59-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/e/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> has been made radioactive by use of a particle accelerator, including by use of a fusion machine; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbbd4cf5a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/e/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> if made radioactive by use of a particle accelerator that is not a fusion machine, is produced, extracted, or converted after extraction, before, on, or after <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date>, for use for a commercial, medical, or research activity; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbd4cf5b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> any discrete source of naturally occurring radioactive material, other than source material, that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbbd4cf5c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/e/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Commission, in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the head of any other appropriate Federal agency, determines would pose a threat similar to the threat posed by a discrete source of radium-226 to the public health and safety or the common defense and security; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbbd4cf5d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/e/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> before, on, or after <date date="2005-08-08">August 8, 2005</date>, is extracted or converted after extraction for use in a commercial, medical, or research activity.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf5e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/f"><num value="f">(f)</num><content> The term “Commission” means the Atomic Energy Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf5f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/g"><num value="g">(g)</num><content> The term “common defense and security” means the common defense and security of the United States.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf60-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/h"><num value="h">(h)</num><content> The term “defense information” means any information in any category determined by any Government agency authorized to classify information, as being information respecting, relating to, or affecting the national defense.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf61-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> The term “design” means (1) specifications, plans, drawings, blueprints, and other items of like nature; (2) the information contained therein; or (3) the research and development data pertinent to the information contained therein.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf62-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/j"><num value="j">(j)</num><content> The term “extraordinary nuclear occurrence” means any event causing a discharge or dispersal of source, special nuclear, or byproduct material from its intended place of confinement in amounts offsite, or causing radiation levels offsite, which the Nuclear Regulatory Commission or the Secretary of Energy, as appropriate, determines to be substantial, and which the Nuclear Regulatory Commission or the Secretary of Energy, as appropriate, determines has resulted or will probably result in substantial damages to persons offsite or property offsite. Any determination by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission or the Secretary of Energy, as appropriate, that such an event has, or has not, occurred shall be final and conclusive, and no other official or any court shall have power or jurisdiction to review any such determination. The Nuclear Regulatory Commission or the Secretary of Energy, as appropriate, shall establish criteria in writing setting forth the basis upon which such determination shall be made. As used in this subsection, “offsite” means away from “the location” or “the contract location” as defined in the applicable Nuclear Regulatory Commission or the Secretary of Energy, as appropriate, indemnity agreement, entered into pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2210">section 2210 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf63-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/k"><num value="k">(k)</num><content> The term “financial protection” means the ability to respond in damages for public liability and to meet the costs of investigating and defending claims and settling suits for such damages.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf64-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/l"><num value="l">(l)</num><content> The term “Government agency” means any executive department, commission, independent establishment, corporation, wholly or partly owned by the United States of America which is an instrumentality of the United States, or any board, bureau, division, service, office, officer, authority, administration, or other establishment in the executive branch of the Government.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf65-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/m"><num value="m">(m)</num><content> The term “indemnitor” means (1) any insurer with respect to his obligations under a policy of insurance furnished as proof of financial protection; (2) any licensee, contractor or other person who is obligated under any other form of financial protection, with respect to such obligations; and (3) the Nuclear Regulatory Commission or the Secretary of Energy, as appropriate, with respect to any obligation undertaken by it in indemnity agreement entered into pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2210">section 2210 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf66-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/n"><num value="n">(n)</num><content> The term “international arrangement” means any international agreement hereafter approved by the Congress or any treaty during the time such agreement or treaty is in full force and effect, but does not include any agreement for cooperation.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf67-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/o"><num value="o">(o)</num><content> The term “Energy Committees” means the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf68-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/p"><num value="p">(p)</num><content> The term “licensed activity” means an activity licensed pursuant to this chapter and covered by the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2210/a">section 2210(a) of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf69-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/q"><num value="q">(q)</num><content> The term “nuclear incident” means any occurrence, including an extraordinary nuclear occurrence, within the United States causing, within or outside the United States, bodily injury, sickness, disease, or death, or loss of or damage to property, or loss of use of property, arising out of or resulting from the radioactive, toxic, explosive, or other hazardous properties of source, special nuclear, or byproduct material: <i>Provided, however</i>, That as the term is used in section 2210(<i>l</i>) of this title, it shall include any such occurrence outside the United States: <i>And provided further</i>, That as the term is used in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2210/d">section 2210(d) of this title</ref>, it shall include any such occurrence outside the United States: <i>And provided further</i>, That as the term is used in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2210/c">section 2210(c) of this title</ref>, it shall include any such occurrence outside both the United States and any other nation if such occurrence arises out of or results from the radioactive, toxic, explosive, or other hazardous properties of source, special nuclear, or byproduct material licensed pursuant to subchapters V, VI, VII, and IX of this division, which is used in connection with the operation of a licensed stationary production or utilization facility or which moves outside the territorial limits of the United States in transit from one person licensed by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission to another person licensed by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf6a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/r"><num value="r">(r)</num><content> The term “operator” means any individual who manipulates the controls of a utilization or production facility.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf6b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/s"><num value="s">(s)</num><content> The term “person” means (1) any individual, corporation, partnership, firm, association, trust, estate, public or private institution, group, Government agency other than the Commission, any State or any political subdivision of, or any political entity within a State, any foreign government or nation or any political subdivision of any such government or nation, or other entity; and (2) any legal successor, representative, agent, or agency of the foregoing.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf6c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/t"><num value="t">(t)</num><content> The term “person indemnified” means (1) with respect to a nuclear incident occurring within the United States or outside the United States as the term is used in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2210/c">section 2210(c) of this title</ref>, and with respect to any nuclear incident in connection with the design, development, construction, operation, repair, maintenance, or use of the nuclear ship Savannah, the person with whom an indemnity agreement is executed or who is required to maintain financial protection, and any other person who may be liable for public liability or (2) with respect to any other nuclear incident occurring outside the United States, the person with whom an indemnity agreement is executed and any other person who may be liable for public liability by reason of his activities under any contract with the Secretary of Energy or any project to which indemnification under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2210/d">section 2210(d) of this title</ref> has been extended or under any subcontract, purchase order, or other agreement, of any tier, under any such contract or project.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf6d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/u"><num value="u">(u)</num><content> The term “produce”, when used in relation to special nuclear material, means (1) to manufacture, make, produce, or refine special nuclear material; (2) to separate special nuclear material from other substances in which such material may be contained; or (3) to make or to produce new special nuclear material.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf6e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> The term “production facility” means (1) any equipment or device determined by rule of the Commission to be capable of the production of special nuclear material in such quantity as to be of significance to the common defense and security, or in such manner as to affect the health and safety of the public; or (2) any important component part especially designed for such equipment or device as determined by the Commission. Except with respect to the export of a uranium enrichment production facility, such term as used in subchapters IX and XV shall not include any equipment or device (or important component part especially designed for such equipment or device) capable of separating the isotopes of uranium or enriching uranium in the isotope 235.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf6f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/w"><num value="w">(w)</num><content> The term “public liability” means any legal liability arising out of or resulting from a nuclear incident or precautionary evacuation (including all reasonable additional costs incurred by a State, or a political subdivision of a State, in the course of responding to a nuclear incident or a precautionary evacuation), except: (i) claims under State or Federal workmen’s compensation acts of employees of persons indemnified who are employed at the site of and in connection with the activity where the nuclear incident occurs; (ii) claims arising out of an act of war; and (iii) whenever used in subsections (a), (c), and (k) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2210">section 2210 of this title</ref>, claims for loss of, or damage to, or loss of use of property which is located at the site of and used in connection with the licensed activity where the nuclear incident occurs. “Public liability” also includes damage to property of persons indemnified: <i>Provided</i>, That such property is covered under the terms of the financial protection required, except property which is located at the site of and used in connection with the activity where the nuclear incident occurs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf70-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/x"><num value="x">(x)</num><content> The term “research and development” means (1) theoretical analysis, exploration, or experimentation; or (2) the extension of investigative findings and theories of a scientific or technical nature into practical application for experimental and demonstration purposes, including the experimental production and testing of models, devices, equipment, materials, and processes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf71-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/y"><num value="y">(y)</num><content> The term “Restricted Data” means all data concerning (1) design, manufacture, or utilization of atomic weapons; (2) the production of special nuclear material; or (3) the use of special nuclear material in the production of energy, but shall not include data declassified or removed from the Restricted Data category pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2162">section 2162 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf72-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/z"><num value="z">(z)</num><content> The term “source material” means (1) uranium, thorium, or any other material which is determined by the Commission pursuant to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2091">section 2091 of this title</ref> to be source material; or (2) ores containing one or more of the foregoing materials, in such concentration as the Commission may by regulation determine from time to time.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd4cf73-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/aa"><num value="aa">(aa)</num><content> The term “special nuclear material” means (1) plutonium, uranium enriched in the isotope 233 or in the isotope 235, and any other material which the Commission, pursuant to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2071">section 2071 of this title</ref>, determines to be special nuclear material, but does not include source material; or (2) any material artificially enriched by any of the foregoing, but does not include source material.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd73f74-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/bb"><num value="bb">(bb)</num><content> The term “United States” when used in a geographical sense includes all territories and possessions of the United States, the Canal Zone and Puerto Rico.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd73f75-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/cc"><num value="cc">(cc)</num><content> The term “utilization facility” means (1) any equipment or device, except an atomic weapon, determined by rule of the Commission to be capable of making use of special nuclear material in such quantity as to be of significance to the common defense and security, or in such manner as to affect the health and safety of the public, or peculiarly adapted for making use of atomic energy in such quantity as to be of significance to the common defense and security, or in such manner as to affect the health and safety of the public; or (2) any important component part especially designed for such equipment or device as determined by the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd73f76-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/dd"><num value="dd">(dd)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Fusion Machine</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “fusion machine” means a machine that is capable of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbd73f77-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/dd/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> transforming atomic nuclei, through fusion processes, into different elements, isotopes, or other particles; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbd73f78-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/dd/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> directly capturing and using the resultant products, including particles, heat, or other electromagnetic radiation.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd73f79-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/ee"><num value="ee">(ee)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">High-level Radioactive Waste; Spent Nuclear Fuel</inline>.—</heading><content>The terms “high-level radioactive waste” and “spent nuclear fuel” have the meanings given such terms in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s10101">section 10101 of this title</ref>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd73f7a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/ff"><num value="ff">(ff)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Legal Costs</inline>.—</heading><content>As used in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2210">section 2210 of this title</ref>, the term “legal costs” means the costs incurred by a plaintiff or a defendant in initiating, prosecuting, investigating, settling, or defending claims or suits for damage arising under such section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd73f7b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/gg"><num value="gg">(gg)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Nuclear Waste Activities</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “nuclear waste activities”, as used in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2210">section 2210 of this title</ref>, means activities subject to an agreement of indemnification under subsection (d) of such section, that the Secretary of Energy is authorized to undertake, under this chapter or any other law, involving the storage, handling, transportation, treatment, or disposal of, or research and development on, spent nuclear fuel, high-level radioactive waste, or transuranic waste, including (but not limited to) activities authorized to be carried out under the Waste Isolation Pilot Project under <ref href="/us/pl/96/164/s213">section 213 of Public Law 96–164</ref> (<ref href="/us/stat/93/1265">93 Stat. 1265</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd73f7c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/hh"><num value="hh">(hh)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Precautionary Evacuation</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The term “precautionary evacuation” means an evacuation of the public within a specified area near a nuclear facility, or the transportation route in the case of an accident involving transportation of source material, special nuclear material, byproduct material, high-level radioactive waste, spent nuclear fuel, or transuranic waste to or from a production or utilization facility, if the evacuation is—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbd73f7d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/hh/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the result of any event that is not classified as a nuclear incident but that poses imminent danger of bodily injury or property damage from the radiological properties of source material, special nuclear material, byproduct material, high-level radioactive waste, spent nuclear fuel, or transuranic waste, and causes an evacuation; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbd73f7e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/hh/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> initiated by an official of a State or a political subdivision of a State, who is authorized by State law to initiate such an evacuation and who reasonably determined that such an evacuation was necessary to protect the public health and safety.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd73f7f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Public Liability Action</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “public liability action”, as used in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2210">section 2210 of this title</ref>, means any suit asserting public liability. A public liability action shall be deemed to be an action arising under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2210">section 2210 of this title</ref>, and the substantive rules for decision in such action shall be derived from the law of the State in which the nuclear incident involved occurs, unless such law is inconsistent with the provisions of such section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbd73f80-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2014/jj"><num value="jj">(jj)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Transuranic Waste</inline>.—</heading><content>The term “transuranic waste” means material contaminated with elements that have an atomic number greater than 92, including neptunium, plutonium, americium, and curium, and that are in concentrations greater than 10 nanocuries per gram, or in such other concentrations as the Nuclear Regulatory Commission may prescribe to protect the public health and safety.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbbd73f81-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, title I, § 11, as added <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-30/ch1073/s1">Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/922">68 Stat. 922</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/act/1956-08-06/ch1015/s1">Aug. 6, 1956, ch. 1015, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/1069">70 Stat. 1069</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/256/s3">Pub. L. 85–256, § 3</ref>, <date date="1957-09-02">Sept. 2, 1957</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/71/576">71 Stat. 576</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/602/s1">Pub. L. 85–602, § 1</ref>, <date date="1958-08-08">Aug. 8, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/525">72 Stat. 525</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/206">Pub. L. 87–206</ref>, §§ 2, 3, <date date="1961-09-06">Sept. 6, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/476">75 Stat. 476</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/615">Pub. L. 87–615</ref>, §§ 4, 5, <date date="1962-08-29">Aug. 29, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/410">76 Stat. 410</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/645/s1/a">Pub. L. 89–645, § 1(a)</ref>, <date date="1966-10-13">Oct. 13, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/891">80 Stat. 891</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/197/s1">Pub. L. 94–197, § 1</ref>, <date date="1975-12-31">Dec. 31, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/1111">89 Stat. 1111</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/604/tII/s201">Pub. L. 95–604, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1978-11-08">Nov. 8, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3033">92 Stat. 3033</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/408">Pub. L. 100–408</ref>, §§ 4(b)–5(b), 11(b), (d)(2), 16(a)(1), (b)(1), (2), (d)(1)–(3), <date date="1988-08-20">Aug. 20, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1069">102 Stat. 1069</ref>, 1070, 1076, 1078–1080; <ref href="/us/pl/101/575/s5/a">Pub. L. 101–575, § 5(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2835">104 Stat. 2835</ref>; renumbered title I and amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tIX/s902/a/8">Pub. L. 102–486, title IX, § 902(a)(8)</ref>, title XI, § 1102, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2944">106 Stat. 2944</ref>, 2955; <ref href="/us/pl/103/437/s15/f/1">Pub. L. 103–437, § 15(f)(1)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4592">108 Stat. 4592</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/134/tIII/s3116/b/1">Pub. L. 104–134, title III, § 3116(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1996-04-26">Apr. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1321-349">110 Stat. 1321–349</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/58/tVI/s651/e/1">Pub. L. 109–58, title VI, § 651(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="2005-08-08">Aug. 8, 2005</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/119/806">119 Stat. 806</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/47/dG/tI/s107/d">Pub. L. 118–47, div. G, title I, § 107(d)</ref>, <date date="2024-03-23">Mar. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/857">138 Stat. 857</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/67/dB/tII/s205/a">Pub. L. 118–67, div. B, title II, § 205(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-07-09">July 9, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1460">138 Stat. 1460</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbbd73f82-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbbd73f83-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbbd73f84-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-30/ch1073/s1">act Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/919">68 Stat. 919</ref>, known as the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2011">section 2011 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definition of Canal Zone, referred to in subsec. (bb), see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3602/b">section 3602(b) of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/96/164/s213">Section 213 of Public Law 96–164</ref>, referred to in subsec. (gg), is <ref href="/us/pl/96/164/tII/s213">Pub. L. 96–164, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="1979-12-29">Dec. 29, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/1265">93 Stat. 1265</ref>, which is not classified to the Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idbbd73f85-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 11 of <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/768">60 Stat. 768</ref>, which related to patents and inventions, was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1811">section 1811 of this title</ref>, prior to the general amendment of act <date date="1946-08-01">Aug. 1, 1946</date>, by act <date date="1954-08-30">Aug. 30, 1954</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Sections 12 to 19 of <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/770-775">60 Stat. 770–775</ref>, which related to authority, powers and duties of Atomic Energy Commission; compensation for acquisition of private property; judicial review; Joint Committee of Congress on Atomic Energy; penalties for violation of certain provisions of chapter 14 of this title, injunctions, subpoena of witnesses, and production of documents; reports and recommendations to Congress; definitions; and authorization of appropriations, were classified to sections 1812 to 1819, respectively, of this title, and section 20 of <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/775">60 Stat. 775</ref>, which related to separability of provisions of the act, was set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1801">section 1801 of this title</ref>, prior to the general amendment of act <date date="1946-08-01">Aug. 1, 1946</date>, by act <date date="1954-08-30">Aug. 30, 1954</date>. Section numbers 12 to 20 were not repeated in the general amendment of act <date date="1946-08-01">Aug. 1, 1946</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbbd73f86-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (e)(3)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/118/67/s205/a/1/A/i">Pub. L. 118–67, § 205(a)(1)(A)(i)</ref>, inserted “, including by use of a fusion machine” after “particle accelerator”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3)(B)(ii). <ref href="/us/pl/118/67/s205/a/1/A/ii">Pub. L. 118–67, § 205(a)(1)(A)(ii)</ref>, inserted “if made radioactive by use of a particle accelerator that is not a fusion machine,” before “is produced”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (q). <ref href="/us/pl/118/47">Pub. L. 118–47</ref>, in second proviso, substituted “occurrence outside the United States:” for “occurrence outside the United States if such occurrence involves source, special nuclear, or byproduct material owned by, and used by or under contract with, the United States:”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (dd). <ref href="/us/pl/118/67/s205/a/5">Pub. L. 118–67, § 205(a)(5)</ref>, added subsec. (dd). Former subsec. (dd) redesignated (ee).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (ee). <ref href="/us/pl/118/67/s205/a/4">Pub. L. 118–67, § 205(a)(4)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (dd) as (ee) and inserted heading. Former subsec. (ee) redesignated (jj).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/118/67/s205/a/2">Pub. L. 118–67, § 205(a)(2)</ref>, inserted heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (ff) to (jj). <ref href="/us/pl/118/67/s205/a/2">Pub. L. 118–67, § 205(a)(2)</ref>, (3), inserted headings for subsecs. (ff) to (hh), redesignated subsecs. (ee) to (hh) and (jj) as (jj), (gg), (hh), (ii), and (ff), respectively, and transferred the subsecs. to appear in alphabetical order.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2005—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/109/58">Pub. L. 109–58</ref> substituted “means—” for “means”, realigned margins of pars. (1) and (2), and added pars. (3) and (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (v). <ref href="/us/pl/104/134">Pub. L. 104–134</ref>, which directed the amendment of subsec. (v) by striking out “or the construction and operation of a uranium enrichment facility using Atomic Vapor Laser Isotope Separation technology”, was executed by striking out “or the construction and operation of a uranium enrichment production facility using Atomic Vapor Laser Isotope Separation technology” before “, such term as used”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (<i>o</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/103/437">Pub. L. 103–437</ref> substituted “ ‘Energy Committees’ means the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives” for “ ‘Joint Committee’ means the Joint Committee on Atomic Energy”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (v). <ref href="/us/pl/102/486">Pub. L. 102–486</ref> amended last sentence generally. Prior to amendment, last sentence read as follows: “Except with respect to the export of a uranium enrichment production facility, such term as used in subchapters IX and XV shall not include any equipment or device (or important component part especially designed for such equipment or device) capable of separating the isotopes of uranium or enriching uranium in the isotope 235.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (v). <ref href="/us/pl/101/575">Pub. L. 101–575</ref> inserted at end “Except with respect to the export of a uranium enrichment production facility, such term as used in subchapters IX and XV shall not include any equipment or device (or important component part especially designed for such equipment or device) capable of separating the isotopes of uranium or enriching uranium in the isotope 235.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsecs. (j), (m). <ref href="/us/pl/100/408/s16/b/1">Pub. L. 100–408, § 16(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “Nuclear Regulatory Commission or the Secretary of Energy, as appropriate,” for “Commission” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (q). <ref href="/us/pl/100/408/s16/d/1">Pub. L. 100–408, § 16(d)(1)</ref>, substituted “section” for “subsection” in three places, which for purposes of codification was translated as “section”, thus requiring no change in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/408/s16/a/1">Pub. L. 100–408, § 16(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Nuclear Regulatory Commission” for “Commission” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (t). <ref href="/us/pl/100/408/s16/d/2">Pub. L. 100–408, § 16(d)(2)</ref>, substituted “section” for “subsection” in two places, which for purposes of codification was translated as “section”, thus requiring no change in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/408/s16/b/2">Pub. L. 100–408, § 16(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “Secretary of Energy” for “Commission” in cl. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (w). <ref href="/us/pl/100/408/s16/d/3">Pub. L. 100–408, § 16(d)(3)</ref>, substituted “subsections (a), (c), and (k) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2210">section 2210 of this title</ref>” for “section 2210(a), (c), and (k) of this title”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/408/s5/a">Pub. L. 100–408, § 5(a)</ref>, inserted “or precautionary evacuation (including all reasonable additional costs incurred by a State, or a political subdivision of a State, in the course of responding to a nuclear incident or a precautionary evacuation)” after first reference to “nuclear incident”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (dd) to (ff). <ref href="/us/pl/100/408/s4/b">Pub. L. 100–408, § 4(b)</ref>, added subsecs. (dd) to (ff).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (gg). <ref href="/us/pl/100/408/s5/b">Pub. L. 100–408, § 5(b)</ref>, added subsec. (gg).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (hh). <ref href="/us/pl/100/408/s11/b">Pub. L. 100–408, § 11(b)</ref>, added subsec. (hh).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (jj). <ref href="/us/pl/100/408/s11/d/2">Pub. L. 100–408, § 11(d)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (jj).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/95/604">Pub. L. 95–604</ref> designated existing provisions as cl. (1) and added cl. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (q). <ref href="/us/pl/94/197">Pub. L. 94–197</ref> substituted “source, special nuclear, or byproduct material” for “facility or device” and inserted proviso to include within term as used in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2210/c">section 2210(c) of this title</ref> any occurrence outside both the United States and any other nation.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (t). <ref href="/us/pl/94/197">Pub. L. 94–197</ref> expanded definition to include nuclear incidents occurring outside the United States as the term is used in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2210/c">section 2210(c) of this title</ref> and inserted reference to person required to maintain financial protection.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/89/645/s1/a/2">Pub. L. 89–645, § 1(a)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (j). Former subsec. (j) redesignated (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (k), (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/89/645/s1/a/1">Pub. L. 89–645, § 1(a)(1)</ref>, redesignated former subsecs. (j) and (k) as (k) and (<i>l</i>), respectively. Former subsec. (<i>l</i>) redesignated (n).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/89/645/s1/a/3">Pub. L. 89–645, § 1(a)(3)</ref>, added subsec. (m). Former subsec. (m) redesignated (<i>o</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (n) to (p). <ref href="/us/pl/89/645/s1/a/1">Pub. L. 89–645, § 1(a)(1)</ref>, redesignated former subsecs. (<i>l</i>) to (n) as (n) to (p), respectively. Former subsecs. (n) to (p) redesignated (p) to (r), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (q). <ref href="/us/pl/89/645/s1/a/1">Pub. L. 89–645, § 1(a)(1)</ref>, (4), redesignated former subsec. (<i>o</i>) as (q) and inserted “, including an extraordinary nuclear occurrence,” between “occurrence” and “within”, respectively. Former subsec. (q) redesignated (s).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (r) to (cc). <ref href="/us/pl/89/645/s1/a/1">Pub. L. 89–645, § 1(a)(1)</ref>, redesignated former subsecs. (p) to (aa) as (r) to (cc), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Subsec. (<i>o</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/87/615/s4">Pub. L. 87–615, § 4</ref>, enlarged definition of “nuclear incident” to include any occurrence within the United States causing any of the listed injuries and damages within or outside the United States, provided that as used in section 2210(<i>l</i>) of this title, term shall “include” instead of “mean” any such occurrence outside the United States, and that as used in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2210/d">section 2210(d) of this title</ref>, the term shall include any such occurrence outside the United States if such occurrence involves a facility or devise owned by, and used by or under contract with, the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (r). <ref href="/us/pl/87/615/s5">Pub. L. 87–615, § 5</ref>, limited definition of “person indemnified” to nuclear incidents occurring within the United States, or in connection with the nuclear ship Savannah, and inserted provisions with respect to nuclear incidents occurring outside the United States.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1961—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/87/206/s2">Pub. L. 87–206, § 2</ref>, included <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2121/c">section 2121(c) of this title</ref> in enumeration.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (u). <ref href="/us/pl/87/206/s3">Pub. L. 87–206, § 3</ref>, designated existing provisions as cls. (i) and (ii) and added cl. (iii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—Subsec. (<i>o</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/85/602">Pub. L. 85–602</ref> inserted proviso defining “nuclear incident” as it is used in section 2210(<i>l</i>) of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1957—Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/85/256">Pub. L. 85–256</ref> added subsec. (j). Former subsec. (j) redesignated (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (k) to (m). <ref href="/us/pl/85/256">Pub. L. 85–256</ref>, redesignated former subsecs. (j) to (<i>l</i>) as (k) to (m), respectively. Former subsec. (m) redesignated (p).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n). <ref href="/us/pl/85/256">Pub. L. 85–256</ref> added subsec. (n). Former subsec. (n) redesignated (q).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>o</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/85/256">Pub. L. 85–256</ref> added subsec. (<i>o</i>). Former subsec. (<i>o</i>) redesignated (s).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (p), (q). <ref href="/us/pl/85/256">Pub. L. 85–256</ref> redesignated former subsecs. (m) and (n) as (p) and (q), respectively. Former subsecs. (p) and (q) redesignated (t) and (u), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (r). <ref href="/us/pl/85/256">Pub. L. 85–256</ref> added subsec. (r). Former subsec. (r) redesignated (w).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (s), (t). <ref href="/us/pl/85/256">Pub. L. 85–256</ref> redesignated former subsecs. (<i>o</i>) and (p) as (s) and (t), respectively. Former subsecs. (s) and (t) redesignated (x) and (y), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (u). <ref href="/us/pl/85/256">Pub. L. 85–256</ref> added subsec. (u). Former subsec. (u) redesignated (z).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (v) to (aa). <ref href="/us/pl/85/256">Pub. L. 85–256</ref> redesignated former subsecs. (q) to (v) as (v) to (aa), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1956—Subsec. (u). Act <date date="1956-08-06">Aug. 6, 1956</date>, substituted “the Canal Zone and Puerto Rico” for “and the Canal Zone”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbbd73f87-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idbbd73f88-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Commerce of House of Representatives by <ref href="/us/pl/104/14/s1/a">section 1(a) of Pub. L. 104–14</ref>, set out as a note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t2/s21">section 21 of Title 2</ref>, The Congress. Committee on Commerce of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives, and jurisdiction over matters relating to securities and exchanges and insurance generally transferred to Committee on Financial Services of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Seventh Congress, <date date="2001-01-03">Jan. 3, 2001</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbbd73f89-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/408/s20">Pub. L. 100–408, § 20</ref>, <date date="1988-08-20">Aug. 20, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1084">102 Stat. 1084</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/408/s20">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> Except as provided in subsection (b), the amendments made by this Act [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2282a">section 2282a of this title</ref> and amending this section and sections 2210 and 2273 of this title] shall become effective on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1988-08-20">Aug. 20, 1988</date>] and shall be applicable with respect to nuclear incidents occurring on or after such date.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The amendments made by section 11 [amending this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2210">section 2210 of this title</ref>] shall apply to nuclear incidents occurring before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Section 234A of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2282a">section 2282a of this title</ref>] shall not apply to any violation occurring before the date of the enactment of this Act.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Section 223 c. of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2273/c">section 2273(c) of this title</ref>] shall not apply to any violation occurring before the date of enactment of this Act.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbbd73f8a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/604/tII/s208">Pub. L. 95–604, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1978-11-08">Nov. 8, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3041">92 Stat. 3041</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/604/tII/s208">“Except as otherwise provided in this title [see <ref href="/us/pl/95/604/s202/b">section 202(b) of Pub. L. 95–604</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2113">section 2113 of this title</ref>] the amendments made by this title [enacting sections 2022 and 2114 of this title, amending this section and sections 2021, 2111, and 2201 of this title, and enacting provisions set out as notes under sections 2021 and 2113 of this title] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1978-11-08">Nov. 8, 1978</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbbd73f8b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Atomic Energy Commission abolished and functions transferred by sections 5814 and 5841 of this title. See also Transfer of Functions notes set out under those sections.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
