<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb41e9fc5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s203"><num value="203">§ 203.</num><heading> Organization of Service</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Service shall consist of (1) the Office of the Surgeon General, (2) the National Institutes of Health, (3) the Bureau of Medical Services, and <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002001">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002001"><num>1</num> So in original. The “and” probably should not appear.</note> (4) the Bureau of State Services, and <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002002">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002002"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by “(5)”.</note> the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality. The Secretary is authorized and directed to assign to the Office of the Surgeon General,<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002003">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002003"><num>3</num> See 1993 Amendment note below.</note> to the National Institutes of Health, to the Bureau of Medical Services, and to the Bureau of State Services, respectively, the several functions of the Service, and to establish within them such divisions, sections, and other units as he may find necessary; and from time to time abolish, transfer, and consolidate divisions, sections, and other units and assign their functions and personnel in such manner as he may find necessary for efficient operation of the Service. No division shall be established, abolished, or transferred, and no divisions shall be consolidated, except with the approval of the Secretary. The National Institutes of Health shall be administered as a part of the field service. The Secretary may delegate to any officer or employee of the Service such of his powers and duties under this chapter, except the making of regulations, as he may deem necessary or expedient.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idb41e9fc6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title II, § 202, <ref href="/us/stat/58/683">58 Stat. 683</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-16/ch481/s6/b">June 16, 1948, ch. 481, § 6(b)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/469">62 Stat. 469</ref>; 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 1, §§ 5, 8, eff. <date date="1953-04-11">Apr. 11, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 2053, <ref href="/us/stat/67/631">67 Stat. 631</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/43/tXX/s2008/g">Pub. L. 103–43, title XX, § 2008(g)</ref>, <date date="1993-06-10">June 10, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/212">107 Stat. 212</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/129/s2/b/2">Pub. L. 106–129, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1999-12-06">Dec. 6, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1670">113 Stat. 1670</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb41e9fc7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb41e9fc8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb41e9fc9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—<ref href="/us/pl/106/129">Pub. L. 106–129</ref> substituted “Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality” for “Agency for Health Care Policy and Research”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—<ref href="/us/pl/103/43/s2008/g/2">Pub. L. 103–43, § 2008(g)(2)</ref>, inserted “, and the Agency for Health Care Policy and Research” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/43/s2008/g/1">Pub. L. 103–43, § 2008(g)(1)</ref>, which directed the amendment of this section by striking “Surgeon General” the second and subsequent times that such term appears and inserting “Secretary”, was executed by making the substitution before “is authorized and directed” and before “may delegate to any officer” and by leaving unchanged “Surgeon General” in the phrase “assign to the Office of the Surgeon General” in second sentence, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1948—Act <date date="1948-06-16">June 16, 1948</date>, substituted “National Institutes of Health” for “National Institute of Health” in cl. (2).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb41e9fca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idb41e9fcb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Health and Human Services” substituted in text for “Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare” pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/s509/b">section 509(b) of Pub. L. 96–88</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s3508/b">section 3508(b) of Title 20</ref>, Education.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idb41e9fcc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idb41e9fcd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Bureau of Medical Services, Bureau of State Services, National Institutes of Health, excluding several research Institutes in agency, and Office of Surgeon General abolished by section 3 of Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1966, eff. <date date="1966-06-25">June 25, 1966</date>, 31 F.R. 8855, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1610">80 Stat. 1610</ref>, and all functions thereof transferred to Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare by section 1 of Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1966, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s202">section 202 of this title</ref>. Office of Surgeon General reestablished within the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Health, see Notice of Department of Health and Human Services, Office of the Assistant Secretary for Health, <date date="1987-03-30">Mar. 30, 1987</date>, 52 F.R. 11754.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of Federal Security Administrator transferred to Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, and all agencies of Federal Security Agency transferred to Department of Health, Education, and Welfare by section 5 of Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1953, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3501">section 3501 of this title</ref>. Federal Security Agency and office of Administrator abolished by section 8 of Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1953.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
