<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb4211116-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s206"><num value="206">§ 206.</num><heading> Assignment of officers</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4211117-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s206/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Deputy Surgeon General</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Surgeon General shall assign one commissioned officer from the Regular Corps to administer the Office of the Surgeon General, to act as Surgeon General during the absence or disability of the Surgeon General or in the event of a vacancy in that office, and to perform such other duties as the Surgeon General may prescribe, and while so assigned he shall have the title of Deputy Surgeon General.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4211118-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s206/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Assistant Surgeons General</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Surgeon General shall assign eight commissioned officers from the Regular Corps to be, respectively, the Director of the National Institutes of Health, the Chief of the Bureau of State Services, the Chief of the Bureau of Medical Services, the Chief Medical Officer of the United States Coast Guard, the Chief Dental Officer of the Service, the Chief Nurse Officer of the Service, the Chief Pharmacist Officer of the Service, and the Chief Sanitary Engineering Officer of the Service, and while so serving they shall each have the title of Assistant Surgeon General.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4211119-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s206/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Creation of temporary positions as Assistant Surgeons General</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb421111a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s206/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Surgeon General, with the approval of the Secretary, is authorized to create special temporary positions in the grade of Assistant Surgeons General when necessary for the proper staffing of the Service. The Surgeon General may assign officers of either the Regular Corps or the Ready Reserve Corps to any such temporary position, and while so serving they shall each have the title of Assistant Surgeon General.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb421111b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s206/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Except as provided in this paragraph, the number of special temporary positions created by the Surgeon General under paragraph (1) shall not on any day exceed 1 per centum of the highest number, during the ninety days preceding such day, of officers of the Regular Corps on active duty and officers of the Ready Reserve Corps on active duty for more than thirty days. If on any day the number of such special temporary positions exceeds such 1 per centum limitation, for a period of not more than one year after such day, the number of such special temporary positions shall be reduced for purposes of complying with such 1 per centum limitation only by the resignation, retirement, death, or transfer to a position of a lower grade, of any officer holding any such temporary position.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb421111c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s206/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Designation of Assistant Surgeon General with respect to absence, disability, or vacancy in offices of Surgeon General and Deputy Surgeon General</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Surgeon General shall designate the Assistant Surgeon General who shall serve as Surgeon General in case of absence or disability, or vacancy in the offices, of both the Surgeon General and the Deputy Surgeon General.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb421111d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title II, § 205, <ref href="/us/stat/58/684">58 Stat. 684</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1948-02-28/ch83/s3">Feb. 28, 1948, ch. 83, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/39">62 Stat. 39</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-16/ch481/s6/b">June 16, 1948, ch. 481, § 6(b)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/469">62 Stat. 469</ref>; 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 1, §§ 5, 8, eff. <date date="1953-04-11">Apr. 11, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 2053, <ref href="/us/stat/67/631">67 Stat. 631</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/76/tIII">Pub. L. 96–76, title III</ref>, §§ 302(b), 303, <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/584">93 Stat. 584</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/136/dA/tIII/s3214/e/3">Pub. L. 116–136, div. A, title III, § 3214(e)(3)</ref>, <date date="2020-03-27">Mar. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/373">134 Stat. 373</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb421111e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb421111f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb4211120-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/116/136">Pub. L. 116–136</ref> substituted “Ready Reserve Corps” for “Reserve Corps” in pars. (1) and (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/96/76/s302/b">Pub. L. 96–76, § 302(b)</ref>, inserted provisions relating to assignment of Chief Nurse Officer and Chief Pharmacist Officer, and substituted “eight” for “six”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/76/s303">Pub. L. 96–76, § 303</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), struck out provisions relating to maximum number of special temporary positions, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1948—Subsec. (b). Act <date date="1948-06-16">June 16, 1948</date>, substituted “National Institutes of Health” for “National Institute of Health”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c), (d). Act <date date="1948-02-28">Feb. 28, 1948</date>, added subsec. (c) and redesignated former subsec. (c) as (d).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb4211121-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idb4211122-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Health and Human Services” substituted for “Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare” in subsec. (c)(1) pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/s509/b">section 509(b) of Pub. L. 96–88</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s3508/b">section 3508(b) of Title 20</ref>, Education.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb4211123-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1979 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/76/tIII/s314">Pub. L. 96–76, title III, § 314</ref>, <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/587">93 Stat. 587</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/76/tIII/s314">“The amendments made by sections 303, 304, 305, 306, 307, and 313 [amending this section, sections 207, 209, 210b, and 211 of this title, and sections 201, 415, and 1006 of Title 37, Pay and Allowances of the Uniformed Services] shall take effect on <date date="1979-10-01">October 1, 1979</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idb4211124-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of <date date="2002-11-25">November 25, 2002</date>, as modified, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t6/s542">section 542 of Title 6</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idb4211125-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idb4211126-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Office of Surgeon General, together with office held by Deputy Surgeon General, Bureau of Medical Services, including office of Chief of Bureau of Medical Services, Bureau of State Services, including office of Chief of Bureau of State Services, and National Institutes of Health, including office of Director of National Institutes of Health, abolished by section 3 of Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1966, eff. <date date="1966-06-25">June 25, 1966</date>, 31 F.R. 8855, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1610">80 Stat. 1610</ref>, and functions thereof transferred to Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare by section 1 of Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1966, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s202">section 202 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of Federal Security Administrator transferred to Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare and all agencies of Federal Security Agency transferred to Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, by section 5 of Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1953, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3501">section 3501 of this title</ref>. Federal Security Agency and office of Administrator abolished by section 8 of Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1953.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
