<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbbe32719-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2074"><num value="2074">§ 2074.</num><heading> Foreign distribution of special nuclear material</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbe3271a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2074/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation; distribution to International Atomic Energy Agency; procedure for distribution; repurchase of unconsumed materials; price; purchase of materials produced outside United States; price</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission is authorized to cooperate with any nation or group of nations by distributing special nuclear material and to distribute such special nuclear material, pursuant to the terms of an agreement for cooperation to which such nation or group of nations is a party and which is made in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153">section 2153 of this title</ref>. Unless hereafter otherwise authorized by law the Commission shall be compensated for special nuclear material so distributed at not less than the Commission’s published charges applicable to the domestic distribution of such material, except that the Commission to assist and encourage research on peaceful uses or for medical therapy may so distribute without charge during any calendar year only a quantity of such material which at the time of transfer does not exceed in value $10,000 in the case of one nation or $50,000 in the case of any group of nations. The Commission may distribute to the International Atomic Energy Agency, or to any group of nations, only such amounts of special nuclear materials and for such period of time as are authorized by Congress: <i>Provided, however</i>, That, (i) notwithstanding this provision, the Commission is hereby authorized, subject to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153">section 2153 of this title</ref>, to distribute to the Agency five thousand kilograms of contained uranium-235, five hundred grams of uranium-233, and three kilograms of plutonium, together with the amounts of special nuclear material which will match in amount the sum of all quantities of special nuclear materials made available by all other members of the Agency to <date date="1960-06-01">June 1, 1960</date>; and (ii) notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this subsection, the Commission may distribute to the International Atomic Energy Agency, or to any group of nations, such other amounts of special nuclear materials and for such other periods of time as are established in writing by the Commission: <i>Provided, however</i>, That before they are established by the Commission pursuant to this subdivision (ii), such proposed amounts and periods shall be submitted to the Congress and referred to the Energy Committees and a period of sixty days shall elapse while Congress is in session (in computing such sixty days, there shall be excluded the days on which either House is not in session because of an adjournment of more than three days): <i>And provided further</i>, That any such proposed amounts and periods shall not become effective if during such sixty-day period the Congress passes a concurrent resolution stating in substance that it does not favor the proposed action: <i>And provided further</i>, That prior to the elapse of the first thirty days of any such sixty-day period the Energy Committees shall submit to their respective houses reports of their views and recommendations respecting the proposed amounts and periods and an accompanying proposed concurrent resolution stating in substance that the Congress favors, or does not favor, as the case may be, the proposed amounts or periods. The Commission may agree to repurchase any special nuclear material distributed under a sale arrangement pursuant to this subsection which is not consumed in the course of the activities conducted in accordance with the agreement for cooperation, or any uranium remaining after irradiation of such special nuclear material, at repurchase price not to exceed the Commission’s sale price for comparable special nuclear material or uranium in effect at the time of delivery of such material to the Commission. The Commission may also agree to purchase, consistent with and within the period of the agreement for cooperation, special nuclear material produced in a nuclear reactor located outside the United States through the use of special nuclear material which was leased or sold pursuant to this subsection. Under any such agreement the Commission shall purchase only such material as is delivered to the Commission during any period when there is in effect a guaranteed purchase price for the same material produced in a nuclear reactor by a person licensed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2134">section 2134 of this title</ref>, established by the Commission pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2076">section 2076 of this title</ref>, and the price to be paid shall be the price so established by the Commission and in effect for the same material delivered to the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbe3271b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2074/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Distribution to persons outside United States of plutonium and other special nuclear material exempted under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2077/d">section 2077(d) of this title</ref>; compensation; reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding the provisions of sections 2153 and 2154 of this title and section 125 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, the Commission is authorized to distribute to any person outside the United States (1) plutonium containing 80 per centum or more by weight of plutonium-238, and (2) other special nuclear material when it has, in accordance with sub<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2077/d">section 2077(d) of this title</ref>, exempted certain classes or quantities of such other special nuclear material or kinds of uses or users thereof from the requirements for a license set forth in this subchapter. Unless hereafter otherwise authorized by law, the Commission shall be compensated for special nuclear material so distributed at not less than the Commission’s published charges applicable to the domestic distribution of such material. The Commission shall not distribute any plutonium containing 80 per centum or more by weight of plutonium-238 to any person under this subsection if, in its opinion, such distribution would be inimical to the common defense and security. The Commission may require such reports regarding the use of material distributed pursuant to the provisions of this subsection as it deems necessary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbe3271c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2074/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Licensing or granting permission to others to distribute special nuclear material; conditions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission is authorized to license or otherwise permit others to distribute special nuclear material to any person outside the United States under the same conditions, except as to charges, as would be applicable if the material were distributed by the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbe3271d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2074/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Laboratory samples; medical devices; monitoring or other instruments; emergencies</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The authority to distribute special nuclear material under this section other than under an export license granted by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission shall extend only to the following small quantities of special nuclear material (in no event more than five hundred grams per year of the uranium isotope 233, the uranium isotope 235, or plutonium contained in special nuclear material to any recipient):</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbe3271e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2074/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> which are contained in laboratory samples, medical devices, or monitoring or other instruments; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbe3271f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2074/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the distribution of which is needed to deal with an emergency situation in which time is of the essence.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbe32720-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2074/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Arrangements for storage or disposition of irradiated fuel elements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The authority in this section to commit United States funds for any activities pursuant to any subsequent arrangement under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2160/a/2/E">section 2160(a)(2)(E) of this title</ref> shall be subject to the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2160">section 2160 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbbe32721-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, title I, § 54, as added <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-30/ch1073/s1">Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/931">68 Stat. 931</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/85/177/s7">Pub. L. 85–177, § 7</ref>, <date date="1957-08-28">Aug. 28, 1957</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/71/455">71 Stat. 455</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/206/s4">Pub. L. 87–206, § 4</ref>, <date date="1961-09-06">Sept. 6, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/476">75 Stat. 476</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/489/s9">Pub. L. 88–489, § 9</ref>, <date date="1964-08-26">Aug. 26, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/604">78 Stat. 604</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/377/s2">Pub. L. 93–377, § 2</ref>, <date date="1974-08-17">Aug. 17, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/473">88 Stat. 473</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/242/tIII">Pub. L. 95–242, title III</ref>, §§ 301(a), 303(b)(1), <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/125">92 Stat. 125</ref>, 131; renumbered title I, <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tIX/s902/a/8">Pub. L. 102–486, title IX, § 902(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2944">106 Stat. 2944</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/437/s15/f/3">Pub. L. 103–437, § 15(f)(3)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4592">108 Stat. 4592</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbbe32722-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbbe32723-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbbe32724-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 125 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, referred to in subsec. (b), is section 125 of <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/85/14">Pub. L. 85–14</ref>, <date date="1957-04-12">Apr. 12, 1957</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/71/11">71 Stat. 11</ref>, and is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153">section 2153 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbbe32725-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/103/437">Pub. L. 103–437</ref> substituted “Energy Committees and a period” for “Joint Committee and a period” and “Energy Committees shall submit to their respective houses reports of their views” for “Joint Committee shall submit a report to the Congress of its views”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/242/s301/a">Pub. L. 95–242, § 301(a)</ref>, added subsec. (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/95/242/s303/b/1">Pub. L. 95–242, § 303(b)(1)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—<ref href="/us/pl/93/377">Pub. L. 93–377</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), designated initial proviso as cl. (i), added cl. (ii) and references to groups of nations, and substituted references to this subsection for references to this section, and added subsecs. (b) and (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1964—<ref href="/us/pl/88/489">Pub. L. 88–489</ref> authorized repurchase of unconsumed special nuclear materials, or any uranium remaining after irradiation of such materials, at a price not exceeding Commission’s sale price for comparable material in effect at time of delivery to Commission, and purchase of special nuclear material produced outside United States through use of material leased or sold under this section, during any period when there is a guaranteed purchase price for same material as produced under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2134">section 2134 of this title</ref>, for such price as established by the Commission.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1961—<ref href="/us/pl/87/206">Pub. L. 87–206</ref> inserted “five hundred grams of uranium 233 and three kilograms of plutonium” after “five thousand kilograms of contained uranium 235”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1957—<ref href="/us/pl/85/177">Pub. L. 85–177</ref> inserted provisions requiring compensation at domestic charges for materials distributed abroad except for peaceful or medical therapy uses, and required Commission to obtain authorization of Congress for materials to be contributed to Agency beyond amount made available by all other members of Agency to <date date="1960-07-01">July 1, 1960</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbbe32726-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbbe32727-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/242">Pub. L. 95–242</ref> effective <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, except as otherwise provided and regardless of any requirement for the promulgation of implementing regulations, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/242/s603/c">section 603(c) of Pub. L. 95–242</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3201">section 3201 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
