<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb4235b74-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s210"><num value="210">§ 210.</num><heading> Pay and allowances</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4235b75-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s210/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Commissioned officers of Regular Corps and Ready Reserve Corps; special pay for active duty; incentive special pay for Public Health Service nurses</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4235b76-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s210/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Commissioned officers of the Regular Corps and Ready Reserve Corps shall be entitled to receive such pay and allowances as are now or may hereafter be authorized by law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4235b77-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s210/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> For provisions relating to the receipt of special pay by commissioned officers of the Regular Corps and Ready Reserve Corps while on active duty, see section 303a(b) or 373 of title 37.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4235b78-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s210/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Purchase of supplies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Commissioned officers on active duty and retired officers entitled to retired pay pursuant to section 211(g)(3), 212, or 213a(a) of this title, shall be permitted to purchase supplies from the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Marine Corps at the same price as is charged officers thereof.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4235b79-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s210/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Members of national advisory or review councils or committees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Members of the National Advisory Health Council and members of other national advisory or review councils or committees established under this chapter, including members of the Technical Electronic Product Radiation Safety Standards Committee and the Board of Regents of the National Library of Medicine, but excluding ex officio members, while attending conferences or meetings of their respective councils or committees or while otherwise serving at the request of the Secretary, shall be entitled to receive compensation at rates to be fixed by the Secretary, but at rates not exceeding the daily equivalent of the rate specified at the time of such service for grade GS–18 of the General Schedule, including traveltime; and while away from their homes or regular places of business they may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized by <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5703">section 5703 of title 5</ref> for persons in the Government service employed intermittently.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4235b7a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s210/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Field employees</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Field employees of the Service, except those employed on a per diem or fee basis, who render part-time duty and are also subject to call at any time for services not contemplated in their regular part-time employment, may be paid annual compensation for such part-time duty and, in addition, such fees for such other services as the Surgeon General may determine; but in no case shall the total paid to any such employee for any fiscal year exceed the amount of the minimum annual salary rate of the classification grade of the employee.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4235b7b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s210/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional pay for service at Gillis W. Long Hansen’s Disease Center</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any civilian employee of the Service who is employed at the Gillis W. Long Hansen’s Disease Center on <date date="1986-04-07">April 7, 1986</date>, shall be entitled to receive, in addition to any compensation to which the employee may otherwise be entitled and for so long as the employee remains employed at the Center, an amount equal to one-fourth of such compensation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4235b7c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s210/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Allowances included in fellowships</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Individuals appointed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s209/g">section 209(g) of this title</ref> shall have included in their fellowships such stipends or allowances, including travel and subsistence expenses, as the Surgeon General may deem necessary to procure qualified fellows.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4235b7d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s210/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Positions in professional, scientific and executive service; compensation; appointment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary is authorized to establish and fix the compensation for, within the Public Health Service, not more than one hundred and seventy-nine positions, of which not less than one hundred and fifteen shall be for the National Institutes of Health, not less than five shall be for the National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism for individuals engaged in research on alcohol abuse and alcoholism, not less than ten shall be for the National Center for Health Services Research, not less than twelve shall be for the National Center for Health Statistics, and not less than seven shall be for the National Center for Health Care Technology, in the professional, scientific, and executive service, each such position being established to effectuate those research and development activities of the Public Health Service which require the services of specially qualified scientific, professional and administrative personnel: <i>Provided</i>, That the rates of compensation for positions established pursuant to the provisions of this subsection shall not be less than the minimum rate of grade 16 of the General Schedule nor more than (1) the highest rate of grade 18 of the General Schedule, or (2) in the case of two such positions, the rate specified, at the time the service in the position is performed, for level II of the Executive Schedule (<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5313">5 U.S.C. 5313</ref>); and such rates of compensation for all positions included in this proviso shall be subject to the approval of the Director of the Office of Personnel Management. Positions created pursuant to this subsection shall be included in the classified civil service of the United States, but appointments to such positions shall be made without competitive examination upon approval of the proposed appointee’s qualifications by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management or such officers or agents as it may designate for this purpose.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb4235b7e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title II, § 208, formerly § 209, <ref href="/us/stat/58/686">58 Stat. 686</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1946-07-03/ch538/s5/a">July 3, 1946, ch. 538, § 5(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/422">60 Stat. 422</ref>; renumbered § 208 and amended <ref href="/us/act/1948-02-28/ch83/s5/a">Feb. 28, 1948, ch. 83, § 5(a)</ref>, (g), (h), <ref href="/us/stat/62/40">62 Stat. 40</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-16/ch481/s4/d">June 16, 1948, ch. 481, § 4(d)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/467">62 Stat. 467</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-24/ch621/s4/d">June 24, 1948, ch. 621, § 4(d)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/601">62 Stat. 601</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1949-10-12/ch681">Oct. 12, 1949, ch. 681</ref>, title V, § 521(b), <ref href="/us/stat/63/834">63 Stat. 834</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1950-08-09/ch654/s1">Aug. 9, 1950, ch. 654, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/426">64 Stat. 426</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1950-08-15/ch714">Aug. 15, 1950, ch. 714</ref>, §§ 3(e), 4(b), <ref href="/us/stat/64/447">64 Stat. 447</ref>; 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 1, §§ 5, 8 eff. <date date="1953-04-11">Apr. 11, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 2053, <ref href="/us/stat/67/631">67 Stat. 631</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1955-08-01/ch437">Aug. 1, 1955, ch. 437</ref>, title II, § 201, <ref href="/us/stat/69/407">69 Stat. 407</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1956-06-29/ch477">June 29, 1956, ch. 477</ref>, title II, § 201, <ref href="/us/stat/70/430">70 Stat. 430</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1956-07-31/ch804">July 31, 1956, ch. 804</ref>, title I, § 117(b), <ref href="/us/stat/70/741">70 Stat. 741</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/462/s12/e">Pub. L. 85–462, § 12(e)</ref>, <date date="1958-06-20">June 20, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/214">72 Stat. 214</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/85/929/s9">Pub. L. 85–929, § 9</ref>, <date date="1958-09-06">Sept. 6, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1789">72 Stat. 1789</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/415/s5/b">Pub. L. 86–415, § 5(b)</ref>, <date date="1960-04-08">Apr. 8, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/34">74 Stat. 34</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/86/703/tII/s201">Pub. L. 86–703, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1960-09-02">Sept. 2, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/764">74 Stat. 764</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/649">Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, §§ 11(3), 14b, <date date="1962-09-07">Sept. 7, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/497">76 Stat. 497</ref>, 499; <ref href="/us/pl/87/793/tVI/s1001/d">Pub. L. 87–793, title VI, § 1001(d)</ref>, <date date="1962-10-11">Oct. 11, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/864">76 Stat. 864</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/426/tIII/s305/1">Pub. L. 88–426, title III, § 305(1)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-14">Aug. 14, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/422">78 Stat. 422</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/574/tV/s501">Pub. L. 90–574, title V, § 501</ref>, <date date="1968-10-15">Oct. 15, 1968</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/82/1012">82 Stat. 1012</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/515/tVI/s601/b/1">Pub. L. 91–515, title VI, § 601(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-30">Oct. 30, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1310">84 Stat. 1310</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/157/tIII/s301/a">Pub. L. 92–157, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1971-11-18">Nov. 18, 1971</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/85/463">85 Stat. 463</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/83/tIII/s312">Pub. L. 95–83, title III, § 312</ref>, <date date="1977-08-01">Aug. 1, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/398">91 Stat. 398</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/623/s11/a">Pub. L. 95–623, § 11(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3455">92 Stat. 3455</ref>; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3783">92 Stat. 3783</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/32/s7/g">Pub. L. 96–32, § 7(g)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-10">July 10, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/84">93 Stat. 84</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/398/tVIII/s805">Pub. L. 96–398, title VIII, § 805</ref>, <date date="1980-10-07">Oct. 7, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/1608">94 Stat. 1608</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/117/s3/a">Pub. L. 99–117, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1985-10-07">Oct. 7, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/491">99 Stat. 491</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/tXVII/s17002/a/1">Pub. L. 99–272, title XVII, § 17002(a)(1)</ref>, (b), <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/359">100 Stat. 359</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/607/tVII/s706">Pub. L. 100–607, title VII, § 706</ref>, <date date="1988-11-04">Nov. 4, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3159">102 Stat. 3159</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title VI, § 634(b)], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–159; <ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dA/tVI/s618/i">Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title VI, § 618(i)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1427">131 Stat. 1427</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/136/dA/tIII/s3214/e/2">Pub. L. 116–136, div. A, title III, § 3214(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="2020-03-27">Mar. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/373">134 Stat. 373</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb4235b7f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb4235b80-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb4235b81-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Classified civil service, referred to in subsec. (g), as meaning “competitive service”, see <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s2102/c">section 2102(c) of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idb4235b82-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 208 of act <date date="1944-07-01">July 1, 1944</date>, was renumbered section 207 and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s209">section 209 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb4235b83-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/116/136">Pub. L. 116–136</ref> substituted “Regular Corps and Ready Reserve Corps” for “Regular and Reserve Corps” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2017—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/115/91">Pub. L. 115–91</ref> inserted “or 373” after “section 303a(b)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/106/398">Pub. L. 106–398</ref> added par. (2) and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(2)(A) Except as provided in subparagraph (B), commissioned medical and dental officers in the Regular and Reserve Corps shall while on active duty be paid special pay in the same amounts as, and under the same terms and conditions which apply to, the special pay now or hereafter paid to commissioned medical and dental officers of the Armed Forces under chapter 5 of title 37.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) A commissioned medical officer in the Regular or Reserve Corps (other than an officer serving in the Indian Health Service) may not receive additional special pay under <ref href="/us/usc/t37/s302/a/4">section 302(a)(4) of title 37</ref> for any period during which the officer is providing obligated service under (i) <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254m">section 254m of this title</ref>, (ii) <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s234/e">section 234(e) of this title</ref> (as such section was in effect prior to <date date="1977-10-01">October 1, 1977</date>), or (iii) <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s294u">section 294u of this title</ref> (as such section was in effect between <date date="1977-10-01">October 1, 1977</date>, and <date date="1981-08-13">August 13, 1981</date>).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title VI, § 634(b)(1)], struck out par. (3) which read as follows: “Commissioned nurse officers in the Regular and Reserve Corps shall, while in active duty, be paid incentive special pay in the same amounts as, and under the same terms and conditions which apply to, the incentive special pay now or hereafter paid to commissioned nurse officers of the Armed Forces under chapter 5 of title 37.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/607">Pub. L. 100–607</ref> added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1986—Subsec. (a)(2)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/s17002/a/1">Pub. L. 99–272, § 17002(a)(1)</ref>, inserted “(other than an officer serving in the Indian Health Service)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/99/272/s17002/b">Pub. L. 99–272, § 17002(b)</ref>, amended subsec. (e) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (e) read as follows: “Whenever any noncommissioned officer or other employee of the Service is assigned for duty which the Surgeon General finds requires intimate contact with persons afflicted with leprosy, he may be entitled to receive, as provided by regulations of the President, in addition to any pay or compensation to which he may otherwise be entitled, not more than one-half of such pay or compensation.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/99/117">Pub. L. 99–117</ref> substituted “(A) Except as provided in subparagraph (B), commissioned” for “Commissioned”, and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1980—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/96/398">Pub. L. 96–398</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1) and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/96/32">Pub. L. 96–32</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5703">section 5703 of title 5</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5703/b">section 5703(b) of title 5</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/95/623">Pub. L. 95–623</ref> increased limitation on establishment of positions to one hundred and seventy-nine from one hundred and fifty-five and required minimum number of positions for certain National Centers: ten, National Center for Health Services Research; twelve, National Center for Health Statistics; and seven, National Center for Health Care Technology.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/95/83">Pub. L. 95–83</ref> increased limitation on establishment of positions to one hundred and fifty-five from one hundred and fifty and required not less than five for the National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism for individuals engaged in research on alcohol abuse and alcoholism.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1971—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/92/157">Pub. L. 92–157</ref>, which directed that “subsection (g)” be substituted for “section 209(f)”, was executed by substituting “<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s209/g">section 209(g) of this title</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s209/f">section 209(f) of this title</ref>”, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/91/515">Pub. L. 91–515</ref> extended coverage to encompass members of other national review councils or national advisory or review committees established under this chapter, including members of the Technical Electronic Product Radiation Safety Standards Committee and the Board of Regents of the National Library of Medicine, authorized service to be at the request of the Secretary in place of the Surgeon General, and revised rates of compensation and travel allowances.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1968—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/90/574">Pub. L. 90–574</ref> inserted “(1)” after “nor more than” and added cl. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/87/649">Pub. L. 87–649</ref> struck out sentence which permitted commissioned officers on active duty to make allotments from their pay, and substituted “Commissioned officers on active duty and retired officers” for “Such officers, and retired officers.” See <ref href="/us/usc/t37/s704">section 704 of Title 37</ref>, Pay and Allowances of the Uniformed Services.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/87/793">Pub. L. 87–793</ref> substituted provisions requiring the rates of compensation to be not less than the minimum rate of grade 16 nor more than the highest rate of grade 18 of the General Schedule, for provisions which prescribed annual rates of compensation of not less than $12,500 nor more than $19,000.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1960—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/86/415">Pub. L. 86–415</ref> authorized retired officers entitled to retired pay pursuant to section 211(g)(3), 212, or 213a(a) of this title, to purchase supplies, and included the purchase of supplies from the Air Force.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/86/703">Pub. L. 86–703</ref> substituted “one hundred and fifty” for “eighty-five” and “one hundred and fifteen” for “seventy-three”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/85/929">Pub. L. 85–929</ref> substituted “in the professional, scientific, and executive service” for “in the professional and scientific service”, and substituted “of specially qualified scientific, professional, and administrative personnel” for “of specially qualified scientific or professional personnel”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/85/462">Pub. L. 85–462</ref>, substituted “eighty-five positions, of which not less than seventy-three shall be for the National Institutes of Health” for “sixty positions”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1956—Subsec. (g). Act <date date="1956-06-29">June 29, 1956</date>, substituted “$20,000” for “$15,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1955—Subsec. (g). Act <date date="1955-08-01">Aug. 1, 1955</date>, increased from thirty to sixty the number of positions which the Administrator may establish in the professional and scientific service.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1950—Subsec. (b). Act <date date="1950-08-09">Aug. 9, 1950</date>, struck out “and may be granted leaves of absence without any deduction from their pay” after “allotments from their pay” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). Act <date date="1950-08-15">Aug. 15, 1950</date>, § 3(e), made provisions applicable to members of all national advisory councils.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). Act <date date="1950-08-15">Aug. 15, 1950</date>, § 4(b), added subsec. (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1949—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1949-10-12">Oct. 12, 1949</date>, made section applicable to Reserve officers.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). Act <date date="1949-10-12">Oct. 12, 1949</date>, redesignated subsec. (c) as (b) and repealed former subsec. (b) relating to Reserve officers.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). Act <date date="1949-10-12">Oct. 12, 1949</date>, redesignated subsec. (e) as (c). Former subsec. (c) redesignated (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). Act <date date="1949-10-12">Oct. 12, 1949</date>, redesignated subsec. (f) as (d) and repealed former subsec. (d) relating to female commissioned officers and defining “dependent”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). Act <date date="1949-10-12">Oct. 12, 1949</date>, redesignated subsec. (g) as (e) and struck out references to allowances. Former subsec. (e) redesignated (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). Act <date date="1949-10-12">Oct. 12, 1949</date>, redesignated subsec. (h) as (f). Former subsec. (f) redesignated (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (g), (h). Act <date date="1949-10-12">Oct. 12, 1949</date>, redesignated subsecs. (g) and (h) as (e) and (f), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1948—Subsec. (b). Act <date date="1948-02-28">Feb. 28, 1948</date>, inserted “except as otherwise provided by law”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). Acts <date date="1948-06-16">June 16, 1948</date>, § 4(d), and <date date="1948-06-24">June 24, 1948</date>, § 4(d), made section applicable to the National Advisory Heart Council and increased the per diem of all members from $25 to $50, and made section applicable to the National Advisory Dental Research Council, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). Act <date date="1948-02-28">Feb. 28, 1948</date>, substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s209/f">section 209(f) of this title</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s209/d">section 209(d) of this title</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1946—Subsec. (e). Act <date date="1946-07-03">July 3, 1946</date>, inserted “members of the National Advisory Mental Health Council”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb425cb84-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idb425cb85-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reference to the Gillis W. Long Hansen’s Disease Center deemed to refer to the National Hansen’s Disease Programs Center, pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/107/220/s2">section 2 of Pub. L. 107–220</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s247e">section 247e of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Health and Human Services” substituted for “Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare” in subsecs. (c) and (g) pursuant <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/s509/b">section 509(b) of Pub. L. 96–88</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s3508/b">section 3508(b) of Title 20</ref>, Education.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb425cb86-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1986 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/272/tXVII/s17002/a/2">Pub. L. 99–272, title XVII, § 17002(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1986-04-07">Apr. 7, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/359">100 Stat. 359</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/272/tXVII/s17002/a/2">“The amendment made by paragraph (1) [amending this section] shall take effect as of <date date="1985-10-07">October 7, 1985</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb425cb87-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1985 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/117/s3/b">Pub. L. 99–117, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1985-10-07">Oct. 7, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/492">99 Stat. 492</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/117/s3/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall not diminish any benefits under an agreement entered into before the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1985-10-07">Oct. 7, 1985</date>] by a commissioned medical officer in the Regular Corps or the Reserve Corps of the Public Health Service.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb425cb88-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1962 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/87/793">Pub. L. 87–793</ref> effective first day of first pay period which begins on or after <date date="1962-10-11">Oct. 11, 1962</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/87/793/tVI/s1008">Pub. L. 87–793, title VI, § 1008</ref>, <date date="1962-10-11">Oct. 11, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/868">76 Stat. 868</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/87/649">Pub. L. 87–649</ref> effective <date date="1962-11-01">Nov. 1, 1962</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/87/649/s15">section 15 of Pub. L. 87–649</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t37/s101">section 101 of Title 37</ref>, Pay and Allowances of the Uniformed Services.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb425cb89-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1960 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/86/415">Pub. L. 86–415</ref> effective <date date="1960-07-01">July 1, 1960</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/86/415/s8/a">section 8(a) of Pub. L. 86–415</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s209">section 209 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb425cb8a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1958 Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/85/929">Pub. L. 85–929</ref> effective <date date="1958-09-06">Sept. 6, 1958</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/85/929/s6/a">section 6(a) of Pub. L. 85–929</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s342">section 342 of Title 21</ref>, Food and Drugs.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/85/462">Pub. L. 85–462</ref> effective <date date="1958-06-20">June 20, 1958</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/85/462/s17/b">section 17(b) of Pub. L. 85–462</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb425cb8b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1956 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by act <date date="1956-07-31">July 31, 1956</date>, effective at beginning of first pay period commencing after <date date="1956-06-30">June 30, 1956</date>, see section 120 of act <date date="1956-07-31">July 31, 1956</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb425cb8c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1950 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/act/1950-08-09/ch654/s3/a">Act Aug. 9, 1950, ch. 654, § 3(a)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/426">64 Stat. 426</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/act/1950-08-09/ch654/s3/a">“Sections 1 and 2 of this Act [amending this section and enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s210–1">section 210–1 of this title</ref>] shall become effective on <date date="1950-07-01">July 1, 1950</date>.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb425cb8d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1949 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by act <date date="1949-10-12">Oct. 12, 1949</date>, effective <date date="1949-10-01">Oct. 1, 1949</date>, see section 533(a) of act <date date="1949-10-12">Oct. 12, 1949</date>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t33/s854a">section 854a of Title 33</ref>, Navigation and Navigable Waters.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="repeals" id="idb425cb8e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Repeals</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/act/1956-07-31/ch804/tI/s117/b">Act July 31, 1956, ch. 804, title I, § 117(b)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/741">70 Stat. 741</ref>, cited as a credit to this section, which amended subsec. (g) of this section to increase the salary rates, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/88/426/tIII/s305/1">Pub. L. 88–426, title III, § 305(1)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-14">Aug. 14, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/422">78 Stat. 422</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb425cb8f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Advisory Committees</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/93/641/s6">Pub. L. 93–641, § 6</ref>, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2275">88 Stat. 2275</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s217a">section 217a of this title</ref>, provided that an advisory committee established pursuant to the Public Health Service Act shall terminate at such time as may be specifically prescribed by an Act of Congress enacted after <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb425cb90-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Other Laws to GS–16, 17, or 18 Pay Rates</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References in laws to the rates of pay for GS–16, 17, or 18, or to maximum rates of pay under the General Schedule, to be considered references to rates payable under specified sections of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, see section 529 [title I, § 101(c)(1)] of <ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref>, set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5376">section 5376 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb425cb91-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Maximum Pay and Allowances for Specific Fiscal Years</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/436/tII/s208">Pub. L. 100–436, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1988-09-20">Sept. 20, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1699">102 Stat. 1699</ref>, provided in part that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/436/tII/s208">“No funds appropriated for the fiscal year ending <date date="1989-09-30">September 30, 1989</date>, by this or any other Act, may be used to pay basic pay, special pays, basic allowances for subsistence and basic allowances for quarters of the commissioned corps of the Public Health Service described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s204">section 204 of title 42</ref>, United States Code, at a level that exceeds 110 percent of the Executive Level I [<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5312">5 U.S.C. 5312</ref>] annual rate of basic pay”.</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>Similar provisions were contained in the following prior appropriation acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101/h/tII/s208">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(h) [title II, § 208]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1329-256">101 Stat. 1329–256</ref>, 1329–274.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/500/s101/i/tII/s208">Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(i) [H.R. 5233, title II, § 208]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1783-287">100 Stat. 1783–287</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/99/591/s101/i/tII/s208">Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(i) [H.R. 5233, title II, § 208]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3341-287">100 Stat. 3341–287</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/178/tII/s208">Pub. L. 99–178, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1985-12-12">Dec. 12, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/1119">99 Stat. 1119</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/619/tII/s208">Pub. L. 98–619, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1984-11-08">Nov. 8, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/3321">98 Stat. 3321</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/98/139/tII/s208">Pub. L. 98–139, title II, § 208</ref>, <date date="1983-10-31">Oct. 31, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/888">97 Stat. 888</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb425cb92-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Nurses and Allied Health Professionals</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/436/tII/s214">Pub. L. 100–436, title II, § 214</ref>, <date date="1988-09-20">Sept. 20, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1700">102 Stat. 1700</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/436/tII/s214">“Funds made available for fiscal year 1989 and hereafter to the National Institutes of Health shall be available for payment of nurses and allied health professionals using pay, schedule options, benefits, and other authorities as provided for the nurses of the Veterans’ Administration under 38 U.S.C. chapter 73.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idb425cb93-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idb425cb94-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Director of the Office of Personnel Management” substituted for “Civil Service Commission” in subsec. (g) pursuant to Reorg. Plan No. 2 of 1978, § 102, 43 F.R. 36037, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3783">92 Stat. 3783</ref>, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1101">section 1101 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees, which transferred functions vested by statute in United States Civil Service Commission to Director of Office of Personnel Management (except as otherwise specified), effective <date date="1979-01-01">Jan. 1, 1979</date>, as provided by section 1–102 of Ex. Ord. No. 12107, <date date="1978-12-28">Dec. 28, 1978</date>, 44 F.R. 1055, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s1101">section 1101 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of Public Health Service, Surgeon General of Public Health Service, and all other officers and employees of Public Health Service, and functions of all agencies of or in Public Health Service transferred to Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare by Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1966, eff. <date date="1966-06-25">June 25, 1966</date>, 31 F.R. 8855, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1610">80 Stat. 1610</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s202">section 202 of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of Federal Security Administrator transferred to Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare and all agencies of Federal Security Agency transferred to Department of Health, Education, and Welfare by section 5 of Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1953, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3501">section 3501 of this title</ref>. Federal Security Agency and office of Administrator abolished by section 8 of Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1953.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="idb425cb95-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of President delegated to Secretary of Health and Human Services, see Ex. Ord. No. 11140, eff. <date date="1964-01-30">Jan. 30, 1964</date>, 29 F.R. 1637, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s202">section 202 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
