<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbbe7e20b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2121"><num value="2121">§ 2121.</num><heading> Authority of Commission</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbe7e20c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2121/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Research and development; weapons production; hazardous wastes; transfers of technologies</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission is authorized to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbe7e20d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2121/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> conduct experiments and do research and development work in the military application of atomic energy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbe7e20e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2121/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> engage in the production of atomic weapons, or atomic weapon parts, except that such activities shall be carried on only to the extent that the express consent and direction of the President of the United States has been obtained, which consent and direction shall be obtained at least once each year;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbe7e20f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2121/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> provide for safe storage, processing, transportation, and disposal of hazardous waste (including radioactive waste) resulting from nuclear materials production, weapons production and surveillance programs, and naval nuclear propulsion programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbe7e210-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2121/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> carry out research on and development of technologies needed for the effective negotiation and verification of international agreements on control of special nuclear materials and nuclear weapons; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbe7e211-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2121/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> under applicable law (other than this paragraph) and consistent with other missions of the Department of Energy, make transfers of federally owned or originated technology to State and local governments, private industry, and universities or other nonprofit organizations so that the prospects for commercialization of such technology are enhanced.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbe7e212-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2121/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Material for Department of Defense use</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President from time to time may direct the Commission (1) to deliver such quantities of special nuclear material or atomic weapons to the Department of Defense for such use as he deems necessary in the interest of national defense, or (2) to authorize the Department of Defense to manufacture, produce, or acquire any atomic weapon or utilization facility for military purposes: <i>Provided, however</i>, That such authorization shall not extend to the production of special nuclear material other than that incidental to the operation of such utilization facilities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbe7e213-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2121/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Sale, lease, or loan to other Nations of materials for military applications</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President may authorize the Commission or the Department of Defense, with the assistance of the other, to cooperate with another nation and, notwithstanding the provisions of section 2077, 2092, or 2111 of this title, to transfer by sale, lease, or loan to that nation, in accordance with terms and conditions of a program approved by the President—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbe7e214-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2121/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> nonnuclear parts of atomic weapons provided that such nation has made substantial progress in the development of atomic weapons, and other nonnuclear parts of atomic weapons systems involving Restricted Data provided that such transfer will not contribute significantly to that nation’s atomic weapon design, development, or fabrication capability; for the purpose of improving that nation’s state of training and operational readiness;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbe7e215-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2121/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> utilization facilities for military applications; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbe7e216-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2121/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> source, byproduct, or special nuclear material for research on, development of, production of, or use in utilization facilities for military applications; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbe7e217-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2121/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> source, byproduct, or special nuclear material for research on, development of, or use in atomic weapons: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the transfer of such material to that nation is necessary to improve its atomic weapon design, development, or fabrication capability: <i>And provided further</i>, That such nation has made substantial progress in the development of atomic weapons,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">whenever the President determines that the proposed cooperation and each proposed transfer arrangement for the nonnuclear parts of atomic weapons and atomic weapons systems, utilization facilities or source, byproduct, or special nuclear material will promote and will not constitute an unreasonable risk to the common defense and security, while such other nation is participating with the United States pursuant to an international arrangement by substantial and material contributions to the mutual defense and security: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the cooperation is undertaken pursuant to an agreement entered into in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153">section 2153 of this title</ref>: <i>And provided further</i>, That if an agreement for cooperation arranged pursuant to this subsection provides for transfer of utilization facilities for military applications the Commission, or the Department of Defense with respect to cooperation it has been authorized to undertake, may authorize any person to transfer such utilization facilities for military applications in accordance with the terms and conditions of this subsection and of the agreement for cooperation.</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbbe7e218-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, title I, § 91, as added <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-30/ch1073/s1">Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/936">68 Stat. 936</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/85/479/s1">Pub. L. 85–479, § 1</ref>, <date date="1958-07-02">July 2, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/276">72 Stat. 276</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/189/dC/tXXXI/s3157">Pub. L. 101–189, div. C, title XXXI, § 3157</ref>, <date date="1989-11-29">Nov. 29, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1684">103 Stat. 1684</ref>; renumbered title I, <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tIX/s902/a/8">Pub. L. 102–486, title IX, § 902(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2944">106 Stat. 2944</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbbe7e219-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbbe7e21a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idbbe7e21b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to this section were contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1806/a">section 1806(a) of this title</ref>, prior to the general amendment and renumbering of act <date date="1946-08-01">Aug. 1, 1946</date>, by act <date date="1954-08-30">Aug. 30, 1954</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbbe7e21c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (a)(3) to (5). <ref href="/us/pl/101/189">Pub. L. 101–189</ref> added pars. (3) to (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1958—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/85/479">Pub. L. 85–479</ref> added subsec. (c).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbbe7e21d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbe7e21e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Form of Certifications Regarding Safety or Reliability of Nuclear Weapons Stockpile</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dC/tXXXI/s3194">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [div. C, title XXXI, § 3194]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–481, which was formerly set out as a note under this section, was renumbered <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s4206">section 4206 of Pub. L. 107–314</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dC/tXXXI/s3141/e/7">Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXI, § 3141(e)(7)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1759">117 Stat. 1759</ref>, and classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2526">section 2526 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, and was repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s6118">section 6118 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces, by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dC/tXXXI/s3111/a">Pub. L. 119–60, div. C, title XXXI, § 3111(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1356">139 Stat. 1356</ref>, 1458.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbe7e21f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Authority To Provide Certificate of Commendation to Department of Energy and Contractor Employees for Exemplary Service in Stockpile Stewardship and Security</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dC/tXXXI/s3195">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [div. C, title XXXI, § 3195]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–481, which was formerly set out as a note under this section, was renumbered <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s4605">section 4605 of Pub. L. 107–314</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dC/tXXXI/s3141/i/6">Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXI, § 3141(i)(6)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1778">117 Stat. 1778</ref>, and classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2705">section 2705 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, and was repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s6244">section 6244 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces, by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dC/tXXXI/s3111/a">Pub. L. 119–60, div. C, title XXXI, § 3111(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1417">139 Stat. 1417</ref>, 1458.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbe7e220-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Nuclear Weapons Stockpile Life Extension Program</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dC/tXXXI/s3133">Pub. L. 106–65, div. C, title XXXI, § 3133</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/926">113 Stat. 926</ref>, which was formerly set out as a note under this section, was renumbered <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s4204">section 4204 of Pub. L. 107–314</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dC/tXXXI/s3141/e/5/A">Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXI, § 3141(e)(5)(A)</ref>–(C), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1758">117 Stat. 1758</ref>, and classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2524">section 2524 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, and was repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s6116">section 6116 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces, by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dC/tXXXI/s3111/a">Pub. L. 119–60, div. C, title XXXI, § 3111(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1352">139 Stat. 1352</ref>, 1458.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbe7e221-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report on Stockpile Stewardship Criteria</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/261/dC/tXXXI/s3158">Pub. L. 105–261, div. C, title XXXI, § 3158</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2257">112 Stat. 2257</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tX/s1067/3">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(3)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/774">113 Stat. 774</ref>, which was formerly set out as a note under this section, was renumbered <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s4202">section 4202 of Pub. L. 107–314</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dC/tXXXI/s3141/e/3">Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXI, § 3141(e)(3)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1758">117 Stat. 1758</ref>, and classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2522">section 2522 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, and was repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s6113">section 6113 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces, by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dC/tXXXI/s3111/a">Pub. L. 119–60, div. C, title XXXI, § 3111(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1345">139 Stat. 1345</ref>, 1458.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbe7e222-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Panel To Assess the Reliability, Safety, and Security of the United States Nuclear Stockpile</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/105/261/dC/tXXXI/s3159">Pub. L. 105–261, div. C, title XXXI, § 3159</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2258">112 Stat. 2258</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dA/tX/s1067/3">Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(3)</ref>, <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/774">113 Stat. 774</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/107/dC/tXXXI/s3156">Pub. L. 107–107, div. C, title XXXI, § 3156</ref>, <date date="2001-12-28">Dec. 28, 2001</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1379">115 Stat. 1379</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/dC/tXXXI/s3175">Pub. L. 107–314, div. C, title XXXI, § 3175</ref>, <date date="2002-12-02">Dec. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/2745">116 Stat. 2745</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/314/dC/tXXXI/s3175">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirement for Panel</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, shall enter into a contract with a federally funded research and development center to establish a panel for the assessment of the certification process for the reliability, safety, and security of the United States nuclear stockpile.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Composition and Administration of Panel</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The panel shall consist of private citizens of the United States with knowledge and expertise in the technical aspects of design, manufacture, and maintenance of nuclear weapons.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The federally funded research and development center shall be responsible for establishing appropriate procedures for the panel, including selection of a panel chairman.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Duties of Panel</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Each year the panel shall review and assess the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> The annual certification process, including the conclusions and recommendations resulting from the process, for the safety, security, and reliability of the nuclear weapons stockpile of the United States, as carried out by the directors of the national weapons laboratories.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The long-term adequacy of the process of certifying the safety, security, and reliability of the nuclear weapons stockpile of the United States.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The adequacy of the criteria established by the Secretary of Energy pursuant to section 3158 [formerly set out as a note above] for achieving the purposes for which those criteria are established.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than October 1 of 1999 and 2000, and not later than <date date="2002-02-01">February 1, 2002</date>, the panel shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives a report setting forth its findings and conclusions resulting from the review and assessment carried out for the year covered by the report. The report shall be submitted in classified and unclassified form.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Cooperation of Other Agencies</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The panel may secure directly from the Department of Energy, the Department of Defense, or any of the national weapons laboratories or plants or any other Federal department or agency information that the panel considers necessary to carry out its duties.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> For carrying out its duties, the panel shall be provided full and timely cooperation by the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Defense, the Commander of United States Strategic Command, the Directors of the Los Alamos National Laboratory, the Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory, the Sandia National Laboratories, the Savannah River Site, the Y–12 Plant, the Pantex Facility, and the Kansas City Plant, and any other official of the United States that the chairman of the panel determines as having information described in paragraph (1).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of Defense shall each designate at least one officer or employee of the Department of Energy and the Department of Defense, respectively, to serve as a liaison officer between the department and the panel.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Energy shall each contribute 50 percent of the amount of funds that are necessary for the panel to carry out its duties. Funds available for the Department of Energy for the National Nuclear Security Administration shall be available for the Department of Energy contribution.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Termination of Panel</inline>.—</heading><content>The panel shall terminate <date date="2003-04-01">April 1, 2003</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Initial Implementation</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense shall enter into the contract required under subsection (a) not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>]. The panel shall convene its first meeting not later than 30 days after the date as of which all members of the panel have been appointed.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Follow-Up Report</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than <date date="2003-02-01">February 1, 2003</date>, the panel shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives a follow-up report assessing progress toward meeting the expectations set forth by the panel for the United States stockpile stewardship program, and making recommendations for corrective legislative action where progress has been unsatisfactory.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbe7e223-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plan for Stewardship, Management, and Certification of Warheads in the Nuclear Weapons Stockpile</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dC/tXXXI/s3151">Pub. L. 105–85, div. C, title XXXI, § 3151</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2041">111 Stat. 2041</ref>, which was formerly set out as a note under this section, was renumbered <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s4203">section 4203 of Pub. L. 107–314</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dC/tXXXI/s3141/e/4">Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXI, § 3141(e)(4)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1758">117 Stat. 1758</ref>, and classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2523">section 2523 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, and was repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s6114">section 6114 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces, by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dC/tXXXI/s3111/a">Pub. L. 119–60, div. C, title XXXI, § 3111(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1346">139 Stat. 1346</ref>, 1458.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbe7e224-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Commission on Maintaining United States Nuclear Weapons Expertise</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dC/tXXXI/s3162">Pub. L. 104–201, div. C, title XXXI, § 3162</ref>, <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2843">110 Stat. 2843</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dC/tXXXI/s3163">Pub. L. 105–85, div. C, title XXXI, § 3163</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2049">111 Stat. 2049</ref>, established the Commission on Maintaining United States Nuclear Weapons Expertise to develop a plan to attract qualified personnel to the nuclear weapons complex and directed the Commission to submit a report to the Secretary of Energy and to Congress by <date date="1999-03-15">Mar. 15, 1999</date>, 30 days after which the Commission would terminate.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbe7e225-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Tritium Production Program</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dC/tXXXI/s3133">Pub. L. 104–106, div. C, title XXXI, § 3133</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/618">110 Stat. 618</ref>, which was formerly set out as a note under this section, was renumbered <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s4231">section 4231 of Pub. L. 107–314</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dC/tXXXI/s3141/e/16/A">Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXI, § 3141(e)(16)(A)</ref>–(C), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1761">117 Stat. 1761</ref>, and classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2541">section 2541 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, and was repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s6141">section 6141 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces, by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dC/tXXXI/s3111/a">Pub. L. 119–60, div. C, title XXXI, § 3111(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1372">139 Stat. 1372</ref>, 1458.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbe7e226-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Manufacturing Infrastructure for Refabrication and Certification of Nuclear Weapons Stockpile</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dC/tXXXI/s3137">Pub. L. 104–106, div. C, title XXXI, § 3137</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/620">110 Stat. 620</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/104/201/dC/tXXXI/s3132/a">Pub. L. 104–201, div. C, title XXXI, § 3132(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1996-09-23">Sept. 23, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/2829">110 Stat. 2829</ref>, which was formerly set out as a note under this section, was renumbered <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s4212">section 4212 of Pub. L. 107–314</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dC/tXXXI/s3141/e/13/A">Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXI, § 3141(e)(13)(A)</ref>–(C), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1760">117 Stat. 1760</ref>, and classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2532">section 2532 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, and was repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s6122">section 6122 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces, by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dC/tXXXI/s3111/a">Pub. L. 119–60, div. C, title XXXI, § 3111(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1358">139 Stat. 1358</ref>, 1458.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbe7e227-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Fellowship Program for Development of Skills Critical to Department of Energy Nuclear Weapons Complex</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dC/tXXXI/s3140">Pub. L. 104–106, div. C, title XXXI, § 3140</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/621">110 Stat. 621</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/106/65/dC/tXXXI/s3162/a">Pub. L. 106–65, div. C, title XXXI, § 3162(a)</ref>–(d), <date date="1999-10-05">Oct. 5, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/943">113 Stat. 943</ref>, which was formerly set out as a note under this section, was renumbered <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s4623">section 4623 of Pub. L. 107–314</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dC/tXXXI/s3141/i/10">Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXI, § 3141(i)(10)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1779">117 Stat. 1779</ref>, and classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2723">section 2723 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, and was repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s6253">section 6253 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces, by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dC/tXXXI/s3111/a">Pub. L. 119–60, div. C, title XXXI, § 3111(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1418">139 Stat. 1418</ref>, 1458.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbe7e228-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study on Nuclear Test Readiness Postures</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dC/tXXXI/s3152">Pub. L. 104–106, div. C, title XXXI, § 3152</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/623">110 Stat. 623</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dC/tXXXI/s3192">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [div. C, title XXXI, § 3192]</ref>, <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–480, which was formerly set out as a note under this section, was renumbered <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s4208">section 4208 of Pub. L. 107–314</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dC/tXXXI/s3141/e/9">Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXI, § 3141(e)(9)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1759">117 Stat. 1759</ref>, and was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2528">section 2528 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dC/tXXXI/s3133/e/1/A">Pub. L. 112–239, div. C, title XXXI, § 3133(e)(1)(A)</ref>, (2), <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2192">126 Stat. 2192</ref>, 2193.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbe7e229-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Report on Waste Streams Generated by Nuclear Weapons Production Cycle</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/337/dC/tXXXI/s3154">Pub. L. 103–337, div. C, title XXXI, § 3154</ref>, <date date="1994-10-05">Oct. 5, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3091">108 Stat. 3091</ref>, directed Secretary of Energy, not later than <date date="1996-03-31">Mar. 31, 1996</date>, to submit to Congress report containing description of all waste streams generated before 1992 during each step of complete cycle of production and disposition of nuclear weapon components by Department of Energy, with description for each such step to be based on unit of analysis appropriate for that step, and to include estimate of volume of waste generated per unit of analysis and analysis of characteristics of each waste stream.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbe7e22a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prohibition on Research and Development of Low-Yield Nuclear Weapons</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dC/tXXXI/s3136">Pub. L. 103–160, div. C, title XXXI, § 3136</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1946">107 Stat. 1946</ref>, expressed policy of United States with respect to research and development of low-yield nuclear weapons, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dC/tXXXI/s3116/a">Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXI, § 3116(a)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1746">117 Stat. 1746</ref>.</p>
<p>[<ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dC/tXXXI/s3116/b">Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXI, § 3116(b)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1746">117 Stat. 1746</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/136/dC/tXXXI/s3116/b">“Nothing in the repeal made by subsection (a) [repealing <ref href="/us/pl/103/160/s3136">section 3136 of Pub. L. 103–160</ref>, formerly set out as a note above] shall be construed as authorizing the testing, acquisition, or deployment of a low-yield nuclear weapon.”</quotedContent>
]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbe7e22b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Stockpile Stewardship Program</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dC/tXXXI/s3156">Pub. L. 105–85, div. C, title XXXI, § 3156</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2045">111 Stat. 2045</ref>, expressed findings of Congress and policy of United States about the direction and conduct of the stockpile stewardship program, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/105/261/dC/tXXXI/s3157">Pub. L. 105–261, div. C, title XXXI, § 3157</ref>, <date date="1998-10-17">Oct. 17, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2257">112 Stat. 2257</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dC/tXXXI/s3138">Pub. L. 103–160, div. C, title XXXI, § 3138</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1946">107 Stat. 1946</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dC/tXXXI/s3152/e">Pub. L. 105–85, div. C, title XXXI, § 3152(e)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2042">111 Stat. 2042</ref>, which was formerly set out as a note under this section, was renumbered <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s4201">section 4201 of Pub. L. 107–314</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dC/tXXXI/s3141/e/2">Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXI, § 3141(e)(2)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1758">117 Stat. 1758</ref>, and classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2521">section 2521 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, and was repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s6111">section 6111 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces, by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dC/tXXXI/s3111/a">Pub. L. 119–60, div. C, title XXXI, § 3111(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1344">139 Stat. 1344</ref>, 1458.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbe7e22c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Limitations on United States Nuclear Weapons Testing</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tII/s261">Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title II, § 261</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1608">107 Stat. 1608</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/103/160/dA/tII/s261">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Limitation on Obligation of Funds</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Defense may not obligate funds in preparation for any activity of the Department of Defense, including the so-called ‘Mighty Uncle’ test, to study the effects of a nuclear weapon explosion through underground nuclear weapons testing unless that test is permitted in accordance with the provisions of <ref href="/us/pl/102/377/s507">section 507 of Public Law 102–377</ref> [set out below] (<ref href="/us/stat/106/1343">106 Stat. 1343</ref>).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Certain Actions Not Prohibited</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Subsection (a) does not preclude the Secretary of Defense, acting through the Director of the Defense Nuclear Agency, from—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> proceeding with underground nuclear test tunnel deactivation and environmental cleanup; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> expending funds for infrastructure activities not covered by the limitation in subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Funding</inline>.—</heading><content>Of the funds authorized to be appropriated pursuant to section 201 [<ref href="/us/stat/107/1583">107 Stat. 1583</ref>] for Defense-wide activities, not more than $38,000,000 may be used for activities described in subsection (b).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dC/tXXXI/s3137">Pub. L. 103–160, div. C, title XXXI, § 3137</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1946">107 Stat. 1946</ref>, which was formerly set out as a note under this section, was renumbered <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s4211">section 4211 of Pub. L. 107–314</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dC/tXXXI/s3141/e/12/A">Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXI, § 3141(e)(12)(A)</ref>–(C), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1760">117 Stat. 1760</ref>, and was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2531">section 2531 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dC/tXXXI/s3131/d/3">Pub. L. 112–239, div. C, title XXXI, § 3131(d)(3)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2181">126 Stat. 2181</ref>.</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/102/377/tV/s507">Pub. L. 102–377, title V, § 507</ref>, <date date="1992-10-02">Oct. 2, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1343">106 Stat. 1343</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dC/tXXXI/s3141/e/11">Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXI, § 3141(e)(11)</ref>, <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1760">117 Stat. 1760</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/136/dC/tXXXI/s3141/e/11">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> Hereafter, funds made available by this Act or any other Act for fiscal year 1993 or for any other fiscal year may be available for conducting a test of a nuclear explosive device only if the conduct of that test is permitted in accordance with the provisions of this section.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> No underground test of a nuclear weapon may be conducted by the United States after <date date="1992-09-30">September 30, 1992</date>, and before <date date="1993-07-01">July 1, 1993</date>.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><chapeau> On and after <date date="1993-07-01">July 1, 1993</date>, and before <date date="1997-01-01">January 1, 1997</date>, an underground test of a nuclear weapon may be conducted by the United States—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><chapeau> only if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the President has submitted the annual report required under subsection (d);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> 90 days have elapsed after the submittal of that report in accordance with that subsection; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Congress has not agreed to a joint resolution described in subsection (d)(3) within that 90-day period; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> only if the test is conducted during the period covered by the report.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Not later than March 1, of each year beginning after 1992, the President shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives, in classified and unclassified forms, a report containing the following matters:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> A schedule for resumption of the Nuclear Testing Talks with Russia.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> A plan for achieving a multilateral comprehensive ban on the testing of nuclear weapons on or before <date date="1996-09-30">September 30, 1996</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> An assessment of the number and type of nuclear warheads that will remain in the United States stockpile of active nuclear weapons on <date date="1996-09-30">September 30, 1996</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="D">“(D)</num><chapeau> For each fiscal year after fiscal year 1992, an assessment of the number and type of nuclear warheads that will remain in the United States stockpile of nuclear weapons and that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> will not be in the United States stockpile of active nuclear weapons;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> will remain under the control of the Department of Defense; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="iii">“(iii)</num><content> will not be transferred to the Department of Energy for dismantlement.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="E">“(E)</num><content> A description of the safety features of each warhead that is covered by an assessment referred to in subparagraph (C) or (D).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="F">“(F)</num><content> A plan for installing one or more modern safety features in each warhead identified in the assessment referred to in subparagraph (C), as determined after an analysis of the costs and benefits of installing such feature or features in the warhead, should have one or more of such features.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="G">“(G)</num><content> An assessment of the number and type of nuclear weapons tests, not to exceed 5 tests in any period covered by an annual report under this paragraph and a total of 15 tests in the 4-fiscal year period beginning with fiscal year 1993, that are necessary in order to ensure the safety of each nuclear warhead in which one or more modern safety features are installed pursuant to the plan referred to in subparagraph (F).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="H">“(H)</num><content> A schedule, in accordance with subparagraph (G), for conducting at the Nevada test site, each of the tests enumerated in the assessment pursuant to subparagraph (G).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The first annual report shall cover the period beginning on the date on which a resumption of testing of nuclear weapons is permitted under subsection (c) and ending on <date date="1994-09-30">September 30, 1994</date>. Each annual report thereafter shall cover the fiscal year following the fiscal year in which the report is submitted.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> For the purposes of paragraph (1), ‘joint resolution’ means only a joint resolution introduced after the date on which the Committees referred to in that paragraph receive the report required by that paragraph the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: ‘The Congress disapproves the report of the President on nuclear weapons testing, dated          .’ (the blank space being appropriately filled in).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> No report is required under this subsection after 1996.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), during a period covered by an annual report submitted pursuant to subsection (d), nuclear weapons may be tested only as follows:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Only those nuclear explosive devices in which modern safety features have been installed pursuant to the plan referred to in subsection (d)(1)(F) may be tested.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Only the number and types of tests specified in the report pursuant to subsection (d)(1)(G) may be conducted.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> One test of the reliability of a nuclear weapon other than one referred to in paragraph (1)(A) may be conducted during any period covered by an annual report, but only if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> within the first 60 days after the beginning of that period, the President certifies to Congress that it is vital to the national security interests of the United States to test the reliability of such a nuclear weapon; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> within the 60-day period beginning on the date that Congress receives the certification, Congress does not agree to a joint resolution described in subparagraph (B).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> For the purposes of subparagraph (A), ‘joint resolution’ means only a joint resolution introduced after the date on which the Congress receives the certification referred to in that subparagraph the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: ‘The Congress disapproves the testing of a nuclear weapon covered by the certification of the President dated          .’ (the blank space being appropriately filled in).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The President may authorize the United Kingdom to conduct in the United States, within a period covered by an annual report, one test of a nuclear weapon if the President determines that it is in the national interests of the United States to do so. Such a test shall be considered as one of the tests within the maximum number of tests that the United States is permitted to conduct during that period under paragraph (1)(B).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> [Transferred to former <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2530">section 2530 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense. See <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s6121">section 6121 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces.]</heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><content> In the computation of the 90-day period referred to in subsection (c)(1) and the 60-day period referred to in subsection (e)(2)(A)(ii), the days on which either House is not in session because of an adjournment of more than 3 days to a day certain shall be excluded.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><chapeau> In this section, the term ‘modern safety feature’ means any of the following features:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> An insensitive high explosive (IHE).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Fire resistant pits (FRP).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> An enhanced detonation safety (ENDS) system.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbea522d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Nuclear Test Ban Readiness Program</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/456/dA/tXIV/s1436">Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XIV, § 1436</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2075">102 Stat. 2075</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dC/tXXXI/s3152/i">Pub. L. 105–85, div. C, title XXXI, § 3152(i)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2042">111 Stat. 2042</ref>, which was formerly set out as a note under this section, was renumbered <ref href="/us/pl/107/314/s4207">section 4207 of Pub. L. 107–314</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/108/136/dC/tXXXI/s3141/e/8/A">Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXI, § 3141(e)(8)(A)</ref>–(C), <date date="2003-11-24">Nov. 24, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/1759">117 Stat. 1759</ref>, and classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s2527">section 2527 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, and was repealed and restated as <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s6119">section 6119 of Title 10</ref>, Armed Forces, by <ref href="/us/pl/119/60/dC/tXXXI/s3111/a">Pub. L. 119–60, div. C, title XXXI, § 3111(a)</ref>, (b)(1), <date date="2025-12-18">Dec. 18, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/1356">139 Stat. 1356</ref>, 1458.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbbea522e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="idbbea522f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Authority vested in President by subsec. (c) of this section delegated to Secretary of Defense and Secretary of Energy, see section 2(a)(1) of Ex. Ord. No. 10841, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153">section 2153 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
