<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbbea5268-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2134"><num value="2134">§ 2134.</num><heading> Medical, industrial, and commercial licenses</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbea5269-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2134/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Medical therapy</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission is authorized to issue licenses to persons applying therefor for utilization facilities for use in medical therapy. In issuing such licenses the Commission is directed to permit the widest amount of effective medical therapy possible with the amount of special nuclear material available for such purposes and to impose the minimum amount of regulation consistent with its obligations under this chapter to promote the common defense and security and to protect the health and safety of the public.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbea526a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2134/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Industrial and commercial purposes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">As provided for in subsection (b) or (c) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2132">section 2132 of this title</ref>, or where specifically authorized by law, the Commission is authorized to issue licenses under this subsection to persons applying therefor for utilization and production facilities for industrial and commercial purposes. In issuing licenses under this subsection, the Commission shall impose the minimum amount of such regulations and terms of license as will permit the Commission to fulfill its obligations under this chapter.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbea526b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2134/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Research and development activities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbbea526c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2134/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), the Commission is authorized to issue licenses to persons applying therefor for utilization and production facilities useful in the conduct of research and development activities of the types specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2051">section 2051 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbbea526d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2134/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commission is directed to impose only such minimum amount of regulation of the licensee as the Commission finds will permit the Commission to fulfill its obligations under this chapter to promote the common defense and security and to protect the health and safety of the public and will permit the conduct of widespread and diverse research and development.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idbbea526e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2134/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on utilization facilities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Commission may issue a license under this section for a utilization facility useful in the conduct of research and development activities of the types specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2051">section 2051 of this title</ref> if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbbea526f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2134/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> not more than 75 percent of the annual costs to the licensee of owning and operating the facility are devoted to the sale, other than for research and development or education and training, of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbbea5270-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2134/c/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> nonenergy services;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbbea5271-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2134/c/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> energy; or</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idbbea5272-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2134/c/3/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> a combination of nonenergy services and energy; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idbbea5273-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2134/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> not more than 50 percent of the annual costs to the licensee of owning and operating the facility are devoted to the sale of energy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbea5274-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2134/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No license under this section may be given to any person for activities which are not under or within the jurisdiction of the United States, except for the export of production or utilization facilities under terms of an agreement for cooperation arranged pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153">section 2153 of this title</ref> or except under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2139">section 2139 of this title</ref>. No license may be issued to any corporation or other entity if the Commission knows or has reason to believe it is owned, controlled, or dominated by an alien, a foreign corporation, or a foreign government. In any event, no license may be issued to any person within the United States if, in the opinion of the Commission, the issuance of a license to such person would be inimical to the common defense and security or to the health and safety of the public.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbbea5275-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, title I, § 104, as added <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-30/ch1073/s1">Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/937">68 Stat. 937</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/91/560/s5">Pub. L. 91–560, § 5</ref>, <date date="1970-12-19">Dec. 19, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1472">84 Stat. 1472</ref>; renumbered title I, <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tIX/s902/a/8">Pub. L. 102–486, title IX, § 902(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2944">106 Stat. 2944</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/439/tI/s106/b">Pub. L. 115–439, title I, § 106(b)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5577">132 Stat. 5577</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/67/dB/tVI/s601">Pub. L. 118–67, div. B, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="2024-07-09">July 9, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1481">138 Stat. 1481</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbbea5276-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbbea5277-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbbea5278-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a), (b), and (c)(2), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-30/ch1073/s1">act Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/919">68 Stat. 919</ref>, known as the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2011">section 2011 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbbea5279-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/118/67">Pub. L. 118–67</ref> inserted subsec. heading; designated first sentence as par. (1), inserted par. heading, and substituted “Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), the Commission” for “The Commission”; designated second sentence as par. (2) and inserted heading; and substituted par. (3) for third sentence which read as follows: “The Commission is authorized to issue licenses under this section for utilization facilities useful in the conduct of research and development activities of the types specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2051">section 2051 of this title</ref> in which the licensee sells research and testing services and energy to others, subject to the condition that the licensee shall recover not more than 75 percent of the annual costs to the licensee of owning and operating the facility through sales of nonenergy services, energy, or both, other than research and development or education and training, of which not more than 50 percent may be through sales of energy.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/115/439">Pub. L. 115–439</ref> struck out “and which are not facilities of the type specified in subsection (b)” after “<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2051">section 2051 of this title</ref>” and inserted at end “The Commission is authorized to issue licenses under this section for utilization facilities useful in the conduct of research and development activities of the types specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2051">section 2051 of this title</ref> in which the licensee sells research and testing services and energy to others, subject to the condition that the licensee shall recover not more than 75 percent of the annual costs to the licensee of owning and operating the facility through sales of nonenergy services, energy, or both, other than research and development or education and training, of which not more than 50 percent may be through sales of energy.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/91/560">Pub. L. 91–560</ref> substituted provisions authorizing the issue of licenses for utilization or production facilities for industrial or commercial purposes (i) where specifically authorized by law or (ii) where the facility was constructed or operated under an arrangement with the Commission entered into under the cooperative power reactor demonstration program, and the applicable statutory authorization does not require licensing under section 2133, or (iii) where the facility was theretofore licensed under section 2134(b), for provisions authorizing the issue of licenses for utilization and production facilities involved in the conduct of research and development activities leading to the demonstration of the practical value of such facilities for industrial and commercial purposes.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbbea527a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbea527b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Encouraging Private Investment in Research and Test Reactors</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/439/tI/s106/a">Pub. L. 115–439, title I, § 106(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-01-14">Jan. 14, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5577">132 Stat. 5577</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/439/tI/s106/a">“The purpose of this section [amending this section] is to encourage private investment in research and test reactors.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
