<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbbecc3a7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2139"><num value="2139">§ 2139.</num><heading> Component and other parts of facilities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbecc3a8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2139/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Licenses for domestic activities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With respect to those utilization and production facilities which are so determined by the Commission pursuant to section 2014(v)(2) or 2014(cc)(2) of this title the Commission may issue general licenses for domestic activities required to be licensed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2131">section 2131 of this title</ref>, if the Commission determines in writing that such general licensing will not constitute an unreasonable risk to the common defense and security.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbecc3a9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2139/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Export licenses</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">After consulting with the Secretaries of State, Energy, and Commerce, the Commission is authorized and directed to determine which component parts as defined in section 2014(v)(2) or 2014(cc)(2) of this title and which other items or substances are especially relevant from the standpoint of export control because of their significance for nuclear explosive purposes. Except as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2155/b/2">section 2155(b)(2) of this title</ref>, no such component, substance, or item which is so determined by the Commission shall be exported unless the Commission issues a general or specific license for its export after finding, based on a reasonable judgment of the assurances provided and other information available to the Federal Government, including the Commission, that the following criteria or their equivalent are met: (1) IAEA safeguards as required by Article III (2) of the Treaty will be applied with respect to such component, substance, or item; (2) no such component, substance, or item will be used for any nuclear explosive device or for research on or development of any nuclear explosive device; and (3) no such component, substance, or item will be retransferred to the jurisdiction of any other nation or group of nations unless the prior consent of the United States is obtained for such retransfer; and after determining in writing that the issuance of each such general or specific license or category of licenses will not be inimical to the common defense and security: <i>Provided</i>, That a specific license shall not be required for an export pursuant to this section if the component, item or substance is covered by a facility license issued pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2155">section 2155 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbecc3aa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2139/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Exports inimical to common defense and security of United States</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission shall not issue an export license under the authority of subsection (b) if it is advised by the executive branch, in accordance with the procedures established under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2155/a">section 2155(a) of this title</ref>, that the export would be inimical to the common defense and security of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbbecc3ab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, title I, § 109, as added <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-30/ch1073/s1">Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/939">68 Stat. 939</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/87/615/s9">Pub. L. 87–615, § 9</ref>, <date date="1962-08-29">Aug. 29, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/411">76 Stat. 411</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/89/645/s1/b">Pub. L. 89–645, § 1(b)</ref>, <date date="1966-10-13">Oct. 13, 1966</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/80/891">80 Stat. 891</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/242/tIII/s309/a">Pub. L. 95–242, title III, § 309(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/141">92 Stat. 141</ref>; renumbered title I, <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tIX/s902/a/8">Pub. L. 102–486, title IX, § 902(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2944">106 Stat. 2944</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/dG/tXII/s1225/d/2">Pub. L. 105–277, div. G, title XII, § 1225(d)(2)</ref>, <date date="1998-10-21">Oct. 21, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/2681-774">112 Stat. 2681–774</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbbecc3ac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbbecc3ad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbbecc3ae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref> struck out “and the Director” after “Energy, and Commerce”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/242">Pub. L. 95–242</ref> designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and substituted “the Commission may issue general licenses for domestic activities required to be licensed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2131">section 2131 of this title</ref>, if the Commission determines in writing that such general licensing will not constitute an unreasonable risk to the common defense and security” for “the Commission may (a) issue general licenses for activities required to be licensed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2131">section 2131 of this title</ref>, if the Commission determines in writing that such general licensing will not constitute an unreasonable risk to the common defense and security, and (b) issue licenses for the export of such facilities, if the Commission determines in writing that each export will not constitute an unreasonable risk to the common defense and security”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b), (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/242">Pub. L. 95–242</ref> added subsecs. (b) and (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1966—<ref href="/us/pl/89/645">Pub. L. 89–645</ref> substituted “section 2014(v)(2) or 2014 (cc)(2)” for “section 2014(t)(2) or 2014(aa)(2)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—<ref href="/us/pl/87/615">Pub. L. 87–615</ref> substituted “section 2014(t)(2) or 2014(aa)(2)” for “section 2014(p)(2) or 2014(v)(2)”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbbecc3af-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbbecc3b0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/277">Pub. L. 105–277</ref> effective on earlier of <date date="1999-04-01">Apr. 1, 1999</date>, or date of abolition of the United States Arms Control and Disarmament Agency pursuant to reorganization plan described in <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6601">section 6601 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/277/s1201">section 1201 of Pub. L. 105–277</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s6511">section 6511 of Title 22</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbbecc3b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/95/242">Pub. L. 95–242</ref> effective <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, except as otherwise provided and regardless of any requirement for the promulgation of implementing regulations, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/242/s603/c">section 603(c) of Pub. L. 95–242</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3201">section 3201 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbecc3b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Exports Contracted for Prior to <date date="1977-11-01">Nov. 1, 1977</date>, Made Within One Year of <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>; Savings Provision</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/95/242/tIII/s309/d">Pub. L. 95–242, title III, § 309(d)</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/142">92 Stat. 142</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/242/tIII/s309/d">“The amendments to section 109 of the 1954 Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2139">42 U.S.C. 2139</ref>] made by this section shall not affect the approval of exports contracted for prior to <date date="1977-11-01">November 1, 1977</date>, which are made within one year of the date of enactment of such amendments [<date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbbecc3b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbecc3b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Performance of Functions Pending Development of Procedures</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The performance of functions under this chapter, as amended by the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Act of 1978, <ref href="/us/pl/95/242">Pub. L. 95–242</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/120">92 Stat. 120</ref>, not to be delayed pending development of procedures even though as many as 120 days [after <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>] are allowed for establishing those procedures, see section 5(b) of Ex. Ord. No. 12058, <date date="1978-05-11">May 11, 1978</date>, 43 F.R. 20947, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3201">section 3201 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
