<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbbef0d29-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2153c"><num value="2153c">§ 2153c.</num><heading> Renegotiation of agreements for cooperation</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbef0d2a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2153c/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Application to existing agreements of undertakings required of new agreements after <date date="1978-03-10">March 10, 1978</date></heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall initiate a program immediately to renegotiate agreements for cooperation in effect on <date date="1978-03-10">March 10, 1978</date>, or otherwise to obtain the agreement of parties to such agreements for cooperation to the undertakings that would be required for new agreements under the 1954 Act. To the extent that an agreement for cooperation in effect on <date date="1978-03-10">March 10, 1978</date>, with a cooperating party contains provisions equivalent to any or all of the criteria set forth in section 127 of the 1954 Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2156">42 U.S.C. 2156</ref>] with respect to materials and equipment transferred pursuant thereto or with respect to any special nuclear material used in or produced through the use of any such material or equipment, any renegotiated agreement with that cooperating party shall continue to contain an equivalent provision with respect to such transferred materials and equipment and such special nuclear material. To the extent that an agreement for cooperation in effect on <date date="1978-03-10">March 10, 1978</date>, with a cooperating party does not contain provisions with respect to any nuclear materials and equipment which have previously been transferred under an agreement for cooperation with the United States and which are under the jurisdiction or control of the cooperating party and with respect to any special nuclear material which is used in or produced through the use thereof and which is under the jurisdiction or control of the cooperating party, which are equivalent to any or all of those required for new and amended agreements for cooperation under section 123 a. of the 1954 Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153/a">42 U.S.C. 2153(a)</ref>], the President shall vigorously seek to obtain the application of such provisions with respect to such nuclear materials and equipment and such special nuclear material. Nothing in this Act or in the 1954 Act shall be deemed to relinquish any rights which the United States may have under any agreement for cooperation in force on <date date="1978-03-10">March 10, 1978</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbef0d2b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2153c/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Presidential review of export agreement conditions and policy goals</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall annually review each of requirements (1) through (9) set forth for inclusion in agreements for cooperation under section 123 a. of the 1954 Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153/a">42 U.S.C. 2153(a)</ref>] and the export policy goals set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153b">section 2153b of this title</ref> to determine whether it is in the interest of United States non-proliferation objectives for any such requirements or export policies which are not already being applied as export criteria to be enacted as additional export criteria.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbef0d2c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2153c/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Presidential proposals for additional export criteria</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the President proposes enactment of any such requirements or export policies as additional export criteria or to take any other action with respect to such requirements or export policy goals for the purpose of encouraging adherence by nations and groups of nations to such requirements and policies, he shall submit such a proposal together with an explanation thereof to the Congress.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbef0d2d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2153c/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Congressional action</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate or the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, after reviewing the President’s annual report or any proposed legislation, determines that it is in the interest of United States non-proliferation objectives to take any action with respect to such requirements or export policy goals, it shall report a joint resolution to implement such determination. Any joint resolution so reported shall be considered in the Senate and the House of Representatives, respectively, under applicable procedures provided for the consideration of resolutions pursuant to subsection <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003261">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003261"><num>1</num> So in original.</note> 130 b. through g. of the 1954 Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2159/b">42 U.S.C. 2159(b)</ref> through (g)].</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbbef0d2e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/242/tIV/s404">Pub. L. 95–242, title IV, § 404</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/147">92 Stat. 147</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/437/s15/g">Pub. L. 103–437, § 15(g)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4593">108 Stat. 4593</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbbef0d2f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbbef0d30-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbbef0d31-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (a), means the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Act of 1978, <ref href="/us/pl/95/242">Pub. L. 95–242</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/120">92 Stat. 120</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 47 (§ 3201 et seq.) of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3201">section 3201 of Title 22</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbbef0d32-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Act of 1978, and not as part of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 which comprises this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153b">Section 2153b of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (b), was in the original “section 401”, meaning <ref href="/us/pl/95/242/s401">section 401 of Pub. L. 95–242</ref>, which amended <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153">section 2153 of this title</ref>. Section 401 has been translated as <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153b">section 2153b of this title</ref>, which was enacted by <ref href="/us/pl/95/242/s403">section 403 of Pub. L. 95–242</ref>, to reflect the probable intent of Congress in view of the reference to the export policy goals which are set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153b">section 2153b of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbbef0d33-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/103/437">Pub. L. 103–437</ref> substituted “Foreign Affairs” for “International Relations”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbbef0d34-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idbbef0d35-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, except as otherwise provided and regardless of any requirements for the promulgation of implementing regulations, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/242/s603/c">section 603(c) of Pub. L. 95–242</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3201">section 3201 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbef0d36-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Supply of Additional Low-Enriched Uranium Under International Agreements for Cooperation in Civil Uses of Nuclear Energy</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/96/280">Pub. L. 96–280</ref>, <date date="1980-06-18">June 18, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/550">94 Stat. 550</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/96/280">
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="1">“Section 1.</num><content> Limits contained in agreements for cooperation on the amount of low-enriched uranium which may be transferred by or exported from the United States pursuant thereto shall not be construed to preclude transfer or export of amounts of low-enriched uranium in excess of such limits to nations which are parties to the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons.</content>
</section>
<section style="-uslm-lc:I21"><num value="2">“Sec. 2.</num><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a"> (a)</num><content> The terms used in this joint resolution shall have the meanings ascribed to them by the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 [this chapter] and by the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Act of 1978 [<ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3201">22 U.S.C. 3201</ref> et seq.].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><content> The term ‘low-enriched uranium’ means uranium enriched to less than 20 per centum in the isotope 235.”</content>
</subsection>
</section>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="idbbef0d37-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definitions of terms used in this section, see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3203">section 3203 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbbef0d38-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="idbbef0d39-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Secretary of State responsible for performing functions vested in President under this section, see section 2(a) of Ex. Ord. No. 12058, <date date="1978-05-11">May 11, 1978</date>, 43 F.R. 20947, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3201">section 3201 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbef0d3a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Performance of Functions Pending Development of Procedures</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The performance of functions under the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Act of 1978, <ref href="/us/pl/95/242">Pub. L. 95–242</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/120">92 Stat. 120</ref>, not to be delayed pending development of procedures even though as many as 120 days [after <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>] are allowed for establishing those procedures, see section 5(b) of Ex. Ord. No. 12058, <date date="1978-05-11">May 11, 1978</date>, 43 F.R. 20947, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3201">section 3201 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
