<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbbef0d08-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2153a"><num value="2153a">§ 2153a.</num><heading> Approval for enrichment after export of source or special nuclear material; export of major critical components of enrichment facilities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbef0d09-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2153a/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Except as specifically provided in any agreement for cooperation, no source or special nuclear material hereafter exported from the United States may be enriched after export without the prior approval of the United States for such enrichment: <i>Provided</i>, That the procedures governing such approvals shall be identical to those set forth for the approval of proposed subsequent arrangements under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2160">section 2160 of this title</ref>, and any commitments from the recipient which the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of State deem necessary to ensure that such approval will be obtained prior to such enrichment shall be obtained prior to the submission of the executive branch judgment regarding the export in question and shall be set forth in such submission: <i>And provided further</i>, That no source or special nuclear material shall be exported for the purpose of enrichment or reactor fueling to any nation or group of nations which has, after <date date="1978-03-10">March 10, 1978</date>, entered into a new or amended agreement for cooperation with the United States, except pursuant to such agreement.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbef0d0a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2153a/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> In addition to other requirements of law, no major critical component of any uranium enrichment, nuclear fuel reprocessing, or heavy water production facility shall be exported under any agreement for cooperation (except an agreement for cooperation pursuant to section 2121(c), 2164(b), or 2164(c) of this title) unless such agreement for cooperation specifically designates such components as items to be exported pursuant to the agreement for cooperation. For purposes of this subsection, the term “major critical component” means any component part or group of component parts which the President determines to be essential to the operation of a complete uranium enrichment, nuclear fuel reprocessing, or heavy water production facility.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbbef0d0b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/242/tIV/s402">Pub. L. 95–242, title IV, § 402</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/145">92 Stat. 145</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbbef0d0c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbbef0d0d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbbef0d0e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Act of 1978, and not as part of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbbef0d0f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idbbef0d10-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, except as otherwise provided and regardless of any requirements for the promulgation of implementing regulations, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/242/s603/c">section 603(c) of Pub. L. 95–242</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3201">section 3201 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbbef0d11-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="delegationOfFunctions" id="idbbef0d12-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Delegation of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Delegation or assignment to Secretary of Energy of function vested in President under subsec. (b) of this section, see section 1(a) of Ex. Ord. No. 12058, <date date="1978-05-11">May 11, 1978</date>, 43 F.R. 20947, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3201">section 3201 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbef0d13-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Performance of Functions Pending Development of Procedures</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The performance of functions under the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Act of 1978, <ref href="/us/pl/95/242">Pub. L. 95–242</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/120">92 Stat. 120</ref>, not to be delayed pending development of procedures even though as many as 120 days [after <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>] are allowed for establishing those procedures, see section 5(b) of Ex. Ord. No. 12058, <date date="1978-05-11">May 11, 1978</date>, 43 F.R. 20947, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3201">section 3201 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
