<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbbf17e98-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2155a"><num value="2155a">§ 2155a.</num><heading> Regulations establishing Commission procedures covering grant, suspension, revocation, or amendment of nuclear export licenses or exemptions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbf17e99-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2155a/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> Omitted</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbf17e9a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2155a/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> Within one hundred and twenty days of <date date="1978-03-10">March 10, 1978</date>, the Commission shall, after consultations with the Secretary of State, promulgate regulations establishing procedures (1) for the granting, suspending, revoking, or amending of any nuclear export license or exemption pursuant to its statutory authority; (2) for public participation in nuclear export licensing proceedings when the Commission finds that such participation will be in the public interest and will assist the Commission in making the statutory determinations required by the 1954 Act, including such public hearings and access to information as the Commission deems appropriate: <i>Provided</i>, That judicial review as to any such finding shall be limited to the determination of whether such finding was arbitrary and capricious; (3) for a public written Commission opinion accompanied by the dissenting or separate views of any Commissioner, in those proceedings where one or more Commissioners have dissenting or separate views on the issuance of an export license; and (4) for public notice of Commission proceedings and decisions, and for recording of minutes and votes of the Commission: <i>Provided further</i>, That until the regulations required by this subsection have been promulgated, the Commission shall implement the provisions of this Act under temporary procedures established by the Commission.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbbf17e9b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2155a/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> The procedures to be established pursuant to subsection (b) shall constitute the exclusive basis for hearings in nuclear export licensing proceedings before the Commission and, notwithstanding section 189 a. of the 1954 Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2239/a">42 U.S.C. 2239(a)</ref>], shall not require the Commission to grant any person an on-the-record hearing in such a proceeding.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbbf17e9c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/95/242/tIII/s304/b">Pub. L. 95–242, title III, § 304(b)</ref>, (c), <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/135">92 Stat. 135</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbbf17e9d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbbf17e9e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbbf17e9f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This Act, referred to in subsec. (b), means the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Act of 1978, <ref href="/us/pl/95/242">Pub. L. 95–242</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/120">92 Stat. 120</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 47 (§ 3201 et seq.) of Title 22. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3201">section 3201 of Title 22</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbbf17ea0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Act of 1978, and not as part of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 which comprises this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section is based on subsecs. (b) and (c) of <ref href="/us/pl/95/242">Pub. L. 95–242</ref>. Subsecs. (a) and (d) of <ref href="/us/pl/95/242">Pub. L. 95–242</ref> enacted sections 2155 and 2156a, respectively, of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbbf17ea1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idbbf17ea2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, except as otherwise provided and regardless of any requirements for the promulgation of implementing regulations, see <ref href="/us/pl/95/242/s603/c">section 603(c) of Pub. L. 95–242</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3201">section 3201 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="idbbf17ea3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definitions of terms used in this section, see <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3203">section 3203 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbbf17ea4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbf17ea5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Performance of Functions Pending Development of Procedures</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The performance of functions under the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Act of 1978, <ref href="/us/pl/95/242">Pub. L. 95–242</ref>, <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/120">92 Stat. 120</ref>, not to be delayed pending development of procedures even though as many as 120 days [after <date date="1978-03-10">Mar. 10, 1978</date>] are allowed for establishing those procedures, see section 5(b) of Ex. Ord. No. 12058, <date date="1978-05-11">May 11, 1978</date>, 43 F.R. 20947, set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t22/s3201">section 3201 of Title 22</ref>, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
