<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbbfb1b9a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2167"><num value="2167">§ 2167.</num><heading> Safeguards information</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbfb1b9b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2167/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Confidentiality of certain types of information; issuance of regulations and orders; considerations for exercise of Commission’s authority; disclosure of routes and quantities of shipment; civil penalties; withholding of information from Congressional committees</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In addition to any other authority or requirement regarding protection from disclosure of information, and subject to subsection (b)(3) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">section 552 of title 5</ref>, the Commission shall prescribe such regulations, after notice and opportunity for public comment, or issue such orders, as necessary to prohibit the unauthorized disclosure of safeguards information which specifically identifies a licensee’s or applicant’s detailed—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbfb1b9c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2167/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> control and accounting procedures or security measures (including security plans, procedures, and equipment) for the physical protection of special nuclear material, by whomever possessed, whether in transit or at fixed sites, in quantities determined by the Commission to be significant to the public health and safety or the common defense and security;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbfb1b9d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2167/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> security measures (including security plans, procedures, and equipment) for the physical protection of source material or byproduct material, by whomever possessed, whether in transit or at fixed sites, in quantities determined by the Commission to be significant to the public health and safety or the common defense and security; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbfb1b9e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2167/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> security measures (including security plans, procedures, and equipment) for the physical protection of and the location of certain plant equipment vital to the safety of production or utilization facilities involving nuclear materials covered by paragraphs (1) and (2) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003265">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003265"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by a semicolon.</note></content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">if the unauthorized disclosure of such information could reasonably be expected to have a significant adverse effect on the health and safety of the public or the common defense and security by significantly increasing the likelihood of theft, diversion, or sabotage of such material or such facility. The Commission shall exercise the authority of this subsection—</continuation>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbfb1b9f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2167/a/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> so as to apply the minimum restrictions needed to protect the health and safety of the public or the common defense and security, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbfb1ba0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2167/a/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> upon a determination that the unauthorized disclosure of such information could reasonably be expected to have a significant adverse effect on the health and safety of the public or the common defense and security by significantly increasing the likelihood of theft, diversion, or sabotage of such material or such facility.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Nothing in this chapter shall authorize the Commission to prohibit the public disclosure of information pertaining to the routes and quantities of shipments of source material, by-product material, high level nuclear waste, or irradiated nuclear reactor fuel. Any person, whether or not a licensee of the Commission, who violates any regulation adopted under this section shall be subject to the civil monetary penalties of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2282">section 2282 of this title</ref>. Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize the withholding of information from the duly authorized committees of the Congress.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbfb1ba1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2167/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Regulations or orders issued under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2201/b">section 2201(b) of this title</ref> for purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2273">section 2273 of this title</ref></heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2273">section 2273 of this title</ref>, any regulations or orders prescribed or issued by the Commission under this section shall also be deemed to be prescribed or issued under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2201/b">section 2201(b) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbfb1ba2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2167/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Judicial review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any determination by the Commission concerning the applicability of this section shall be subject to judicial review pursuant to subsection (a)(4)(B) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s552">section 552 of title 5</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbfb1ba3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2167/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports to Congress; contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Upon prescribing or issuing any regulation or order under subsection (a) of this section, the Commission shall submit to Congress a report that:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbfb1ba4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2167/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> specifically identifies the type of information the Commission intends to protect from disclosure under the regulation or order;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbfb1ba5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2167/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> specifically states the Commission’s justification for determining that unauthorized disclosure of the information to be protected from disclosure under the regulation or order could reasonably be expected to have a significant adverse effect on the health and safety of the public or the common defense and security by significantly increasing the likelihood of theft, diversion, or sabotage of such material or such facility, as specified under subsection (a) of this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbbfb1ba6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2167/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> provides justification, including proposed alternative regulations or orders, that the regulation or order applies only the minimum restrictions needed to protect the health and safety of the public or the common defense and security.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbbfb1ba7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, title I, § 147, as added <ref href="/us/pl/96/295/tII/s207/a/1">Pub. L. 96–295, title II, § 207(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1980-06-30">June 30, 1980</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/94/788">94 Stat. 788</ref>; renumbered title I, <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tIX/s902/a/8">Pub. L. 102–486, title IX, § 902(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2944">106 Stat. 2944</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbbfb1ba8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbbfb1ba9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbbfb1baa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">This chapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this Act”, meaning <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-30/ch1073/s1">act Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/919">68 Stat. 919</ref>, known as the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2011">section 2011 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbbfb1bab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsection (e) of this section, which required the Commission to submit to Congress on a quarterly basis a report detailing the Commission’s application during that period of every regulation or order prescribed or issued under this section, terminated, effective <date date="2000-05-15">May 15, 2000</date>, pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/104/66/s3003">section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66</ref>, as amended, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1113">section 1113 of Title 31</ref>, Money and Finance. See, also, item 7 on page 186 of House Document No. 103–7.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
