<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbbfd65df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2181"><num value="2181">§ 2181.</num><heading> Inventions relating to atomic weapons, and filing of reports</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbfd65e0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2181/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Denial of patent; revocation of prior patents</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No patent shall hereafter be granted for any invention or discovery which is useful solely in the utilization of special nuclear material or atomic energy in an atomic weapon. Any patent granted for any such invention or discovery is revoked, and just compensation shall be made therefor.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbfd65e1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2181/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Denial of rights; revocation of prior rights</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No patent hereafter granted shall confer any rights with respect to any invention or discovery to the extent that such invention or discovery is used in the utilization of special nuclear material or atomic energy in atomic weapons. Any rights conferred by any patent heretofore granted for any invention or discovery are revoked to the extent that such invention or discovery is so used, and just compensation shall be made therefor.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbfd65e2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2181/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Report of invention to Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the United States Patent and Trademark Office</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person who has made or hereafter makes any invention or discovery useful in the production or utilization of special nuclear material or atomic energy, shall file with the Commission a report containing a complete description thereof unless such invention or discovery is described in an application for a patent filed with the Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the United States Patent and Trademark Office by such person within the time required for the filing of such report. The report covering any such invention or discovery shall be filed on or before the one hundred and eightieth day after such person first discovers or first has reason to believe that such invention or discovery is useful in such production or utilization.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbfd65e3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2181/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Report to Commission by Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the United States Patent and Trademark Office</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the United States Patent and Trademark Office shall notify the Commission of all applications for patents heretofore or hereafter filed which, in his opinion, disclose inventions or discoveries required to be reported under subsection (c), and shall provide the Commission access to all such applications.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbbfd65e4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2181/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Confidential information; circumstances permitting disclosure</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Reports filed pursuant to subsection (c) of this section, and applications to which access is provided under subsection (d) of this section, shall be kept in confidence by the Commission, and no information concerning the same given without authority of the inventor or owner unless necessary to carry out the provisions of any Act of Congress or in such special circumstances as may be determined by the Commission.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbbfd65e5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, title I, § 151, as added <ref href="/us/act/1954-08-30/ch1073/s1">Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/943">68 Stat. 943</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/87/206">Pub. L. 87–206</ref>, §§ 7–9, <date date="1961-09-06">Sept. 6, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/477">75 Stat. 477</ref>; renumbered title I, <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tIX/s902/a/8">Pub. L. 102–486, title IX, § 902(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2944">106 Stat. 2944</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/9/tIV/s4732/b/18">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4732(b)(18)]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1536">113 Stat. 1536</ref>, 1501A–585.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbbfd65e6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbbfd65e7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idbbfd65e8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to this section were contained in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1811/a">section 1811(a) of this title</ref>, prior to the general amendment and renumbering of act <date date="1946-08-01">Aug. 1, 1946</date>, by act <date date="1954-08-30">Aug. 30, 1954</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbbfd65e9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1999—Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref> substituted “Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the United States Patent and Trademark Office” for “Commissioner of Patents”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1961—<ref href="/us/pl/87/206/s7">Pub. L. 87–206, § 7</ref>, substituted provision concerning inventions relating to atomic weapons and filing of reports for provision relating to military utilization in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/87/206/s8">Pub. L. 87–206, § 8</ref>, struck out designation as cl. (1) of provision relating to production or utilization of special nuclear material or atomic energy and cls. (2) and (3) relating to utilization of special nuclear material in an atomic weapon and utilization of atomic energy in an atomic weapon, respectively, and substituted “the one hundred and eightieth day” for “whichever of the following is the later: either the ninetieth day after completion of such invention or discovery; or the ninetieth day”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/87/206/s9">Pub. L. 87–206, § 9</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbbfd65ea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idbbfd65eb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1999 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref> effective 4 months after <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, see section 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4731] of <ref href="/us/pl/106/113">Pub. L. 106–113</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s1">section 1 of Title 35</ref>, Patents.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbbfd65ec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Emergency Relief From Postal Situation Affecting Atomic Energy Cases</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Excusal of delayed fees or actions affected by postal situation beginning on <date date="1970-03-18">Mar. 18, 1970</date>, and ending on or about <date date="1970-03-30">Mar. 30, 1970</date>, see note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t35/s111">section 111 of Title 35</ref>, Patents.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
