<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc17a429-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2286e"><num value="2286e">§ 2286e.</num><heading> Reports</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc17a42a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2286e/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Board report</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc17a42b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2286e/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Board shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services, Appropriations, and Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Armed Services, Appropriations, and Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate each year, at the same time that the President submits the budget to Congress pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105/a">section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, a written report concerning its activities under this subchapter, including all recommendations made by the Board, during the year preceding the year in which the report is submitted. The Board may also issue periodic unclassified reports on matters within the Board’s responsibilities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idbc17a42c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2286e/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The annual report under paragraph (1) shall include an assessment of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc17a42d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2286e/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the improvements in the safety of Department of Energy defense nuclear facilities during the period covered by the report;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc17a42e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2286e/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the improvements in the safety of Department of Energy defense nuclear facilities resulting from actions taken by the Board or taken on the basis of the activities of the Board; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc17a42f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2286e/a/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the outstanding safety problems, if any, of Department of Energy defense nuclear facilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc17a430-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2286e/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> DOE report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Energy shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services, Appropriations, and Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Armed Services, Appropriations, and Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate each year, at the same time that the President submits the budget to Congress pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105/a">section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, a written report concerning the activities of the Department of Energy under this subchapter during the year preceding the year in which the report is submitted.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbc17a431-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1946-08-01/ch724">Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724</ref>, title I, § 316, as added <ref href="/us/pl/100/456/dA/tXIV/s1441/a/1">Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XIV, § 1441(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2082">102 Stat. 2082</ref>; renumbered title I, <ref href="/us/pl/102/486/tIX/s902/a/8">Pub. L. 102–486, title IX, § 902(a)(8)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-24">Oct. 24, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/2944">106 Stat. 2944</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/112/239/dC/tXXXII/s3202/d">Pub. L. 112–239, div. C, title XXXII, § 3202(d)</ref>, <date date="2013-01-02">Jan. 2, 2013</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/126/2220">126 Stat. 2220</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbc17a432-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbc17a433-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbc17a434-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2013—Subsecs. (a)(1), (b). <ref href="/us/pl/112/239">Pub. L. 112–239</ref> substituted “Committees on Armed Services, Appropriations, and Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Armed Services, Appropriations, and Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate” for “Committees on Armed Services and on Appropriations of the Senate and to the Speaker of the House of Representatives”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbc17a435-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbc17a436-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Certification of Budget Sufficiency</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/91/dC/tXXXII/s3201/b">Pub. L. 115–91, div. C, title XXXII, § 3201(b)</ref>, <date date="2017-12-12">Dec. 12, 2017</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/131/1908">131 Stat. 1908</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/91/dC/tXXXII/s3201/b">“Not later than 10 days after the date on which the budget of the President for fiscal year 2019 or any fiscal year thereafter is submitted to Congress pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s1105/a">section 1105(a) of title 31</ref>, United States Code, the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board shall submit to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] a letter certifying that the requested budget is sufficient to carry out the mission of the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board during the fiscal year covered by the budget request.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbc17a437-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Reporting Requirements</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/456/dA/tXIV/s1441/c">Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title XIV, § 1441(c)</ref>, (d), <date date="1988-09-29">Sept. 29, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2084">102 Stat. 2084</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/456/dA/tXIV/s1441/c">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements for First Annual Report</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Before submission of the first annual report by the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board under section 316(a) of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 [subsec. (a) of this section] (as added by subsection (a)), the Board shall conduct a study on whether nuclear facilities of the Department of Energy that are excluded from the definition of ‘Department of Energy defense nuclear facility’ in section 318(1)(C) of such Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2286g/1/C">section 2286g(1)(C) of this title</ref>] (hereafter in this subsection referred to as ‘non-defense nuclear facilities’) should be subject to independent external oversight. The Board shall include in such first annual report the results of such study and the recommendation of the Board on whether non-defense nuclear facilities should be subject to independent external oversight.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> If the Board recommends in the report that non-defense nuclear facilities should be subject to such oversight, the report shall include a discussion of alternative mechanisms for implementing such oversight, including mechanisms such as a separate executive agency and oversight as a part of the Board’s responsibilities. The discussion of alternative mechanisms of oversight also shall include considerations of budgetary costs, protection of the security of sensitive nuclear weapons information, and the similarities and differences in the design, construction, operation, and decommissioning of defense and non-defense nuclear facilities of the Department of Energy.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Requirements for Fifth Annual Report</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The fifth annual report submitted by the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board under section 316(a) of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 [subsec. (a) of this section] (as added by subsection (a)) shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> an assessment of the degree to which the overall administration of the Board’s activities are believed to meet the objectives of Congress in establishing the Board;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> recommendations for continuation, termination, or modification of the Board’s functions and programs, including recommendations for transition to some other independent oversight arrangement if it is advisable; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> recommendations for appropriate transition requirements in the event that modifications are recommended.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
