<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc17a473-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2292"><num value="2292">§ 2292.</num><heading> Authorization of appropriations for research and development program; authority to enter into contracts; period of contracts; equivalent amounts for research and development program</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Commission, in accordance with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2017/a/2">section 2017(a)(2) of this title</ref>, the sum of $3,000,000 as an initial authorization for fiscal year 1959 for use in a cooperative program of research and development in connection with the types of reactors selected by the Commission and the Community under the joint program. The Commission may enter into contracts for such periods as it deems necessary, but in no event to exceed five years, for the purpose of conducting the research and development program authorized by this section: <i>Provided</i>, That the Community authorizes an equivalent amount for use in the cooperative program of research and development.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbc17a474-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/85/846/s3">Pub. L. 85–846, § 3</ref>, <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1084">72 Stat. 1084</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbc17a475-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbc17a476-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbc17a477-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the EURATOM Cooperation Act of 1958 which comprises this subchapter, and not as part of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
