<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc17a47c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2294"><num value="2294">§ 2294.</num><heading> Authorization for sale or lease of uranium and plutonium; amounts; lien for nonpayment; uranium enrichment services</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Pursuant to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2074">section 2074 of this title</ref>, there is hereby authorized for sale or lease to the Community—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" role="listItem" class="indent1">an amount of contained uranium 235 which does not exceed that necessary to support the fuel cycle of power reactors located within the Community having a total installed capacity of thirty-five thousand megawatts of electric energy, together with twenty-five thousand kilograms of contained uranium 235 for other purposes;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" role="listItem" class="indent1">one thousand five hundred kilograms of plutonium; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I12" role="listItem" class="indent1">thirty kilograms of uranium 233;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">in accordance with the provisions of an agreement or agreements for cooperation between the Government of the United States and the Community entered into pursuant to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2153">section 2153 of this title</ref>: <i>Provided</i>, That the Government of the United States obtains the equivalent of a first lien on any such material sold to the Community for which payment is not made in full at the time of transfer. The Commission may enter into contracts to provide, after <date date="1968-12-31">December 31, 1968</date>, for the producing or enriching of all, or part of, the above-mentioned contained uranium 235 pursuant to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2201/v/B">section 2201(v)(B) of this title</ref> in lieu of sale or lease thereof.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbc17a47d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/85/846/s5">Pub. L. 85–846, § 5</ref>, <date date="1958-08-28">Aug. 28, 1958</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/72/1085">72 Stat. 1085</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/206/s19">Pub. L. 87–206, § 19</ref>, <date date="1961-09-06">Sept. 6, 1961</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/75/479">75 Stat. 479</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/88/394/s5">Pub. L. 88–394, § 5</ref>, <date date="1964-08-01">Aug. 1, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/376">78 Stat. 376</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/190/s13">Pub. L. 90–190, § 13</ref>, <date date="1967-12-14">Dec. 14, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/578">81 Stat. 578</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/88">Pub. L. 93–88</ref>, <date date="1973-08-14">Aug. 14, 1973</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/87/296">87 Stat. 296</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbc17a47e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbc17a47f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbc17a480-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the EURATOM Cooperation Act of 1958 which comprises this subchapter, and not as part of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbc17a481-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1973—<ref href="/us/pl/93/88">Pub. L. 93–88</ref> substituted “an amount of contained uranium 235 which does not exceed that necessary to support the fuel cycle of power reactors located within the Community having a total installed capacity of thirty-five thousand megawatts of electric energy, together with twenty-five thousand kilograms of contained uranium for other purposes” for “two hundred fifteen thousand kilograms of contained uranium 235”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1967—<ref href="/us/pl/90/190">Pub. L. 90–190</ref> increased from seventy thousand to two hundred fifteen thousand kilograms of contained uranium 235 and from five hundred to one thousand five hundred kilograms of plutonium respectively the amount of material authorized to be sold or leased to the Community, and inserted provision authorizing the Commission, after <date date="1968-12-31">Dec. 31, 1968</date>, to perform uranium enrichment services for the Community, pursuant to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2201/v/B">section 2201(v)(B) of this title</ref>, in lieu of the sale or lease of such material.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1964—<ref href="/us/pl/88/394">Pub. L. 88–394</ref> increased the amount of contained uranium 235 from thirty thousand kilograms to seventy thousand kilograms, and plutonium, from nine kilograms to five hundred kilograms.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1961—<ref href="/us/pl/87/206">Pub. L. 87–206</ref> substituted “Nine kilograms” for “One kilogram” of plutonium and inserted item reading “Thirty kilograms of uranium 233” and “or agreements”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
