<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc1a15cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2297h–2"><num value="2297h–2">§ 2297h–2.</num><heading> Method of sale</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc1a15cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2297h–2/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board of Directors of the Corporation, with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury, shall transfer ownership of the assets and obligations of the Corporation to the private corporation established under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2297h–3">section 2297h–3 of this title</ref> (which may be consummated through a merger or consolidation effected in accordance with, and having the effects provided under, the law of the State of incorporation of the private corporation, as if the Corporation were incorporated thereunder).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc1a15cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2297h–2/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Board determination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Board, with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury, shall select the method of transfer and establish terms and conditions for the transfer that will provide the maximum proceeds to the Treasury of the United States and will provide for the long-term viability of the private corporation, the continued operation of the gaseous diffusion plants, and the public interest in maintaining reliable and economical domestic uranium mining and enrichment industries.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc1a15ce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2297h–2/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Adequate proceeds</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of the Treasury shall not allow the privatization of the Corporation unless before the sale date the Secretary of the Treasury determines that the method of transfer will provide the maximum proceeds to the Treasury consistent with the principles set forth in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2297h–1/a">section 2297h–1(a) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc1a15cf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2297h–2/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Application of securities laws</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any offering or sale of securities by the private corporation shall be subject to the Securities Act of 1933 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77a">15 U.S.C. 77a</ref> et seq.), the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78a">15 U.S.C. 78a</ref> et seq.), and the provisions of the Constitution and laws of any State, territory, or possession of the United States relating to transactions in securities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc1a15d0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2297h–2/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Expenses</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Expenses of privatization shall be paid from Corporation revenue accounts in the United States Treasury.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbc1a15d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/104/134/tIII/s3104">Pub. L. 104–134, title III, § 3104</ref>, <date date="1996-04-26">Apr. 26, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/1321-336">110 Stat. 1321–336</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbc1a15d2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbc1a15d3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbc1a15d4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Securities Act of 1933, referred to in subsec. (d), is <ref href="/us/act/1933-05-27/ch38/tI">act May 27, 1933, ch. 38, title I</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/74">48 Stat. 74</ref>, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 77a et seq.) of chapter 2A of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s77a">section 77a of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Securities Exchange Act of 1934, referred to in subsec. (d), is <ref href="/us/act/1934-06-06/ch404">act June 6, 1934, ch. 404</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/48/881">48 Stat. 881</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 2B (§ 78a et seq.) of Title 15. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s78a">section 78a of Title 15</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbc1a15d5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the USEC Privatization Act and also as part of the Omnibus Consolidated Rescissions and Appropriations Act of 1996, and not as part of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
