<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc2140c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2326"><num value="2326">§ 2326.</num><heading> Deductions from sales price</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc2140c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2326/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Improvements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In addition to any other deduction which may be permitted from the sales price for property, there shall, upon application by the prospective purchaser, be deducted the amount by which the current fair market value of the Government’s interest in the premises is enhanced as a result of improvements to the premises made by, or at the expense of, the prospective purchaser: <i>Provided</i>, That, with reference to commercial property, the improvement credit allowed shall be the value of the enhancement of the Government’s interest in the property, as determined by the Commission on the basis of the appraisal provided for under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2322">section 2322 of this title</ref>: <i>Provided further</i>, That such credit shall be reduced to the extent that lessee has been previously compensated therefor, as determined by the Commission, under the terms of the lease or otherwise.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc2140c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2326/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Improvements by occupant of single family or duplex house</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An occupant of a single family or duplex house shall, upon application therefor, be entitled to a credit, against the purchase price of any residential property purchased through the exercise of a priority right established under the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2332">section 2332 of this title</ref>, for the amount by which the current fair market value of the Government’s interest in the single family or duplex house of which he was an occupant is enhanced as a result of improvements to the premises of such single family or duplex house made by, or at the expense of, such occupant.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc2140c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2326/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination of value of improvements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The value of the improvements as specified in subsections (a) and (b) shall be determined in accordance with the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2322">section 2322 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc2140c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2326/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional deduction to persons purchasing property without benefit of indemnity provisions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Persons purchasing property pursuant to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2342">section 2342 of this title</ref>, who do not desire to avail themselves of the indemnity provisions contained in sections 2363 to 2366 of this title, shall be entitled to an additional deduction of 10 per centum of the appraised value of the property in addition to any other deduction set forth in this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbc2140c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-08-04/ch543">Aug. 4, 1955, ch. 543</ref>, ch. 3, § 36, <ref href="/us/stat/69/474">69 Stat. 474</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1956-07-25/ch731/s1">July 25, 1956, ch. 731, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/653">70 Stat. 653</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/719/s6">Pub. L. 87–719, § 6</ref>, <date date="1962-09-28">Sept. 28, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/664">76 Stat. 664</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbc2140c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbc2140ca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbc2140cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/87/719">Pub. L. 87–719</ref> substituted authorization of a credit for improvements by occupant of single family or duplex house for such improvements by junior occupant of duplex house.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1956—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1956-07-25">July 25, 1956</date>, authorized an improvement credit for commercial property.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbc2140cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbc2140cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Atomic Energy Commission abolished and functions transferred by sections 5814 and 5841 of this title. See also Transfer of Functions notes set out under those sections.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
