<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc214135-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2349"><num value="2349">§ 2349.</num><heading> Hanford project; disposal of property</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In addition to any other authority the Commission may have, the Commission is authorized, without regard to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>, to lease land, and to sell, lease, including leases with options to purchase, and otherwise dispose of improvements thereon, and such equipment and other personal property as is determined to be directly related thereto, in the Commission’s Hanford project in and near Richland, Washington, upon a determination by the Commission that such disposition will serve to prevent or reduce the adverse economic impact of actual or anticipated reductions in Commission programs in that area: <i>Provided, however</i>, That the compensation to the Government for any such disposition shall be the estimated fair market value or estimated fair rental value of the property as determined by the Commission: <i>Provided further</i>, That before the Commission makes any disposition of property under the authority of this section, the basis for the proposed disposition (with necessary background and explanatory data) shall be submitted to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and a period of forty-five days shall elapse while Congress is in session (in computing such forty-five-days, there shall be excluded the days on which either House is not in session because of adjournment of more than three days): <i>Provided, however</i>, That those Committees, after having received the basis for the proposed disposition, may by resolution in writing waive the conditions of, or all or any portion of, such forty-five-day period.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idbc214136-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-08-04/ch543">Aug. 4, 1955, ch. 543</ref>, ch. 11, § 120, as added <ref href="/us/pl/88/394/s4">Pub. L. 88–394, § 4</ref>, <date date="1964-08-01">Aug. 1, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/376">78 Stat. 376</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/437/s15/i">Pub. L. 103–437, § 15(i)</ref>, <date date="1994-11-02">Nov. 2, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/4593">108 Stat. 4593</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbc214137-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbc214138-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbc214139-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In text, “<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>” substituted for “section 3709 of the Revised Statutes, as amended” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s6/c">Pub. L. 111–350, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3854">124 Stat. 3854</ref>, which Act enacted Title 41, Public Contracts.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbc21413a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1994—<ref href="/us/pl/103/437">Pub. L. 103–437</ref> substituted “submitted to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives” for “submitted to the Joint Committee on Atomic Energy” and “That those Committees” for “That the Joint Committee on Atomic Energy”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbc21413b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbc21413c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Atomic Energy Commission abolished and functions transferred by sections 5814 and 5841 of this title. See also Transfer of Functions notes set out under those sections.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
