<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc214143-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2362"><num value="2362">§ 2362.</num><heading> Financing by Commission</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc214144-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2362/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Acceptance of residential property notes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the event that the Commission finds that financing on reasonable terms is not available from other sources, the Commission may, in order to facilitate the sale of residential property under subchapter IV of this chapter, accept, in partial payment of the purchase price of any such property notes secured by first mortgages on such terms and conditions as the Commission shall deem appropriate. In the case of houses and apartment buildings, the maturity and percentage of appraised value in connection with such notes and mortgages shall not exceed those prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1715n/a">section 1715n(a) of title 12</ref>, and the interest rate shall equal the interest rate plus the premium being charged (and any periodic service charge being authorized by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development for properties of similar character) under <ref href="/us/usc/t12/s1715n/a">section 1715n(a) of title 12</ref>, at the effective date of such notes and mortgages.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc214145-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2362/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Advances</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In connection with the sale of residential property financed under subsection (a) of this section, the Commission is authorized to make advances for necessary repairs, or for the rehabilitation, modernization, rebuilding or enlargement of single and duplex residential properties to priority purchasers, and to include such advances in the amount of the note secured by the mortgage on such property.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc214146-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2362/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Acceptance of commercial property notes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In the event that the Commission finds that financing on reasonable terms is not available from other sources, the Commission may, in order to facilitate the sale of commercial property under subchapter IV of this chapter, accept, in partial payment of the purchase price of any commercial property notes secured by first mortgages on such terms and conditions as the Commission shall deem appropriate.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc214147-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2362/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Sale of notes and mortgages</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission may sell any notes and mortgages acquired under subsections (a) and (c) of this section on terms set by the Commission. Notwithstanding any other provisions of law and without regard to the provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>, the Commission may, in accordance with such terms and conditions as it may prescribe, (1) enter into contracts for servicing any of the notes and mortgages it has acquired, and (2) sell or enter into contracts to sell to a servicer any notes and mortgages with respect to which a servicing contract has been entered into by the servicer with the Commission: <i>Provided</i>, That with respect to sales of notes and mortgages under (2) the Commission shall comply with <ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref> unless it determines that such compliance would not be feasible.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbc214148-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-08-04/ch543">Aug. 4, 1955, ch. 543</ref>, ch. 6, § 62, <ref href="/us/stat/69/478">69 Stat. 478</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1956-07-25/ch731/s2">July 25, 1956, ch. 731, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/70/653">70 Stat. 653</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/87/719">Pub. L. 87–719</ref>, §§ 15, 16, <date date="1962-09-28">Sept. 28, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/665">76 Stat. 665</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/19/s11">Pub. L. 90–19, § 11</ref>, <date date="1967-05-25">May 25, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/23">81 Stat. 23</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbc214149-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbc21414a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idbc21414b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (d), “<ref href="/us/usc/t41/s6101">section 6101 of title 41</ref>” substituted for “section 3709 of the Revised Statutes” in two places on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/111/350/s6/c">Pub. L. 111–350, § 6(c)</ref>, <date date="2011-01-04">Jan. 4, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/3854">124 Stat. 3854</ref>, which Act enacted Title 41, Public Contracts.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbc21414c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1967—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/90/19">Pub. L. 90–19</ref> substituted “Secretary of Housing and Urban Development” for “Federal Housing Commissioner”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1962—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/87/719/s15">Pub. L. 87–719, § 15</ref>, substituted “such property” for “house, apartment building, or dormitory”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/87/719/s16">Pub. L. 87–719, § 16</ref>, inserted provisions respecting servicing contracts and compliance with advertising requirements for public purchases when feasible.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1956—Subsec. (a). Act <date date="1956-07-25">July 25, 1956</date>, reenacted subsec. (a) without change.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b), (c). Act <date date="1956-07-25">July 25, 1956</date>, added subsecs. (b) and (c) and redesignated former subsec. (b) as (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). Act <date date="1956-07-25">July 25, 1956</date>, redesignated former subsec. (b) as (d) and included notes and mortgages acquired under subsec. (c) of this section.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbc21414d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbc21414e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Atomic Energy Commission abolished and functions transferred by sections 5814 and 5841 of this title. See also Transfer of Functions notes set out under those sections.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
