<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc214166-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2366"><num value="2366">§ 2366.</num><heading> Conditions of indemnity; purchase of property by Commission</heading>
<chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Commission shall make the indemnity payment specified by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2365">section 2365 of this title</ref> only if the Commission receives a notice from the then owner of the property that he is about to sell the property for a sum less than the unpaid balance of the real or hypothetical loan calculated pursuant to such section. Such payment shall be made only if—</chapeau><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc214167-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2366/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> notice is given to the Commission at a time when the conditions of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2364">section 2364 of this title</ref> are satisfied;</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc214168-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2366/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> the sale is made within such time as the Commission may prescribe and in a manner which the Commission determined to afford adequate assurance of a fair price without excessive costs; and</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc214169-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2366/c"><num value="c">(c)</num><content> the Commission is given such prior notice of the sale and such opportunity to become a purchaser as it shall prescribe.</content>
</subsection>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">In such circumstances the Commission is authorized to purchase the property. Sales pursuant to this section and payment by the Commission of such amount, if any, as is owing pursuant to sections 2363 to 2366 of this title shall end the obligation of the Commission under sections 2363 to 2366 of this title with respect to that property.</continuation>
<sourceCredit id="idbc21416a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-08-04/ch543">Aug. 4, 1955, ch. 543</ref>, ch. 6, § 66, <ref href="/us/stat/69/479">69 Stat. 479</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbc21416b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbc21416c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbc21416d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Atomic Energy Commission abolished and functions transferred by sections 5814 and 5841 of this title. See also Transfer of Functions notes set out under those sections.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
