<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc2141ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2391"><num value="2391">§ 2391.</num><heading> Assistance to governmental entities</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc2141bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2391/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual assistance payments; extensions; determination of amount and recipient</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">From the date of transfer of any municipal installations to a governmental or other entity at or for the community, the Administrator is authorized, for a period of ten years, to make annual assistance payments of just and reasonable sums to the State, county, or local entity having jurisdiction to collect property taxes or to the entity receiving the installation transferred hereunder: <i>Provided, however</i>, That with respect to the cities of Oak Ridge, Tennessee, and Richland, Washington, the Richland School District, the Los Alamos School Board, and the county of Los Alamos, New Mexico, the Administrator is authorized to continue to make assistance payments of just and reasonable sums after expiration of such ten-year period: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Administrator is also authorized to make payments of just and reasonable sums to Anderson County and Roane County, Tennessee. In determining the amount and recipient of such payments the Administrator shall consider—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc2141bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2391/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the approximate real property taxes and assessments for local improvements which would be paid to the governmental entity upon property within the community if such property were not exempt from taxation by reason of Federal ownership;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc2141bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2391/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the maintaining of municipal services at a level which will not impede the recruitment or retention of personnel essential to the Energy Research and Development Administration programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc2141be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2391/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the fiscal problems peculiar to the governmental entity by reason of the construction at the community as a single-purpose national defense installation under emergency conditions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc2141bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2391/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the municipal services and other burdens imposed on the governmental or other entities at the community by the United States in its operations in the project area; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc2141c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2391/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the tax revenues and sources available to the governmental entity, its efforts and diligence in collection of taxes, assessment of property, and the efficiency of its operations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc2141c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2391/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Special interim payments</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Special interim payments may be made under the provisions of this section to any governmental entity which—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc2141c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2391/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> has a special burden due to the requirements under law imposed upon it in assisting in effectuating the purposes of this chapter for which it will not otherwise receive adequate compensation or revenues; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc2141c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2391/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> will suffer a tax loss or lapse in place of which it will not receive any other adequate revenues until the new governmental entities contemplated by this subchapter are receiving their normal taxes and performing their normal functions.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc238ab4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2391/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Payments for special burdens</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Payments made under this section shall be payments made for special burdens imposed on the local governmental entities in accordance with the second sentence of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2208">section 2208 of this title</ref>. Payments may be made under this section notwithstanding the provisions of the Act of <date date="1950-09-30">September 30, 1950</date> <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn003289">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn003289"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> (Public Law 874, Eighty-first Congress), as amended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc238ab5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2391/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Recommendation for further assistance payments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With respect to any entity not less than six months prior to the expiration of the ten-year period referred to in subsection (a) (or not less than six months prior to <date date="1979-06-30">June 30, 1979</date>, in the case of the cities of Oak Ridge, Tennessee, and Richland, Washington, and the Richland School District; or not less than six months prior to <date date="1986-06-30">June 30, 1986</date>, in the case of Anderson County and Roane County, Tennessee; or not later than <date date="1996-06-30">June 30, 1996</date>, in the case of the Los Alamos School Board and the county of Los Alamos, New Mexico), the Administrator shall present to the appropriate committees of the House of Representatives and the Senate recommendations as to the need for any further assistance payments to such entity. If the recommendation under the preceding sentence regarding the Los Alamos School Board or the county of Los Alamos, New Mexico, indicates a need for further assistance for the school board or the county, as the case may be, after <date date="1997-06-30">June 30, 1997</date>, the recommendation shall include a report and plan describing the actions required to eliminate the need for further assistance for the school board or the county, including a proposal for legislative action to carry out the plan.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc238ab6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2391/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Reduction or termination of assistance payments; determination by Administrator of financial self-sufficiency</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In exercising the authority of subsection (a) the Administrator shall assure that the governmental or other entities receiving assistance hereunder utilize all reasonable, available means to achieve financial self-sufficiency to the end that assistance payments by the Administrator may be reduced or terminated at the earliest practical time.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbc238ab7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1955-08-04/ch543">Aug. 4, 1955, ch. 543</ref>, ch. 9, § 91, <ref href="/us/stat/69/481">69 Stat. 481</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/90/190/s2">Pub. L. 90–190, § 2</ref>, <date date="1967-12-14">Dec. 14, 1967</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/81/576">81 Stat. 576</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/187/tVI/s601/1">Pub. L. 94–187, title VI, § 601(1)</ref>–(6), <date date="1975-12-31">Dec. 31, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/1077">89 Stat. 1077</ref>, 1078; <ref href="/us/pl/95/238/tII/s205/a">Pub. L. 95–238, title II, § 205(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-02-25">Feb. 25, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/60">92 Stat. 60</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/104/106/dC/tXXXI/s3161/c">Pub. L. 104–106, div. C, title XXXI, § 3161(c)</ref>, <date date="1996-02-10">Feb. 10, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/627">110 Stat. 627</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbc238ab8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbc238ab9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbc238aba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act of <date date="1950-09-30">September 30, 1950</date>, referred to in subsec. (c), is <ref href="/us/act/1950-09-30/ch1124">act Sept. 30, 1950, ch. 1124</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/64/1100">64 Stat. 1100</ref>, popularly known as the Educational Agencies Financial Aid Act, which was classified generally to chapter 13 (§ 236 et seq.) of Title 20, Education, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/103/382/tIII/s331/b">Pub. L. 103–382, title III, § 331(b)</ref>, <date date="1994-10-20">Oct. 20, 1994</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/108/3965">108 Stat. 3965</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idbc238abb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1996—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/104/106">Pub. L. 104–106</ref> substituted “; or not later than <date date="1996-06-30">June 30, 1996</date>, in the case of the Los Alamos School Board and the county of Los Alamos, New Mexico” for “, and the Los Alamos School Board; and not less than six months prior to <date date="1987-06-30">June 30, 1987</date>, in the case of the county of Los Alamos, New Mexico” and inserted at end “If the recommendation under the preceding sentence regarding the Los Alamos School Board or the county of Los Alamos, New Mexico, indicates a need for further assistance for the school board or the county, as the case may be, after <date date="1997-06-30">June 30, 1997</date>, the recommendation shall include a report and plan describing the actions required to eliminate the need for further assistance for the school board or the county, including a proposal for legislative action to carry out the plan.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/95/238/s205/a/1">Pub. L. 95–238, § 205(a)(1)</ref>, inserted provisions for applicability to the Los Alamos School Board and the county of Los Alamos, New Mexico, and substituted provisions authorizing Administrator to make payments for provisions requiring Administrator to make payments.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/238/s205/a/2">Pub. L. 95–238, § 205(a)(2)</ref>, inserted provisions for applicability to the Los Alamos School Board and the county of Los Alamos, New Mexico, and substituted provision requiring presentation to the appropriate committees of the House and the Senate for provision requiring presentation to the Joint Committee on Atomic Energy.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/94/187/s601/1">Pub. L. 94–187, § 601(1)</ref>, (5), substituted “Administrator” for “Commission” in three places and inserted at end of first sentence “: <i>Provided further</i>, That the Administrator is also authorized to make payments of just and reasonable sums to Anderson County and Roane County, Tennessee”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/94/187/s601/2">Pub. L. 94–187, § 601(2)</ref>, substituted “Energy Research and Development Administration” for “atomic energy”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/94/187/s601/1">Pub. L. 94–187, § 601(1)</ref>, (3), (6), substituted “Administrator” for “Commission”, struck out “its” before “recommendations”, and inserted “; or not less than six months prior to <date date="1986-06-30">June 30, 1986</date>, in the case of Anderson County and Roane County, Tennessee” after “Richland School District” in parenthetical text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/94/187/s601/1">Pub. L. 94–187, § 601(1)</ref>, (4), substituted “Administrator” for “Commission” in two places and struck out “itself” after “shall assure”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1967—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/90/190/s2/1">Pub. L. 90–190, § 2(1)</ref>, authorized the Commission, with respect to the cities of Oak Ridge, Tenn., and Richland, Wash., and the Richland School District, to continue to make assistance payments of just and reasonable sums after the expiration of the ten-year period following the date of transfer of any municipal installation, and added par. (5).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/90/190/s2/2">Pub. L. 90–190, § 2(2)</ref>, inserted “(or not less than six months prior to <date date="1979-06-30">June 30, 1979</date>, in the case of the Cities of Oak Ridge, Tennessee, and Richland, Washington, and the Richland School District),” after “subsection (a) of this section”, substituted “assistance” for “contribution”, and struck out requirement that if Commission proposes further contribution payments, it shall propose a definite schedule of such payments which will provide for an orderly and reasonably prompt withdrawal of Commission from participation in and contribution toward local government.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/90/190/s2/3">Pub. L. 90–190, § 2(3)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idbc238abc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idbc238abd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Energy Research and Development Administration terminated and functions vested by law in Administrator thereof transferred to Secretary of Energy (unless otherwise specifically provided) by sections 7151(a) and 7293 of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbc238abe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Conveyance to Los Alamos, New Mexico</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/383/dC/tXXXI/s3120">Pub. L. 111–383, div. C, title XXXI, § 3120</ref>, <date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/4514">124 Stat. 4514</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/117/263/dE/tLIX/s5942">Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LIX, § 5942</ref>, <date date="2022-12-23">Dec. 23, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/3470">136 Stat. 3470</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/263/dE/tLIX/s5942">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Environmental Restoration</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Secretary of Energy determines under any authority previously established by law that a parcel of land described in subsection (c) requires environmental restoration or remediation, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, complete the environmental restoration or remediation of the parcel not later than <date date="2032-09-30">September 30, 2032</date>, and otherwise in compliance with such law.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Conveyance or Transfer</inline>.—</heading><content>If the Secretary determines under any authority previously established by law that environmental restoration or remediation cannot reasonably be expected to be completed with respect to a parcel of land described in subsection (c) by <date date="2032-09-30">September 30, 2032</date>, the Secretary shall not convey or transfer the parcel of land.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Parcels of Land</inline>.—</heading><content>A parcel of land described in this subsection is a parcel of land under the jurisdiction or administrative control of the Secretary at or in the vicinity of Los Alamos National Laboratory that the Secretary has previously identified as suitable for conveyance or transfer in a report submitted to the congressional defense committees [Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives] prior to the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2011-01-07">Jan. 7, 2011</date>].”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p><ref href="/us/pl/105/119/tVI/s632">Pub. L. 105–119, title VI, § 632</ref>, <date date="1997-11-26">Nov. 26, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2523">111 Stat. 2523</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/108/375/dC/tXXXI/s3148">Pub. L. 108–375, div. C, title XXXI, § 3148</ref>, <date date="2004-10-28">Oct. 28, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/2177">118 Stat. 2177</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/364/dC/tXXXI/s3119">Pub. L. 109–364, div. C, title XXXI, § 3119</ref>, <date date="2006-10-17">Oct. 17, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2509">120 Stat. 2509</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/364/dC/tXXXI/s3119">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Energy shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> except as provided in paragraph (2), convey, without consideration, to the Incorporated County of Los Alamos, New Mexico (in this section referred to as the ‘County’), or to the designee of the County, fee title to the parcels of land that are allocated for conveyance to the County in the agreement under subsection (e);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> notwithstanding paragraph (1) and the agreement under subsection (e), convey, without consideration, to the Board of Education of the Los Alamos Public Schools, New Mexico, within the County, fee title to the parcels of land identified by the Department of Energy as Parcel A–8 and Parcel A–15–1 that are currently located in Technical Area–21 of Los Alamos National Laboratory upon the entry of Los Alamos Public Schools and the County into an agreement for the use of the parcel of land identified as Parcel A–8; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> transfer to the Secretary of the Interior, in trust for the Pueblo of San Ildefonso (in this section referred to as the ‘Pueblo’), administrative jurisdiction over the parcels that are allocated for transfer to the Secretary of the Interior in such agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Preliminary Identification of Parcels of Land for Conveyance or Transfer</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1997-11-26">Nov. 26, 1997</date>], the Secretary of Energy shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report identifying the parcels of land under the jurisdiction or administrative control of the Secretary at or in the vicinity of Los Alamos National Laboratory that are suitable for conveyance or transfer under this section.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> A parcel is suitable for conveyance or transfer for purposes of paragraph (1) if the parcel—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> is not required to meet the national security mission of the Department of Energy or will not be required for that purpose before the end of the 10-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> is likely to be conveyable or transferable, as the case may be, under this section not later than the end of such period; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> is suitable for use for a purpose specified in subsection (h).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Review of Title</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1997-11-26">Nov. 26, 1997</date>], the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report setting forth the results of a title search on each parcel of land identified as suitable for conveyance or transfer under subsection (b), including an analysis of any claims against or other impairments to the fee title to each such parcel.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> In the period beginning on the date of the completion of the title search with respect to a parcel under paragraph (1) and ending on the date of the submittal of the report under that paragraph, the Secretary shall take appropriate actions to resolve the claims against or other impairments, if any, to fee title that are identified with respect to the parcel in the title search.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Environmental Restoration</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Not later than 21 months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1997-11-26">Nov. 26, 1997</date>], the Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> identify the environmental restoration or remediation, if any, that is required with respect to each parcel of land identified under subsection (b) to which the United States has fee title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> carry out any review of the environmental impact of the conveyance or transfer of each such parcel that is required under the provisions of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</ref> et seq.); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> submit to Congress a report setting forth the results of the activities under subparagraphs (A) and (B).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> If the Secretary determines under paragraph (1) that a parcel described in paragraph (1)(A) requires environmental restoration or remediation, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, complete the environmental restoration or remediation of the parcel not later than <date date="2012-11-26">November 26, 2012</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="e">“(e)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Agreement for Allocation of Parcels</inline>.—</heading><content>As soon as practicable after completing the review of titles to parcels of land under subsection (c), but not later than 90 days after the submittal of the report under subsection (d)(1)(C), the County and the Pueblo shall submit to the Secretary an agreement between the County and the Pueblo which allocates between the County and the Pueblo the parcels identified for conveyance or transfer under subsection (b).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="f">“(f)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Plan for Conveyance and Transfer</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Not later than 90 days after the date of the submittal to the Secretary of Energy of the agreement under subsection (e), the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a plan for conveying or transferring parcels of land under this section in accordance with the allocation specified in the agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The plan under paragraph (1) shall provide for the completion of the conveyance or transfer of parcels under this section not later than 9 months after the date of the submittal of the plan under that paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="g">“(g)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Conveyance or Transfer</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), the Secretary shall convey or transfer parcels of land in accordance with the allocation specified in the agreement submitted to the Secretary under subsection (e).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> In the case of a parcel allocated under the agreement that is not available for conveyance or transfer in accordance with the requirement in subsection (f)(2) by reason of its requirement to meet the national security mission of the Department, the Secretary shall convey or transfer the parcel, as the case may be, when the parcel is no longer required for that purpose.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> In the case of a parcel allocated under the agreement that is not available for conveyance or transfer in accordance with such requirement by reason of requirements for environmental restoration or remediation, the Secretary shall convey or transfer the parcel, as the case may be, upon the completion of the environmental restoration or remediation that is required with respect to the parcel.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> If the Secretary determines that environmental restoration or remediation cannot reasonably be expected to be completed with respect to a parcel by <date date="2012-11-26">November 26, 2012</date>, the Secretary shall not convey or transfer the parcel under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="h">“(h)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Conveyed or Transferred Land</inline>.—</heading><content>The parcels of land conveyed or transferred under this section shall be used for historic, cultural, or environmental preservation purposes, economic diversification purposes, or community self-sufficiency purposes.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="i">“(i)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Treatment of Conveyances and Transfers</inline>.—</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The purpose of the conveyances and transfers under this section is to fulfill the obligations of the United States with respect to Los Alamos National Laboratory, New Mexico, under sections 91 and 94 of the Atomic Energy Community Act of 1955 (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2391">42 U.S.C. 2391</ref>, 2394).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Upon the completion of the conveyance or transfer of the parcels of land available for conveyance or transfer under this section, the Secretary shall make no further payments with respect to Los Alamos National Laboratory under section 91 or section 94 of the Atomic Energy Community Act of 1955.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="j">“(j)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Repeal of Superseded Provision</inline>.—</heading><content>In the event of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1998 [<ref href="/us/pl/105/85">Pub. L. 105–85</ref>] by reason of the approval of the President of the conference report to accompany the bill (H.R. 1119) of the 105th Congress, section 3165 of such Act [<ref href="/us/pl/105/85/s3165">section 3165 of Pub. L. 105–85</ref>, see below] is repealed.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/85/dC/tXXXI/s3165">Pub. L. 105–85, div. C, title XXXI, § 3165</ref>, <date date="1997-11-18">Nov. 18, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2050">111 Stat. 2050</ref>, contained provisions similar to <ref href="/us/pl/105/119/s632">section 632 of Pub. L. 105–119</ref>, set out above, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/105/119/tVI/s632/j">Pub. L. 105–119, title VI, § 632(j)</ref>, <date date="1997-11-26">Nov. 26, 1997</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/111/2525">111 Stat. 2525</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbc238abf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Community Assistance Payments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/145/tXV/s1532">Pub. L. 99–145, title XV, § 1532</ref>, <date date="1985-11-08">Nov. 8, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/773">99 Stat. 773</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/99/661/dC/tI/s3133">Pub. L. 99–661, div. C, title I, § 3133</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/4063">100 Stat. 4063</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/160/dC/tXXXI/s3158">Pub. L. 103–160, div. C, title XXXI, § 3158</ref>, <date date="1993-11-30">Nov. 30, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/1956">107 Stat. 1956</ref>, provided that, with certain limitations, the Secretary of Energy may obligate funds during fiscal year 1986 to provide a final financial settlement with Anderson County and Roane County, Tennessee, and the City of Oak Ridge, Tennessee, and terminate all annual assistance payments to those entities and to make advance payment of payments in lieu of property taxes for fiscal years 1986 through 1995, and that the Secretary shall report to Congress by <date date="1986-02-01">Feb. 1, 1986</date>, the Secretary’s recommendations concerning financial assistance payments to local governmental entities.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idbc238ac0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Nonapplicability of Title II of <ref href="/us/pl/95/238">Pub. L. 95–238</ref> to Any Authorization or Appropriation for Military Application of Nuclear Energy, Etc.; Definitions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Nonapplicability of provisions of title II of <ref href="/us/pl/95/238">Pub. L. 95–238</ref> with respect to any authorization or appropriation for any military application of nuclear energy, etc., see <ref href="/us/pl/95/238/s209">section 209 of Pub. L. 95–238</ref>, <date date="1978-02-25">Feb. 25, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/76">92 Stat. 76</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s5821">section 5821 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
