<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb4879b06-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s239l–1"><num value="239l–1">§ 239l–1.</num><heading> Administration</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4879b07-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s239l–1/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The business of the Track shall be conducted by the Surgeon General with funds appropriated for and provided by the Department of Health and Human Services. The National Health Care Workforce Commission shall assist the Surgeon General in an advisory capacity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4879b08-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s239l–1/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Faculty</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4879b09-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s239l–1/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Surgeon General, after considering the recommendations of the National Health Care Workforce Commission, shall obtain the services of such professors, instructors, and administrative and other employees as may be necessary to operate the Track, but utilize when possible, existing affiliated health professions training institutions. Members of the faculty and staff shall be employed under salary schedules and granted retirement and other related benefits prescribed by the Secretary so as to place the employees of the Track faculty on a comparable basis with the employees of fully accredited schools of the health professions within the United States.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4879b0a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s239l–1/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Titles</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Surgeon General may confer academic titles, as appropriate, upon the members of the faculty.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4879b0b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s239l–1/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Nonapplication of provisions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The limitations in <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5373">section 5373 of title 5</ref> shall not apply to the authority of the Surgeon General under paragraph (1) to prescribe salary schedules and other related benefits.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4879b0c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s239l–1/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Agreements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Surgeon General may negotiate agreements with agencies of the Federal Government to utilize on a reimbursable basis appropriate existing Federal medical resources located in the United States (or locations selected in accordance with section 239<i>l</i>(a)(2) of this title). Under such agreements the facilities concerned will retain their identities and basic missions. The Surgeon General may negotiate affiliation agreements with accredited universities and health professions training institutions in the United States. Such agreements may include provisions for payments for educational services provided students participating in Department of Health and Human Services educational programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4879b0d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s239l–1/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Programs</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Surgeon General may establish the following educational programs for Track students:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4879b0e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s239l–1/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Postdoctoral, postgraduate, and technological programs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4879b0f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s239l–1/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A cooperative program for medical, dental, physician assistant, pharmacy, behavioral and mental health, public health, and nursing students.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4879b10-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s239l–1/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Other programs that the Surgeon General determines necessary in order to operate the Track in a cost-effective manner.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4879b11-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s239l–1/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Continuing medical education</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Surgeon General shall establish programs in continuing medical education for members of the health professions to the end that high standards of health care may be maintained within the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4879b12-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s239l–1/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority of the Surgeon General</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4879b13-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s239l–1/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Surgeon General is authorized—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4879b14-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s239l–1/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to enter into contracts with, accept grants from, and make grants to any nonprofit entity for the purpose of carrying out cooperative enterprises in medical, dental, physician assistant, pharmacy, behavioral and mental health, public health, and nursing research, consultation, and education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4879b15-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s239l–1/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to enter into contracts with entities under which the Surgeon General may furnish the services of such professional, technical, or clerical personnel as may be necessary to fulfill cooperative enterprises undertaken by the Track;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4879b16-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s239l–1/f/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> to accept, hold, administer, invest, and spend any gift, devise, or bequest of personal property made to the Track, including any gift, devise, or bequest for the support of an academic chair, teaching, research, or demonstration project;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4879b17-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s239l–1/f/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> to enter into agreements with entities that may be utilized by the Track for the purpose of enhancing the activities of the Track in education, research, and technological applications of knowledge; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4879b18-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s239l–1/f/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> to accept the voluntary services of guest scholars and other persons.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4879b19-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s239l–1/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Surgeon General may not enter into any contract with an entity if the contract would obligate the Track to make outlays in advance of the enactment of budget authority for such outlays.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4879b1a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s239l–1/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Scientists</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Scientists or other medical, dental, or nursing personnel utilized by the Track under an agreement described in paragraph (1) may be appointed to any position within the Track and may be permitted to perform such duties within the Track as the Surgeon General may approve.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4879b1b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s239l–1/f/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Volunteer services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A person who provides voluntary services under the authority of subparagraph (E) of paragraph (1) shall be considered to be an employee of the Federal Government for the purposes of chapter 81 of title 5, relating to compensation for work-related injuries, and to be an employee of the Federal Government for the purposes of chapter 171 of title 28, relating to tort claims. Such a person who is not otherwise employed by the Federal Government shall not be considered to be a Federal employee for any other purpose by reason of the provision of such services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb4879b1c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title II, § 272, as added <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tV/s5315">Pub. L. 111–148, title V, § 5315</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/637">124 Stat. 637</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
