<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb48c5686-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s242"><num value="242">§ 242.</num><heading> Studies and investigations on use and misuse of narcotic drugs and other drugs; annual report to Attorney General; cooperation with States</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb48c5687-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s242/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> In carrying out the purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s241">section 241 of this title</ref> with respect to drugs the use or misuse of which might result in drug abuse or dependency, the studies and investigations authorized therein shall include the use and misuse of narcotic drugs and other drugs. Such studies and investigations shall further include the quantities of crude opium, coca leaves, and their salts, derivatives, and preparations, and other drugs subject to control under the Controlled Substances Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s801">21 U.S.C. 801</ref> et seq.] and Controlled Substances Import and Export Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t21/s951">21 U.S.C. 951</ref> et seq.], together with reserves thereof, necessary to supply the normal and emergency medicinal and scientific requirements of the United States. The results of studies and investigations of the quantities of narcotic drugs or other drugs subject to control under such Acts, together with reserves of such drugs, that are necessary to supply the normal and emergency medicinal and scientific requirements of the United States, shall be reported not later than the first day of April of each year to the Attorney General, to be used at his discretion in determining manufacturing quotas or importation requirements under such Acts.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb48c5688-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s242/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> The Surgeon General shall cooperate with States for the purpose of aiding them to solve their narcotic drug problems and shall give authorized representatives of the States the benefit of his experience in the care, treatment, and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts to the end that each State may be encouraged to provide adequate facilities and methods for the care and treatment of its narcotic addicts.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb48c5689-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title III, § 302, <ref href="/us/stat/58/692">58 Stat. 692</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/513/tII/s701/j">Pub. L. 91–513, title II, § 701(j)</ref>, <date date="1970-10-27">Oct. 27, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1282">84 Stat. 1282</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb48c568a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb48c568b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb48c568c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Controlled Substances Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is title II of <ref href="/us/pl/91/513">Pub. L. 91–513</ref>, <date date="1970-10-27">Oct. 27, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1242">84 Stat. 1242</ref>, which is classified principally to subchapter I (§ 801 et seq.) of chapter 13 of Title 21, Food and Drugs. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s801">section 801 of Title 21</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Controlled Substances Import and Export Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is title III of <ref href="/us/pl/91/513">Pub. L. 91–513</ref>, <date date="1970-10-27">Oct. 27, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1285">84 Stat. 1285</ref>, which is classified principally to subchapter II (§ 951 et seq.) of chapter 13 of Title 21. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s951">section 951 of Title 21</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb48c568d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/91/513">Pub. L. 91–513</ref> inserted references to drug dependency, drugs other than narcotic drugs, and substances subject to control under the Controlled Substances Act and the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act, substituted the first day of April of each year for the first day of September of each year as the date by which the study results must be submitted, substituted the Attorney General for the Secretary of the Treasury as the officer to whom the report is to be submitted, and struck out references to the Narcotic Drugs Import and Export Act.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb48c568e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idb48c568f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Health and Human Services” substituted for “Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare” pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/s509/b">section 509(b) of Pub. L. 96–88</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s3508/b">section 3508(b) of Title 20</ref>, Education.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb48c5690-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1970 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/513">Pub. L. 91–513</ref> effective on first day of seventh calendar month that begins after <date date="1970-10-26">Oct. 26, 1970</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/513/s704">section 704 of Pub. L. 91–513</ref>, set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s801">section 801 of Title 21</ref>, Food and Drugs.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="savings" id="idb48c5691-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Savings Provision</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/91/513">Pub. L. 91–513</ref> not to affect or abate any prosecutions for violation of law or any civil seizures or forfeitures and injunctive proceedings commenced prior to the effective date of such amendment, and all administrative proceedings pending before the Bureau of Narcotics and Dangerous Drugs on <date date="1970-10-27">Oct. 27, 1970</date>, to be continued and brought to final determination in accord with laws and regulations in effect prior to <date date="1970-10-27">Oct. 27, 1970</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/513/s702">section 702 of Pub. L. 91–513</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s321">section 321 of Title 21</ref>, Food and Drugs.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb48c5692-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Marihuana and Health Reporting</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/91/296/tV">Pub. L. 91–296, title V</ref>, <date date="1970-06-30">June 30, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/352">84 Stat. 352</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/95/461/s3/a">Pub. L. 95–461, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-10-14">Oct. 14, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/1268">92 Stat. 1268</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/tV/s509/b">Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/695">93 Stat. 695</ref>, known as the Marihuana and Health Reporting Act, which required the Secretary of Health and Human Services, after consultation with the Surgeon General and other appropriate individuals, to transmit a report to the Congress on or before <date date="1971-01-31">January 31, 1971</date>, and biennially thereafter (1) containing current information on the health consequences of using marihuana, and (2) containing such recommendations for legislative and administrative action as he may deem appropriate, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/98/24/s2/d">Pub. L. 98–24, § 2(d)</ref>, <date date="1983-04-26">Apr. 26, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/97/182">97 Stat. 182</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idb48c5693-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idb48c5694-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Office of Surgeon General abolished by section 3 of Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1966, eff. <date date="1966-06-25">June 25, 1966</date>, 31 F.R. 8855, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1610">80 Stat. 1610</ref>, and functions thereof transferred to Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare by section 1 of Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1966, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s202">section 202 of this title</ref>. Office of Surgeon General reestablished within the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Health, see Notice of Department of Health and Human Services, Office of the Assistant Secretary for Health, <date date="1987-03-30">Mar. 30, 1987</date>, 52 F.R. 11754.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
