<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb495cb86-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s242o"><num value="242o">§ 242o.</num><heading> Health conferences; publication of health educational information</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb495cb87-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s242o/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><content> A conference of the health authorities in and among the several States shall be called annually by the Secretary. Whenever in his opinion the interests of the public health would be promoted by a conference, the Secretary may invite as many of such health authorities and officials of other State or local public or private agencies, institutions, or organizations to confer as he deems necessary or proper. Upon the application of health authorities of five or more States it shall be the duty of the Secretary to call a conference of all State health authorities joining in the request. Each State represented at any conference shall be entitled to a single vote. Whenever at any such conference matters relating to mental health are to be discussed, the mental health authorities of the respective States shall be invited to attend.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb495cb88-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s242o/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><content> From time to time the Secretary shall issue information related to public health, in the form of publications or otherwise, for the use of the public, and shall publish weekly reports of health conditions in the United States and other countries and other pertinent health information for the use of persons and institutions concerned with health services.</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb495cb89-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title III, § 310, formerly §§ 309, 310, as added <ref href="/us/pl/93/353/tI/s107/a">Pub. L. 93–353, title I, § 107(a)</ref>, <date date="1974-07-23">July 23, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/371">88 Stat. 371</ref>; renumbered § 310, <ref href="/us/pl/95/623/s6/a">Pub. L. 95–623, § 6(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3447">92 Stat. 3447</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb495cb8a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb495cb8b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb495cb8c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a) of this section consists of former section 309 of act <date date="1944-07-01">July 1, 1944</date>, prior to the renumbering of that section as section 310(a) by <ref href="/us/pl/95/623">Pub. L. 95–623</ref>. Subsec. (b) of this section consists of former section 310 of act <date date="1944-07-01">July 1, 1944</date>, prior to the renumbering of that section as section 310(b) by <ref href="/us/pl/95/623">Pub. L. 95–623</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idb495cb8d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 310 of act <date date="1944-07-01">July 1, 1944</date>, was renumbered section 329, and was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254b">section 254b of this title</ref> prior to the general amendment of subpart I (§ 254b et seq.) of part D of this subchapter by <ref href="/us/pl/104/299">Pub. L. 104–299</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those comprising subsec. (a) of this section were contained in section 312 of <ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373/tIII">act July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title III</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/58/693">58 Stat. 693</ref>, as amended (formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s244">section 244 of this title</ref>), prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/93/353/s102/a">Pub. L. 93–353, § 102(a)</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Provisions similar to those comprising subsec. (b) of this section were contained in section 315 of <ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373/tIII">act July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title III</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/58/695">58 Stat. 695</ref>; <date date="1970-10-30">Oct. 30, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/91/515/tII/s282">Pub. L. 91–515, title II, § 282</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1308">84 Stat. 1308</ref> (formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s247">section 247 of this title</ref>), prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/93/353/s102/a">Pub. L. 93–353, § 102(a)</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
