<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb4983d34-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s242v–2"><num value="242v–2">§ 242v–2.</num><heading> Protecting America’s biomedical research enterprise</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4983d35-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s242v–2/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, in consultation with the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs, the Director of National Intelligence, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and the heads of other relevant departments and agencies, and in consultation with research institutions and research advocacy organizations or other relevant experts, as appropriate, shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4983d36-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s242v–2/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> identify ways to improve the protection of intellectual property and other proprietary information, as well as identifiable, sensitive information of participants in biomedical research and development, from national security risks and other applicable threats, including the identification of gaps in policies and procedures in such areas related to biomedical research and development supported by the Department of Health and Human Services, and make recommendations to institutions of higher education or other entities that have traditionally received Federal funding for biomedical research to protect such information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4983d37-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s242v–2/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> identify or develop strategies to prevent, mitigate, and address national security risks and threats in biomedical research and development supported by the Federal Government, including such threats associated with foreign talent programs, by countries seeking to exploit United States technology and other proprietary information as it relates to such biomedical research and development, and make recommendations for additional policies and procedures to protect such information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4983d38-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s242v–2/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> identify national security risks and potential misuse of proprietary information, and identifiable, sensitive information of biomedical research participants and other applicable risks, including with respect to peer review, and make recommendations for additional policies and procedures to protect such information;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4983d39-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s242v–2/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> develop a framework to identify areas of biomedical research and development supported by the Federal Government that are emerging areas of interest for state actors and would compromise national security if they were to be subjected to undue foreign influence; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4983d3a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s242v–2/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> regularly review recommendations or policies developed under this section and make additional recommendations or updates, as appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4983d3b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s242v–2/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Report to President and to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 1 year after <date date="2022-12-29">December 29, 2022</date>, the Secretary shall prepare and submit, in a manner that does not compromise national security, to the President and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate, the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives, and other congressional committees as appropriate, a report on the findings and recommendations pursuant to subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb4983d3c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dFF/tII/s2324">Pub. L. 117–328, div. FF, title II, § 2324</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5767">136 Stat. 5767</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb4983d3d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb4983d3e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb4983d3f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Prepare for and Respond to Existing Viruses, Emerging New Threats, and Pandemics Act, also known as the PREVENT Pandemics Act, and also as part of the Health Extenders, Improving Access to Medicare, Medicaid, and CHIP, and Strengthening Public Health Act of 2022, and not as part of the Public Health Service Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb4983d40-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="definitions" id="idb4983d41-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Definition of “Secretary”</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary” means the Secretary of Health and Human Services, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s242v/a/1">section 242v(a)(1) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
