<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb49f692c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s246a"><num value="246a">§ 246a.</num><heading> Bureau of State Services management fund; establishment; advancements; availability</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of facilitating the economical and efficient conduct of operations in the Bureau of State Services which are financed by two or more appropriations where the costs of operation are not readily susceptible of distribution as charges to such appropriations, there is established the Bureau of State Services management fund. Such amounts as the Secretary may determine to represent a reasonable distribution of estimated costs among the various appropriations involved may be advanced each year to this fund and shall be available for expenditure for such costs under such regulations as may be prescribed by the Secretary: <i>Provided</i>, That funds advanced to this fund shall be available only in the fiscal year in which they are advanced: <i>Provided further</i>, That final adjustments of advances in accordance with actual costs shall be effected wherever practicable with the appropriations from which such funds are advanced.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idb49f692d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/86/703/tII/s201">Pub. L. 86–703, title II, § 201</ref>, <date date="1960-09-02">Sept. 2, 1960</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/74/765">74 Stat. 765</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/515/tII/s282">Pub. L. 91–515, title II, § 282</ref>, <date date="1970-10-30">Oct. 30, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/1308">84 Stat. 1308</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb49f692e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb49f692f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb49f6930-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was not enacted as part of the Public Health Service Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb49f6931-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—<ref href="/us/pl/91/515">Pub. L. 91–515</ref> substituted “Secretary” for “Surgeon General” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
