<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb49f694c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b"><num value="247b">§ 247b.</num><heading> Project grants for preventive health services</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb49f694d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Grant authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may make grants to States, and in consultation with State health authorities, to political subdivisions of States and to other public entities to assist them in meeting the costs of establishing and maintaining preventive health service programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb49f694e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Application</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No grant may be made under section (a) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002037">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002037"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be “subsection (a)”.</note> unless an application therefor has been submitted to, and approved by, the Secretary. Such an application shall be in such form and be submitted in such manner as the Secretary shall by regulation prescribe and shall provide—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb49f694f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a complete description of the type and extent of the program for which the applicant is seeking a grant under subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb49f6950-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> with respect to each such program (A) the amount of Federal, State, and other funds obligated by the applicant in its latest annual accounting period for the provision of such program, (B) a description of the services provided by the applicant in such program in such period, (C) the amount of Federal funds needed by the applicant to continue providing such services in such program, and (D) if the applicant proposes changes in the provision of the services in such program, the priorities of such proposed changes, reasons for such changes, and the amount of Federal funds needed by the applicant to make such changes;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb49f6951-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> assurances satisfactory to the Secretary that the program which will be provided with funds under a grant under subsection (a) will be provided in a manner consistent with the State health plan in effect under section 300m–3(c) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002038">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002038"><num>2</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title and in those cases where the applicant is a State, that such program will be provided, where appropriate, in a manner consistent with any plans in effect under an application approved under section 247 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002038">2</ref> of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb49f6952-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> assurances satisfactory to the Secretary that the applicant will provide for such fiscal control and fund accounting procedures as the Secretary by regulation prescribes to assure the proper disbursement of and accounting for funds received under grants under subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb49f6953-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> assurances satisfactory to the Secretary that the applicant will provide for periodic evaluation of its program or programs;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb49f6954-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> assurances satisfactory to the Secretary that the applicant will make such reports (in such form and containing such information as the Secretary may by regulation prescribe) as the Secretary may reasonably require and keep such records and afford such access thereto as the Secretary may find necessary to assure the correctness of, and to verify, such reports;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb49f6955-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> assurances satisfactory to the Secretary that the applicant will comply with any other conditions imposed by this section with respect to grants; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb49f6956-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> such other information as the Secretary may by regulation prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb49f6957-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Approval; annual project review</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb49f6958-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall not approve an application submitted under subsection (b) for a grant for a program for which a grant was previously made under subsection (a) unless the Secretary determines—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb49f6959-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the program for which the application was submitted is operating effectively to achieve its stated purpose,</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb49f695a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the applicant complied with the assurances provided the Secretary when applying for such previous grant, and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb49f695b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the applicant will comply with the assurances provided with the application.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb49f695c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall review annually the activities undertaken by each recipient of a grant under subsection (a) to determine if the program assisted by such grant is operating effectively to achieve its stated purposes and if the recipient is in compliance with the assurances provided the Secretary when applying for such grant.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb49f695d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Amount of grant; payment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The amount of a grant under subsection (a) shall be determined by the Secretary. Payments under such grants may be made in advance on the basis of estimates or by the way of reimbursement, with necessary adjustments on account of underpayments or overpayments, and in such installments and on such terms and conditions as the Secretary finds necessary to carry out the purposes of such grants.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb49f695e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Reduction</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, at the request of a recipient of a grant under subsection (a), may reduce the amount of such grant by—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb49f695f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the fair market value of any supplies (including vaccines and other preventive agents) or equipment furnished the grant recipient, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb49f6960-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the amount of the pay, allowances, and travel expenses of any officer or employee of the Government when detailed to the grant recipient and the amount of any other costs incurred in connection with the detail of such officer or employee,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">when the furnishing of such supplies or equipment or the detail of such an officer or employee is for the convenience of and at the request of such grant recipient and for the purpose of carrying out a program with respect to which the grant under subsection (a) is made. The amount by which any such grant is so reduced shall be available for payment by the Secretary of the costs incurred in furnishing the supplies or equipment, or in detailing the personnel, on which the reduction of such grant is based, and such amount shall be deemed as part of the grant and shall be deemed to have been paid to the grant recipient.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb49f6961-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Recordkeeping; audit authority</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb49f6962-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Each recipient of a grant under subsection (a) shall keep such records as the Secretary shall by regulation prescribe, including records which fully disclose the amount and disposition by such recipient of the proceeds of such grant, the total cost of the undertaking in connection with which such grant was made, and the amount of that portion of the cost of the undertaking supplied by other sources, and such other records as will facilitate an effective audit.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb49f6963-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary and the Comptroller General of the United States, or any of their duly authorized representatives, shall have access for the purpose of audit and examination to any books, documents, papers, and records of the recipient of grants under subsection (a) that are pertinent to such grants.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb49f6964-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of grant funds; mandatory treatment pro­hibited</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb49f6965-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Nothing in this section shall limit or otherwise restrict the use of funds which are granted to a State or to an agency or a political subdivision of a State under provisions of Federal law (other than this section) and which are available for the conduct of preventive health service programs from being used in connection with programs assisted through grants under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb49f6966-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Nothing in this section shall be construed to require any State or any agency or political subdivision of a State to have a preventive health service program which would require any person, who objects to any treatment provided under such a program, to be treated or to have any child or ward treated under such program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb49f6967-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Reports</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall include, as part of the report required by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300u–4">section 300u–4 of this title</ref>, a report on the extent of the problems presented by the diseases and conditions referred to in subsection (j); on the amount of funds obligated under grants under subsection (a) in the preceding fiscal year for each of the programs listed in subsection (j); and on the effectiveness of the activities assisted under grants under subsection (a) in controlling such diseases and conditions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb49f6968-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Technical assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may provide technical assistance to States, State health authorities, and other public entities in connection with the operation of their preventive health service programs.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb49f6969-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb49f696a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Except for grants for immunization programs the authorization of appropriations for which are established in paragraph (2), for grants under subsections (a) and (k)(1) for preventive health service programs to immunize without charge children, adolescents, and adults against vaccine-preventable diseases, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary. Not more than 10 percent of the total amount appropriated under the preceding sentence for any fiscal year shall be available for grants under subsection (k)(1) for such fiscal year.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb49f696b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> For grants under subsection (a) for preventive health service programs for the provision without charge of immunizations with vaccines approved for use, and recommended for routine use, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb49f696c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Additional grants to States, political subdivisions, and other public and nonprofit private entities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb49f696d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/k/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary may make grants to States, political subdivisions of States, and other public and nonprofit private entities for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb49f696e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/k/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> research into the prevention and control of diseases that may be prevented through vaccination;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb49f696f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/k/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> demonstration projects for the prevention and control of such diseases;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb49f6970-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/k/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> public information and education programs for the prevention and control of such diseases;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb49f6971-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/k/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> education, training, and clinical skills improvement activities in the prevention and control of such diseases for health professionals (including allied health personnel);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb49f6972-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/k/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><chapeau> planning, implementation, and evaluation of activities to address vaccine-preventable diseases, including activities to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb49f6973-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/k/1/E/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> identify communities at high risk of outbreaks related to vaccine-preventable diseases, including through improved data collection and analysis;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb49f6974-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/k/1/E/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> pilot innovative approaches to improve vaccination rates in communities and among populations with low rates of vaccination;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb49f6975-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/k/1/E/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> reduce barriers to accessing vaccines and evidence-based information about the health effects of vaccines;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb49f6976-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/k/1/E/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> partner with community organizations and health care providers to develop and deliver evidence-based interventions, including culturally and linguistically appropriate interventions, to increase vaccination rates;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb49f6977-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/k/1/E/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> improve delivery of evidence-based vaccine-related information to parents and others; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb49f6978-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/k/1/E/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> improve the ability of State, local, Tribal, and territorial public health departments to engage communities at high risk for outbreaks related to vaccine-preventable diseases, including, as appropriate, with local educational agencies, as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7801">section 7801 of title 20</ref>; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb49f6979-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/k/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> research related to strategies for improving awareness of scientific and evidence-based vaccine-related information, including for communities with low rates of vaccination, in order to understand barriers to vaccination, improve vaccination rates, and assess the public health outcomes of such strategies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb49f697a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/k/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Secretary may make grants to States, political subdivisions of States, and other public and nonprofit private entities for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb49f697b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/k/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> research into the prevention and control of diseases and conditions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb49f697c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/k/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> demonstration projects for the prevention and control of such diseases and conditions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb49f697d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/k/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> public information and education programs for the prevention and control of such diseases and conditions; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb49f697e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/k/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> education, training, and clinical skills improvement activities in the prevention and control of such diseases and conditions for health professionals (including allied health personnel).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb49f697f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/k/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> No grant may be made under this subsection unless an application therefor is submitted to the Secretary in such form, at such time, and containing such information as the Secretary may by regulation prescribe.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb49f6980-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/k/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Subsections (d), (e), and (f) of this section shall apply to grants under this subsection in the same manner as such subsections apply to grants under subsection (a) of this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb49f6981-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to purchase recommended vaccines for adults</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb49f6982-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/l/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may negotiate and enter into contracts with manufacturers of vaccines for the purchase and delivery of vaccines for adults as provided for under subsection (e).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb49f6983-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/l/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> State purchase</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A State may obtain additional quantities of such adult vaccines (subject to amounts specified to the Secretary by the State in advance of negotiations) through the purchase of vaccines from manufacturers at the applicable price negotiated by the Secretary under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb49f6984-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/m"><num value="m" class="bold">(m)</num><heading class="bold"> Demonstration program to improve immunization coverage</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb49f6985-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/m/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall establish a demonstration program to award grants to States to improve the provision of recommended immunizations for children, adolescents, and adults through the use of evidence-based, population-based interventions for high-risk populations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb49f6986-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/m/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> State plan</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">To be eligible for a grant under paragraph (1), a State shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including a State plan that describes the interventions to be implemented under the grant and how such interventions match with local needs and capabilities, as determined through consultation with local authorities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb49f6987-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/m/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Funds received under a grant under this subsection shall be used to implement interventions that are recommended by the Task Force on Community Preventive Services (as established by the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention) or other evidence-based interventions, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb49f6988-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/m/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> providing immunization reminders or recalls for target populations of clients, patients, and consumers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb49f6989-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/m/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> educating targeted populations and health care providers concerning immunizations in combination with one or more other interventions;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb49f698a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/m/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> reducing out-of-pocket costs for families for vaccines and their administration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb49f698b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/m/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> carrying out immunization-promoting strategies for participants or clients of public programs, including assessments of immunization status, referrals to health care providers, education, provision of on-site immunizations, or incentives for immunization;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb49f698c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/m/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> providing for home visits that promote immunization through education, assessments of need, referrals, provision of immunizations, or other services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb49f698d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/m/3/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> providing reminders or recalls for immunization providers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb49f698e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/m/3/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> conducting assessments of, and providing feedback to, immunization providers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb49f698f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/m/3/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> any combination of one or more interventions described in this paragraph; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb49f6990-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/m/3/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> immunization information systems to allow all States to have electronic databases for immunization records.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb49f6991-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/m/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Consideration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In awarding grants under this subsection, the Secretary shall consider any reviews or recommendations of the Task Force on Community Preventive Services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb49f6992-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/m/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Evaluation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 3 years after the date on which a State receives a grant under this subsection, the State shall submit to the Secretary an evaluation of progress made toward improving immunization coverage rates among high-risk populations within the State.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb49f6993-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/m/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Report to Congress</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 4 years after <date date="2010-03-23">March 23, 2010</date>,<sup>2</sup> the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report concerning the effectiveness of the demonstration program established under this subsection together with recommendations on whether to continue and expand such program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb49f6994-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/m/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection, such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2010 through 2014.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb49f6995-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b/n"><num value="n" class="bold">(n)</num><heading class="bold"> Vaccination data</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall expand and enhance, and, as appropriate, establish and improve, programs and conduct activities to collect, monitor, and analyze vaccination coverage data to assess levels of protection from vaccine-preventable diseases, including by assessing factors contributing to underutilization of vaccines and variations of such factors, and identifying communities at high risk of outbreaks associated with vaccine-preventable diseases.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb49f6996-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title III, § 317, as added <ref href="/us/pl/87/868/s2">Pub. L. 87–868, § 2</ref>, <date date="1962-10-23">Oct. 23, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/1155">76 Stat. 1155</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/89/109/s2">Pub. L. 89–109, § 2</ref>, <date date="1965-08-05">Aug. 5, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/435">79 Stat. 435</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/91/464/s2">Pub. L. 91–464, § 2</ref>, <date date="1970-10-16">Oct. 16, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/988">84 Stat. 988</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/92/449/tI/s101">Pub. L. 92–449, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="1972-09-30">Sept. 30, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/748">86 Stat. 748</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/93/354/s4">Pub. L. 93–354, § 4</ref>, <date date="1974-07-23">July 23, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/376">88 Stat. 376</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/63/tVI/s601">Pub. L. 94–63, title VI, § 601</ref>, <date date="1975-07-29">July 29, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/346">89 Stat. 346</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/317/tII/s202/a">Pub. L. 94–317, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1976-06-23">June 23, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/700">90 Stat. 700</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/94/380/s2">Pub. L. 94–380, § 2</ref>, <date date="1976-08-12">Aug. 12, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1113">90 Stat. 1113</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/626/tII">Pub. L. 95–626, title II</ref>, §§ 202, 204(b)(2), <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3574">92 Stat. 3574</ref>, 3583; <ref href="/us/pl/96/32/s6/i">Pub. L. 96–32, § 6(i)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-10">July 10, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/83">93 Stat. 83</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tIX/s928">Pub. L. 97–35, title IX, § 928</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/569">95 Stat. 569</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/98/555/s2">Pub. L. 98–555, § 2</ref>, <date date="1984-10-30">Oct. 30, 1984</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/98/2854">98 Stat. 2854</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/117/s11/c">Pub. L. 99–117, § 11(c)</ref>, <date date="1985-10-07">Oct. 7, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/495">99 Stat. 495</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/177/tI">Pub. L. 100–177, title I</ref>, §§ 110(a), 111, <date date="1987-12-01">Dec. 1, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/990">101 Stat. 990</ref>, 991; <ref href="/us/pl/101/368/s2">Pub. L. 101–368, § 2</ref>, <date date="1990-08-15">Aug. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/446">104 Stat. 446</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/502/s2/a">Pub. L. 101–502, § 2(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-03">Nov. 3, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1285">104 Stat. 1285</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/183/tIII/s301/b">Pub. L. 103–183, title III, § 301(b)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-14">Dec. 14, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2235">107 Stat. 2235</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/392/tIII/s303">Pub. L. 105–392, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3586">112 Stat. 3586</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/106/310/dA/tXVII/s1711">Pub. L. 106–310, div. A, title XVII, § 1711</ref>, <date date="2000-10-17">Oct. 17, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1152">114 Stat. 1152</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tIV/s4204/a">Pub. L. 111–148, title IV, § 4204(a)</ref>–(c), <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/571">124 Stat. 571</ref>, 572; <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dBB/tIII/s311/b">Pub. L. 116–260, div. BB, title III, § 311(b)</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2924">134 Stat. 2924</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb49f6997-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb49f6998-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb49f6999-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300m–3">Section 300m–3 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (b)(3), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/99/660/tVII/s701/a">Pub. L. 99–660, title VII, § 701(a)</ref>, <date date="1986-11-14">Nov. 14, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3799">100 Stat. 3799</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s247">Section 247 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (b)(3), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/99/117/s12/b">Pub. L. 99–117, § 12(b)</ref>, <date date="1985-10-07">Oct. 7, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/495">99 Stat. 495</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><date date="2010-03-23">March 23, 2010</date>, referred to in subsec. (m)(6), was in the original “the date of enactment of the Affordable Health Choices Act”, and was translated as meaning the date of enactment of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, <ref href="/us/pl/111/148">Pub. L. 111–148</ref>, to reflect the probable intent of Congress. No act named the “Affordable Health Choices Act” has been enacted.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb49f699a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsec. (k)(1)(E), (F). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s311/b/1">Pub. L. 116–260, § 311(b)(1)</ref>, added subpars. (E) and (F).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (n). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/s311/b/2">Pub. L. 116–260, § 311(b)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (n).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (j)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s4204/c/1">Pub. L. 111–148, § 4204(c)(1)</ref>, struck out “for each of the fiscal years 1998 through 2005” after “necessary”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s4204/c/2">Pub. L. 111–148, § 4204(c)(2)</ref>, struck out “after <date date="1997-10-01">October 1, 1997</date>,” after “routine use,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (<i>l</i>), (m). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s4204/a">Pub. L. 111–148, § 4204(a)</ref>, (b), added subsecs. (<i>l</i>) and (m).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2000—Subsec. (j)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/106/310">Pub. L. 106–310</ref> substituted “1998 through 2005” for “1998 through 2002” in first sentence.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (j)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/105/392/s303/1">Pub. L. 105–392, § 303(1)</ref>, substituted “children, adolescents, and adults against vaccine-preventable diseases, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 1998 through 2002.” for “individuals against vaccine-preventable diseases, there are authorized to be appropriated $205,000,000 for fiscal year 1991, and such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 1992 through 1995.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/392/s303/2">Pub. L. 105–392, § 303(2)</ref>, substituted “1997” for “1990”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/103/183/s301/b/1">Pub. L. 103–183, § 301(b)(1)</ref>, redesignated subpars. (A) and (B) of par. (1) as pars. (1) and (2), respectively, substituted “established in paragraph (2)” for “established in subparagraph (B)” in par. (1), and struck out former par. (2), which read as follows: “For grants under subsection (a) of this section for preventive health service programs for the prevention, control, and elimination of tuberculosis, and for grants under subsection (k)(2) of this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $24,000,000 for fiscal year 1988, $31,000,000 for fiscal year 1989, $36,000,000 for fiscal year 1990, $36,000,000 for fiscal year 1991, and such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 1992 through 1995. Not more than 10 percent of the total amount appropriated under the preceding sentence for any fiscal year shall be available for grants under subsection (k)(2) of this section for such fiscal year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/103/183/s301/b/2/A">Pub. L. 103–183, § 301(b)(2)(A)</ref>, (B), redesignated par. (3) as (2) and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows: “The Secretary may make grants to States, political subdivisions of States, and other public and nonprofit private entities for—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) research into the prevention, control, and elimination of tuberculosis, especially research concerning strains of tuberculosis resistant to drugs and research concerning cases of tuberculosis that affect certain populations;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) demonstration projects for the prevention, control, and elimination of tuberculosis;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(C) public information and education programs for prevention, control, and elimination of tuberculosis; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(D) education, training, and clinical skills improvement activities in the prevention, control, and elimination of tuberculosis for health professionals, including allied health personnel.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/103/183/s301/b/2/B">Pub. L. 103–183, § 301(b)(2)(B)</ref>, redesignated par. (4) as (3). Former par. (3) redesignated (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/103/183/s301/b/2/B">Pub. L. 103–183, § 301(b)(2)(B)</ref>, (C), redesignated par. (5) as (4) and made technical amendments to references to subsections (d), (e), and (f) of this section and subsection (a) of this section, to reflect change in references to corresponding provisions of original act. Former par. (4) redesignated (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/103/183/s301/b/3">Pub. L. 103–183, § 301(b)(3)</ref>, struck out subsec. (<i>l</i>) which related to establishment and function of Advisory Council for the Elimination of Tuberculosis.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (j)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/101/502/s2/a/1">Pub. L. 101–502, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, substituted provisions authorizing appropriations for fiscal years 1991 through 1995 for provisions authorizing appropriations for fiscal years 1988 through 1990.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/101/502/s2/a/2">Pub. L. 101–502, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, substituted <date date="1990-10-01">Oct. 1, 1990</date>, for <date date="1987-12-01">Dec. 1, 1987</date>, and provisions authorizing appropriations as may be necessary for provisions authorizing appropriations for fiscal years 1988 to 1990.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/101/502/s2/a/3">Pub. L. 101–502, § 2(a)(3)</ref>, struck out subpar. (C) which, on the implementation of part 2 of subchapter XIX of this chapter, authorized appropriations for grants under subsec. (a) of this section for fiscal years 1988 to 1990.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/368/s2/c">Pub. L. 101–368, § 2(c)</ref>, inserted provisions authorizing appropriations of $36,000,000 for fiscal year 1991, and such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 1992 through 1995.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/368/s2/a/1">Pub. L. 101–368, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “preventive health service programs for the prevention, control, and elimination of tuberculosis” for “preventive health service programs for tuberculosis”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k)(2)(A) to (D). <ref href="/us/pl/101/368/s2/a/2">Pub. L. 101–368, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “prevention, control, and elimination” for “prevention and control”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/101/368/s2/b">Pub. L. 101–368, § 2(b)</ref>, added subsec. (<i>l</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/100/177">Pub. L. 100–177</ref>, §§ 110(a), 111(a), amended subsec. (j) generally, substituting provisions authorizing appropriations for fiscal years 1988 to 1990 for grants under subsecs. (a) and (k) of this section for former provisions authorizing appropriations for fiscal years 1982 to 1987 for grants under subsec. (a) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/100/177/s111/b">Pub. L. 100–177, § 111(b)</ref>, added subsec. (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/99/117">Pub. L. 99–117</ref> amended directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s928/b">Pub. L. 97–35, § 928(b)</ref>, to correct a technical error. See 1981 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1984—Subsec. (j)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/98/555/s2/a">Pub. L. 98–555, § 2(a)</ref>, substituted “immunize individuals against vaccine-preventable diseases” for “immunize children against immunizable diseases” and inserted provisions authorizing appropriations for fiscal years ending <date date="1985-09-30">Sept. 30, 1985</date>, 1986, and 1987.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/98/555/s2/b">Pub. L. 98–555, § 2(b)</ref>, inserted provisions authorizing appropriations for fiscal years ending <date date="1985-09-30">Sept. 30, 1985</date>, 1986, and 1987.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s928/a">Pub. L. 97–35, § 928(a)</ref>, struck out par. (1) which related to grants to State health authorities, and redesignated par. (2) as entire section and, as so redesignated, struck out reference to former par. (1).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s928/b">Pub. L. 97–35, § 928(b)</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/99/117">Pub. L. 99–117</ref>, substituted provisions authorizing appropriations for fiscal years ending <date date="1982-09-30">Sept. 30, 1982</date>, 1983, and 1984, for provisions setting forth appropriations through fiscal year ending <date date="1981-09-30">Sept. 30, 1981</date>, and provisions setting forth limitations, conditions, etc., for appropriations.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (j)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/96/32">Pub. L. 96–32</ref> added par. (4), redesignated former par. (4) as (5) and, in par. (5) as so redesignated, substituted “paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (4)” for “paragraph (1), (2), or (3)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—<ref href="/us/pl/95/626/s202">Pub. L. 95–626, § 202</ref>, amended section generally, substituting provisions relating to proj­ect grants for preventive health services for provisions relating to grants for disease control programs.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/95/626/s204/b/2">Pub. L. 95–626, § 204(b)(2)</ref>, struck out “Except as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s247c">section 247c of this title</ref>,” before “No funds appropriated under any provision of this chapter”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1976—<ref href="/us/pl/94/317">Pub. L. 94–317</ref> amended section generally to include many non-communicable diseases as well as expanding coverage of communicable diseases, increased appropriations for grants, widened scope of Secretary’s authority to make grants and enter into contracts to include nonprofit private entities, and required a report from the Secretary on the effectiveness of all Federal and other public and private activities in controlling the diseases covered under this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (j) to (<i>l</i>). <ref href="/us/pl/94/380">Pub. L. 94–380</ref> added subsecs. (j) to (<i>l</i>).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1975—Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/94/63/s601/b">Pub. L. 94–63, § 601(b)</ref>, inserted authorization of appropriation for fiscal year 1976.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/94/63/s601/a">Pub. L. 94–63, § 601(a)</ref>, inserted reference to diseases borne by rodents.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1974—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/93/354/s4/1">Pub. L. 93–354, § 4(1)</ref>–(3), substituted “communicable and other disease control” for “communicable disease control”, “communicable and other diseases” for “communicable diseases”, and “communicable and other disease control program” for “communicable disease program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/93/354/s4/1">Pub. L. 93–354, § 4(1)</ref>, (4), substituted “communicable or other disease” for “communicable disease” in cl. (i) and “communicable and other disease control” for “communicable disease control” in cl. (ii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b)(3), (d)(1), (2), (3), (f)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/93/354/s4/1">Pub. L. 93–354, § 4(1)</ref>, substituted “communicable and other disease control” for “communicable disease control”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/93/354/s4/1">Pub. L. 93–354, § 4(1)</ref>, (5), substituted “communicable and other disease control” for “communicable disease control” in two places and inserted reference to diabetes mellitus.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/93/354/s4/1">Pub. L. 93–354, § 4(1)</ref>, substituted “communicable and other disease control” for “communicable disease control”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1972—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/92/449">Pub. L. 92–449</ref> substituted provision for grants by the Secretary in consultation with the State health authority to agencies and political subdivisions of States, for former provision for grants by the Secretary with the approval of the State health authority to political subdivisions or instrumentalities of States, incorporated existing provisions in provision designated as cl. (1), inserting “, in the area served by the applicant for the grant,”, substituted a cl. (2) reading “design of the applicant’s communicable disease program to determine its effectiveness”, for former provision reading “levels of performance in preventing and controlling such diseases”, struck out appropriations authorization of $75,000,000 and $90,000,000 for fiscal years ending <date date="1971-06-30">June 30, 1971</date>, and 1972, now covered for subsequent years in subsec. (d), and struck out provision for use of grants to meet cost of studies to determine the control needs of communities and the means of best meeting such needs, now covered in subsec. (h)(1) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/92/449">Pub. L. 92–449</ref> substituted provisions of par. (1) respecting applications for grants, submission, approval, form, and content of applications; par. (2) respecting application requirements; and par. (3) incorporating former subsec. (g) provisions respecting consent of individuals for former definitions provision now incorporated in subsec. (h) of this section.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/92/449">Pub. L. 92–449</ref> designated existing provisions as par. (1) and among minor punctuation changes inserted “under grants” after “Payments”; and redesignated former subsec. (d) as par. (2), inserted “of the Government” after “officer or employee”, substituted “in detailing the personnel” for “personal services”, and struck out provision that reduced amount shall, for purposes of subsec. (c), be deemed to have been paid to the agency.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/92/449">Pub. L. 92–449</ref> substituted provisions respecting authorization of appropriations and limitation on use of funds for provisions respecting grant reduction.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/92/449">Pub. L. 92–449</ref> substituted provisions for emergency plan development and authorization of appropriations for provisions relating to use of funds.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/92/449">Pub. L. 92–449</ref> substituted provisions respecting conditional limitation on use of funds for provisions for an annual report.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/92/449">Pub. L. 92–449</ref> incorporated former subsec. (f) provisions in introductory text and cl. (3), prescribed a January 1 submission date, and inserted provisions of cls. (1), (2), and (4). Former subsec. (g) consent of individuals provision respecting communicable disease control and vaccination assistance were covered in subsec. (b)(3) of this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s247c/h">section 247c(h) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/92/449">Pub. L. 92–449</ref> redesignated former subsec. (b) as (h), substituted in introductory text “this section” for “this subsection”, and in par. (1) struck out “venereal disease” after “tuberculosis,”, inserted “(other than venereal disease)” after “other communicable diseases”, and included in definition of “communicable disease control program” vaccination programs, laboratory services, and control studies.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/92/449">Pub. L. 92–449</ref> redesignated former subsec. (e) as (i), inserted reference to agency of a State, and substituted “under provisions of Federal law (other than this chapter)” for “under other provisions of this chapter or other Federal law”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/91/464">Pub. L. 91–464</ref> authorized appropriation of $75,000,000 for fiscal year ending <date date="1971-06-30">June 30, 1971</date>, and $90,000,000 for fiscal year ending <date date="1972-06-30">June 30, 1972</date>, and made award of grants dependent upon extent of communicable disease and success of programs and permitted use of grants for meeting cost of programs and studies to control communicable diseases and struck out reference to purchase of vaccines and use of grants for salaries and expenses of personnel and to authority of the Surgeon General.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/91/464">Pub. L. 91–464</ref> substituted definitions of “communicable disease control program” and “State” for definition of “immunization program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/91/464">Pub. L. 91–464</ref> substituted reference to Secretary for reference to Surgeon General and struck out provisions relating to purchasing and furnishing of vaccines and requirement of obtaining assurances from recipients of grants.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/91/464">Pub. L. 91–464</ref> substituted reference to Secretary for reference to Surgeon General and struck out reference to Public Health Service.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/91/464">Pub. L. 91–464</ref> struck out reference to title V of the Social Security Act and substituted provisions for the use of funds for the conduct of communicable disease control programs for provisions for the purchase of vaccine or for organizing, promoting, conducting, or participating in immunization programs.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (f), (g). <ref href="/us/pl/91/464">Pub. L. 91–464</ref> added subsecs. (f) and (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1965—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/89/109/s2/a">Pub. L. 89–109, § 2(a)</ref>, (b), (d)(1), inserted “and each of the next three fiscal years”, substituted “any fiscal year ending prior to <date date="1968-07-01">July 1, 1968</date>” for “the fiscal years ending <date date="1963-06-30">June 30, 1963</date>, and <date date="1964-06-30">June 30, 1964</date>”, “tetanus, and measles” for “and tetanus”, “of preschool age” for “under the age of five years”, and “immunization” for “intensive community vaccination”, and permitted grants to be used to pay costs in connection with immunization of other infectious diseases.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/89/109/s2/c">Pub. L. 89–109, § 2(c)</ref>, (d)(1), substituted “against the diseases referred to in subsection (a) of this section” for “against poliomyelitis, diphtheria, whooping cough, and tetanus”, “of preschool age” for “who are under the age of five years” and “immunization” for “intensive community vaccination” in two places.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/89/109/s2/d/1">Pub. L. 89–109, § 2(d)(1)</ref>, (e), inserted “on the basis of estimates” and “(with necessary adjustments on account of underpayments or overpayments)” in par. (1), and substituted “immunization” for “intensive community vaccination” in pars. (2) and (3).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb4a1b28b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb4a1b28c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1978 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/626/tII/s202">Pub. L. 95–626, title II, § 202</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3574">92 Stat. 3574</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/96/32/s6/g">Pub. L. 96–32, § 6(g)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-10">July 10, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/83">93 Stat. 83</ref>, provided that the amendment made by that section is effective <date date="1978-10-01">Oct. 1, 1978</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb4a1b28d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1976 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/94/317/tII/s202/a">Pub. L. 94–317, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3574">92 Stat. 3574</ref>, provided that the amendment made by that section is effective with respect to grants under this section for fiscal years beginning after <date date="1975-06-30">June 30, 1975</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb4a1b28e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1975 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/94/63/tVI/s608">Pub. L. 94–63, title VI, § 608</ref>, <date date="1975-07-29">July 29, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/89/352">89 Stat. 352</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/94/63/tVI/s608">“Except as may otherwise be specifically provided, the amendments made by this title [enacting sections 300c–21 and 300c–22 of this title, amending this section, and enacting provisions set out as notes under sections 289, 289k–2, and 1395x of this title] and by titles I [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s246">section 246 of this title</ref> and enacting provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s246">section 246 of this title</ref>], II [enacting sections 300a–6a and 300a–8 of this title, amending sections 300 and 300a–1 to 300a–4 of this title, repealing <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3505c">section 3505c of this title</ref>, and enacting provision set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300">section 300 of this title</ref>], III [enacting sections 2689 to 2689aa of this title, amending sections 2691 and 2693 to 2696 of this title, and enacting provisions set out as notes under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2689">section 2689 of this title</ref>], IV [amending sections 218 and 254b of this title and enacting provision set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254b">section 254b of this title</ref>], and V [enacting <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254c">section 254c of this title</ref> and amending <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s246">section 246 of this title</ref>] of this Act shall take effect <date date="1975-07-01">July 1, 1975</date>. The amendments made by this title and by such titles to the provisions of law amended by this title and by such titles are made to such provisions as amended by title VII of this Act [amending sections 246, 254b, 300, 300a–1 to 300a–3 of this title and sections 2681, 2687, 2688a, 2688d, 2688j–1, 2688j–2, 2688<i>l</i>, 2688<i>l</i>–1, 2688n–1, 2688<i>o</i>, and 2688u of this title].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb4a1b28f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1972 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/92/449/tI/s102">Pub. L. 92–449, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1972-09-30">Sept. 30, 1972</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/86/750">86 Stat. 750</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/92/449/tI/s102">“The amendment made by <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s101">section 101 of this title</ref> [amending this section] shall apply to grants made under section 317 of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s247b">42 U.S.C. 247b</ref>] after <date date="1972-06-30">June 30, 1972</date>, except that subsection (d) of such section as amended by section 101 shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1972-09-30">Sept. 30, 1972</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb4a1b290-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Rule of Construction Regarding Access to Immunizations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tIV/s4204/d">Pub. L. 111–148, title IV, § 4204(d)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/572">124 Stat. 572</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/111/148/tIV/s4204/d">“Nothing in this section [amending this section] (including the amendments made by this section), or any other provision of this Act [see Tables for classification] (including any amendments made by this Act) shall be construed to decrease children’s access to immunizations.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb4a1b291-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Assistance of Administrator of Veterans’ Affairs in Administration of National Swine Flu Immunization Program of 1976; Claims for Damages</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/94/420/s3">Pub. L. 94–420, § 3</ref>, <date date="1976-09-23">Sept. 23, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1301">90 Stat. 1301</ref>, provided that, in order to assist Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare in carrying out National Swine Flu Immunization Program of 1976 pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s247b/j">42 U.S.C. 247b(j)</ref>, as added by <ref href="/us/pl/94/380">Pub. L. 94–380</ref>, Administrator of Veterans’ Affairs, in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s247b/j">42 U.S.C. 247b(j)</ref>, could authorize administration of vaccine, procured under such program and provided by Secretary at no cost to Veterans’ Administration, to eligible veterans (voluntarily requesting such vaccine) in connection with provision of care for a disability under chapter 17 of title 38, in any health care facility under jurisdiction of Administrator, and provided for consideration and processing of claims and suits for damages for personal injury or death, in connection with administration of vaccine.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb4a1b292-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study by Secretary of Scope and Extent of Liability Arising Out of Immunization Program; Alternative Protective Approaches; Report to Congress</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/94/380/s3">Pub. L. 94–380, § 3</ref>, <date date="1976-08-12">Aug. 12, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1118">90 Stat. 1118</ref>, directed Secretary to conduct a study of liability for personal injuries or death arising out of immunization programs and of alternative approaches to provide protection against such liability and report to Congress on findings of such study by <date date="1977-08-12">Aug. 12, 1977</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
