<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb4a4242a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a"><num value="247b–4a">§ 247b–4a.</num><heading> Early detection, diagnosis, and interventions for newborns and infants with hearing loss</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a4242b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this section only, the following terms in this section are defined as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a4242c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Hearing screening</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Newborn and infant hearing screening consists of objective physiologic procedures to detect possible hearing loss and to identify newborns and infants who, after rescreening, require further audiologic and medical evaluations.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a4242d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Audiologic evaluation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Audiologic evaluation consists of procedures to assess the status of the auditory system; to establish the site of the auditory disorder; the type and degree of hearing loss, and the potential effects of hearing loss on communication; and to identify appropriate treatment and referral options. Referral options should include linkage to State IDEA part C coordinating agencies or other appropriate agencies, medical evaluation, hearing aid/sensory aid assessment, audiologic rehabilitation treatment, national and local consumer, self-help, parent, and education organizations, and other family-centered services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a4242e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Medical evaluation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Medical evaluation by a physician consists of key components including history, examination, and medical decision making focused on symptomatic and related body systems for the purpose of diagnosing the etiology of hearing loss and related physical conditions, and for identifying appropriate treatment and referral options.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a4242f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/a/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Medical intervention</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Medical intervention is the process by which a physician provides medical diagnosis and direction for medical and/or surgical treatment options of hearing loss and/or related medical disorder associated with hearing loss.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a42430-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/a/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Audiologic rehabilitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Audiologic rehabilitation (intervention) consists of procedures, techniques, and technologies to facilitate the receptive and expressive communication abilities of a child with hearing loss.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a42431-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/a/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Early intervention</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Early intervention (e.g., nonmedical) means providing appropriate services for the child with hearing loss and ensuring that families of the child are provided comprehensive, consumer-oriented information about the full range of family support, training, information services, communication options and are given the opportunity to consider the full range of educational and program placements and options for their child.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a42432-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Purposes</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The purposes of this section are to clarify the authority within the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">42 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.] to authorize statewide newborn and infant hearing screening, evaluation and intervention programs and systems, technical assistance, a national applied research program, and interagency and private sector collaboration for policy development, in order to assist the States in making progress toward the following goals:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4a42433-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> All babies born in hospitals in the United States and its territories should have a hearing screening before leaving the birthing facility. Babies born in other countries and residing in the United States via immigration or adoption should have a hearing screening as early as possible.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4a42434-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> All babies who are not born in hospitals in the United States and its territories should have a hearing screening within the first 3 months of life.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4a42435-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Appropriate audiologic and medical evaluations should be conducted by 3 months for all newborns and infants suspected of having hearing loss to allow appropriate referral and provisions for audiologic rehabilitation, medical and early intervention before the age of 6 months.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4a42436-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> All newborn and infant hearing screening programs and systems should include a component for audiologic rehabilitation, medical and early intervention options that ensures linkage to any new and existing statewide systems of intervention and rehabilitative services for newborns and infants with hearing loss.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4a42437-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Public policy in regard to newborn and infant hearing screening and intervention should be based on applied research and the recognition that newborns, infants, toddlers, and children who are deaf or hard-of-hearing have unique language, learning, and communication needs, and should be the result of consultation with pertinent public and private sectors.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a42438-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Statewide newborn and infant hearing screening, evaluation and intervention programs and systems</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Under the existing authority of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">42 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.], the Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the “Secretary”), acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall make awards of grants or cooperative agreements to develop statewide newborn and infant hearing screening, evaluation and intervention programs and systems for the following purposes:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4a42439-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> To develop and monitor the efficacy of statewide newborn and infant hearing screening, evaluation and intervention programs and systems. Early intervention includes referral to schools and agencies, including community, consumer, and parent-based agencies and organizations and other programs mandated by part C of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1431">20 U.S.C. 1431</ref> et seq.], which offer programs specifically designed to meet the unique language and communication needs of deaf and hard-of-hearing newborns, infants, toddlers, and children.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4a4243a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> To collect data on statewide newborn and infant hearing screening, evaluation and intervention programs and systems that can be used for applied research, program evaluation and policy development.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a4243b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Technical assistance, data management, and applied research</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a4243c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Under the existing authority of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">42 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.], the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall make awards of grants or cooperative agreements to provide technical assistance to State agencies to complement an intramural program and to conduct applied research related to newborn and infant hearing screening, evaluation and intervention programs and systems. The program shall develop standardized procedures for data management and program effectiveness and costs, such as—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a4243d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to ensure quality monitoring of newborn and infant hearing loss screening, evaluation, and intervention programs and systems;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a4243e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to provide technical assistance on data collection and management;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a4243f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> to study the costs and effectiveness of newborn and infant hearing screening, evaluation and intervention programs and systems conducted by State-based programs in order to answer issues of importance to State and national policymakers;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a42440-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/d/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> to identify the causes and risk factors for congenital hearing loss;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a42441-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/d/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> to study the effectiveness of newborn and infant hearing screening, audiologic and medical evaluations and intervention programs and systems by assessing the health, intellectual and social developmental, cognitive, and language status of these children at school age; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a42442-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/d/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> to promote the sharing of data regarding early hearing loss with State-based birth defects and developmental disabilities monitoring programs for the purpose of identifying previously unknown causes of hearing loss.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a42443-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> National Institutes of Health</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Under the existing authority of the Public Health Service Act, the Director of the National Institutes of Health, acting through the Director of the National Institute on Deafness and Other Communication Disorders, shall for purposes of this section, continue a program of research and development on the efficacy of new screening techniques and technology, including clinical studies of screening methods, studies on efficacy of intervention, and related research.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a42444-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination and collaboration</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a42445-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Under the existing authority of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">42 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.], in carrying out programs under this section, the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and the Director of the National Institutes of Health shall collaborate and consult with other Federal agencies; State and local agencies, including those responsible for early intervention services pursuant to title XIX of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</ref> et seq.] (Medicaid Early and Periodic Screening, Diagnosis and Treatment Program); title XXI of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1397aa">42 U.S.C. 1397aa</ref> et seq.], (State Children’s Health Insurance Program); title V of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s701">42 U.S.C. 701</ref> et seq.] (Maternal and Child Health Block Grant Program); and part C of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1431">20 U.S.C. 1431</ref> et seq.]; consumer groups of and that serve individuals who are deaf and hard-of-hearing and their families; appropriate national medical and other health and education specialty organizations; persons who are deaf and hard-of-hearing and their families; other qualified professional personnel who are proficient in deaf or hard-of-hearing children’s language and who possess the specialized knowledge, skills, and attributes needed to serve deaf and hard-of-hearing newborns, infants, toddlers, children, and their families; third-party payers and managed care organizations; and related commercial industries.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a42446-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Policy development</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Under the existing authority of the Public Health Service Act, the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and the Director of the National Institutes of Health shall coordinate and collaborate on recommendations for policy development at the Federal and State levels and with the private sector, including consumer, medical and other health and education professional-based organizations, with respect to newborn and infant hearing screening, evaluation and intervention programs and systems.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a42447-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> State early detection, diagnosis, and intervention programs and systems; data collection</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Under the existing authority of the Public Health Service Act, the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration and the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shall coordinate and collaborate in assisting States to establish newborn and infant hearing screening, evaluation and intervention programs and systems under subsection (c) and to develop a data collection system under subsection (d).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a42448-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to preempt any State law.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a42449-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a4244a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Statewide newborn and infant hearing screening, evaluation and intervention programs and systems</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For the purpose of carrying out subsection (c) under the existing authority of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">42 U.S.C. 201</ref> et seq.], there are authorized to the Health Resources and Services Administration appropriations in the amount of $5,000,000 for fiscal year 2000, $8,000,000 for fiscal year 2001, and such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2002.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a4244b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Technical assistance, data management, and applied research; Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For the purpose of carrying out subsection (d)(1) under the existing authority of the Public Health Service Act, there are authorized to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, appropriations in the amount of $5,000,000 for fiscal year 2000, $7,000,000 for fiscal year 2001, and such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2002.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a4244c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–4a/g/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Technical assistance, data management, and applied research; National Institute on Deafness and Other Communication Disorders</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For the purpose of carrying out subsection (d)(2) under the existing authority of the Public Health Service Act, there are authorized to the National Institute on Deafness and Other Communication Disorders appropriations for such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2000 through 2002.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb4a4244d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/106/113/dB/s1000/a/4/tVI/s601">Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(4) [title VI, § 601]</ref>, <date date="1999-11-29">Nov. 29, 1999</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/113/1535">113 Stat. 1535</ref>, 1501A–276.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb4a4244e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb4a4244f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb4a42450-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Public Health Service Act, referred to in subsecs. (b) to (e) and (g), is <ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">act July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/58/682">58 Stat. 682</ref>, which is classified generally to this chapter (§ 201 et seq.). For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">section 201 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, referred to in subsecs. (c)(1) and (e)(1), is title VI of <ref href="/us/pl/91/230">Pub. L. 91–230</ref>, <date date="1970-04-13">Apr. 13, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/175">84 Stat. 175</ref>. Part C of the Act is classified generally to subchapter III (§ 1431 et seq.) of chapter 33 of Title 20, Education. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1400">section 1400 of Title 20</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Social Security Act, referred to in subsec. (e)(1), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/620">49 Stat. 620</ref>. Titles V, XIX, and XXI of the Act are classified generally to subchapters V (§ 701 et seq.), XIX (§ 1396 et seq.), and XXI (§ 1397aa et seq.), respectively, of chapter 7 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1305">section 1305 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb4a42451-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Departments of Labor, Health, and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2000, and not as part of the Public Health Service Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
