<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb4ab5001-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–15"><num value="247b–15">§ 247b–15.</num><heading> Surveillance and education regarding infections associated with illicit drug use and other risk factors</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4ab5002-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–15/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may (directly or through grants to public and nonprofit private entities) provide for programs for the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4ab5003-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–15/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> To cooperate with States and Indian tribes in implementing or maintaining a national system to determine the incidence of infections commonly associated with illicit drug use, such as viral hepatitis, human immunodeficiency virus, and infective endocarditis, and to assist the States in determining the prevalence of such infections, which may include the reporting of cases of such infections.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4ab5004-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–15/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> To identify, counsel, and offer testing to individuals who are at risk of infections described in paragraph (1) resulting from illicit drug use, receiving blood transfusions prior to July 1992, or other risk factors.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4ab5005-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–15/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> To provide appropriate referrals for counseling, testing, and medical treatment of individuals identified under paragraph (2) and to ensure, to the extent practicable, the provision of appropriate follow-up services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4ab5006-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–15/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> To develop and disseminate public information and education programs for the detection and control of infections described in paragraph (1), with priority given to high-risk populations as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4ab5007-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–15/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> To improve the education, training, and skills of health professionals in the detection and control of infections described in paragraph (1), including to improve coordination of treatment of substance use disorders and infectious diseases, with priority given to substance use disorder treatment providers, pediatricians and other primary care providers, obstetrician-gynecologists, and infectious disease clinicians, including HIV clinicians.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4ab5008-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–15/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Laboratory procedures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may (directly or through grants to public and nonprofit private entities) carry out programs to provide for improvements in the quality of clinical-laboratory procedures regarding infections described in subsection (a)(1).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4ab5009-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–15/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given that term in <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5304">section 5304 of title 25</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4ab500a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–15/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of carrying out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $40,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb4ab500b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title III, § 317N, as added <ref href="/us/pl/106/310/dA/tXVIII/s1801">Pub. L. 106–310, div. A, title XVIII, § 1801</ref>, <date date="2000-10-17">Oct. 17, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1152">114 Stat. 1152</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/115/271/tVII/s7141">Pub. L. 115–271, title VII, § 7141</ref>, <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4056">132 Stat. 4056</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/119/44/tI/s102">Pub. L. 119–44, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="2025-12-01">Dec. 1, 2025</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/139/670">139 Stat. 670</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb4ab500c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb4ab500d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb4ab500e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2025—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/119/44">Pub. L. 119–44</ref> substituted “fiscal years 2026 through 2030” for “fiscal years 2019 through 2023”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—<ref href="/us/pl/115/271">Pub. L. 115–271</ref> amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section related to surveillance and education regarding hepatitis C virus.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb4ab500f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb4ab5010-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study and Demonstration Projects Regarding Cases of Hepatitis C Among Certain Emergency Response Employees</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A]</ref>, title XVII, § 1704], <date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1654">114 Stat. 1654</ref>, 1654A–365, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/398/s1/dA">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Study Regarding Prevalence Among Certain Emergency Response Employees.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the ‘Secretary’), in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, shall conduct a study to determine—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> an estimate of the prevalence of hepatitis C among designated emergency response employees in the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the likely means through which such employees become infected with such disease in the course of performing their duties as such employees.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Designated emergency response employees</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this section, the term ‘designated emergency response employees’ means firefighters, paramedics, and emergency medical technicians who are employees or volunteers of units of local government.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Date certain for completion; report to congress</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall commence the study under paragraph (1) not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2000-10-30">Oct. 30, 2000</date>]. Not later than one year after such date, the Secretary shall complete the study and submit to the Congress a report describing the findings of the study.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Demonstration Projects Regarding Training and Treatment.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, shall make grants to qualifying local governments for the purpose of carrying out demonstration projects that (directly or through arrangements with nonprofit private entities) carry out each of the following activities:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Training designated emergency response employees in minimizing the risk of infection with hepatitis C in performing their duties as such employees.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> Testing such employees for infection with the disease.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> Treating the employees for the disease.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Qualifying local governments</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this section, the term ‘qualifying local government’ means a unit of local government whose population of designated emergency response employees has a prevalence of hepatitis C that is not less than 200 percent of the national average for the prevalence of such disease in such populations.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Confidentiality</inline>.—</heading><content>A grant may be made under paragraph (1) only if the qualifying local government involved agrees to ensure that information regarding the testing or treatment of designated emergency response employees pursuant to the grant is maintained confidentially in a manner not inconsistent with applicable law.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Evaluations</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall provide for an evaluation of each demonstration project under paragraph (1) in order to determine the extent to which the project has been effective in carry [sic] out the activities described in such paragraph.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to congress</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 180 days after the date on which all grants under paragraph (1) have been expended, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report providing—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> a summary of evaluations under paragraph (4); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the recommendations of the Secretary for administrative or legislative initiatives regarding the activities described in paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Authorization of Appropriations</inline>.—</heading><content>For the purpose of carrying out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Health and Human Services and the Department of Labor $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2001.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
