<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb4a694b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6"><num value="247b–6">§ 247b–6.</num><heading> National strategy for combating and eliminating tuberculosis</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may make grants to States, political subdivisions, and other public entities for preventive health service programs for the prevention, control, and elimination of tuberculosis.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Research and development; demonstration projects; education and training</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With respect to the prevention, treatment, control, and elimination of tuberculosis, the Secretary may, directly or through grants to public or nonprofit private entities, carry out the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4a694b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Research, with priority given to research and development concerning latent tuberculosis infection, strains of tuberculosis resistant to drugs, and research concerning cases of tuberculosis that affect certain populations at risk for tuberculosis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4a694b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Research and development and related activities to develop new tools for the elimination of tuberculosis, including drugs, diagnostics, vaccines, and public health interventions, such as directly observed therapy and non-pharmaceutical intervention, and methods to enhance detection and response to outbreaks of tuberculosis, including multidrug resistant tuberculosis. The Secretary is encouraged to give priority to programmatically relevant research so that new tools can be utilized in public health practice.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4a694ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Demonstration projects for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a694bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the development of regional capabilities to prevent, control, and eliminate tuberculosis and prevent multidrug resistant and extensively drug resistant strains of tuberculosis;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a694bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the intensification of efforts to reduce health disparities in the incidence of tuberculosis;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a694bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> the intensification of efforts to control tuberculosis along the United States-Mexico border and among United States-Mexico binational populations, including through expansion of the scope and number of programs that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4a694be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/b/3/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> detect and treat binational cases of tuberculosis; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4a694bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/b/3/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> treat high-risk cases of tuberculosis referred from Mexican health departments;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a694c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/b/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> the intensification of efforts to prevent, detect, and treat tuberculosis among foreign-born persons who are in the United States;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a694c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/b/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> the intensification of efforts to prevent, detect, and treat tuberculosis among populations and settings documented as having a high risk for tuberculosis; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a694c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/b/3/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> tuberculosis detection, control, and prevention.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4a694c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Public information and education activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4a694c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Education, training, clinical skills improvement activities, and workplace exposure prevention for health professionals, including allied health personnel and emergency response employees.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4a694c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> Support of Centers to carry out activities under paragraphs (1) through (4).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4a694c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> Collaboration with international organizations and foreign countries in carrying out such activities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4a694c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> Develop, enhance, and expand information technologies that support tuberculosis control including surveillance and database management systems with cross-jurisdictional capabilities, which shall conform to the standards and implementation specifications for such information technologies as recommended by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Cooperation with providers of primary health services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may make a grant under subsection (a) or (b) only if the applicant for the grant agrees that, in carrying out activities under the grant, the applicant will cooperate with public and nonprofit private providers of primary health services or substance abuse services, including entities receiving assistance under section 254b, 254b, or 256a of this title <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002047">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002047"><num>1</num> See References in Text notes below.</note> or under subchapter III–A or XVII.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Application for grant</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694ca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may make a grant under subsection (a) or (b) only if an application for the grant is submitted to the Secretary and the application, subject to paragraph (2), is in such form, is made in such manner, and contains such agreements, assurances, and information as the Secretary determines to be necessary to carry out the subsection involved.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Plan for prevention, control, and elimination</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may make a grant under subsection (a) only if the application under paragraph (1) contains a plan regarding the prevention, control, and elimination of tuberculosis in the geographic area with respect to which the grant is sought.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination of amount of nonfederal contributions</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/d/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Priority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In awarding grants under subsection (a) or (b), the Secretary shall give highest priority to an applicant that provides assurances that the applicant will contribute non-Federal funds to carry out activities under this section, which may be provided directly or through donations from public or private entities and may be in cash or in kind, including equipment or services.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694ce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/d/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal amounts not to be included as contributions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Amounts provided by the Federal Government, or services assisted or subsidized to any significant extent by the Federal Government, may not be included in determining the amount of non-Federal contributions as described in subparagraph (A).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694cf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Supplies and services in lieu of grant funds</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694d0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Upon the request of a grantee under subsection (a) or (b), the Secretary may, subject to paragraph (2), provide supplies, equipment, and services for the purpose of aiding the grantee in carrying out the subsection involved and, for such purpose, may detail to the State any officer or employee of the Department of Health and Human Services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Corresponding reduction in payments</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">With respect to a request described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall reduce the amount of payments under the grant involved by an amount equal to the costs of detailing personnel and the fair market value of any supplies, equipment, or services provided by the Secretary. The Secretary shall, for the payment of expenses incurred in complying with such request, expend the amounts withheld.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694d2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Advisory Council</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694d3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish an advisory council to be known as the Advisory Council for the Elimination of Tuberculosis (in this subsection referred to as the “Council”).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694d4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Council shall provide advice and recommendations regarding the elimination of tuberculosis to the Secretary. In addition, the Council shall, with respect to eliminating such disease, provide to the Secretary and other appropriate Federal officials advice on—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a694d5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> coordinating the activities of the Department of Health and Human Services and other Federal agencies that relate to the disease, including activities under subsection (b);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a694d6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> responding rapidly and effectively to emerging issues in tuberculosis; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a694d7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> efficiently utilizing the Federal resources involved.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694d8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Comprehensive plan</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694d9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In carrying out paragraph (2), the Council shall make or update recommendations on the development, revision, and implementation of a comprehensive plan to eliminate tuberculosis in the United States.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694da-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In carrying out subparagraph (A), the Council may consult with appropriate public and private entities, which may, subject to the direction or discretion of the Secretary, include—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4a694db-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> individuals who are scientists, physicians, laboratorians, and other health professionals, who are not officers or employees of the Federal Government and who represent the disciplines relevant to tuberculosis elimination;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4a694dc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> members of public-private partnerships or private entities established to address the elimination of tuberculosis;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4a694dd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> members of national and international nongovernmental organizations whose purpose is to eliminate tuberculosis;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4a694de-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/3/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> members from the general public who are knowledgeable with respect to tuberculosis elimination including individuals who have or have had tuberculosis; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4a694df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/3/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> scientists, physicians, laboratorians, and other health professionals who reside in a foreign country with a substantial incidence or prevalence of tuberculosis, and who represent the specialties and disciplines relevant to the research under consideration.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694e0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain components of plan</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In carrying out subparagraph (A), the Council shall, subject to the direction or discretion of the Secretary—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4a694e1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/3/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> consider recommendations for the involvement of the United States in continuing global and cross-border tuberculosis control activities in countries where a high incidence of tuberculosis directly affects the United States; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4a694e2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/3/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> review the extent to which progress has been made toward eliminating tuberculosis.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694e3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Biennial report</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694e4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/4/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Council shall submit a biennial report to the Secretary, as determined necessary by the Secretary, on the activities carried under this section. Each such report shall include the opinion of the Council on the extent to which its recommendations regarding the elimination of tuberculosis have been implemented, including with respect to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4a694e5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> activities under subsection (b); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4a694e6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the national plan referred to in paragraph (3).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694e7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/4/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Public</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Secretary shall make a report submitted under subparagraph (A) public.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694e8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Composition</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Council shall be composed of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a694e9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> ex officio representatives from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the National Institutes of Health, the United States Agency for International Development, the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, the Health Resources and Services Administration, the United States-Mexico Border Health Commission, and other Federal departments and agencies that carry out significant activities related to tuberculosis;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a694ea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> State and local tuberculosis control and public health officials;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a694eb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> individuals who are scientists, physicians, laboratorians, and other health professionals who represent disciplines relevant to tuberculosis elimination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a694ec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/5/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> members of national and international nongovernmental organizations established to address the elimination of tuberculosis.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694ed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> Staff, information, and other assistance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall provide to the Council such staff, information, and other assistance as may be necessary to carry out the duties of the Council.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694ee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal Tuberculosis Task Force</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694ef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Federal Tuberculosis Task Force (in this subsection referred to as the “Task Force”) shall provide to the Secretary and other appropriate Federal officials advice on research into new tools under subsection (b)(2), including advice regarding the efficient utilization of the Federal resources involved.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Comprehensive plan for new tools development</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Task Force shall make recommendations on the development of a comprehensive plan for the creation of new tools for the elimination of tuberculosis, including drugs, diagnostics, and vaccines.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/g/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In developing the comprehensive plan under paragraph (1),<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002048">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002048"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be “paragraph (2),”.</note> the Task Force shall consult with external parties including representatives from groups such as—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a694f2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/g/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> scientists, physicians, laboratorians, and other health professionals who represent the specialties and disciplines relevant to the research under consideration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a694f3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/g/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> members from public-private partnerships, private entities, or foundations (or both) engaged in activities relevant to research under consideration;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a694f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/g/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> members of national and international nongovernmental organizations established to address tuberculosis elimination;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a694f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/g/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> members from the general public who are knowledgeable with respect to tuberculosis including individuals who have or have had tuberculosis; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4a694f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/g/3/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> scientists, physicians, laboratorians, and other health professionals who reside in a foreign country with a substantial incidence or prevalence of tuberculosis, and who represent the specialties and disciplines relevant to the research under consideration.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/h/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> General program</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/h/1/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For the purpose of carrying out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $200,000,000 for fiscal year 2009, $210,000,000 for fiscal year 2010, $220,500,000 for fiscal year 2011, $231,525,000 for fiscal year 2012, and $243,101,250 for fiscal year 2013.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/h/1/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Reservation for emergency grants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Of the amounts appropriated under subparagraph (A) for a fiscal year, the Secretary may reserve not more than 25 percent for emergency grants under subsection (a) for any geographic area, State, political subdivision of a State, or other public entity in which there is, relative to other areas, a substantial number of cases of tuberculosis, multidrug resistant tuberculosis, or extensively drug resistant tuberculosis or a substantial rate of increase in such cases.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/h/1/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Priority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In allocating amounts appropriated under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall give priority to allocating such amounts for grants under subsection (a).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694fc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/h/1/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Allocation of funds</heading><clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694fd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/h/1/D/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement of formula</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">Of the amounts appropriated under subparagraph (A), not reserved under subparagraph (B), and allocated by the Secretary for grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall distribute a portion of such amounts to grantees under subsection (a) on the basis of a formula.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694fe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/h/1/D/ii"><num value="ii" class="bold">(ii)</num><heading class="bold"> Relevant factors</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">The formula developed by the Secretary under clause (i) shall take into account the level of tuberculosis morbidity and case complexity in the respective geographic area and may consider other factors relevant to tuberculosis in such area.</p>
</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I77" class="indent5 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a694ff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/h/1/D/iii"><num value="iii" class="bold">(iii)</num><heading class="bold"> No change to formula required</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3">This subparagraph does not require the Secretary to modify the formula that was used by the Secretary to distribute funds to grantees under subsection (a) for fiscal year 2009.</p>
</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4a69500-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/h/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The authorization of appropriations established in paragraph (1) for a fiscal year is effective only if the amount appropriated under such paragraph for such year equals or exceeds the amount appropriated to carry out this section for fiscal year 2009.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb4a69501-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title III, § 317E, as added <ref href="/us/pl/103/183/tIII/s301/a">Pub. L. 103–183, title III, § 301(a)</ref>, <date date="1993-12-14">Dec. 14, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/2233">107 Stat. 2233</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/105/392/tIV">Pub. L. 105–392, title IV</ref>, §§ 401(b)(1), 405, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3587">112 Stat. 3587</ref>, 3588; <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/tVI/s601/a">Pub. L. 107–251, title VI, § 601(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-10-26">Oct. 26, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1664">116 Stat. 1664</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/163/s2/m/1">Pub. L. 108–163, § 2(m)(1)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-06">Dec. 6, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2023">117 Stat. 2023</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/392/tI">Pub. L. 110–392, title I</ref>, §§ 101, 111(a), (c), 131, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4196">122 Stat. 4196</ref>, 4197, 4199, 4200.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb4a69502-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb4a69503-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb4a69504-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254b">section 254b of this title</ref> the first place appearing, referred to in subsec. (c), was in the original a reference to section 329, meaning section 329 of act <date date="1944-07-01">July 1, 1944</date>, which was omitted in the general amendment of subpart I (§ 254b et seq.) of part D of this subchapter by <ref href="/us/pl/104/299/s2">Pub. L. 104–299, § 2</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3626">110 Stat. 3626</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s256a">Section 256a of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (c), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/104/299/s4/a/3">Pub. L. 104–299, § 4(a)(3)</ref>, <date date="1996-10-11">Oct. 11, 1996</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/110/3645">110 Stat. 3645</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb4a69505-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—<ref href="/us/pl/110/392/s101/1">Pub. L. 110–392, § 101(1)</ref>, substituted “National strategy for combating and eliminating tuberculosis” for “Preventive health services regarding tuberculosis” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/110/392/s101/2">Pub. L. 110–392, § 101(2)</ref>, amended subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (b) related to research, demonstration projects, education, and training for the purpose of prevention, control, and elimination of tuberculosis.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/110/392/s101/3">Pub. L. 110–392, § 101(3)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2) to (6). <ref href="/us/pl/110/392/s111/a">Pub. L. 110–392, § 111(a)</ref>, added pars. (2) to (5), redesignated former par. (5) as (6), and struck out former pars. (2) to (4) which related to general duties, certain activities, and composition of the Council, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/110/392/s111/c/2">Pub. L. 110–392, § 111(c)(2)</ref>, added subsec. (g). Former subsec. (g) redesignated (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/110/392/s131">Pub. L. 110–392, § 131</ref>, added subsec. (h) and struck out former subsec. (h) which authorized appropriations for grants, research, demonstration projects, education, and training for fiscal years 1994 to 2002.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/110/392/s111/c/1">Pub. L. 110–392, § 111(c)(1)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (g) as (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/108/163">Pub. L. 108–163</ref> substituted “254b” for “254c, 254b(h)” before “, or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251">Pub. L. 107–251</ref> substituted “254b(h)” for “256”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (g)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/105/392/s405/1/A">Pub. L. 105–392, § 405(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “2002” for “1998”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/105/392/s405/1/B">Pub. L. 105–392, § 405(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “25 percent” for “$50,000,000”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/392/s405/2">Pub. L. 105–392, § 405(2)</ref>, substituted “2002” for “1998”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/105/392/s401/b/1">Pub. L. 105–392, § 401(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “carrying out subsection (b)” for “making grants under subsection (b)”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb4a69506-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb4a69507-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2003 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/163">Pub. L. 108–163</ref> deemed to have taken effect immediately after the enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/107/251">Pub. L. 107–251</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/163/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 108–163</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s233">section 233 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb4a69508-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1998 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/105/392/s401/b/1">section 401(b)(1) of Pub. L. 105–392</ref> deemed to have taken effect immediately after enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/103/183">Pub. L. 103–183</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/105/392/s401/e">section 401(e) of Pub. L. 105–392</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s242m">section 242m of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb4a69509-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Construction of 2008 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/110/392/tI/s111/b">Pub. L. 110–392, title I, § 111(b)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/4199">122 Stat. 4199</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/110/392/tI/s111/b">“With respect to the advisory council under section 317E(f) of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s247b–6/f">42 U.S.C. 247b–6(f)</ref>], the amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] may not be construed as terminating the membership on such council of any individual serving as such a member as of the day before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2008-10-13">Oct. 13, 2008</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb4a6950a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Advisory Councils</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Advisory councils established after <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on the date of their establishment, unless, in the case of a council established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such council is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a council established by Congress, its duration is otherwise provided by law. See sections 1001(2) and 1013 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/93/641/s6">Pub. L. 93–641, § 6</ref>, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2275">88 Stat. 2275</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s217a">section 217a of this title</ref>, provided that an advisory committee established pursuant to the Public Health Service Act shall terminate at such time as may be specifically prescribed by an Act of Congress enacted after <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
