<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb4ebb44e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254c–9"><num value="254c–9">§ 254c–9.</num><heading> Establishment of program of grants</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4ebb44f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254c–9/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall in accordance with sections 254c–9 to 254c–13 of this title make grants to provide for projects for the establishment, operation, and coordination of effective and cost-efficient systems for the delivery of essential services to individuals with lupus and their families.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4ebb450-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254c–9/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Recipients of grants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A grant under subsection (a) may be made to an entity only if the entity is a public or nonprofit private entity, which may include a State or local government; a public or nonprofit private hospital, community-based organization, hospice, ambulatory care facility, community health center, migrant health center, or homeless health center; or other appropriate public or nonprofit private entity.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4ebb451-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254c–9/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Certain activities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To the extent practicable and appropriate, the Secretary shall ensure that projects under subsection (a) provide services for the diagnosis and disease management of lupus. Activities that the Secretary may authorize for such projects may also include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4ebb452-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254c–9/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Delivering or enhancing outpatient, ambulatory, and home-based health and support services, including case management and comprehensive treatment services, for individuals with lupus; and delivering or enhancing support services for their families.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4ebb453-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254c–9/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Delivering or enhancing inpatient care management services that prevent unnecessary hospitalization or that expedite discharge, as medically appropriate, from inpatient facilities of individuals with lupus.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4ebb454-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254c–9/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Improving the quality, availability, and organization of health care and support services (including transportation services, attendant care, homemaker services, day or respite care, and providing counseling on financial assistance and insurance) for individuals with lupus and support services for their families.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4ebb455-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254c–9/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Integration with other programs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To the extent practicable and appropriate, the Secretary shall integrate the program under sections 254c–9 to 254c–13 of this title with other grant programs carried out by the Secretary, including the program under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254b">section 254b of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb4ebb456-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/106/505/tV/s521">Pub. L. 106–505, title V, § 521</ref>, <date date="2000-11-13">Nov. 13, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2343">114 Stat. 2343</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb4ebb457-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb4ebb458-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb4ebb459-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Lupus Research and Care Amendments of 2000, and also as part of the Public Health Improvement Act, and not as part of the Public Health Service Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
