<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb4f2dff9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f"><num value="254f">§ 254f.</num><heading> Corps personnel</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f2dffa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Conditions necessary for assignment of Corps personnel to area; contents of application for assignment; assignment to particular facility; approval of applications</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f2dffb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary may assign members of the Corps to provide, under regulations promulgated by the Secretary, health services in or to a health professional shortage area during the assignment period only if—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f2dffc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a public or private entity, which is located or has a demonstrated interest in such area makes application to the Secretary for such assignment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f2dffd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> such application has been approved by the Secretary;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f2dffe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the entity agrees to comply with the requirements of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254g">section 254g of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f2dfff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><chapeau> the Secretary has (i) conducted an evaluation of the need and demand for health manpower for the area, the intended use of Corps members to be assigned to the area, community support for the assignment of Corps members to the area, the area’s efforts to secure health manpower for the area, and the fiscal management capability of the entity to which Corps members would be assigned and (ii) on the basis of such evaluation has determined that—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f2e000-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/a/1/D/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> there is a need and demand for health manpower for the area;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f2e001-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/a/1/D/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> there has been appropriate and efficient use of any Corps members assigned to the entity for the area;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f2e002-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/a/1/D/III"><num value="III">(III)</num><content> there is general community support for the assignment of Corps members to the entity;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f2e003-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/a/1/D/IV"><num value="IV">(IV)</num><content> the area has made unsuccessful efforts to secure health manpower for the area;</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f2e004-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/a/1/D/V"><num value="V">(V)</num><content> there is a reasonable prospect of sound fiscal management, including efficient collection of fee-for-service, third-party, and other appropriate funds, by the entity with respect to Corps members assigned to such entity; and</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f2e005-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/a/1/D/VI"><num value="VI">(VI)</num><content> the entity demonstrates willingness to support or facilitate mentorship, professional development, and training opportunities for Corps members.</content>
</subclause>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">An application for assignment of a Corps member to a health professional shortage area shall include a demonstration by the applicant that the area or population group to be served by the applicant has a shortage of personal health services and that the Corps member will be located so that the member will provide services to the greatest number of persons residing in such area or included in such population group. Such a demonstration shall be made on the basis of the criteria prescribed by the Secretary under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254e/b">section 254e(b) of this title</ref> and on additional criteria which the Secretary shall prescribe to determine if the area or population group to be served by the applicant has a shortage of personal health services.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f2e006-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Corps members may be assigned to a Federal health care facility, but only upon the request of the head of the department or agency of which such facility is a part.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f2e007-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In approving applications for assignment of members of the Corps the Secretary shall not discriminate against applications from entities which are not receiving Federal financial assistance under this chapter. In approving such applications, the Secretary shall give preference to applications in which a nonprofit entity or public entity shall provide a site to which Corps members may be assigned.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f2e008-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Corps member income assurances; grants respecting sufficiency of financial resources</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f2e009-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary may not approve an application for the assignment of a member of the Corps described in subparagraph (C) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254d/a/1">section 254d(a)(1) of this title</ref> to an entity unless the application of the entity contains assurances satisfactory to the Secretary that the entity (A) has sufficient financial resources to provide the member of the Corps with an income of not less than the income to which the member would be entitled if the member was a member described in subparagraph (B) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254d/a/1">section 254d(a)(1) of this title</ref>, or (B) would have such financial resources if a grant was made to the entity under paragraph (2).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f2e00a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f2e00b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> If in approving an application of an entity for the assignment of a member of the Corps described in subparagraph (C) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254d/a/1">section 254d(a)(1) of this title</ref> the Secretary determines that the entity does not have sufficient financial resources to provide the member of the Corps with an income of not less than the income to which the member would be entitled if the member was a member described in subparagraph (B) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254d/a/1">section 254d(a)(1) of this title</ref>, the Secretary may make a grant to the entity to assure that the member of the Corps assigned to it will receive during the period of assignment to the entity such an income.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f2e00c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The amount of any grant under subparagraph (A) shall be determined by the Secretary. Payments under such a grant may be made in advance or by way of reimbursement, and at such intervals and on such conditions, as the Secretary finds necessary. No grant may be made unless an application therefor is submitted to and approved by the Secretary. Such an application shall be in such form, submitted in such manner, and contain such information, as the Secretary shall by regulation prescribe.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f2e00d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Assignment of members without regard to ability of area to pay for services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall assign Corps members to entities in health professional shortage areas without regard to the ability of the individuals in such areas, population groups, medical facilities, or other public facilities to pay for such services.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f2e00e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Entities entitled to aid; forms of assistance; coordination of efforts; agreements for assignment of Corps members; qualified entity</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f2e00f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Secretary may provide technical assistance to a public or private entity which is located in a health professional shortage area and which desires to make an application under this section for assignment of a Corps member to such area. Assistance provided under this paragraph may include assistance to an entity in (A) analyzing the potential use of health professions personnel in defined health services delivery areas by the residents of such areas, (B) determining the need for such personnel in such areas, (C) determining the extent to which such areas will have a financial base to support the practice of such personnel and the extent to which additional financial resources are needed to adequately support the practice, (D) determining the types of inpatient and other health services that should be provided by such personnel in such areas, and (E) developing long-term plans for addressing health professional shortages and improving access to health care. The Secretary shall encourage entities that receive technical assistance under this paragraph to communicate with other communities, State Offices of Rural Health, State Primary Care Associations and Offices, and other entities concerned with site development and community needs assessment.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f2e010-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary may provide, to public and private entities which are located in a health professional shortage area to which area a Corps member has been assigned, technical assistance to assist in the retention of such member in such area after the completion of such member’s assignment to the area.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f2e011-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The Secretary may provide, to health professional shortage areas to which no Corps member has been assigned, (A) technical assistance to assist in the recruitment of health manpower for such areas, and (B) current information on public and private programs which provide assistance in the securing of health manpower.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f2e012-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f2e013-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/d/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall undertake to demonstrate the improvements that can be made in the assignment of members of the Corps to health professional shortage areas and in the delivery of health care by Corps members in such areas through coordination with States, political subdivisions of States, agencies of States and political subdivisions, and other public and private entities which have expertise in the planning, development, and operation of centers for the delivery of primary health care. In carrying out this subparagraph, the Secretary shall enter into agreements with qualified entities which provide that if—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f2e014-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/d/4/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the entity places in effect a program for the planning, development, and operation of centers for the delivery of primary health care in health professional shortage areas which reasonably addresses the need for such care in such areas, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f2e015-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/d/4/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> under the program the entity will perform the functions described in subparagraph (B),</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Secretary will assign under this section members of the Corps in accordance with the program.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f2e016-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/d/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term “qualified entity” means a State, political subdivision of a State, an agency of a State or political subdivision, or other public or private entity operating solely within one State, which the Secretary determines is able—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f2e017-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/d/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to analyze the potential use of health professions personnel in defined health services delivery areas by the residents of such areas;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f2e018-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/d/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to determine the need for such personnel in such areas and to recruit, select, and retain health professions personnel (including members of the National Health Service Corps) to meet such need;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f2e019-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/d/4/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> to determine the extent to which such areas will have a financial base to support the practice of such personnel and the extent to which additional financial resources are needed to adequately support the practice;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f2e01a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/d/4/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> to determine the types of inpatient and other health services that should be provided by such personnel in such areas;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f2e01b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/d/4/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><content> to assist such personnel in the development of their clinical practice and fee schedules and in the management of their practice;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f2e01c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/d/4/B/vi"><num value="vi">(vi)</num><content> to assist in the planning and development of facilities for the delivery of primary health care; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f2e01d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/d/4/B/vii"><num value="vii">(vii)</num><content> to assist in establishing the governing bodies of centers for the delivery of such care and to assist such bodies in defining and carrying out their responsibilities.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f2e01e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Practice within State by Corps member</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other law, any member of the Corps licensed to practice medicine, osteopathic medicine, dentistry, or any other health profession in any State shall, while serving in the Corps, be allowed to practice such profession in any State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb4f2e01f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title III, § 333, as added <ref href="/us/pl/94/484/tIV/s407/b/3">Pub. L. 94–484, title IV, § 407(b)(3)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2272">90 Stat. 2272</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXVII/s2703">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXVII, § 2703</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/904">95 Stat. 904</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/177/tIII">Pub. L. 100–177, title III</ref>, §§ 303, 304, <date date="1987-12-01">Dec. 1, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1004">101 Stat. 1004</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/607/tVI/s629/a/2">Pub. L. 100–607, title VI, § 629(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-04">Nov. 4, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3146">102 Stat. 3146</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/tI/s103">Pub. L. 101–597, title I, § 103</ref>, title IV, § 401(b)[(a)], <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3015">104 Stat. 3015</ref>, 3035; <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/tIII/s303">Pub. L. 107–251, title III, § 303</ref>, <date date="2002-10-26">Oct. 26, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1645">116 Stat. 1645</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/163/s2/g">Pub. L. 108–163, § 2(g)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-06">Dec. 6, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2022">117 Stat. 2022</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/110/355/s3/c">Pub. L. 110–355, § 3(c)</ref>, <date date="2008-10-08">Oct. 8, 2008</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/122/3993">122 Stat. 3993</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb4f2e020-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb4f2e021-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb4f2e022-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2008—Subsec. (a)(1)(D)(ii)(VI). <ref href="/us/pl/110/355">Pub. L. 110–355</ref> added subcl. (VI).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (a)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/108/163">Pub. L. 108–163</ref> realigned margin.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s303/1/A/i">Pub. L. 107–251, § 303(1)(A)(i)</ref>, struck out “(specified in the agreement described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254g">section 254g of this title</ref>)” after “assignment period” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s303/1/A/ii">Pub. L. 107–251, § 303(1)(A)(ii)</ref>, struck out “nonprofit” before “private entity”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s303/1/A/iii">Pub. L. 107–251, § 303(1)(A)(iii)</ref>, added subpar. (C) and struck out former subpar. (C) which read as follows: “an agreement has been entered into between the entity which has applied and the Secretary, in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254g">section 254g of this title</ref>; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s303/1/B">Pub. L. 107–251, § 303(1)(B)</ref>, inserted at end “In approving such applications, the Secretary shall give preference to applications in which a nonprofit entity or public entity shall provide a site to which Corps members may be assigned.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s303/2">Pub. L. 107–251, § 303(2)</ref>, struck out “nonprofit” before “private entity” in first sentence, added cl. (E), and inserted at end “The Secretary shall encourage entities that receive technical assistance under this paragraph to communicate with other communities, State Offices of Rural Health, State Primary Care Associations and Offices, and other entities concerned with site development and community needs assessment.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s303/2/A">Pub. L. 107–251, § 303(2)(A)</ref>, struck out “nonprofit” before “private entities”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s303/2/A">Pub. L. 107–251, § 303(2)(A)</ref>, struck out “nonprofit” before “private entities” in introductory provisions of subpar. (A) and before “private entity” in introductory provisions of subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s401/b">Pub. L. 101–597, § 401(b)[(a)]</ref>, substituted reference to health professional shortage area for reference to health manpower shortage area in introductory and closing provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1)(D)(ii)(II). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s103/a">Pub. L. 101–597, § 103(a)</ref>, substituted “has been” and “any Corps” for “will be” and “Corps”, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s103/b">Pub. L. 101–597, § 103(b)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (d) as (b) and struck out former subsec. (b) which related to approval of application for assignment of Corps personnel subject to review and comment on application by health service agencies in designated area.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s401/b">Pub. L. 101–597, § 401(b)[(a)]</ref>, substituted reference to health professional shortage area for reference to health manpower shortage area.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s103/b">Pub. L. 101–597, § 103(b)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (e) as (c) and struck out former subsec. (c) which related to applications, consideration and approval by Secretary, priorities, cooperation with Corps members, and comments by health professionals and societies in designated areas.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s401/b">Pub. L. 101–597, § 401(b)[(a)]</ref>, substituted reference to health professional shortage area for reference to health manpower shortage area wherever appearing in pars. (1) to (4)(A)(i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s103/b/2">Pub. L. 101–597, § 103(b)(2)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (g) as (d). Former subsec. (d) redesignated (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s103/b/2">Pub. L. 101–597, § 103(b)(2)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (i) as (e). Former subsec. (e) redesignated (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s103/b/1">Pub. L. 101–597, § 103(b)(1)</ref>, struck out subsec. (f) which provided for selection of Corps members for assignment upon basis of characteristics.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s103/b/2">Pub. L. 101–597, § 103(b)(2)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (g) as (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s103/b/1">Pub. L. 101–597, § 103(b)(1)</ref>, struck out subsec. (h) which related to study and contracts for study of methods of assignments of Corps members.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s103/b/2">Pub. L. 101–597, § 103(b)(2)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (i) as (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (j), (k). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s103/b/1">Pub. L. 101–597, § 103(b)(1)</ref>, struck out subsecs. (j) and (k) which provided for placement of physicians in medically underserved areas and assignment of family physicians, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/100/607">Pub. L. 100–607</ref> substituted “osteopathic medicine” for “osteopathy”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/100/177/s303">Pub. L. 100–177, § 303</ref>, added subsec. (j).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/100/177/s304">Pub. L. 100–177, § 304</ref>, added subsec. (k).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2703/a">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2703(a)</ref>, (b), amended par. (1)(D) generally and, among changes, made numerous changes in nomenclature, inserted at end of par. (1) provisions respecting application, and added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2703/c">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2703(c)</ref>, struck out par. (2) which related to special considerations, and redesignated pars. (3) and (4) as (2) and (3), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (d) to (f). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2703/d">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2703(d)</ref>, added subsec. (d) and redesignated former subsecs. (d), (e), and (f) as (e), (f), and (g), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2703/d">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2703(d)</ref>, (e), redesignated former subsec. (f) as (g) and substituted “may” for “shall” in pars. (1) to (3), inserted provisions respecting health professions personnel in par. (1), added par. (4), and struck out requirement respecting demonstrated interest in pars. (1) and (2). Former subsec. (g) redesignated (h).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (h). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2703/d">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2703(d)</ref>, (f), redesignated former subsec. (g) as (h) and directed that “may” be substituted for “shall” which was executed by substituting “may” for “shall” in two places preceding par. (1). Former subsec. (h) redesignated (i).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2703/d">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2703(d)</ref>, (g), redesignated former subsec. (h) as (i) and inserted reference to other health profession.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb4f2e023-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb4f2e024-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2003 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/163">Pub. L. 108–163</ref> deemed to have taken effect immediately after the enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/107/251">Pub. L. 107–251</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/163/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 108–163</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s233">section 233 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb4f2e025-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXVII/s2703/d">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXVII, § 2703(d)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/905">95 Stat. 905</ref>, provided that the amendment made by that section is effective <date date="1981-10-01">Oct. 1, 1981</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb4f2e026-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Flexibility for Members of National Health Service Corps During Emergency Period</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/116/136/dA/tIII/s3216">Pub. L. 116–136, div. A, title III, § 3216</ref>, <date date="2020-03-27">Mar. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/375">134 Stat. 375</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/116/136/dA/tIII/s3216">“During the public health emergency declared by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under section 319 of the Public Health Service Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s247d">42 U.S.C. 247d</ref>) on <date date="2020-01-31">January 31, 2020</date>, with respect to COVID–19, the Secretary may, notwithstanding section 333 of the Public Health Service Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254f">42 U.S.C. 254f</ref>), assign members of the National Health Service Corps, with the voluntary agreement of such corps members, to provide such health services at such places, and for such number of hours, as the Secretary determines necessary to respond to such emergency, provided that such places are within a reasonable distance of the site to which such members were originally assigned, and the total number of hours required are the same as were required of such members prior to the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2020-03-27">Mar. 27, 2020</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
