<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb4f2e027-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1"><num value="254f–1">§ 254f–1.</num><heading> Priorities in assignment of Corps personnel</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f2e028-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In approving applications made under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254f">section 254f of this title</ref> for the assignment of Corps members, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f2e029-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> give priority to any such application that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f2e02a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> is made regarding the provision of primary health services to a health professional shortage area with the greatest such shortage; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f2e02b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> is made by an entity that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4f2e02c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/a/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> serves a health professional shortage area described in subparagraph (A);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4f2e02d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/a/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> coordinates the delivery of primary health services with related health and social services;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4f2e02e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/a/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> has a documented record of sound fiscal management; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4f2e02f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/a/1/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> will experience a negative impact on its capacity to provide primary health services if a Corps member is not assigned to the entity;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f2e030-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> with respect to the geographic area in which the health professional shortage area is located, take into consideration the willingness of individuals in the geographic area, and of the appropriate governmental agencies or health entities in the area, to assist and cooperate with the Corps in providing effective primary health services; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f2e031-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> take into consideration comments of medical, osteopathic, dental, or other health professional societies whose members deliver services to the health professional shortage area, or if no such societies exist, comments of physicians, dentists, or other health professionals delivering services to the area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f2e032-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of criteria for determining priorities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f2e033-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall establish criteria specifying the manner in which the Secretary makes a determination under subsection (a)(1)(A) of the health professional shortage areas with the greatest such shortages.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f2e034-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Publication of criteria</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The criteria required in paragraph (1) shall be published in the Federal Register not later than <date date="1991-07-01">July 1, 1991</date>. Any revisions made in the criteria by the Secretary shall be effective upon publication in the Federal Register.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f2e035-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Notifications regarding priorities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f2e036-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Proposed list</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall prepare and publish a proposed list of health professional shortage areas and entities that would receive priority under subsection (a)(1) in the assignment of Corps members. The list shall contain the information described in paragraph (2), and the relative scores and relative priorities of the entities submitting applications under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254f">section 254f of this title</ref>, in a proposed format. All such entities shall have 30 days after the date of publication of the list to provide additional data and information in support of inclusion on the list or in support of a higher priority determination and the Secretary shall reasonably consider such data and information in preparing the final list under paragraph (2).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f2e037-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Preparation of list for applicable period</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For the purpose of carrying out paragraph (3), the Secretary shall prepare and, as appropriate, update a list of health professional shortage areas and entities that are receiving priority under subsection (a)(1) in the assignment of Corps members. Such list—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f2e038-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> shall include a specification, for each such health professional shortage area, of the entities for which the Secretary has provided an authorization to receive assignments of Corps members in the event that Corps members are available for the assignments; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f2e039-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> shall, of the entities for which an authorization described in subparagraph (A) has been provided, specify—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4f2e03a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/c/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the entities provided such an authorization for the assignment of Corps members who are participating in the Scholarship Program;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4f2e03b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/c/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the entities provided such an authorization for the assignment of Corps members who are participating in the Loan Repayment Program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4f2e03c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/c/2/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the entities provided such an authorization for the assignment of Corps members who have become Corps members other than pursuant to contractual obligations under the Scholarship or Loan Repayment Programs.</content>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I32" class="indent2 firstIndent0">The Secretary may set forth such specifications by medical specialty.</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f2e03d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Notification of affected parties</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f2e03e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/c/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Entities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Not later than 30 days after the Secretary has added to a list under paragraph (2) an entity specified as described in subparagraph (A) of such paragraph, the Secretary shall notify such entity that the entity has been provided an authorization to receive assignments of Corps members in the event that Corps members are available for the assignments.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f2e03f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/c/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Individuals</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">In the case of an individual obligated to provide service under the Scholarship Program, not later than 3 months before the date described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254m/b/5">section 254m(b)(5) of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall provide to such individual the names of each of the entities specified as described in paragraph (2)(B)(i) that is appropriate for the individual’s medical specialty and discipline.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f2e040-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Revisions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">If the Secretary proposes to make a revision in the list under paragraph (2), and the revision would adversely alter the status of an entity with respect to the list, the Secretary shall notify the entity of the revision. Any entity adversely affected by such a revision shall be notified in writing by the Secretary of the reasons for the revision and shall have 30 days from such notification to file a written appeal of the determination involved which shall be reasonably considered by the Secretary before the revision to the list becomes final. The revision to the list shall be effective with respect to assignment of Corps members beginning on the date that the revision becomes final.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f2e041-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation on number of entities offered as assignment choices in Scholarship Program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f2e042-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination of available Corps members</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">By April 1 of each calendar year, the Secretary shall determine the number of participants in the Scholarship Program who will be available for assignments under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254f">section 254f of this title</ref> during the program year beginning on July 1 of that calendar year.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f2e043-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Determination of number of entities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">At all times during a program year, the number of entities specified under subsection (c)(2)(B)(i) shall be—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f2e044-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> not less than the number of participants determined with respect to that program year under paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f2e045-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> not greater than twice the number of participants determined with respect to that program year under paragraph (1).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb4f2e046-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title III, § 333A, as added and amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/tI/s104">Pub. L. 101–597, title I, § 104</ref>, title IV, § 401(b)[(a)], <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3015">104 Stat. 3015</ref>, 3035; <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/tIII/s304">Pub. L. 107–251, title III, § 304</ref>, <date date="2002-10-26">Oct. 26, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1646">116 Stat. 1646</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/163/s2/h">Pub. L. 108–163, § 2(h)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-06">Dec. 6, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2022">117 Stat. 2022</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb4f2e047-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb4f2e048-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb4f2e049-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/108/163">Pub. L. 108–163</ref> substituted “30 days from such notification” for “30 days”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s304/1">Pub. L. 107–251, § 304(1)</ref>, struck out “, as determined in accordance with subsection (b) of this section” after “such shortage”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s304/2">Pub. L. 107–251, § 304(2)</ref>, (7), redesignated subsec. (c) as (b) and struck out heading and text of former subsec. (b). Text read as follows: “In making a determination under subsection (a)(1)(A) of this section of the health professional shortage areas with the greatest such shortages, the Secretary may consider only the following factors:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) The ratio of available health manpower to the number of individuals in the area or population group involved, or served by the medical facility or other public facility involved.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) Indicators of need as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(A) The rate of low birthweight births.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(B) The rate of infant mortality.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(C) The rate of poverty.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(D) Access to primary health services, taking into account the distance to such services.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s304/7">Pub. L. 107–251, § 304(7)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (d) as (c). Former subsec. (c) redesignated (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s304/3">Pub. L. 107–251, § 304(3)</ref>, struck out second sentence, which read as follows: “Such criteria shall specify the manner in which the factors described in subsection (b) of this section are implemented regarding such a determination.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s304/7">Pub. L. 107–251, § 304(7)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (e) as (d). Former subsec. (d) redesignated (c).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s304/4/B">Pub. L. 107–251, § 304(4)(B)</ref>, added par. (1). Former par. (1) redesignated (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s304/4/C">Pub. L. 107–251, § 304(4)(C)</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted “paragraph (3)” for “paragraph (2)” and “prepare and, as appropriate, update a list of health professional shortage areas and entities” for “prepare a list of health professional shortage areas” and struck out “for the period applicable under subsection (f) of this section” after “Corps members”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s304/4/A">Pub. L. 107–251, § 304(4)(A)</ref>, redesignated par. (1) as (2). Former par. (2) redesignated (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s304/4/D">Pub. L. 107–251, § 304(4)(D)</ref>, added par. (3) and struck out heading and text of former par. (3). Text read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(A) Not later than 30 days after the preparation of each list under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall notify entities specified for purposes of subparagraph (A) of such paragraph of the fact that the entities have been provided an authorization to receive assignments of Corps members in the event that Corps members are available for the assignments.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) In the case of individuals with respect to whom a period of obligated service under the Scholarship Program will begin during the period under subsection (f) of this section for which a list under paragraph (1) is prepared, the Secretary shall, not later than 30 days after the preparation of each such list, provide to such individuals the names of each of the entities specified for purposes of paragraph (1)(B)(i) that is appropriate to the medical specialty of the individuals.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s304/4/A">Pub. L. 107–251, § 304(4)(A)</ref>, redesignated par. (2) as (3). Former par. (3) redesignated (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s304/4/E">Pub. L. 107–251, § 304(4)(E)</ref>, added par. (4) and struck out heading and text of former par. (4). Text read as follows: “If the Secretary makes a revision in a list under paragraph (1) during the period under subsection (f) of this section to which the list is applicable, and the revision alters the status of an entity with respect to the list, the Secretary shall notify the entity of the effect on the entity of the revision. Such notification shall be provided not later than 30 days after the date on which the revision is made.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s304/4/A">Pub. L. 107–251, § 304(4)(A)</ref>, redesignated par. (3) as (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s304/7">Pub. L. 107–251, § 304(7)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (e) as (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s304/5">Pub. L. 107–251, § 304(5)</ref>, added subsec. (e) and struck out heading and text of former subsec. (e). Text related to limitation on the number of entities offered as assignment choices in the Scholarship Program based on the number of participants available for assignments.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s304/6">Pub. L. 107–251, § 304(6)</ref>, struck out heading and text of subsec. (f), which related to applicable period regarding priorities in assignment of Corps members.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—<ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s401/b">Pub. L. 101–597, § 401(b)[(a)]</ref>, substituted reference to health professional shortage area for reference to health manpower shortage area wherever appearing in subsecs. (a) to (c)(1), (d)(1), and (e)(3).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb4f52a3a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb4f52a3b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2003 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/163">Pub. L. 108–163</ref> deemed to have taken effect immediately after the enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/107/251">Pub. L. 107–251</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/163/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 108–163</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s233">section 233 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
