<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb4f52ab4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l"><num value="254l">§ 254l.</num><heading> National Health Service Corps Scholarship Program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f52ab5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish the National Health Service Corps Scholarship Program to assure, with respect to the provision of primary health services pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254d/a/2">section 254d(a)(2) of this title</ref>—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f52ab6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an adequate supply of physicians, dentists, behavioral and mental health professionals, certified nurse midwives, certified nurse practitioners, and physician assistants; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f52ab7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> if needed by the Corps, an adequate supply of other health professionals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f52ab8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility; application; written contract</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To be eligible to participate in the Scholarship Program, an individual must—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f52ab9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> be accepted for enrollment, or be enrolled, as a full-time student (A) in an accredited (as determined by the Secretary) educational institution in a State and (B) in a course of study or program, offered by such institution and approved by the Secretary, leading to a degree in medicine, osteopathic medicine, dentistry, or other health profession, or an appropriate degree from a graduate program of behavioral and mental health;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f52aba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> be eligible for, or hold, an appointment as a commissioned officer in the Regular or Reserve Corps <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002086">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002086"><num>1</num> See Change of Name note below.</note> of the Service or be eligible for selection for civilian service in the Corps;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f52abb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> submit an application to participate in the Scholarship Program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f52abc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> sign and submit to the Secretary, at the time of submittal of such application, a written contract (described in subsection (f)) to accept payment of a scholarship and to serve (in accordance with this subpart) for the applicable period of obligated service in a health professional shortage area.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f52abd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Review and evaluation of information and forms by prospective applicant</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f52abe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In disseminating application forms and contract forms to individuals desiring to participate in the Scholarship Program, the Secretary shall include with such forms—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f52abf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a fair summary of the rights and liabilities of an individual whose application is approved (and whose contract is accepted) by the Secretary, including in the summary a clear explanation of the damages to which the United States is entitled under section 254<i>o</i> of this title in the case of the individual’s breach of the contract; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f52ac0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> information respecting meeting a service obligation through private practice under an agreement under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254n">section 254n of this title</ref> and such other information as may be necessary for the individual to understand the individual’s prospective participation in the Scholarship Program and service in the Corps, including a statement of all factors considered in approving applications for participation in the Program and in making assignments for participants in the Program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f52ac1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The application form, contract form, and all other information furnished by the Secretary under this subpart shall be written in a manner calculated to be understood by the average individual applying to participate in the Scholarship Program. The Secretary shall make such application forms, contract forms, and other information available to individuals desiring to participate in the Scholarship Program on a date sufficiently early to insure that such individuals have adequate time to carefully review and evaluate such forms and information.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f52ac2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f52ac3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary shall distribute to health professions schools materials providing information on the Scholarship Program and shall encourage the schools to disseminate the materials to the students of the schools.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f52ac4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f52ac5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/c/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> In the case of any health professional whose period of obligated service under the Scholarship Program is nearing completion, the Secretary shall encourage the individual to remain in a health professional shortage area and to continue providing primary health services.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f52ac6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/c/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> During the period in which a health professional is planning and making the transition to private practice from obligated service under the Scholarship Program, the Secretary may provide assistance to the professional regarding such transition if the professional is remaining in a health professional shortage area and is continuing to provide primary health services.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f52ac7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> In the case of entities to which participants in the Scholarship Program are assigned under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254f">section 254f of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall encourage the entities to provide options with respect to assisting the participants in remaining in the health professional shortage areas involved, and in continuing to provide primary health services, after the period of obligated service under the Scholarship Program is completed. The options with respect to which the Secretary provides such encouragement may include options regarding the sharing of a single employment position in the health professions by 2 or more health professionals, and options regarding the recruitment of couples where both of the individuals are health professionals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f52ac8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Factors considered in providing contracts; priorities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f52ac9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1">section 254f–1 of this title</ref>, in providing contracts under the Scholarship Program—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f52aca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Secretary shall consider the extent of the demonstrated interest of the applicants for the contracts in providing primary health services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f52acb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the Secretary, in considering applications from individuals accepted for enrollment or enrolled in dental school, shall consider applications from all individuals accepted for enrollment or enrolled in any accredited dental school in a State; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f52acc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/d/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> may <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002087">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002087"><num>2</num> So in original.</note> consider such other factors regarding the applicants as the Secretary determines to be relevant to selecting qualified individuals to participate in such Program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f52acd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> In providing contracts under the Scholarship Program, the Secretary shall give priority—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f52ace-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> first, to any application for such a contract submitted by an individual who has previously received a scholarship under this section or under section 294z <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002088">3</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002088"><num>3</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f52acf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> second, to any application for such a contract submitted by an individual who has characteristics that increase the probability that the individual will continue to serve in a health professional shortage area after the period of obligated service pursuant to subsection (f) is completed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f52ad0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> third, subject to subparagraph (B), to any application for such a contract submitted by an individual who is from a disadvantaged background.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f52ad1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Commencement of participation in Scholarship Program; notice</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f52ad2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> An individual becomes a participant in the Scholarship Program only upon the Secretary’s approval of the individual’s application submitted under subsection (b)(3) and the Secretary’s acceptance of the contract submitted by the individual under subsection (b)(4).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f79ad3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall provide written notice to an individual promptly upon the Secretary’s approving, under paragraph (1), of the individual’s participation in the Scholarship Program.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f79ad4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Written contract; contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The written contract (referred to in this subpart) between the Secretary and an individual shall contain—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79ad5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> an agreement that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f79ad6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary agrees (i) to provide the individual with a scholarship (described in subsection (g)) in each such school year or years for a period of years (not to exceed four school years) determined by the individual, during which period the individual is pursuing a course of study described in subsection (b)(1)(B), and (ii) to accept (subject to the availability of appropriated funds for carrying out sections 254d through 254h and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254j">section 254j of this title</ref>) the individual into the Corps (or for equivalent service as otherwise provided in this subpart); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f79ad7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> subject to paragraph (2), the individual agrees—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4f79ad8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/f/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to accept provision of such a scholarship to the individual;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4f79ad9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/f/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to maintain enrollment in a course of study described in subsection (b)(1)(B) until the individual completes the course of study;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4f79ada-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/f/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> while enrolled in such course of study, to maintain an acceptable level of academic standing (as determined under regulations of the Secretary by the educational institution offering such course of study);</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4f79adb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/f/1/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> if pursuing a degree from a school of medicine or osteopathic medicine, to complete a residency in a specialty that the Secretary determines is consistent with the needs of the Corps; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4f79adc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/f/1/B/v"><num value="v">(v)</num><chapeau> to serve for a time period (hereinafter in the subpart referred to as the “period of obligated service”) equal to—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb4f79add-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/f/1/B/v/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> one year for each school year for which the individual was provided a scholarship under the Scholarship Program, or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I16" class="indent4" id="idb4f79ade-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/f/1/B/v/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> two years,</content>
</subclause>
</clause>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I66" class="indent3 firstIndent-1"> whichever is greater, as a provider of primary health services in a health professional shortage area (designated under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254e">section 254e of this title</ref>) to which he is assigned by the Secretary as a member of the Corps, or as otherwise provided in this subpart;</continuation>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79adf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a provision that any financial obligation of the United States arising out of a contract entered into under this subpart and any obligation of the individual which is conditioned thereon, is contingent upon funds being appropriated for scholarships under this subpart and to carry out the purposes of sections 254d through 254h and sections 254j and 254k of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79ae0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a statement of the damages to which the United States is entitled, under section 254<i>o</i> of this title, for the individual’s breach of the contract; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79ae1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> such other statements of the rights and liabilities of the Secretary and of the individual, not inconsistent with the provisions of this subpart.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f79ae2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Scholarship provisions; contract with educational institution; increase in monthly stipend</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f79ae3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> A scholarship provided to a student for a school year under a written contract under the Scholarship Program shall consist of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79ae4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> payment to, or (in accordance with paragraph (2)) on behalf of, the student of the amount (except as provided in section 292k <sup>3</sup> of this title) of—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f79ae5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/g/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the tuition of the student in such school year; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f79ae6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/g/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> all other reasonable educational expenses, including fees, books, and laboratory expenses, incurred by the student in such school year; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79ae7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> payment to the student of a stipend of $400 per month (adjusted in accordance with paragraph (3)) for each of the 12 consecutive months beginning with the first month of such school year.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f79ae8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary may contract with an educational institution, in which a participant in the Scholarship Program is enrolled, for the payment to the educational institution of the amounts of tuition and other reasonable educational expenses described in paragraph (1)(A). Payment to such an educational institution may be made without regard to section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f79ae9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/g/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The amount of the monthly stipend, specified in paragraph (1)(B) and as previously adjusted (if at all) in accordance with this paragraph, shall be increased by the Secretary for each school year ending in a fiscal year beginning after <date date="1978-09-30">September 30, 1978</date>, by an amount (rounded to the next highest multiple of $1) equal to the amount of such stipend multiplied by the overall percentage (under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5303">section 5303 of title 5</ref>) of the adjustment (if such adjustment is an increase) in the rates of pay under the General Schedule made effective in the fiscal year in which such school year ends.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f79aea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Employment ceiling of Department unaffected</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, individuals who have entered into written contracts with the Secretary under this section, while undergoing academic training, shall not be counted against any employment ceiling affecting the Department.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb4f79aeb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title III, § 338A, formerly title VII, § 751, as added <ref href="/us/pl/94/484/tIV/s408/b/1">Pub. L. 94–484, title IV, § 408(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2281">90 Stat. 2281</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/215/s5">Pub. L. 95–215, § 5</ref>, <date date="1977-12-19">Dec. 19, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1506">91 Stat. 1506</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/623/s12/c">Pub. L. 95–623, § 12(c)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-09">Nov. 9, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3457">92 Stat. 3457</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/95/626/tI/s113/b">Pub. L. 95–626, title I, § 113(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3563">92 Stat. 3563</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/32/s7/i">Pub. L. 96–32, § 7(i)</ref>, <date date="1979-07-10">July 10, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/84">93 Stat. 84</ref>; renumbered § 338A and amended <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXVII/s2709/a">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXVII, § 2709(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/908">95 Stat. 908</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/99/129/tII/s210/b">Pub. L. 99–129, title II, § 210(b)</ref>, <date date="1985-10-22">Oct. 22, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/537">99 Stat. 537</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/607/tVI/s629/a/2">Pub. L. 100–607, title VI, § 629(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-04">Nov. 4, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3146">102 Stat. 3146</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/509/tV/s529/tI/s101/b/4/K">Pub. L. 101–509, title V, § 529 [title I, § 101(b)(4)(K)]</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/1427">104 Stat. 1427</ref>, 1440; <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/tII/s201">Pub. L. 101–597, title II, § 201</ref>, title IV, § 401(b)[(a)], <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3021">104 Stat. 3021</ref>, 3035; <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/tIII/s309">Pub. L. 107–251, title III, § 309</ref>, <date date="2002-10-26">Oct. 26, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1649">116 Stat. 1649</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/163/s2/j">Pub. L. 108–163, § 2(j)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-06">Dec. 6, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2022">117 Stat. 2022</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb4f79aec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb4f79aed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb4f79aee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s294z">Section 294z of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (d)(2)(A), was omitted in the general revision of subchapter V of this chapter by <ref href="/us/pl/102/408/tI/s102">Pub. L. 102–408, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1992-10-13">Oct. 13, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1994">106 Stat. 1994</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s292k">Section 292k of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (g)(1)(A), was in the original a reference to section 711 of act <date date="1944-07-01">July 1, 1944</date>. Section 711 of that Act was renumbered as section 710 by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXVII/s2720/b">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXVII, § 2720(b)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/915">95 Stat. 915</ref>, and subsequently omitted in the general revision of subchapter V of this chapter by <ref href="/us/pl/102/408/tI/s102">Pub. L. 102–408, title I, § 102</ref>, <date date="1992-10-13">Oct. 13, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1994">106 Stat. 1994</ref>. <ref href="/us/pl/102/408">Pub. L. 102–408</ref> enacted a new section 710 of act <date date="1944-07-01">July 1, 1944</date>, relating to insurance accounts, a new section 711, relating to powers and responsibilities of the Secretary, and a new section 712, relating to participation by Federal credit unions, which are classified to sections 292i, 292j, and 292k, respectively, of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The General Schedule, referred to in subsec. (g)(3), is set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5332">section 5332 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb4f79aef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (g)(2), “section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31” substituted for “section 3648 of the Revised Statutes (<ref href="/us/usc/t31/s529">31 U.S.C. 529</ref>)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/97/258/s4/b">Pub. L. 97–258, § 4(b)</ref>, <date date="1982-09-13">Sept. 13, 1982</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/1067">96 Stat. 1067</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 31, Money and Finance.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s294t">section 294t of this title</ref> prior to its renumbering by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb4f79af0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (d)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/108/163">Pub. L. 108–163</ref> realigned margin.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s309/1">Pub. L. 107–251, § 309(1)</ref>, inserted “behavioral and mental health professionals,” after “dentists,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s309/2">Pub. L. 107–251, § 309(2)</ref>, inserted “, or an appropriate degree from a graduate program of behavioral and mental health” after “other health profession”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s309/3">Pub. L. 107–251, § 309(3)</ref>, made technical amendment to references in original act which appear in subpar. (A) as reference to section 254<i>o</i> of this title and in subpar. (B) as reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254n">section 254n of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1)(B), (C). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s309/4">Pub. L. 107–251, § 309(4)</ref>, added subpar. (B) and redesignated former subpar. (B) as (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1)(B)(iv), (v). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s309/5/A">Pub. L. 107–251, § 309(5)(A)</ref>, added cl. (iv) and redesignated former cl. (iv) as (v).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s309/5/B">Pub. L. 107–251, § 309(5)(B)</ref>, made technical amendment to reference in original act which appears in text as reference to section 254<i>o</i> of this title.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s309/6">Pub. L. 107–251, § 309(6)</ref>, struck out subsec. (i), which required an annual report to Congress on the Scholarship Program.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s201/a/1">Pub. L. 101–597, § 201(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Corps Scholarship Program to assure, with respect to the provision of primary health services pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254d/a/2">section 254d(a)(2) of this title</ref>—” and pars. (1) and (2) for “Corps Scholarship Program (hereinafter in this subpart referred to as the ‘Scholarship Program’) to assure an adequate supply of trained physicians, dentists, and nurses for the National Health Service Corps (hereinafter in this subpart referred to as the ‘Corps’) and, if needed by the Corps, podiatrists, optometrists, pharmacists, clinical psychologists, graduates of schools of veterinary medicine, graduates of schools of public health, graduates of programs in health administration, graduates of programs for the training of physician assistants, expanded function dental auxiliaries, and nurse practitioners (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s296m">section 296m of this title</ref>), and other health professionals.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s401/b">Pub. L. 101–597, § 401(b)[(a)]</ref>, substituted reference to health professional shortage area for reference to health manpower shortage area.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s401/b">Pub. L. 101–597, § 401(b)[(a)]</ref>, substituted reference to health professional shortage area for reference to health manpower shortage area in par. (3)(B), (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s201/b">Pub. L. 101–597, § 201(b)</ref>, inserted par. (1) designation, redesignated former pars. (1) and (2) as subpars. (A) and (B), inserted before period at end of subpar. (B) “, including a statement of all factors considered in approving applications for participation in the Program and in making assignments for participants in the Program”, inserted par. (2) designation, and added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s401/b">Pub. L. 101–597, § 401(b)[(a)]</ref>, substituted reference to health professional shortage area for reference to health manpower shortage area in par. (2)(B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s201/c">Pub. L. 101–597, § 201(c)</ref>, amended subsec. (d) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (d) read as follows: “In determining which applications under the Scholarship Program to approve (and which contracts to accept), the Secretary shall give priority—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) first, to applications made (and contracts submitted) by individuals who have previously received scholarships under the Scholarship Program or under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s294z">section 294z of this title</ref>; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) second, to applications made (and contracts submitted)—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(A) for the school year beginning in calendar year 1978, by individuals who are entering their first, second, or third year of study in a course of study or program described in subsection (b)(1)(B) of this section in such school year;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(B) for the school year beginning in calendar year 1979, by individuals who are entering their first or second year of study in a course of study or program described in subsection (b)(1)(B) of this section in such school year; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(C) for each school year thereafter, by individuals who are entering their first year of study in a course of study or program described in subsection (b)(1)(B) of this section in such school year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1)(B)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s401/b">Pub. L. 101–597, § 401(b)[(a)]</ref>, substituted reference to health professional shortage area for reference to health manpower shortage area in closing provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s201/a/2">Pub. L. 101–597, § 201(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “as a provider of primary health services” after “whichever is greater,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref> substituted “(under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5303">section 5303 of title 5</ref>)” for “(as set forth in the report transmitted to the Congress under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5305">section 5305 of title 5</ref>)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s201/d/1">Pub. L. 101–597, § 201(d)(1)</ref>, amended introductory provisions generally. Prior to amendment, introductory provisions read as follows: “The Secretary shall report to Congress on March 1 of each year—”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(4), (5). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s201/d/2">Pub. L. 101–597, § 201(d)(2)</ref>, added pars. (4) and (5) and struck out former par. (4) which read as follows: “the amount of tuition paid in the aggregate and at each educational institution for the school year beginning in such year and for prior school years.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i)(6). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s401/b">Pub. L. 101–597, § 401(b)[(a)]</ref>, substituted reference to health professional shortage area for reference to health manpower shortage area.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s201/d/2/C">Pub. L. 101–597, § 201(d)(2)(C)</ref>, added par. (6).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/607">Pub. L. 100–607</ref> substituted “osteopathic medicine” for “osteopathy”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1985—Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/99/129">Pub. L. 99–129</ref> struck out “or under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s294z">section 294z of this title</ref> (relating to scholarships for first-year students of exceptional financial need),” after “Scholarship Program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2709/b/1">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2709(b)(1)</ref>, inserted reference to clinical psychologists.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2709/b/2">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2709(b)(2)</ref>, (3), substituted “254<i>o</i>” for “294w” in par. (1), and inserted provisions relating to information concerning meeting the service obligation in par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2709/b/4">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2709(b)(4)</ref>–(6), in par. (1) substituted reference to sections 254d to 254h and 254j of this title, for reference to subpart II of part D of subchapter II of this chapter, in par. (2) substituted reference to sections 254d to 254h, 254j and 254k of this title, for reference to subpart II of part D of subchapter II of this chapter, and in par. (3) substituted “254<i>o</i>” for “294w”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2709/b/7">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2709(b)(7)</ref>, struck out subsec. (j) which related to consultation and participation of schools.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (g)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/96/32">Pub. L. 96–32</ref> substituted “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5305">section 5305 of title 5</ref>” for “<ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5303">section 5303 of title 5</ref>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/95/626">Pub. L. 95–626</ref> substituted “subpart II of part D” for “subpart II of part C” in pars. (1)(A) and (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/95/623">Pub. L. 95–623</ref> substituted March 1 for December 1 as the date for Secretary’s annual report to Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (d)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/95/215">Pub. L. 95–215</ref> substituted provisions relating to the school years beginning in calendar years 1978 and 1979 for provisions relating to the school year ending in the fiscal year beginning <date date="1977-10-01">Oct. 1, 1977</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb4f79af1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idb4f79af2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reference to Reserve Corps of the Public Health Service deemed to be a reference to the Ready Reserve Corps, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s204/c/3">section 204(c)(3) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb4f79af3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2003 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/163">Pub. L. 108–163</ref> deemed to have taken effect immediately after the enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/107/251">Pub. L. 107–251</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/163/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 108–163</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s233">section 233 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb4f79af4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref> effective on such date as the President shall determine, but not earlier than 90 days, and not later than 180 days, after <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, see section 529 [title III, § 305] of <ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5301">section 5301 of Title 5</ref>, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb4f79af5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1985 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/99/129/tII/s228">Pub. L. 99–129, title II, § 228</ref>, <date date="1985-10-22">Oct. 22, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/548">99 Stat. 548</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/99/129/tII/s228">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><content> Except as provided in subsection (b), this Act and the amendments and repeals made by this Act [enacting sections 294q–1 to 294q–3 of this title, amending this section and sections 292a, 292b, 292h, 292j, 293c, 294a, 294b, 294d, 294e, 294g, 294j, 294m to 294p, 294z, 295f to 295f–2, 295g, 295g–1, 295g–3, 295g–4, 295g–6 to 295g–8, 295g–8b, 295h, 295h–1a to 295h–1c, 296k, 296<i>l</i>, 296m, 297a, 298b–5, and 300aa–14 of this title, repealing sections 292c, 295 to 295e–5, 295g–2, 295g–5, 295g–8a, and 295g–9 of this title, enacting provisions set out as notes under sections 201, 292h, 293c, 294d, 294n, and 300aa–14 of this title and <ref href="/us/usc/t50/s3811">section 3811 of Title 50</ref>, War and National Defense, and amending provisions set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s298b–5">section 298b–5 of this title</ref>] shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1985-10-22">Oct. 22, 1985</date>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The amendments made by section 101(a) of this Act [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s294a">section 294a of this title</ref>] shall take effect as of <date date="1985-10-01">October 1, 1985</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> The amendments made by section 208(e) of this Act [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s294e">section 294e of this title</ref>] shall take effect nine months after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1985-10-22">Oct. 22, 1985</date>].</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The amendment made by section 208(h) of this Act [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s294a">section 294a of this title</ref>] shall take effect as of <date date="1983-10-01">October 1, 1983</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> The provisions of section 746 of the Public Health Service Act (as added by the amendment made by section 209(h)(2) of this Act) [former <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s294q–2">42 U.S.C. 294q–2</ref>] shall take effect as of <date date="1984-06-30">June 30, 1984</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> The amendments made by section 209(j) of this Act [amending sections 294m and 297a of this title] shall take effect as of <date date="1984-06-30">June 30, 1984</date>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> The amendments made by section 213(a) of this Act [amending <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s295g–1">section 295g–1 of this title</ref>] shall take effect as of <date date="1985-10-01">October 1, 1985</date>.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb4f79af6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1977 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/95/215/s5">Pub. L. 95–215, § 5</ref>, <date date="1977-12-19">Dec. 19, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/1506">91 Stat. 1506</ref>, provided that the amendment made by that section is effective <date date="1977-10-01">Oct. 1, 1977</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb4f79af7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/94/484/tIV/s408/b/1">Pub. L. 94–484, title IV, § 408(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2281">90 Stat. 2281</ref>, provided that the enactment of sections 254<i>l</i> to 254r of this title and repeal of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s234">section 234 of this title</ref> by <ref href="/us/pl/94/484">Pub. L. 94–484</ref> is effective <date date="1977-10-01">Oct. 1, 1977</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb4f79af8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date; Savings Provision; Credit for Period of Internship or Residency Before <date date="1977-09-30">September 30, 1977</date>, Towards Service Obligation</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/94/484/tIV/s408/b/2">Pub. L. 94–484, title IV, § 408(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2288">90 Stat. 2288</ref>, as amended, eff. <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, by <ref href="/us/pl/95/83/tIII/s307/p">Pub. L. 95–83, title III, § 307(p)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-01">Aug. 1, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/394">91 Stat. 394</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/95/83/tIII/s307/p">
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C), the amendment made by paragraph (1) of this subsection [enacting this section and sections 254<i>l</i>–1 to 254r of this title and repealing <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s234">section 234 of this title</ref>] shall apply with respect to scholarships awarded under the National Health Service Corps Scholarship Program from appropriations for such Program for fiscal years beginning after <date date="1977-09-30">September 30, 1977</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> The provisions of section 225(f)(1) of the Public Health Service Act (as in effect on <date date="1977-09-30">September 30, 1977</date>) [former <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s234/f/1">42 U.S.C. 234(f)(1)</ref>] prescribing the financial obligation of a participant in the Public Health and National Health Service Corps Scholarship Program who fails to complete an active duty service obligation incurred under that Program shall apply to any individual who received a scholarship under such Program from appropriations for such Program for any fiscal year ending before <date date="1977-10-01">October 1, 1977</date>.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> If an individual received a scholarship under the Public Health and National Health Service Corps Scholarship Program for any school year beginning before the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>], periods of internship or residency served by such individual in a facility of the National Health Service Corps or other facility of the Public Health Service shall be creditable in satisfying such individual’s service obligation incurred under that Program for such scholarship or for any scholarship received under the National Health Service Corps Scholarship Program for any subsequent school year. If an individual received a scholarship under the Public Health and National Health Service Corps Program for the first time from appropriations for such Program for the fiscal year ending <date date="1977-09-30">September 30, 1977</date>, periods of internship or residency served by such individual in such a facility shall be creditable in satisfying such individual’s service obligation incurred under that Program for such scholarship.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb4f79af9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Scholarship and Loan Repayment Programs</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/107/251/tIII/s302/c">Pub. L. 107–251, title III, § 302(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-10-26">Oct. 26, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1644">116 Stat. 1644</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/107/251/tIII/s302/c">“The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with organizations representing individuals in the dental field and organizations representing publicly funded health care providers, shall develop and implement a plan for increasing the participation of dentists and dental hygienists in the National Health Service Corps Scholarship Program under section 338A of the Public Health Service Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254">42 U.S.C. 254</ref><i>l</i>) and the Loan Repayment Program under section 338B of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254">42 U.S.C. 254</ref><i>l</i>–1).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
