<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb4f79afa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1"><num value="254l–1">§ 254l–1.</num><heading> National Health Service Corps Loan Repayment Program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f79afb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish a program to be known as the National Health Service Corps Loan Repayment Program to assure, with respect to the provision of primary health services pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254d/a/2">section 254d(a)(2) of this title</ref>—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79afc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> an adequate supply of physicians, dentists, behavioral and mental health professionals, certified nurse midwives, certified nurse practitioners, and physician assistants; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79afd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> if needed by the Corps, an adequate supply of other health professionals.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f79afe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To be eligible to participate in the Loan Repayment Program, an individual must—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79aff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79b00-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> have a degree in medicine, osteopathic medicine, dentistry, or another health profession, or an appropriate degree from a graduate program of behavioral and mental health, or be certified as a nurse midwife, nurse practitioner, or physician assistant;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79b01-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> be enrolled in an approved graduate training program in medicine, osteopathic medicine, dentistry, behavioral and mental health, or other health profession; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79b02-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> be enrolled as a full-time student—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f79b03-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/b/1/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> in an accredited (as determined by the Secretary) educational institution in a State; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f79b04-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/b/1/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in the final year of a course of a study or program, offered by such institution and approved by the Secretary, leading to a degree in medicine, osteopathic medicine, dentistry, or other health profession;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79b05-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> be eligible for, or hold, an appointment as a commissioned officer in the Regular or Reserve Corps <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002089">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002089"><num>1</num> See Change of Name note below.</note> of the Service or be eligible for selection for civilian service in the Corps; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79b06-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> submit to the Secretary an application for a contract described in subsection (f) (relating to the payment by the Secretary of the educational loans of the individual in consideration of the individual serving for a period of obligated service).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f79b07-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Information to be included with application and contract forms; understandability; availability</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f79b08-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Summary and information</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In disseminating application forms and contract forms to individuals desiring to participate in the Loan Repayment Program, the Secretary shall include with such forms—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f79b09-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a fair summary of the rights and liabilities of an individual whose application is approved (and whose contract is accepted) by the Secretary, including in the summary a clear explanation of the damages to which the United States is entitled under section 254<i>o</i> of this title in the case of the individual’s breach of the contract; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f79b0a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> information respecting meeting a service obligation through private practice under an agreement under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254n">section 254n of this title</ref> and such other information as may be necessary for the individual to understand the individual’s prospective participation in the Loan Repayment Program and service in the Corps.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f79b0b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Understandability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The application form, contract form, and all other information furnished by the Secretary under this subpart shall be written in a manner calculated to be understood by the average individual applying to participate in the Loan Repayment Program.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f79b0c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/c/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall make such application forms, contract forms, and other information available to individuals desiring to participate in the Loan Repayment Program on a date sufficiently early to ensure that such individuals have adequate time to carefully review and evaluate such forms and information.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f79b0d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/c/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Recruitment and retention</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79b0e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/c/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Secretary shall distribute to health professions schools materials providing information on the Loan Repayment Program and shall encourage the schools to disseminate the materials to the students of the schools.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79b0f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/c/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79b10-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/c/4/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> In the case of any health professional whose period of obligated service under the Loan Repayment Program is nearing completion, the Secretary shall encourage the individual to remain in a health professional shortage area and to continue providing primary health services.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79b11-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/c/4/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> During the period in which a health professional is planning and making the transition to private practice from obligated service under the Loan Repayment Program, the Secretary may provide assistance to the professional regarding such transition if the professional is remaining in a health professional shortage area and is continuing to provide primary health services.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79b12-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/c/4/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> In the case of entities to which participants in the Loan Repayment Program are assigned under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254f">section 254f of this title</ref>, the Secretary shall encourage the entities to provide options with respect to assisting the participants in remaining in the health professional shortage areas involved, and in continuing to provide primary health services, after the period of obligated service under the Loan Repayment Program is completed. The options with respect to which the Secretary provides such encouragement may include options regarding the sharing of a single employment position in the health professions by 2 or more health professionals, and options regarding the recruitment of couples where both of the individuals are health professionals.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f79b13-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Factors considered in providing contracts; priorities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f79b14-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254f–1">section 254f–1 of this title</ref>, in providing contracts under the Loan Repayment Program—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79b15-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/d/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Secretary shall consider the extent of the demonstrated interest of the applicants for the contracts in providing primary health services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79b16-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/d/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> may consider such other factors regarding the applicants as the Secretary determines to be relevant to selecting qualified individuals to participate in such Program.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4f79b17-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> In providing contracts under the Loan Repayment Program, the Secretary shall give priority—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79b18-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> to any application for such a contract submitted by an individual whose training is in a health profession or specialty determined by the Secretary to be needed by the Corps;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79b19-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> to any application for such a contract submitted by an individual who has (and whose spouse, if any, has) characteristics that increase the probability that the individual will continue to serve in a health professional shortage area after the period of obligated service pursuant to subsection (f) is completed; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79b1a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> subject to subparagraph (B), to any application for such a contract submitted by an individual who is from a disadvantaged background.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f79b1b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Approval required for participation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An individual becomes a participant in the Loan Repayment Program only upon the Secretary and the individual entering into a written contract described in subsection (f).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f79b1c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents of contracts</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The written contract (referred to in this subpart) between the Secretary and an individual shall contain—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79b1d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> an agreement that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f79b1e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/f/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> subject to paragraph (3), the Secretary agrees—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4f79b1f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/f/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to pay on behalf of the individual loans in accordance with subsection (g); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4f79b20-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/f/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to accept (subject to the availability of appropriated funds for carrying out sections 254d through 254h of this title and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254j">section 254j of this title</ref>) the individual into the Corps (or for equivalent service as otherwise provided in this subpart); and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f79b21-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/f/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> subject to paragraph (3), the individual agrees—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4f79b22-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/f/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to accept loan payments on behalf of the individual;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4f79b23-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/f/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> in the case of an individual described in subsection (b)(1)(C), to maintain enrollment in a course of study or training described in such subsection until the individual completes the course of study or training;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4f79b24-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/f/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> in the case of an individual described in subsection (b)(1)(C), while enrolled in such course of study or training, to maintain an acceptable level of academic standing (as determined under regulations of the Secretary by the educational institution offering such course of study or training); and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4f79b25-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/f/1/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> to serve for a time period (hereinafter in this subpart referred to as the “period of obligated service”) equal to 2 years or such longer period as the individual may agree to, as a provider of primary health services in a health professional shortage area (designated under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254e">section 254e of this title</ref>) to which such individual is assigned by the Secretary as a member of the Corps or released under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254n">section 254n of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79b26-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a provision permitting the Secretary to extend for such longer additional periods, as the individual may agree to, the period of obligated service agreed to by the individual under paragraph (1)(B)(iv), including extensions resulting in an aggregate period of obligated service in excess of 4 years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79b27-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a provision that any financial obligation of the United States arising out of a contract entered into under this subpart and any obligation of the individual that is conditioned thereon, is contingent on funds being appropriated for loan repayments under this subpart and to carry out the purposes of sections 254d through 254h of this title and sections 254j and 254k of this title;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79b28-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> a statement of the damages to which the United States is entitled, under section 254<i>o</i> of this title for the individual’s breach of the contract; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4f79b29-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/f/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> such other statements of the rights and liabilities of the Secretary and of the individual, not inconsistent with this subpart.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f79b2a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Payments</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f79b2b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A loan repayment provided for an individual under a written contract under the Loan Repayment Program shall consist of payment, in accordance with paragraph (2), on behalf of the individual of the principal, interest, and related expenses on government and commercial loans received by the individual regarding the undergraduate or graduate education of the individual (or both), which loans were made for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f79b2c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/g/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> tuition expenses;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f79b2d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/g/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> all other reasonable educational expenses, including fees, books, and laboratory expenses, incurred by the individual; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f79b2e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/g/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> reasonable living expenses as determined by the Secretary.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f79b2f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Payments for years served</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f79b30-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/g/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">For each year of obligated service that an individual contracts to serve under subsection (f) the Secretary may pay up to $50,000, plus, beginning with fiscal year 2012, an amount determined by the Secretary on an annual basis to reflect inflation, on behalf of the individual for loans described in paragraph (1). In making a determination of the amount to pay for a year of such service by an individual, the Secretary shall consider the extent to which each such determination—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4f79b31-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/g/2/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> affects the ability of the Secretary to maximize the number of contracts that can be provided under the Loan Repayment Program from the amounts appropriated for such contracts;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4f79b32-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/g/2/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> provides an incentive to serve in health professional shortage areas with the greatest such shortages; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb4f79b33-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/g/2/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> provides an incentive with respect to the health professional involved remaining in a health professional shortage area, and continuing to provide primary health services, after the completion of the period of obligated service under the Loan Repayment Program.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f79b34-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/g/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Repayment schedule</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Any arrangement made by the Secretary for the making of loan repayments in accordance with this subsection shall provide that any repayments for a year of obligated service shall be made no later than the end of the fiscal year in which the individual completes such year of service.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f79b35-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/g/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Tax liability</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">For the purpose of providing reimbursements for tax liability resulting from payments under paragraph (2) on behalf of an individual—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f79b36-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/g/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the Secretary shall, in addition to such payments, make payments to the individual in an amount equal to 39 percent of the total amount of loan repayments made for the taxable year involved; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb4f79b37-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/g/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> may make such additional payments as the Secretary determines to be appropriate with respect to such purpose.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f79b38-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/g/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Payment schedule</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary may enter into an agreement with the holder of any loan for which payments are made under the Loan Repayment Program to establish a schedule for the making of such payments.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4f79b39-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254l–1/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Employment ceiling</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, individuals who have entered into written contracts with the Secretary under this section, while undergoing academic or other training, shall not be counted against any employment ceiling affecting the Department.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb4f79b3a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title III, § 338B, as added <ref href="/us/pl/100/177/tII/s201/3">Pub. L. 100–177, title II, § 201(3)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-01">Dec. 1, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/992">101 Stat. 992</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/607/tVI/s629/a/2">Pub. L. 100–607, title VI, § 629(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-04">Nov. 4, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3146">102 Stat. 3146</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/tII/s202/a">Pub. L. 101–597, title II, § 202(a)</ref>–(g)(1), (h), title IV, § 401(b)[(a)], <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3023-3026">104 Stat. 3023–3026</ref>, 3035; <ref href="/us/pl/105/392/tI/s109">Pub. L. 105–392, title I, § 109</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3562">112 Stat. 3562</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/tIII/s310">Pub. L. 107–251, title III, § 310</ref>, <date date="2002-10-26">Oct. 26, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1650">116 Stat. 1650</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/163/s2/k">Pub. L. 108–163, § 2(k)</ref>, <date date="2003-12-06">Dec. 6, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2022">117 Stat. 2022</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tX/s10501/n/4">Pub. L. 111–148, title X, § 10501(n)(4)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/1003">124 Stat. 1003</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb4f79b3b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb4f79b3c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idb4f79b3d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 338B of act <date date="1944-07-01">July 1, 1944</date>, was renumbered section 338C by <ref href="/us/pl/100/177/s201/2">section 201(2) of Pub. L. 100–177</ref> and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254m">section 254m of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb4f79b3e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (g)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148">Pub. L. 111–148</ref> substituted “$50,000, plus, beginning with fiscal year 2012, an amount determined by the Secretary on an annual basis to reflect inflation,” for “$35,000” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/108/163">Pub. L. 108–163</ref> made technical amendment.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s310/1/A">Pub. L. 107–251, § 310(1)(A)</ref>, inserted “behavioral and mental health professionals,” after “dentists,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s310/1/B">Pub. L. 107–251, § 310(1)(B)</ref>, struck out “(including mental health professionals)” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s310/2">Pub. L. 107–251, § 310(2)</ref>, added subpar. (A) and struck out former subpar. (A) which read as follows: “must have a degree in medicine, osteopathic medicine, dentistry, or other health profession, or be certified as a nurse midwife, nurse practioner, or physician assistant;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s310/3">Pub. L. 107–251, § 310(3)</ref>, struck out par. (1) designation and heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s310/4">Pub. L. 107–251, § 310(4)</ref>, struck out subsec. (i), which required an annual report to Congress about the Loan Repayment Program.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (b)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/105/392">Pub. L. 105–392</ref> substituted “behavioral and mental health, or other health profession” for “or other health profession”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s202/a/1">Pub. L. 101–597, § 202(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Corps Loan Repayment Program to assure, with respect to the provision of primary health services pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254d/a/2">section 254d(a)(2) of this title</ref>—” and pars. (1) and (2) for “Corps Loan Repayment Program (hereinafter in this subpart referred to as the ‘Loan Repayment Program’) in order to assure—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) an adequate supply of trained physicians, dentists, and nurses for the Corps; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) if needed by the Corps, an adequate supply of podiatrists, optometrists, pharmacists, clinical psychologists, graduates of schools of veterinary medicine, graduates of schools of public health, graduates of programs in health administration, graduates of programs for the training of physician assistants, expanded function dental auxiliaries, and nurse practitioners (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s296m">section 296m of this title</ref>), and other health professionals.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s202/b/1/A">Pub. L. 101–597, § 202(b)(1)(A)</ref>, amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(A) be enrolled—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) as a full-time student—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(I) in an accredited (as determined by the Secretary) educational institution in a State; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2">“(II) in the final year of a course of study or program, offered by such institution and approved by the Secretary, leading to a degree in medicine, osteopathic medicine, dentistry, or other health profession; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) in an approved graduate training program in medicine, osteopathic medicine, dentistry, or other health profession; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B) have—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) a degree in medicine, osteopathic medicine, dentistry, or other health profession;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) completed an approved graduate training program in medicine, osteopathic medicine, dentistry, or other health profession in a State, except that the Secretary may waive the completion requirement of this clause for good cause; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(iii) a license to practice medicine, osteopathic medicine, dentistry, or other health profession in a State;”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2) to (4). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s202/b/2/A">Pub. L. 101–597, § 202(b)(2)(A)</ref>, inserted “and” at end of par. (2), added par. (3), and struck out former pars. (3) and (4) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(3) submit an application to participate in the Loan Repayment Program; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(4) sign and submit to the Secretary, at the time of the submission of such application, a written contract (described in subsection (f) of this section) to accept repayment of educational loans and to serve (in accordance with this subpart) for the applicable period of obligated service in a health manpower shortage area.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s401/b">Pub. L. 101–597, § 401(b)[(a)]</ref>, substituted reference to health professional shortage area for reference to health manpower shortage area in subpars. (B) and (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s202/c">Pub. L. 101–597, § 202(c)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s401/b">Pub. L. 101–597, § 401(b)[(a)]</ref>, substituted reference to health professional shortage area for reference to health manpower shortage area in par. (2)(B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s202/d">Pub. L. 101–597, § 202(d)</ref>, amended subsec. (d) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (d) read as follows: “In determining which applications under the Loan Repayment Program to approve (and which contracts to accept), the Secretary shall give priority to applications made by—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) individuals whose training is in a health profession or specialty determined by the Secretary to be needed by the Corps; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) individuals who are committed to service in medically underserved areas.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s202/b/2/B">Pub. L. 101–597, § 202(b)(2)(B)</ref>, substituted “only upon the Secretary and the individual entering into a written contract described in subsection (f).” for “only on the Secretary’s approval of the individual’s application submitted under subsection (b)(3) of this section and the Secretary’s acceptance of the contract submitted by the individual under subsection (b)(4) of this section.” in par. (1) and struck out par. (2) which read as follows: “The Secretary shall provide written notice to an individual promptly on—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(A) the Secretary’s approving, under paragraph (1), of the individual’s participation in the Loan Repayment Program; or</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(B) the Secretary’s disapproving an individual’s participation in such Program.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1)(B)(ii), (iii). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s202/b/1/B">Pub. L. 101–597, § 202(b)(1)(B)</ref>, substituted “subsection (b)(1)(C)” for “subsection (b)(1)(A)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(1)(B)(iv). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s401/b">Pub. L. 101–597, § 401(b)[(a)]</ref>, substituted reference to health professional shortage area for reference to health manpower shortage area.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s202/a/2">Pub. L. 101–597, § 202(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “as a provider of primary health services” before “in a health”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s202/e">Pub. L. 101–597, § 202(e)</ref>, inserted before semicolon at end “, including extensions resulting in an aggregate period of obligated service in excess of 4 years”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s202/f/1">Pub. L. 101–597, § 202(f)(1)</ref>, inserted “regarding the undergraduate or graduate education of the individual (or both), which loans were made” after “loans received by the individual”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s401/b">Pub. L. 101–597, § 401(b)[(a)]</ref>, substituted reference to health professional shortage area for reference to health manpower shortage area in cls. (ii) and (iii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s202/f/2/A">Pub. L. 101–597, § 202(f)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “For each year” for “Except as provided in subparagraph (B) and paragraph (3), for each year” and “$35,000” for “$20,000”, inserted at end “In making a determination of the amount to pay for a year of such service by an individual, the Secretary shall consider the extent to which each such determination—”, and added immediately thereafter cls. (i) to (iii).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2)(B), (C). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s202/f/2/B">Pub. L. 101–597, § 202(f)(2)(B)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (C) as (B) and struck out former subpar. (B) which read as follows: “For each year of obligated service that an individual contracts under subsection (f) of this section to serve in the Indian Health Service, or to serve in a health program or facility operated by a tribe or tribal organization under the Indian Self-Determination Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s450f">25 U.S.C. 450f</ref> et seq.), the Secretary may pay up to $25,000 on behalf of the individual for loans described in paragraph (1).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s202/g/1">Pub. L. 101–597, § 202(g)(1)</ref>, amended par. (3) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (3) read as follows: “In addition to payments made under paragraph (2), in any case in which payments on behalf of an individual under the Loan Repayment Program result in an increase in Federal, State, or local income tax liability for such individual, the Secretary may, on the request of such individual, make payments to such individual in a reasonable amount, as determined by the Secretary, to reimburse such individual for all or part of the increased tax liability of the individual.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (i). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s401/b">Pub. L. 101–597, § 401(b)[(a)]</ref>, substituted reference to health professional shortage area for reference to health manpower shortage area in par. (8).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/597/s202/h">Pub. L. 101–597, § 202(h)</ref>, amended subsec. (i) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (i) read as follows: “The Secretary shall, not later than March 1 of each year, submit to the Congress a report specifying—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) the number, and type of health profession training, of individuals receiving loan payments under the Loan Repayment Program;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) the educational institution at which such individuals are receiving their training;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(3) the number of applications filed under this section in the school year beginning in such year and in prior school years; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(4) the amount of loan payments made in the year reported on.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/607">Pub. L. 100–607</ref> substituted “osteopathic medicine” for “osteopathy” wherever appearing.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb4fa0c3f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idb4fa0c40-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reference to Reserve Corps of the Public Health Service deemed to be a reference to the Ready Reserve Corps, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s204/c/3">section 204(c)(3) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb4fa0c41-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2003 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/108/163">Pub. L. 108–163</ref> deemed to have taken effect immediately after the enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/107/251">Pub. L. 107–251</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/163/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 108–163</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s233">section 233 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb4fa0c42-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/597/tII/s202/g/2">Pub. L. 101–597, title II, § 202(g)(2)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3026">104 Stat. 3026</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/597/tII/s202/g/2">“The amendment made by paragraph (1) [amending this section] shall apply only with respect to contracts under section 338B of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254">42 U.S.C. 254</ref><i>l</i>–1] (relating to service in the National Health Service Corps) that are entered into on or after the effective date of this Act [<date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb4fa0c43-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Regulations</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/177/tII/s205">Pub. L. 100–177, title II, § 205</ref>, <date date="1987-12-01">Dec. 1, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1003">101 Stat. 1003</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/177/tII/s205">“Not later than 180 days after the effective date of the amendments made by this title [<date date="1987-12-21">Dec. 21, 1987</date>], the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall issue regulations for the loan repayment programs established by the amendments [enacting this section and sections 254q and 254q–1 of this title, amending sections 242a, 254d, 254g, 254h–1, and 254<i>o</i> of this title, and repealing former <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254q">section 254q of this title</ref>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb4fa0c44-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Clarification on Current Eligibility for Loan Repayment Programs</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/114/255/dB/tIX/s9023">Pub. L. 114–255, div. B, title IX, § 9023</ref>, <date date="2016-12-13">Dec. 13, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1253">130 Stat. 1253</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/114/255/dB/tIX/s9023">“The Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration shall clarify the eligibility pursuant to section 338B(b)(1)(B) of the Public Health Service Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254">42 U.S.C. 254</ref><i>l</i>–1(b)(1)(B)) of child and adolescent psychiatrists for the National Health Service Corps Loan Repayment Program under subpart III of part D of title III of such Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254">42 U.S.C. 254</ref><i>l</i> et seq.).”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
