<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb4fa0c45-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254m"><num value="254m">§ 254m.</num><heading> Obligated service under contract</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4fa0c46-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254m/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Service in full-time clinical practice</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Except as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254n">section 254n of this title</ref>, each individual who has entered into a written contract with the Secretary under section 254<i>l</i> or 254<i>l</i>–1 of this title shall provide service in the full-time clinical practice of such individual’s profession as a member of the Corps for the period of obligated service provided in such contract. The Secretary may treat teaching as clinical practice for up to 20 percent of such period of obligated service. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, with respect to a member of the Corps participating in the teaching health centers graduate medical education program under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s256h">section 256h of this title</ref>, for the purpose of calculating time spent in full-time clinical practice under this section, up to 50 percent of time spent teaching by such member may be counted toward his or her service obligation.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4fa0c47-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254m/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Notice to individual; information for informed decision; eligibility; notice to Secretary; qualification and appointment as commissioned officer; appointment as civilian member; designation of non-United States employee as member; deferment of obligated service</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fa0c48-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254m/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> If an individual is required under subsection (a) to provide service as specified in section 254<i>l</i>(f)(1)(B)(v) or 254<i>l</i>–1(f)(1)(B)(iv) of this title (hereinafter in this subsection referred to as “obligated service”), the Secretary shall, not later than ninety days before the date described in paragraph (5), determine if the individual shall provide such service—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fa0c49-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254m/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> as a member of the Corps who is a commissioned officer in the Regular or Reserve Corps <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002090">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002090"><num>1</num> See Change of Name note below.</note> of the Service or who is a civilian employee of the United States, or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fa0c4a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254m/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> as a member of the Corps who is not such an officer or employee,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">and shall notify such individual of such determination.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fa0c4b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254m/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If the Secretary determines that an individual shall provide obligated service as a member of the Corps who is a commissioned officer in the Service or a civilian employee of the United States, the Secretary shall, not later than sixty days before the date described in paragraph (5), provide such individual with sufficient information regarding the advantages and disadvantages of service as such a commissioned officer or civilian employee to enable the individual to make a decision on an informed basis. To be eligible to provide obligated service as a commissioned officer in the Service, an individual shall notify the Secretary, not later than thirty days before the date described in paragraph (5), of the individual’s desire to provide such service as such an officer. If an individual qualifies for an appointment as such an officer, the Secretary shall, as soon as possible after the date described in paragraph (5), appoint the individual as a commissioned officer of the Regular or Reserve Corps <sup>1</sup> of the Service and shall designate the individual as a member of the Corps.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fa0c4c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254m/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> If an individual provided notice by the Secretary under paragraph (2) does not qualify for appointment as a commissioned officer in the Service, the Secretary shall, as soon as possible after the date described in paragraph (5), appoint such individual as a civilian employee of the United States and designate the individual as a member of the Corps.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fa0c4d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254m/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> If the Secretary determines that an individual shall provide obligated service as a member of the Corps who is not an employee of the United States, the Secretary shall, as soon as possible after the date described in paragraph (5), designate such individual as a member of the Corps to provide such service.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fa0c4e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254m/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fa0c4f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254m/b/5/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> In the case of the Scholarship Program, the date referred to in paragraphs (1) through (4) shall be the date on which the individual completes the training required for the degree for which the individual receives the scholarship, except that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fa0c50-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254m/b/5/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> for an individual receiving such a degree after <date date="2000-09-30">September 30, 2000</date>, from a school of medicine or osteopathic medicine, such date shall be the date the individual completes a residency in a specialty that the Secretary determines is consistent with the needs of the Corps; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fa0c51-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254m/b/5/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> at the request of an individual, the Secretary may, consistent with the needs of the Corps, defer such date until the end of a period of time required for the individual to complete advanced training (including an internship or residency).</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fa0c52-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254m/b/5/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> No period of internship, residency, or other advanced clinical training shall be counted toward satisfying a period of obligated service under this subpart.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fa0c53-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254m/b/5/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> In the case of the Loan Repayment Program, if an individual is required to provide obligated service under such Program, the date referred to in paragraphs (1) through (4)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fa0c54-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254m/b/5/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> shall be the date determined under subparagraph (A) in the case of an individual who is enrolled in the final year of a course of study;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fa0c55-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254m/b/5/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> shall, in the case of an individual who is enrolled in an approved graduate training program in medicine, osteopathic medicine, dentistry, or other health profession, be the date the individual completes such training program; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fa0c56-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254m/b/5/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> shall, in the case of an individual who has a degree in medicine, osteopathic medicine, dentistry, or other health profession and who has completed graduate training, be the date the individual enters into an agreement with the Secretary under section 254<i>l</i>–1 of this title.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4fa0c57-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254m/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Obligated service period; commencement</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An individual shall be considered to have begun serving a period of obligated service—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fa0c58-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254m/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> on the date such individual is appointed as an officer in a Regular or Reserve Corps <sup>1</sup> of the Service or is designated as a member of the Corps under subsection (b)(3) or (b)(4), or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fa0c59-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254m/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> in the case of an individual who has entered into an agreement with the Secretary under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254n">section 254n of this title</ref>, on the date specified in such agreement,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">whichever is earlier.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4fa0c5a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254m/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Assignment of personnel</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall assign individuals performing obligated service in accordance with a written contract under the Scholarship Program to health professional shortage areas in accordance with sections 254d through 254h and sections 254j and 254k of this title. If the Secretary determines that there is no need in a health professional shortage area (designated under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254e">section 254e of this title</ref>) for a member of the profession in which an individual is obligated to provide service under a written contract and if such individual is an officer in the Service or a civilian employee of the United States, the Secretary may detail such individual to serve his period of obligated service as a full-time member of such profession in such unit of the Department as the Secretary may determine.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb4fa0c5b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title III, § 338C, formerly title VII, § 752, as added <ref href="/us/pl/94/484/tIV/s408/b/1">Pub. L. 94–484, title IV, § 408(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2284">90 Stat. 2284</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/626/tI/s113/b">Pub. L. 95–626, title I, § 113(b)</ref>, <date date="1978-11-10">Nov. 10, 1978</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/92/3563">92 Stat. 3563</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/96/76/tII/s202/a">Pub. L. 96–76, title II, § 202(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1979-09-29">Sept. 29, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/582">93 Stat. 582</ref>; renumbered § 338B and amended <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXVII/s2709/a">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXVII, § 2709(a)</ref>, (c), <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/908">95 Stat. 908</ref>, 909; <ref href="/us/pl/97/414/s8/g/1">Pub. L. 97–414, § 8(g)(1)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-04">Jan. 4, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2061">96 Stat. 2061</ref>; renumbered § 338C and amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/177/tII/s201/2">Pub. L. 100–177, title II, § 201(2)</ref>, title III, § 306, <date date="1987-12-01">Dec. 1, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/992">101 Stat. 992</ref>, 1004; <ref href="/us/pl/100/607/tVI/s629/a/2">Pub. L. 100–607, title VI, § 629(a)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-04">Nov. 4, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3146">102 Stat. 3146</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/tIV/s401/b">Pub. L. 101–597, title IV, § 401(b)[(a)]</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3035">104 Stat. 3035</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/tIII/s311">Pub. L. 107–251, title III, § 311</ref>, <date date="2002-10-26">Oct. 26, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1650">116 Stat. 1650</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tV/s5508/b">Pub. L. 111–148, title V, § 5508(b)</ref>, title X, § 10501(n)(5), <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/670">124 Stat. 670</ref>, 1003.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb4fa0c5c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb4fa0c5d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb4fa0c5e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s294u">section 294u of this title</ref> prior to its renumbering by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idb4fa0c5f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 338C of act <date date="1944-07-01">July 1, 1944</date>, was renumbered section 338D by <ref href="/us/pl/100/177/s201/2">section 201(2) of Pub. L. 100–177</ref> and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254n">section 254n of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb4fa0c60-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2010—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s10501/n/5">Pub. L. 111–148, § 10501(n)(5)</ref>, in second sentence, substituted “The Secretary may treat teaching as clinical practice for up to 20 percent of such period of obligated service” for “For the purpose of calculating time spent in full-time clinical practice under this subsection, up to 50 percent of time spent teaching by a member of the Corps may be counted toward his or her service obligation” and inserted at end “Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, with respect to a member of the Corps participating in the teaching health centers graduate medical education program under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s256h">section 256h of this title</ref>, for the purpose of calculating time spent in full-time clinical practice under this section, up to 50 percent of time spent teaching by such member may be counted toward his or her service obligation.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/111/148/s5508/b">Pub. L. 111–148, § 5508(b)</ref>, amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Except as provided in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254n">section 254n of this title</ref>, each individual who has entered into a written contract with the Secretary under section 254<i>l</i> or 254<i>l</i>–1 of this title shall provide service in the full-time clinical practice of such individual’s profession as a member of the Corps for the period of obligated service provided in such contract.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s311/1/A">Pub. L. 107–251, § 311(1)(A)</ref>, substituted “section 254<i>l</i>(f)(1)(B)(v)” for “254<i>l</i>(f)(1)(B)(iv)” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s311/1/B/i">Pub. L. 107–251, § 311(1)(B)(i)</ref>, added subpar. (A) and struck out former subpar. (A) which read as follows: “In the case of the Scholarship Program, with respect to an individual receiving a degree from a school of medicine, osteopathic medicine, dentistry, veterinary medicine, optometry, podiatry, or pharmacy, the date referred to in paragraphs (1) through (4) shall be the date on which the individual completes the training required for such degree, except that—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(i) at the request of such an individual with whom the Secretary has entered into a contract under section 254<i>l</i> of this title prior to <date date="1985-10-01">October 1, 1985</date>, the Secretary shall defer such date until the end of the period of time (not to exceed the number of years specified in subparagraph (B) or such greater period as the Secretary, consistent with the needs of the Corps, may authorize) required for the individual to complete an internship, residency, or other advanced clinical training; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(ii) at the request of such an individual with whom the Secretary has entered into a contract under section 254<i>l</i> of this title on or after <date date="1985-10-01">October 1, 1985</date>, the Secretary may defer such date in accordance with clause (i).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s311/1/B/i">Pub. L. 107–251, § 311(1)(B)(i)</ref>, (iii), redesignated subpar. (C) as (B) and struck out former subpar. (B) which read as follows:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(B)(i) In the case of the Scholarship Program, with respect to an individual receiving a degree from a school of medicine, osteopathic medicine, or dentistry, the number of years referred to in subparagraph (A)(i) shall be 3 years.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“(ii) In the case of the Scholarship Program, with respect to an individual receiving a degree from a school of veterinary medicine, optometry, podiatry, or pharmacy, the number of years referred to in subparagraph (A)(i) shall be 1 year.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s311/1/B/iii">Pub. L. 107–251, § 311(1)(B)(iii)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (E) as (C). Former subpar. (C) redesignated (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5)(C)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s311/1/B/iv">Pub. L. 107–251, § 311(1)(B)(iv)</ref>, substituted “subparagraph (A)” for “subparagraph (A), (B), or (D)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s311/1/B/ii">Pub. L. 107–251, § 311(1)(B)(ii)</ref>, struck out subpar. (D) which read as follows: “In the case of the Scholarship Program, with respect to an individual receiving a degree from an institution other than a school referred to in subparagraph (A), the date referred to in paragraphs (1) through (4) shall be the date on which the individual completes the academic training of the individual leading to such degree.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5)(E). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s311/1/B/iii">Pub. L. 107–251, § 311(1)(B)(iii)</ref>, redesignated subpar. (E) as (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s311/2">Pub. L. 107–251, § 311(2)</ref>, struck out subsec. (e) which related to service under National Research Service Award program as credit against obligated service time.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597">Pub. L. 101–597</ref> substituted reference to health professional shortage area for reference to health manpower shortage area wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/100/607">Pub. L. 100–607</ref> substituted “osteopathic medicine” for “osteopathy” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/177/s306/1">Pub. L. 100–177, § 306(1)</ref>, inserted “or 254<i>l</i>–1”, and made technical amendment to reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254n">section 254n of this title</ref> to reflect renumbering of corresponding section of original act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/177/s306/2">Pub. L. 100–177, § 306(2)</ref>, inserted reference to section 254<i>l</i>–l(f)(1)(B)(iv).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/100/177/s306/3">Pub. L. 100–177, § 306(3)</ref>, substituted par. (5) consisting of subpars. (A) to (E) for former par. (5) consisting of subpars. (A) and (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/100/177/s306/4">Pub. L. 100–177, § 306(4)</ref>, made technical amendment to reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254n">section 254n of this title</ref> to reflect renumbering of corresponding section of original act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/97/414">Pub. L. 97–414</ref> inserted “or under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s234">section 234 of this title</ref> as in effect on <date date="1977-09-30">September 30, 1977</date>” after “Scholarship Program”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2709/c/1">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2709(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “254n” for “294v” and “254<i>l</i>” for “294t”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2709/c/2">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2709(c)(2)</ref>, substituted provisions relating to notice, information, etc., for individuals required to give obligated service, for provisions relating to notice, information, etc., for individuals required to provide service under the Scholarship Program.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2709/c/3">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2709(c)(3)</ref>, (4), in par. (1) inserted reference to designation under subsec. (b)(3) or (4) of this section, and in par. (2) substituted “254n” for “294v”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2709/c/5">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2709(c)(5)</ref>, inserted provision relating to individuals who are officers in the Service or civilian employees of the United States, and substituted reference to sections 254d to 254h, 254j, and 254k of this title, for reference to subpart II of part D of subchapter II of this chapter.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2709/c/6">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2709(c)(6)</ref>, substituted provisions respecting mandatory determination of service requirement, for provisions respecting discretionary determination of service requirement.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1979—Subsec. (b)(5)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/96/76/s202/a">Pub. L. 96–76, § 202(a)</ref>, (b)(1), (2), inserted provisions authorizing a greater period than three years for individuals receiving degrees from schools of medicine, osteopathy, and dentistry, and provisions respecting individuals receiving degrees from schools of veterinary medicine, optometry, podiatry, and pharmacy, and substituted “No period” for “No such period”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/96/76/s202/b/3">Pub. L. 96–76, § 202(b)(3)</ref>, substituted “referred to in subparagraph (A)” for “of medicine, osteopathy, or dentistry”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1978—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/95/626">Pub. L. 95–626</ref> substituted “subpart II of part D” for “subpart II of part C”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb4fa0c61-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idb4fa0c62-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reference to Reserve Corps of the Public Health Service deemed to be a reference to the Ready Reserve Corps, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s204/c/3">section 204(c)(3) of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb4fa0c63-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1981 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXVII/s2709/h">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXVII, § 2709(h)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/912">95 Stat. 912</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/97/35/tXXVII/s2709/h">“The amendments made by paragraphs (2), (3), and (5)(B) of subsection (c) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to contracts entered into under the National Health Service Corps scholarship program under subpart III of part C of title VII of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s294r">42 U.S.C. 294r</ref> et seq.] after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>]. An individual who before such date has entered into such a contract and who has not begun the period of obligated service required under such contract shall be given the opportunity to revise such contract to permit the individual to serve such period as a member of the National Health Service Corps who is not an employee of the United States.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb4fa0c64-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1977-10-01">Oct. 1, 1977</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/484/s408/b/1">section 408(b)(1) of Pub. L. 94–484</ref>, set out in part as a note under section 254<i>l</i> of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb4fa0c65-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date; Savings Provision; Credit for Period of Internship or Residency Before <date date="1977-09-30">September 30, 1977</date>, <inline class="small-caps">Towards Service Obligation</inline></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">See <ref href="/us/pl/94/484/s408/b/2">section 408(b)(2) of Pub. L. 94–484</ref>, set out as a note under section 254<i>l</i> of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb4fa0c66-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Special Retention Pay for Regular or Reserve Officers for Period Officer Is Obligated Under This Section</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/446/tII">Pub. L. 100–446, title II</ref>, <date date="1988-09-27">Sept. 27, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/1816">102 Stat. 1816</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/446/tII">“the Secretary of Health and Human Services may authorize special retention pay under paragraph (4) of <ref href="/us/usc/t37/s302/a">37 U.S.C. 302(a)</ref> to any regular or reserve officer for the period during which the officer is obligated under section 338B [now 338C] of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254m">42 U.S.C. 254m</ref>] and assigned and providing direct health services or serving the officer’s obligation as a specialist”.</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>Similar provisions were contained in the following prior appropriation acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/202/s101/g/tII">Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(g) [title II]</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1329-213">101 Stat. 1329–213</ref>, 1329–246.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/500/s101/h/tII">Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(h) [title II]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-18">Oct. 18, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/1783-242">100 Stat. 1783–242</ref>, 1783–277, and <ref href="/us/pl/99/591/s101/h/tII">Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(h) [title II]</ref>, <date date="1986-10-30">Oct. 30, 1986</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/100/3341-242">100 Stat. 3341–242</ref>, 3341–277.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
