<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb4fa0c85-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o"><num value="254o">§ 254o.</num><heading> Breach of scholarship contract or loan repayment contract</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4fa0c86-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to maintain academic standing; dismissal from institution; voluntary termination; liability; failure to accept payment</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fa0c87-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> An individual who has entered into a written contract with the Secretary under section 254<i>l</i> of this title and who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fa0c88-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> fails to maintain an acceptable level of academic standing in the educational institution in which he is enrolled (such level determined by the educational institution under regulations of the Secretary);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fa0c89-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> is dismissed from such educational institution for disciplinary reasons; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fa0c8a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> voluntarily terminates the training in such an educational institution for which he is provided a scholarship under such contract, before the completion of such training,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">in lieu of any service obligation arising under such contract, shall be liable to the United States for the amount which has been paid to him, or on his behalf, under the contract.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fa0c8b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> An individual who has entered into a written contract with the Secretary under section 254<i>l</i>–1 of this title and who—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fa0c8c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> in the case of an individual who is enrolled in the final year of a course of study, fails to maintain an acceptable level of academic standing in the educational institution in which such individual is enrolled (such level determined by the educational institution under regulations of the Secretary) or voluntarily terminates such enrollment or is dismissed from such educational institution before completion of such course of study; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fa0c8d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> in the case of an individual who is enrolled in a graduate training program, fails to complete such training program and does not receive a waiver from the Secretary under section 254<i>l</i>–1(b)(1)(B)(ii) of this title,</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">in lieu of any service obligation arising under such contract shall be liable to the United States for the amount that has been paid on behalf of the individual under the contract.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4fa0c8e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to commence or complete service obligations; formula to determine liability; payment to United States; recovery of delinquent damages; disclosure to credit reporting agencies</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fa0c8f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fa0c90-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Except as provided in paragraph (2), if an individual breaches his written contract by failing (for any reason not specified in subsection (a) or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254p/d">section 254p(d) of this title</ref>) to begin such individual’s service obligation under section 254<i>l</i> of this title in accordance with section 254m or 254n of this title, to complete such service obligation, or to complete a required residency as specified in section 254<i>l</i>(f)(1)(B)(iv) of this title, the United States shall be entitled to recover from the individual an amount determined in accordance with the formula</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I580483" class="centered">    t−s</continuation>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I580483" class="centered">A= 3ϕ <inline class="small-caps">A</inline>——<inline class="small-caps">B</inline></continuation>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I580483" class="centered">    t</continuation>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">in which “A” is the amount the United States is entitled to recover, “ϕ” is the sum of the amounts paid under this subpart to or on behalf of the individual and the interest on such amounts which would be payable if at the time the amounts were paid they were loans bearing interest at the maximum legal prevailing rate, as determined by the Treasurer of the United States; “t” is the total number of months in the individual’s period of obligated service; and “s” is the number of months of such period served by him in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254m">section 254m of this title</ref> or a written agreement under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254n">section 254n of this title</ref>.</continuation>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fa0c91-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fa0c92-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/b/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Any amount of damages that the United States is entitled to recover under this subsection or under subsection (c) shall, within the 1-year period beginning on the date of the breach of the written contract (or such longer period beginning on such date as specified by the Secretary), be paid to the United States. Amounts not paid within such period shall be subject to collection through deductions in Medicare payments pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ccc">section 1395ccc of this title</ref>.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fa0c93-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/b/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><chapeau> If damages described in clause (i) are delinquent for 3 months, the Secretary shall, for the purpose of recovering such damages—</chapeau><subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fa0c94-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/b/1/B/ii/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> utilize collection agencies contracted with by the Administrator of the General Services Administration; or</content>
</subclause>
<subclause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fa0c95-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/b/1/B/ii/II"><num value="II">(II)</num><content> enter into contracts for the recovery of such damages with collection agencies selected by the Secretary.</content>
</subclause>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fa0c96-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/b/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> Each contract for recovering damages pursuant to this subsection shall provide that the contractor will, not less than once each 6 months, submit to the Secretary a status report on the success of the contractor in collecting such damages. <ref href="/us/usc/t31/s3718">Section 3718 of title 31</ref> shall apply to any such contract to the extent not inconsistent with this subsection.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fa0c97-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/b/1/B/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> To the extent not otherwise prohibited by law, the Secretary shall disclose to all appropriate credit reporting agencies information relating to damages of more than $100 that are entitled to be recovered by the United States under this subsection and that are delinquent by more than 60 days or such longer period as is determined by the Secretary.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fa0c98-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> If an individual is released under section 254n <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002092">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002092"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of this title from a service obligation under section 234 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002092">1</ref> of this title (as in effect on <date date="1977-09-30">September 30, 1977</date>) and if the individual does not meet the service obligation incurred under section 254n <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002092">1</ref> of this title, subsection (f) of such section 234 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002092">1</ref> of this title shall apply to such individual in lieu of paragraph (1) of this subsection.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fa0c99-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> The Secretary may terminate a contract with an individual under section 254<i>l</i> of this title if, not later than 30 days before the end of the school year to which the contract pertains, the individual—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fa0c9a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> submits a written request for such termination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fa0c9b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> repays all amounts paid to, or on behalf of, the individual under section 254<i>l</i>(g) of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4fa0c9c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to commence or complete service obligations for other reasons; determination of liability; payment to United States; waiver of recovery for extreme hardship or good cause shown</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fa0c9d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> If (for any reason not specified in subsection (a) or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254p/d">section 254p(d) of this title</ref>) an individual breaches the written contract of the individual under section 254<i>l</i>–1 of this title by failing either to begin such individual’s service obligation in accordance with section 254m or 254n of this title or to complete such service obligation, the United States shall be entitled to recover from the individual an amount equal to the sum of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fa0c9e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the total of the amounts paid by the United States under section 254<i>l</i>–1(g) of this title on behalf of the individual for any period of obligated service not served;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fa0c9f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> an amount equal to the product of the number of months of obligated service that were not completed by the individual, multiplied by $7,500; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fc5590-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/c/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the interest on the amounts described in subparagraphs (A) and (B), at the maximum legal prevailing rate, as determined by the Treasurer of the United States, from the date of the breach;</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">except that the amount the United States is entitled to recover under this paragraph shall not be less than $31,000.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fc5591-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The Secretary may terminate a contract with an individual under section 254<i>l</i>–1 of this title if, not later than 45 days before the end of the fiscal year in which the contract was entered into, the individual—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fc5592-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> submits a written request for such termination; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb4fc5593-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> repays all amounts paid on behalf of the individual under section 254<i>l</i>–1(g) of this title.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fc5594-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> Damages that the United States is entitled to recover shall be paid in accordance with subsection (b)(1)(B).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4fc5595-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Cancellation of obligation upon death of individual; waiver or suspension of obligation for impossibility, hardship, or unconscionability; release of debt by discharge in bankruptcy, time limitations</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fc5596-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Any obligation of an individual under the Scholarship Program (or a contract thereunder) or the Loan Repayment Program (or a contract thereunder) for service or payment of damages shall be canceled upon the death of the individual.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fc5597-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Secretary shall by regulation provide for the partial or total waiver or suspension of any obligation of service or payment by an individual under the Scholarship Program (or a contract thereunder) or the Loan Repayment Program (or a contract thereunder) whenever compliance by the individual is impossible or would involve extreme hardship to the individual and if enforcement of such obligation with respect to any individual would be unconscionable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fc5598-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fc5599-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Any obligation of an individual under the Scholarship Program (or a contract thereunder) or the Loan Repayment Program (or a contract thereunder) for payment of damages may be released by a discharge in bankruptcy under title 11 only if such discharge is granted after the expiration of the 7-year period beginning on the first date that payment of such damages is required, and only if the bankruptcy court finds that nondischarge of the obligation would be unconscionable.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fc559a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fc559b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/d/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Subparagraph (A) shall apply to any financial obligation of an individual under the provision of law specified in clause (ii) to the same extent and in the same manner as such subparagraph applies to any obligation of an individual under the Scholarship or Loan Repayment Program (or contract thereunder) for payment of damages.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb4fc559c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/d/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The provision of law referred to in clause (i) is subsection (f) of section 234 <sup>1</sup> of this title, as in effect prior to the repeal of such section by <ref href="/us/pl/94/484/s408/b/1">section 408(b)(1) of Public Law 94–484</ref>.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4fc559d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Inapplicability of Federal and State statute of limitations on actions for collection</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of Federal or State law, there shall be no limitation on the period within which suit may be filed, a judgment may be enforced, or an action relating to an offset or garnishment, or other action, may be initiated or taken by the Secretary, the Attorney General, or the head of another Federal agency, as the case may be, for the repayment of the amount due from an individual under this section.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb4fc559e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s254o/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Effective date</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The amendment made by section 313(a)(4) of the Health Care Safety Net Amendments of 2002 (<ref href="/us/pl/107/251">Public Law 107–251</ref>) shall apply to any obligation for which a discharge in bankruptcy has not been granted before the date that is 31 days after <date date="2002-10-26">October 26, 2002</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb4fc559f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title III, § 338E, formerly title VII, § 754, as added <ref href="/us/pl/94/484/tIV/s408/b/1">Pub. L. 94–484, title IV, § 408(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2286">90 Stat. 2286</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/95/83/tIII/s307/g">Pub. L. 95–83, title III, § 307(g)</ref>, <date date="1977-08-01">Aug. 1, 1977</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/91/391">91 Stat. 391</ref>; renumbered § 338D and amended <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXVII/s2709/a">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXVII, § 2709(a)</ref>, (e)(1)–(4)(A), <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/908">95 Stat. 908</ref>, 911; <ref href="/us/pl/97/414/s8/g/2">Pub. L. 97–414, § 8(g)(2)</ref>, <date date="1983-01-04">Jan. 4, 1983</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/96/2061">96 Stat. 2061</ref>; renumbered § 338E and amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/177/tII">Pub. L. 100–177, title II</ref>, §§ 201(2), 202(e), title III, § 308(a), <date date="1987-12-01">Dec. 1, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/992">101 Stat. 992</ref>, 997, 1006; <ref href="/us/pl/100/203/tIV/s4052/b">Pub. L. 100–203, title IV, § 4052(b)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-22">Dec. 22, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1330-97">101 Stat. 1330–97</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/360/tIV/s411/f/10/B">Pub. L. 100–360, title IV, § 411(f)(10)(B)</ref>, <date date="1988-07-01">July 1, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/780">102 Stat. 780</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/597/tII/s203/a">Pub. L. 101–597, title II, § 203(a)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3027">104 Stat. 3027</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/tIII/s313/a">Pub. L. 107–251, title III, § 313(a)</ref>, <date date="2002-10-26">Oct. 26, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1651">116 Stat. 1651</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/108/163/s2">Pub. L. 108–163, § 2</ref>(<i>l</i>)(1), <date date="2003-12-06">Dec. 6, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2022">117 Stat. 2022</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb4fc55a0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb4fc55a1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb4fc55a2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s234">Section 234 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsecs. (b)(2) and (d)(3)(B)(ii), was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/94/484/tIV/s408/b/1">Pub. L. 94–484, title IV, § 408(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1976-10-12">Oct. 12, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/2281">90 Stat. 2281</ref>, effective <date date="1977-10-01">Oct. 1, 1977</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254n">Section 254n of this title</ref>, referred to in subsec. (b)(2), in the original referred to section 753, meaning section 753 of the Public Health Service Act, which was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s294v">section 294v of this title</ref>. Section 753 was redesignated section 338C of the Public Health Service Act by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/tXXVII/s2709/a">Pub. L. 97–35, title XXVII, § 2709(a)</ref>, <date date="1981-08-13">Aug. 13, 1981</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/95/908">95 Stat. 908</ref>, and was transferred to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254n">section 254n of this title</ref>. Section 338C of the Public Health Service Act was renumbered section 338D by <ref href="/us/pl/100/177/tII/s201/2">Pub. L. 100–177, title II, § 201(2)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-01">Dec. 1, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/992">101 Stat. 992</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 313(a)(4) of the Health Care Safety Net Amendments of 2002, referred to in subsec. (f), is <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s313/a/4">section 313(a)(4) of Pub. L. 107–251</ref>, which amended subsec. (d)(3)(A) of this section. See 2002 Amendment note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb4fc55a3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was formerly classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s294w">section 294w of this title</ref> prior to its renumbering by <ref href="/us/pl/97/35">Pub. L. 97–35</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idb4fc55a4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 338E of act <date date="1944-07-01">July 1, 1944</date>, was renumbered section 338F by <ref href="/us/pl/100/177">Pub. L. 100–177</ref> and classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254p">section 254p of this title</ref>, and subsequently renumbered 338G by <ref href="/us/pl/101/597">Pub. L. 101–597</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb4fc55a5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2003—Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/108/163/s2">Pub. L. 108–163, § 2</ref>(<i>l</i>)(1)(A), realigned margins.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/108/163/s2">Pub. L. 108–163, § 2</ref>(<i>l</i>)(1)(B), added subsec. (f).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s313/a/1">Pub. L. 107–251, § 313(a)(1)</ref>, substituted semicolon for comma at end of subpar. (A) and “; or” for comma at end of subpar. (B), struck out “or” at end of subpar. (C), and struck out subpar. (D) which read as follows: “fails to accept payment, or instructs the educational institution in which he is enrolled not to accept payment, in whole or in part, of a scholarship under such contract,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s313/a/2/A/ii">Pub. L. 107–251, § 313(a)(2)(A)(ii)</ref>–(iv), struck out “either” before “to begin”, substituted “254n of this title,” for “254n of this title or”, and inserted “or to complete a required residency as specified in section 254<i>l</i>(f)(1)(B)(iv) of this title,” before “the United States” the first time appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s313/a/2/A/i">Pub. L. 107–251, § 313(a)(2)(A)(i)</ref>, made technical amendment to reference in original act which appears in text as reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254p">section 254p of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s313/a/2/B">Pub. L. 107–251, § 313(a)(2)(B)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s313/a/3/A/ii">Pub. L. 107–251, § 313(a)(3)(A)(ii)</ref>, added subpars. (A) to (C) and concluding provisions and struck out former subpars. (A) to (C) which related, respectively, to amounts to be recovered in the case of a contract for a 2-year period of obligated service, in the case of a contract for a period of obligated service of greater than 2 years where the breach occurred before the end of the first 2 years of such period, and in the case of a contract for a period of obligated service of greater than 2 years, where the breach occurred after the first 2 years of such period.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s313/a/3/A/i">Pub. L. 107–251, § 313(a)(3)(A)(i)</ref>, in introductory provisions, made technical amendment to reference in original act which appears in text as reference to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254p/d">section 254p(d) of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s313/a/3/B">Pub. L. 107–251, § 313(a)(3)(B)</ref>, added par. (2) and struck out former par. (2) which read as follows: “For purposes of paragraph (1), the term ‘unserved obligation penalty’ means the amount equal to the product of the number of months of obligated service that were not completed by an individual, multiplied by $1,000, except that in any case in which the individual fails to serve 1 year, the unserved obligation penalty shall be equal to the full period of obligated service multiplied by $1,000.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s313/a/3/B">Pub. L. 107–251, § 313(a)(3)(B)</ref>, (C), redesignated par. (4) as (3) and struck out former par. (3) which read as follows: “The Secretary may waive, in whole or in part, the rights of the United States to recover amounts under this section in any case of extreme hardship or other good cause shown, as determined by the Secretary.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s313/a/4">Pub. L. 107–251, § 313(a)(4)</ref>, substituted “7-year period” for “five-year period”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s313/a/5">Pub. L. 107–251, § 313(a)(5)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (d)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/101/597">Pub. L. 101–597</ref> designated existing provision as subpar. (A) and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (b)(1)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/100/360">Pub. L. 100–360</ref> made technical amendment to directory language of <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref>, see 1987 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1987—<ref href="/us/pl/100/177/s202/e/6">Pub. L. 100–177, § 202(e)(6)</ref>, inserted “or loan repayment contract” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/100/177/s202/e/1">Pub. L. 100–177, § 202(e)(1)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), and former pars. (1) to (4) as subpars. (A) to (D), respectively, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/177/s202/e/2">Pub. L. 100–177, § 202(e)(2)</ref>, designated existing provisions as subpar. (A), made technical amendments to references to sections 254m, 254n, and 254p of this title wherever appearing to reflect renumbering of corresponding sections of original act, inserted “under section 254<i>l</i> of this title” after first reference to “service obligation” as the probable intent of Congress, struck out at end “Any amount of damages which the United States is entitled to recover under this subsection shall, within the one year period beginning on the date of the breach of the written contract (or such longer period beginning on such date as specified by the Secretary for good cause shown), be paid to the United States.”, and added subpar. (B).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B)(i). <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref>, as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/100/360">Pub. L. 100–360</ref>, inserted at end “Amounts not paid within such period shall be subject to collection through deductions in Medicare payments pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1395ccc">section 1395ccc of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/100/177/s202/e/4">Pub. L. 100–177, § 202(e)(4)</ref>, added subsec. (c). Former subsec. (c) redesignated (d).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/100/177">Pub. L. 100–177</ref>, §§ 202(e)(3), (5), 308(a), redesignated subsec. (c) as (d), in pars. (1), (2), and (3), inserted “or the Loan Repayment Program (or a contract thereunder”, and in par. (3) inserted “, and only if the bankruptcy court finds that nondischarge of the obligation would be unconscionable”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1983—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/97/414">Pub. L. 97–414</ref> substituted “section 254p(d)” for “section 254q(b)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1981—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2709/e/1">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2709(e)(1)</ref>, (2), redesignated subsec. (b) as (a) and, as so redesignated, in introductory text substituted “254<i>l</i>” for “294t” and added par. (4). Former subsec. (a), which related to liability of individual upon failure to accept payment, was struck out.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2709/e/1">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2709(e)(1)</ref>, (3), redesignated subsec. (c) as (b) and, as so redesignated, designated existing provisions as par. (1) and made numerous changes to reflect renumbering of subpart sections, and added par. (2). Former subsec. (b) redesignated (a).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/97/35/s2709/e/1">Pub. L. 97–35, § 2709(e)(1)</ref>, (4)(A), redesignated subsec. (d) as (c) and, as so redesignated, in par. (2) inserted reference to partial or total waiver. Former subsec. (c) redesignated (b).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1977—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/95/83">Pub. L. 95–83</ref> substituted “ ‘ϕ’ is the sum of the amounts paid under this subpart to or on behalf of the individual and the interest on such amounts which would be payable if at the time the amounts were paid they were loans” for “ ‘ϕ’ is the sum of the amount paid under this subpart to or on behalf of the individual and the interest on such amount which would be payable if at the time it was paid it was a loan”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb4fc55a6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb4fc55a7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2003 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendments by <ref href="/us/pl/108/163">Pub. L. 108–163</ref> deemed to have taken effect immediately after the enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/107/251">Pub. L. 107–251</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/108/163/s3">section 3 of Pub. L. 108–163</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s233">section 233 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb4fc55a8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2002 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/107/251/tIII/s313/b">Pub. L. 107–251, title III, § 313(b)</ref>, <date date="2002-10-26">Oct. 26, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1652">116 Stat. 1652</ref>, which provided that the amendment to this section made by <ref href="/us/pl/107/251/s313/a/4">section 313(a)(4) of Pub. L. 107–251</ref> was applicable to any obligation for which a discharge in bankruptcy had not been granted before the date that was 31 days after <date date="2002-10-26">Oct. 26, 2002</date>, was repealed by <ref href="/us/pl/108/163">Pub. L. 108–163</ref>, §§ 2(<i>l</i>)(2), 3, <date date="2003-12-06">Dec. 6, 2003</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/117/2023">117 Stat. 2023</ref>, effective immediately after enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/107/251">Pub. L. 107–251</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb4fc55a9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1990 Amendment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/101/597/tII/s203/b">Pub. L. 101–597, title II, § 203(b)</ref>, <date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/3027">104 Stat. 3027</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/101/597/tII/s203/b">“With respect to any financial obligation of an individual under subsection (f) of section 225 of the Public Health Service Act [former <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s234">42 U.S.C. 234</ref>], as in effect prior to the repeal of such section by <ref href="/us/pl/94/484/s408/b/1">section 408(b)(1) of Public Law 94–484</ref>, the amendment made by subsection (a) of this section [amending this section] applies to any backruptcy [sic] proceeding in which discharge of such an obligation has not been granted before the date that is 31 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="1990-11-16">Nov. 16, 1990</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb4fc55aa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Except as specifically provided in <ref href="/us/pl/100/360/s411">section 411 of Pub. L. 100–360</ref>, amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/360">Pub. L. 100–360</ref>, as it relates to a provision in the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1987, <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref>, effective as if included in the enactment of that provision in <ref href="/us/pl/100/203">Pub. L. 100–203</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/360/s411/a">section 411(a) of Pub. L. 100–360</ref>, set out as a Reference to OBRA; Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t1/s106">section 106 of Title 1</ref>, General Provisions.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb4fc55ab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1977-10-01">Oct. 1, 1977</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/94/484/s408/b/1">section 408(b)(1) of Pub. L. 94–484</ref>, set out in part as a note under section 254<i>l</i> of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb4fc55ac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date; Savings Provision; Credit for Period of Internship or Residency Before <date date="1977-09-30">September 30, 1977</date>, Towards Service Obligation</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">See <ref href="/us/pl/94/484/s408/b/2">section 408(b)(2) of Pub. L. 94–484</ref>, set out as a note under section 254<i>l</i> of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb4fc55ad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Special Repayment Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/177/tII/s204">Pub. L. 100–177, title II, § 204</ref>, <date date="1987-12-01">Dec. 1, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1000">101 Stat. 1000</ref>, provided that an individual who breached a written contract entered into under section 254<i>l</i> of this title by failing either to begin such individual’s service obligation in accordance with <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254m">section 254m of this title</ref> or to complete such service obligation; or otherwise breached such a contract; and, as of <date date="1987-11-01">Nov. 1, 1987</date>, was liable to United States under subsec. (b) of this section was to be relieved of liability to United States under such section if the individual provided notice to Secretary and service in accordance with a written contract with the Secretary that obligated the individual to provide service in accordance with section and authorized Secretary to exclude an individual from relief from liability under this section for reasons related to the individual’s professional competence or conduct.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb4fc55ae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Existing Proceedings</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/100/177/tIII/s308/b">Pub. L. 100–177, title III, § 308(b)</ref>, <date date="1987-12-01">Dec. 1, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/1006">101 Stat. 1006</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/100/177/tIII/s308/b">“The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] applies to any bankruptcy proceeding in which discharge of an obligation under section 338E(d)(3) of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s254">42 U.S.C. 254</ref><i>o</i>(d)(3)] (as redesignated by sections 201(2) and 202(e)(3) of this Act) has not been granted before the date that is 31 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="1987-12-01">Dec. 1, 1987</date>].”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
