<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idbc25fc41-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2642"><num value="2642">§ 2642.</num><heading> Acceleration of public works</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc25fc42-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2642/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible areas</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purposes of this section the term “eligible area” means—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc25fc43-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2642/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> those areas which the Secretary of Labor designates each month as having been areas of substantial unemployment for at least nine of the preceding twelve months; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc25fc44-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2642/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> those areas which are designated by the Secretary of Commerce under subsections (a) and (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2504">section 2504 of this title</ref> as “redevelopment areas”.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc25fc45-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2642/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to initiate and accelerate projects; allocation of funds</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President is authorized to initiate and accelerate in eligible areas those Federal public works projects which have been authorized by Congress, and those public works projects of States and local governments for which Federal financial assistance is authorized under provisions of law other than this chapter, by allocating funds appropriated to carry out this section—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc25fc46-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2642/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to the heads of the departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the Federal Government responsible for the construction of Federal public works projects, and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc25fc47-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2642/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to the heads of the departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the Federal Government responsible for the administration of laws authorizing Federal financial assistance to public works projects of State and local governments.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc25fc48-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2642/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Grants-in-aid; law governing; amount of Federal contributions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">All grants-in-aid made from allocations made by the President under this section shall be made by the head of the department, agency, or instrumentality of the Federal Government administering the law authorizing such grants, and, except as otherwise provided in this subsection, shall be made in accordance with all of the provisions of such law except (1) provisions requiring allocation of funds among the States, and (2) limitations upon the total amount of such grants for any period. Notwithstanding any provisions of such law requiring the Federal contribution to the State or local government involved to be less than a fixed portion of the cost of a project, grants-in-aid may be made under authority of this section which bring the total of all Federal contributions to such project up to 50 per centum of the cost of such project, or up to 75 per centum of the cost of such project if the State or local government does not have economic and financial capacity to assume all of the additional financial obligations required.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc25fc49-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2642/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated not to exceed $900,000,000 to be allocated by the President in accordance with subsection (b) of this section, except that not less than $300,000,000 shall be allocated for public works projects in areas designated by the Secretary of Commerce as redevelopment areas under subsection (b) of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2504">section 2504 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc25fc4a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2642/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Rules and regulations; considerations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The President shall prescribe rules, regulations, and procedures to carry out this section which will assure that adequate consideration is given to the relative needs of eligible areas. In prescribing such rules, regulations, and procedures the President shall consider among other relevant factors (1) the severity of the rates of unemployment in the eligible areas and the duration of such unemployment and (2) the income levels of families and the extent of under­employment in eligible areas.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc25fc4b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2642/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Restrictions on allocated funds</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Funds allocated by the President under this section shall be available only for projects—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc25fc4c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2642/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> which can be initiated or accelerated within a reasonably short period of time;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc25fc4d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2642/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> which will meet an essential public need;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc25fc4e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2642/f/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a substantial portion of which can be completed within twelve months after initiation or acceleration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc25fc4f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2642/f/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> which will contribute significantly to the reduction of local unemployment;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idbc25fc50-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2642/f/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> which are not inconsistent with locally approved comprehensive plans for the jurisdiction affected, wherever such plans exist.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc25fc51-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2642/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Limit on allocations available for projects in any one State</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not more than 10 per centum of all amounts allocated by the President under this section shall be made available for public works projects within any one State.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idbc25fc52-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s2642/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Criteria determining substantial unemployment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The criteria to be used by the Secretary of Labor in determining areas of substantial unemployment for the purposes of paragraph (1) of subsection (a) of this section shall be the criteria established in section 6.3 of title 29 of the Code of Federal Regulations as in effect <date date="1962-05-01">May 1, 1962</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idbc25fc53-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/87/658/s3">Pub. L. 87–658, § 3</ref>, <date date="1962-09-14">Sept. 14, 1962</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/76/542">76 Stat. 542</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idbc25fc54-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idbc25fc55-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idbc25fc56-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t42/s2504">Section 2504 of this title</ref>, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (d), was omitted from the Code.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idbc25fc57-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I86" topic="executiveOrder" id="idbc25fc58-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Executive Order No. 11049</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Ex. Ord. No. 11049, <date date="1962-09-14">Sept. 14, 1962</date>, 27 F.R. 9203, which provided for implementation of public works acceleration program, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 12553, <date date="1986-02-25">Feb. 25, 1986</date>, 51 F.R. 7237.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
