<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb51dc11d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s271"><num value="271">§ 271.</num><heading> Penalties for violation of quarantine laws</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb51dc11e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s271/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Penalties for persons violating quarantine laws</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any person who violates any regulation prescribed under sections 264 to 266 of this title, or any provision of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s269">section 269 of this title</ref> or any regulation prescribed thereunder, or who enters or departs from the limits of any quarantine station, ground, or anchorage in disregard of quarantine rules and regulations or without permission of the quarantine officer in charge, shall be punished by a fine of not more than $1,000 or by imprisonment for not more than one year, or both.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb51dc11f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s271/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Penalties for vessels violating quarantine laws</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any vessel which violates <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s269">section 269 of this title</ref>, or any regulations thereunder or under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s267">section 267 of this title</ref>, or which enters within or departs from the limits of any quarantine station, ground, or anchorage in disregard of the quarantine rules and regulations or without permission of the officer in charge, shall forfeit to the United States not more than $5,000, the amount to be determined by the court, which shall be a lien on such vessel, to be recovered by proceedings in the proper district court of the United States. In all such proceedings the United States attorney shall appear on behalf of the United States; and all such proceedings shall be conducted in accordance with the rules and laws governing cases of seizure of vessels for violation of the revenue laws of the United States.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb51dc120-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s271/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Remittance or mitigation of forfeitures</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With the approval of the Secretary, the Surgeon General may, upon application therefor, remit or mitigate any forfeiture provided for under subsection (b) of this section, and he shall have authority to ascertain the facts upon all such applications.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb51dc121-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title III, § 368, <ref href="/us/stat/58/706">58 Stat. 706</ref>; <ref href="/us/act/1948-06-25/ch646/s1">June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 1</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/62/909">62 Stat. 909</ref>; 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 1, §§ 5, 8, eff. <date date="1953-04-11">Apr. 11, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 2053, <ref href="/us/stat/67/631">67 Stat. 631</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb51dc122-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb51dc123-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idb51dc124-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Health and Human Services” substituted for “Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare” pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/s509/b">section 509(b) of Pub. L. 96–88</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s3508/b">section 3508(b) of Title 20</ref>, Education.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Act <date date="1948-06-25">June 25, 1948</date>, eff. <date date="1948-09-01">Sept. 1, 1948</date>, substituted “United States attorney” for “United States district attorney”. See <ref href="/us/usc/t28/s541">section 541 of Title 28</ref>, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure, and Historical and Revision note thereunder.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idb51dc125-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idb51dc126-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Office of Surgeon General abolished by section 3 of Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1966, eff. <date date="1966-06-25">June 25, 1966</date>, 31 F.R. 8855, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1610">80 Stat. 1610</ref>, and functions thereof transferred to Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare by section 1 of Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1966, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s202">section 202 of this title</ref>. Office of Surgeon General reestablished within the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Health, see Notice of Department of Health and Human Services, Office of the Assistant Secretary for Health, <date date="1987-03-30">Mar. 30, 1987</date>, 52 F.R. 11754.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Functions of Federal Security Administrator transferred to Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare and all agencies of Federal Security Agency transferred to Department of Health, Education, and Welfare by section 5 of Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1953, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3501">section 3501 of this title</ref>. Federal Security Agency and office of Administrator abolished by section 8 of Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1953.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
