<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb52c194e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280c–3"><num value="280c–3">§ 280c–3.</num><heading> Cooperative agreements to States and public health departments for Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb52c194f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280c–3/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, in coordination with the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the heads of other agencies, as appropriate, shall award cooperative agreements to health departments of States, political subdivisions of States, and Indian tribes and tribal organizations, to address Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias, including by reducing cognitive decline, helping meet the needs of caregivers, and addressing unique aspects of Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias to support the development and implementation of evidence-based interventions with respect to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb52c1950-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280c–3/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> educating and informing the public, based on evidence-based public health research and data, about Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb52c1951-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280c–3/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> supporting early detection and diagnosis;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb52c1952-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280c–3/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> reducing the risk of potentially avoidable hospitalizations for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb52c1953-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280c–3/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> reducing the risk of cognitive decline and cognitive impairment associated with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb52c1954-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280c–3/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> improving support to meet the needs of caregivers of individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb52c1955-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280c–3/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> supporting care planning and management for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias.<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002133">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002133"><num>1</num> So in original. The period probably should be “; and”.</note></content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb52c1956-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280c–3/a/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> supporting other relevant activities identified by the Secretary or the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, as appropriate <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002134">2</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002134"><num>2</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by a period.</note></content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb52c1957-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280c–3/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Preference</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In awarding cooperative agreements under this section, the Secretary shall give preference to applications that focus on addressing health disparities, including populations and geographic areas that have the highest prevalence of Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb52c1958-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280c–3/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To be eligible to receive a cooperative agreement under this section, an eligible entity (pursuant to subsection (a)) shall prepare and submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including a plan that describes—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb52c1959-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280c–3/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> how the applicant proposes to develop or expand, programs to educate individuals through partnership engagement, workforce development, guidance and support for programmatic efforts, and evaluation with respect to Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias, and in the case of a cooperative agreement under this section, how the applicant proposes to support other relevant activities identified by the Secretary or Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, as appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb52c195a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280c–3/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the manner in which the applicant will coordinate with Federal, tribal, and State programs related to Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias, and appropriate State, tribal, and local agencies, as well as other relevant public and private organizations or agencies; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb52c195b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280c–3/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the manner in which the applicant will evaluate the effectiveness of any program carried out under the cooperative agreement.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb52c195c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280c–3/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Matching requirement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each health department that is awarded a cooperative agreement under subsection (a) shall provide, from non-Federal sources, an amount equal to 30 percent of the amount provided under such agreement (which may be provided in cash or in-kind) to carry out the activities supported by the cooperative agreement.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb52c195d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280c–3/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Waiver authority</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may waive all or part of the matching requirement described in subsection (d) for any fiscal year for a health department of a State, political subdivision of a State, or Indian tribe and tribal organization (including those located in a rural area or frontier area), if the Secretary determines that applying such matching requirement would result in serious hardship or an inability to carry out the purposes of the cooperative agreement awarded to such health department of a State, political subdivision of a State, or Indian tribe and tribal organization.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb52c195e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280c–3/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Non-duplication of effort</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall ensure that activities under any cooperative agreement awarded under this subpart do not unnecessarily duplicate efforts of other agencies and offices within the Department of Health and Human Services related to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb52c195f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280c–3/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> activities of centers of excellence with respect to Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias described in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s280c–4">section 280c–4 of this title</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb52c1960-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280c–3/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> activities of public health departments with respect to Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias described in this section.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb52c1961-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280c–3/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Relationship to items and services under other programs</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">A State may not make payments from a cooperative agreement under subsection (a) for any item or service to the extent that payment has been made, or can reasonably be expected to be made, with respect to such item or service—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb52c1962-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280c–3/g/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> under any State compensation program, under an insurance policy, or under any Federal or State health benefits program; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb52c1963-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280c–3/g/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> by an entity that provides health services on a prepaid basis.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb52c1964-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title III, § 398, as added <ref href="/us/pl/100/175/tVI/s602">Pub. L. 100–175, title VI, § 602</ref>, <date date="1987-11-29">Nov. 29, 1987</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/101/981">101 Stat. 981</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/101/557/tI/s102/a">Pub. L. 101–557, title I, § 102(a)</ref>, (b), <date date="1990-11-15">Nov. 15, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2767">104 Stat. 2767</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/392/tIII/s302/a">Pub. L. 105–392, title III, § 302(a)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-13">Nov. 13, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3586">112 Stat. 3586</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/115/406/s3">Pub. L. 115–406, § 3</ref>, <date date="2018-12-31">Dec. 31, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/5365">132 Stat. 5365</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb52e6255-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb52e6256-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idb52e6257-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 398 of <ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373/tIII">act July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title III</ref>, formerly § 399a, as added <date date="1965-10-22">Oct. 22, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/89/291/s2">Pub. L. 89–291, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/1066">79 Stat. 1066</ref>; renumbered § 399, <date date="1970-03-13">Mar. 13, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/91/212/s10/c/3">Pub. L. 91–212, § 10(c)(3)</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/67">84 Stat. 67</ref>; renumbered § 398, <date date="1974-07-23">July 23, 1974</date>, <ref href="/us/pl/93/353/tII/s204">Pub. L. 93–353, title II, § 204</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/373">88 Stat. 373</ref>, which related to the continuing availability of appropriated funds, was classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s280b–10">section 280b–10 of this title</ref>, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/99/158/s3/b">Pub. L. 99–158, § 3(b)</ref>, <date date="1985-11-20">Nov. 20, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/879">99 Stat. 879</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb52e6258-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2018—<ref href="/us/pl/115/406/s3/1">Pub. L. 115–406, § 3(1)</ref>, substituted “Cooperative agreements to States and public health departments for Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias” for “Establishment of program” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/115/406/s3/2">Pub. L. 115–406, § 3(2)</ref>, added subsec. (a) and struck out former subsec. (a) which provided that the Secretary would make grants to States for planning, establishing, and operating programs to provide care to Alzheimer’s patients.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (b) to (e). <ref href="/us/pl/115/406/s3/3">Pub. L. 115–406, § 3(3)</ref>, (5), added subsecs. (b) to (e) and struck out former subsec. (b). Prior to amendment, text of subsec. (b) read as follows: “The Secretary may not make a grant under subsection (a) to a State unless the State agrees to expend not less than 50 percent of the grant for the provision of services described in subsection (a)(2).” Former subsec. (c) redesignated (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (f). <ref href="/us/pl/115/406/s3/7">Pub. L. 115–406, § 3(7)</ref>, which directed adding subsec. (f) at the end of the section, was executed by adding subsec. (f) before subsec. (g) as redesignated by <ref href="/us/pl/115/406/s3/4">Pub. L. 115–406, § 3(4)</ref>, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g). <ref href="/us/pl/115/406/s3/6">Pub. L. 115–406, § 3(6)</ref>, which directed amendment of “subsection (f) (as so redesignated)” by substituting “cooperative agreement” for “grant”, was executed by making the substitution in introductory provisions of subsec. (g) as redesignated, to reflect the probable intent of Congress. See below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/115/406/s3/4">Pub. L. 115–406, § 3(4)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (c) as (g).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/105/392/s302/a/1">Pub. L. 105–392, § 302(a)(1)</ref>, struck out “not less than 5, and not more than 15,” after “shall make” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/105/392/s302/a/2">Pub. L. 105–392, § 302(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “who are living in single family homes or in congregate settings” after “disorders” and struck out “and” at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3), (4). <ref href="/us/pl/105/392/s302/a/3">Pub. L. 105–392, § 302(a)(3)</ref>, (4), added par. (3) and redesignated former par. (3) as (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1990—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/101/557/s102/a">Pub. L. 101–557, § 102(a)</ref>, substituted “shall make not less than 5, and not more than 15, grants” for “shall make not less than 3, and not more than 5, grants”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/101/557/s102/b">Pub. L. 101–557, § 102(b)</ref>, substituted “with public and private organizations” for “by public and private organizations”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb52e6259-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb52e625a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section effective <date date="1987-10-01">Oct. 1, 1987</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/175/s701/a">section 701(a) of Pub. L. 100–175</ref>, set out as an Effective Date of 1987 Amendment note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s3001">section 3001 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
