<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb53a70b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a"><num value="280g–4a">§ 280g–4a.</num><heading> Understanding sexual assault care in health systems</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb53a70b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Purpose</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">It is the purpose of this section to identify areas for improvement in health care delivery systems providing forensic examinations to survivors of sexual assault.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb53a70b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Grants</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as “the Secretary”) shall award grants to States and Indian Tribes to develop and implement State and Tribal surveys to identify—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53a70b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the availability of, and patient access to, medical forensic examinations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53a70b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the training level of the health care providers who perform medical forensic examinations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53a70b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the hospitals or clinics that offer medical forensic examinations and whether each hospital or clinic has full-time, part-time, or on-call coverage;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53a70b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> barriers to medical forensic examinations provided through sexual assault care and services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53a70b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> billing and reimbursement practices for medical forensic examinations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53a70b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> State and Tribal requirements, minimum standards, and protocols for training sexual assault examiners for sexual assault forensic examiners and for other personnel involved in medical forensic examinations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53a70ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> the availability of sexual assault forensic examiner training, the frequency of such training, the providers of such training, the State’s or Indian Tribe’s role in such training, and the processes or procedures in place for continuing education of such examiners; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53a70bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> the dedicated Federal and State funding available to support sexual assault forensic examiner training.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb53a70bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a State or Indian Tribe shall submit to the Secretary an application through a competitive process to be determined by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb53a70bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Public dissemination and campaign</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb53a70be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Public availability</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The results of the surveys conducted under grants awarded under this section shall be published by the Secretary on the website of the Department of Health and Human Services on a biennial basis.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb53a70bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Campaigns</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A State or Indian Tribe that receives a grant under this section shall carry out the following activities:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb53a70c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a/d/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Make the findings of the survey conducted using amounts received under the grant public, including a map showing health care providers who perform medical forensic examinations, based on the findings from the State and Tribal surveys under subsection (b)(3).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb53a70c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a/d/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Use the findings to develop a strategic action plan to increase the number of trained medical forensic examiners available in the State or Tribal community and create policies to increase survivor access to trained examiners.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb53a70c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a/d/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><chapeau> Use the findings to develop and implement a public awareness campaign that includes the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb53a70c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a/d/2/C/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> An online toolkit describing how and where sexual assault survivors can obtain assistance and care, including medical forensic examinations, in the State or Tribal community.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb53a70c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a/d/2/C/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> A model standard response protocol for health care providers to implement upon arrival of a patient seeking care for sexual assault.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb53a70c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a/d/2/C/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> A model sexual assault response team protocol incorporating interdisciplinary community coordination between hospitals, emergency departments, hospital administration, local rape crisis programs, law enforcement, prosecuting attorneys, and other health and human service agencies and stakeholders with respect to delivering survivor-centered sexual assault care and medical forensic examinations.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb53a70c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a/d/2/C/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> A notice of applicable laws prohibiting charging or billing survivors of sexual assault for care and services related to sexual assault.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb53a70c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $7,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb53a70c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dW/tV/s503">Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title V, § 503</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/874">136 Stat. 874</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb53a70c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb53a70ca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb53a70cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Violence Against Women Act Reauthorization Act of 2022, and also as part of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2022, and not as part of the Public Health Service Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb53a70cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb53a70cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section not effective until Oct. 1 of the first fiscal year beginning after <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dW/s4/a">section 4(a) of div. W of Pub. L. 117–103</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t15/s6851">section 6851 of Title 15</ref>, Commerce and Trade.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb53a70ce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">National Report on Sexual Assault Services in Nation’s Health System</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dW/tV/s504">Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title V, § 504</ref>, <date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/876">136 Stat. 876</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/103/dW/tV/s504">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-03-15">Mar. 15, 2022</date>], and annually thereafter, the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, in consultation with the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Health Resources and Services Administration, the Indian Health Service, the Office for Victims of Crime of the Department of Justice, the Office on Women’s Health of the Department of Health and Human Services, and the Office of Violence Against Women of the Department of Justice (collectively referred to in this section as the ‘Agencies’), shall submit to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as ‘the Secretary’) a report of existing Federal, Indian Tribe, and State practices relating to medical forensic examinations which may include the findings of the surveys developed under section 503 [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s280g–4a">42 U.S.C. 280g–4a</ref>].</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Core Competencies</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In conducting activities under this section, the Agencies shall address sexual assault forensic examination competencies, including—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> providing medical care to sexual assault patients;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> demonstrating the ability to conduct a medical forensic examination, including an evaluation for evidence collection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> showing compassion and sensitivity towards survivors of sexual assault;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> testifying in Federal, State, local, and Tribal courts; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> other competencies, as the Agencies determine appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Publication</inline>.—</heading><content>The Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality shall establish, maintain, and publish on the website of the Department of Health and Human Services an online public map of availability of sexual assault forensic examinations. Such maps shall clarify if there is full-time, part-time, or on-call coverage.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report to Congress</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 60 days after receiving the report described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Committee on Education and Labor [now Committee on Education and the Workforce] of the House of Representatives recommendations for improving sexual assault forensic examination competencies based on the report described in subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definition of terms used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dW/s504">section 504 of div. W of Pub. L. 117–103</ref>, set out above, see section 12291 Title 34, Crime Control and Law Enforcement, as made applicable by <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dW/s2/b">section 2(b) of div. W of Pub. L. 117–103</ref>, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s12291">section 12291 of Title 34</ref>].</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I87" topic="definitions" id="idb53a70cf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Definitions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For definitions of terms used in this section, see <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s12291">section 12291 of Title 34</ref>, Crime Control and Law Enforcement, as made applicable by <ref href="/us/pl/117/103/dW/s2/b">section 2(b) of div. W of Pub. L. 117–103</ref>, which is set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t34/s12291">section 12291 of Title 34</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
