<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb53f2b84-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–7b"><num value="280g–7b">§ 280g–7b.</num><heading> HHS public-private partnership for rare neurodegenerative diseases</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb53f2b85-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–7b/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than one year after <date date="2021-12-23">December 23, 2021</date>, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall establish and implement a Public-Private Partnership for Neurodegenerative Diseases between the National Institutes of Health, the Food and Drug Administration, and one or more eligible entities (to be known and referred to in this section as the “Partnership”) through cooperative agreements, contracts, or other appropriate mechanisms with such eligible entities, for the purpose of advancing the understanding of neurodegenerative diseases and fostering the development of treatments for amytrophic lateral sclerosis and other rare neurodegenerative diseases. The Partnership shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53f2b86-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–7b/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> establish partnerships and consortia with other public and private entities and individuals with expertise in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and other rare neurodegenerative diseases for the purposes described in this subsection;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53f2b87-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–7b/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> focus on advancing regulatory science and scientific research that will support and accelerate the development and review of drugs for patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and other rare neurodegenerative diseases; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53f2b88-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–7b/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> foster the development of effective drugs that improve the lives of people that suffer from amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and other rare neurodegenerative diseases.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb53f2b89-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–7b/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible entity</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section, the term “eligible entity” means an entity that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53f2b8a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–7b/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> is—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb53f2b8b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–7b/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> an institution of higher education (as such term is defined in section 1001 <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002144">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002144"><num>1</num> See References in Text note below.</note> of title 20) or a consortium of such institutions; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb53f2b8c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–7b/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> an organization described in <ref href="/us/usc/t26/s501/c/3">section 501(c)(3) of title 26</ref> and exempt from tax under subsection (a) of such section;</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53f2b8d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–7b/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> has experienced personnel with clinical and other technical expertise in the field of biomedical sciences and demonstrated connection to the patient population;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53f2b8e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–7b/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> demonstrates to the Secretary’s satisfaction that the entity is capable of identifying and establishing collaborations between public and private entities and individuals with expertise in neurodegenerative diseases, including patients, in order to facilitate—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb53f2b8f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–7b/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> development and critical evaluation of tools, methods, and processes—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb53f2b90-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–7b/b/3/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> to characterize neurodegenerative diseases and their natural history;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb53f2b91-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–7b/b/3/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> to identify molecular targets for neurodegenerative diseases; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb53f2b92-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–7b/b/3/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> to increase efficiency, predictability, and productivity of clinical development of therapies, including advancement of rational therapeutic development and establishment of clinical trial networks; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb53f2b93-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–7b/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> securing funding for the Partnership from Federal and non-Federal governmental sources, foundations, and private individuals; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53f2b94-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–7b/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> provides an assurance that the entity will not accept funding for a Partnership project from any organization that manufactures or distributes products regulated by the Food and Drug Administration unless the entity provides assurances in its agreement with the Secretary that the results of the project will not be influenced by any source of funding.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb53f2b95-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–7b/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Gifts</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb53f2b96-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–7b/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Partnership may solicit and accept gifts, grants, and other donations, establish accounts, and invest and expend funds in support of basic research and research associated with phase 3 clinical trials conducted with respect to investigational drugs that are the subjects of expanded access requests under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s360bbb">section 360bbb of title 21</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb53f2b97-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–7b/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Use</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In addition to any amounts appropriated for purposes of carrying out this section, the Partnership may use, without further appropriation, any funds derived from a gift, grant, or other donation accepted pursuant to paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb53f2b98-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/117/79/s3">Pub. L. 117–79, § 3</ref>, <date date="2021-12-23">Dec. 23, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/1535">135 Stat. 1535</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb53f2b99-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb53f2b9a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb53f2b9b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">Section 1001 of title 20</ref>, referred to in subsec. (b)(1)(A), was in the original “section 1001 of the Higher Education Act of 1965” and was translated as if it had read “section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965” to reflect the probable intent of Congress. Section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">section 1001 of Title 20</ref>, Education, and defines “institution of higher education”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb53f2b9c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Accelerating Access to Critical Therapies for ALS Act, and not as part of the Public Health Service Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
