<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb53f2be3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–10"><num value="280g–10">§ 280g–10.</num><heading> Community Preventive Services Task Force</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb53f2be4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–10/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment and purpose</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shall convene an independent Community Preventive Services Task Force (referred to in this subsection as the “Task Force”) to be composed of individuals with appropriate expertise. Such Task Force shall review the scientific evidence related to the effectiveness, appropriateness, and cost-effectiveness of community preventive interventions for the purpose of developing recommendations, to be published in the Guide to Community Preventive Services (referred to in this section as the “Guide”), for individuals and organizations delivering population-based services, including primary care professionals, health care systems, professional societies, employers, community organizations, non-profit organizations, schools, governmental public health agencies, Indian tribes, tribal organizations and urban Indian organizations, medical groups, Congress and other policy-makers. Community preventive services include any policies, programs, processes or activities designed to affect or otherwise affecting health at the population level.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb53f2be5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–10/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The duties of the Task Force shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53f2be6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–10/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the development of additional topic areas for new recommendations and interventions related to those topic areas, including those related to specific populations and age groups, as well as the social, economic and physical environments that can have broad effects on the health and disease of populations and health disparities among sub-populations and age groups;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53f2be7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–10/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> at least once during every 5-year period, review <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002146">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002146"><num>1</num> So in original. Probably should be followed by “of”.</note> interventions and update <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002146">1</ref> recommendations related to existing topic areas, including new or improved techniques to assess the health effects of interventions, including health impact assessment and population health modeling;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53f2be8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–10/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> improved integration with Federal Government health objectives and related target setting for health improvement;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53f2be9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–10/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the enhanced dissemination of recommendations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53f2bea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–10/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> the provision of technical assistance to those health care professionals, agencies, and organizations that request help in implementing the Guide recommendations; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb53f2beb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–10/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> providing yearly reports to Congress and related agencies identifying gaps in research and recommending priority areas that deserve further examination, including areas related to populations and age groups not adequately addressed by current recommendations.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb53f2bec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–10/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Role of agency</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director shall provide ongoing administrative, research, and technical support for the operations of the Task Force, including coordinating and supporting the dissemination of the recommendations of the Task Force, ensuring adequate staff resources, and assistance to those organizations requesting it for implementation of Guide recommendations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb53f2bed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–10/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination with Preventive Services Task Force</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Task Force shall take appropriate steps to coordinate its work with the U.S. Preventive Services Task Force and the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices, including the examination of how each task force’s recommendations interact at the nexus of clinic and community.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb53f2bee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–10/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Operation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out the duties under subsection (b), the Task Force shall not be subject to the provisions of chapter 10 of title 5.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb53f2bef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280g–10/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each fiscal year to carry out the activities of the Task Force.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb53f2bf0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title III, § 399U, as added <ref href="/us/pl/111/148/tIV/s4003/b/1">Pub. L. 111–148, title IV, § 4003(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="2010-03-23">Mar. 23, 2010</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/124/543">124 Stat. 543</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/117/286/s4/a/230">Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(230)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4331">136 Stat. 4331</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb53f2bf1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb53f2bf2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb53f2bf3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/117/286">Pub. L. 117–286</ref> substituted “chapter 10 of title 5.” for “Appendix 2 of title 5.”</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
