<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb54657b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7"><num value="280h–7">§ 280h–7.</num><heading> Grants to improve trauma support services and mental health care for children and youth in educational settings</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements authorized</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, in coordination with the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, is authorized to award grants to, or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, State educational agencies, local educational agencies, Indian Tribes (as defined in <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5304">section 5304 of title 25</ref>) or their tribal educational agencies, a school operated by the Bureau of Indian Education, a Regional Corporation, or a Native Hawaiian educational organization, for the purpose of increasing student access to evidence-based trauma support services and mental health care by developing innovative initiatives, activities, or programs to link local school systems with local trauma-informed support and mental health systems, including those under the Indian Health Service.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Duration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With respect to a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement awarded or entered into under this section, the period during which payments under such grant, contract or agreement are made to the recipient may not exceed 4 years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An entity that receives a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under this section shall use amounts made available through such grant, contract, or cooperative agreement for evidence-based activities, which shall include any of the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb54657b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Collaborative efforts between school-based service systems and trauma-informed support and mental health service systems to provide, develop, or improve prevention, screening, referral, and treatment and support services to students, such as providing trauma screenings to identify students in need of specialized support.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb54657b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> To implement schoolwide positive behavioral interventions and supports, or other trauma-informed models of support.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb54657ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> To provide professional development to teachers, teacher assistants, school leaders, specialized instructional support personnel, and mental health professionals that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb54657bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> fosters safe and stable learning environments that prevent and mitigate the effects of trauma, including through social and emotional learning;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb54657bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> improves school capacity to identify, refer, and provide services to students in need of trauma support or behavioral health services; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb54657bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> reflects the best practices for trauma-informed identification, referral, and support developed by the Task Force under section 7132.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb54657be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> Services at a full-service community school that focuses on trauma-informed supports, which may include a full-time site coordinator, or other activities consistent with <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7275">section 7275 of title 20</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb54657bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> Engaging families and communities in efforts to increase awareness of child and youth trauma, which may include sharing best practices with law enforcement regarding trauma-informed care and working with mental health professionals to provide interventions, as well as longer term coordinated care within the community for children and youth who have experienced trauma and their families.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb54657c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> To provide technical assistance to school systems and mental health agencies.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb54657c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/c/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> To evaluate the effectiveness of the program carried out under this section in increasing student access to evidence-based trauma support services and mental health care.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb54657c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/c/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> To establish partnerships with or provide subgrants to Head Start agencies (including Early Head Start agencies), public and private preschool programs, child care programs (including home-based providers), or other entities described in subsection (a), to include such entities described in this paragraph in the evidence-based trauma initiatives, activities, support services, and mental health systems established under this section in order to provide, develop, or improve prevention, screening, referral, and treatment and support services to young children and their families.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Applications</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">To be eligible to receive a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under this section, an entity described in subsection (a) shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require, which shall include the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb54657c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> A description of the innovative initiatives, activities, or programs to be funded under the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement, including how such program will increase access to evidence-based trauma support services and mental health care for students, and, as applicable, the families of such students.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb54657c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A description of how the program will provide linguistically appropriate and culturally competent services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb54657c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> A description of how the program will support students and the school in improving the school climate in order to support an environment conducive to learning.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb54657c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/d/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><chapeau> An assurance that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb54657c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/d/4/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> persons providing services under the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement are adequately trained to provide such services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb54657c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/d/4/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> teachers, school leaders, administrators, specialized instructional support personnel, representatives of local Indian Tribes or tribal organizations as appropriate, other school personnel, and parents or guardians of students participating in services under this section will be engaged and involved in the design and implementation of the services.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb54657ca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/d/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> A description of how the applicant will support and integrate existing school-based services with the program in order to provide mental health services for students, as appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb54657cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/d/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> A description of the entities in the community with which the applicant will partner or to which the applicant will provide subgrants in accordance with subsection (c)(8).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Interagency agreements</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Local interagency agreements</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">To ensure the provision of the services described in subsection (c), a recipient of a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under this section, or their designee, shall establish a local interagency agreement among local educational agencies, agencies responsible for early childhood education programs, Head Start agencies (including Early Head Start agencies), juvenile justice authorities, mental health agencies, child welfare agencies, and other relevant agencies, authorities, or entities in the community that will be involved in the provision of such services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657ce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In ensuring the provision of the services described in subsection (c), the local interagency agreement shall specify with respect to each agency, authority, or entity that is a party to such agreement—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb54657cf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the financial responsibility for the services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb54657d0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> the conditions and terms of responsibility for the services, including quality, accountability, and coordination of the services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb54657d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> the conditions and terms of reimbursement among such agencies, authorities, or entities, including procedures for dispute resolution.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657d2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Evaluation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall reserve not more than 3 percent of the funds made available under subsection (<i>l</i>) for each fiscal year to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb54657d3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/f/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> conduct a rigorous, independent evaluation of the activities funded under this section; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb54657d4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/f/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> disseminate and promote the utilization of evidence-based practices regarding trauma support services and mental health care.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657d5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Distribution of awards</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall ensure that grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements awarded or entered into under this section are equitably distributed among the geographical regions of the United States and among tribal, urban, suburban, and rural populations.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657d6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb54657d7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> to prohibit an entity involved with a program carried out under this section from reporting a crime that is committed by a student to appropriate authorities; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb54657d8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> to prevent Federal, State, and tribal law enforcement and judicial authorities from exercising their responsibilities with regard to the application of Federal, tribal, and State law to crimes committed by a student.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657d9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Supplement, not supplant</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Any services provided through programs carried out under this section shall supplement, and not supplant, existing mental health services, including any special education and related services provided under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1400">20 U.S.C. 1400</ref> et seq.).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657da-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation with Indian Tribes</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall, in a timely manner, meaningfully consult with Indian Tribes and their representatives to ensure notice of eligibility.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657db-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657dc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/k/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Elementary school</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “elementary school” has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7801">section 7801 of title 20</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657dd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/k/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Evidence-based</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “evidence-based” has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7801/21/A/i">section 7801(21)(A)(i) of title 20</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657de-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/k/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Native Hawaiian educational organization</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “Native Hawaiian educational organization” has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7517">section 7517 of title 20</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/k/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Local educational agency</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “local educational agency” has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7801">section 7801 of title 20</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657e0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/k/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Regional Corporation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “Regional Corporation” has the meaning given the term in <ref href="/us/usc/t43/s1602">section 1602 of title 43</ref>).<ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002152">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002152"><num>1</num> So in original.</note></p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657e1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/k/6"><num value="6" class="bold">(6)</num><heading class="bold"> School</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “school” means a public elementary school or public secondary school.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657e2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/k/7"><num value="7" class="bold">(7)</num><heading class="bold"> School leader</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “school leader” has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7801">section 7801 of title 20</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657e3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/k/8"><num value="8" class="bold">(8)</num><heading class="bold"> Secondary school</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “secondary school” has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7801">section 7801 of title 20</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657e4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/k/9"><num value="9" class="bold">(9)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Education.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657e5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/k/10"><num value="10" class="bold">(10)</num><heading class="bold"> Specialized instructional support personnel</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “specialized instructional support personnel” has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7801">section 7801 of title 20</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657e6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/k/11"><num value="11" class="bold">(11)</num><heading class="bold"> State educational agency</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “State educational agency” has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7801">section 7801 of title 20</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb54657e7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280h–7/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb54657e8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/115/271/tVII/s7134">Pub. L. 115–271, title VII, § 7134</ref>, <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4051">132 Stat. 4051</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb54657e9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb54657ea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb54657eb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section 7132, referred to in subsec. (c)(3)(C), is <ref href="/us/pl/115/271/s7132">section 7132 of Pub. L. 115–271</ref>, title VII, <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4046">132 Stat. 4046</ref>, which is not classified to the Code.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, referred to in subsec. (i), is title VI of <ref href="/us/pl/91/230">Pub. L. 91–230</ref>, <date date="1970-04-13">Apr. 13, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/175">84 Stat. 175</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 33 (§ 1400 et seq.) of Title 20, Education. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1400">section 1400 of Title 20</ref> and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb54657ec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Substance Use–Disorder Prevention that Promotes Opioid Recovery and Treatment for Patients and Communities Act, also known as the SUPPORT for Patients and Communities Act, and not as part of the Public Health Service Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
