<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb5465801-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280i"><num value="280i">§ 280i.</num><heading> Developmental disabilities surveillance and research program</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5465802-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280i/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Autism spectrum disorder and other developmental disabilities</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5465803-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280i/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may award grants or cooperative agreements to eligible entities for the collection, analysis, and reporting of State epidemiological data for children and adults with autism spectrum disorder and other developmental disabilities. An eligible entity shall assist with the development and coordination of State autism spectrum disorder and other developmental disability surveillance efforts within a region. In making such awards, the Secretary may provide direct technical assistance in lieu of cash.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5465804-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280i/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Data standards</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In submitting epidemiological data to the Secretary pursuant to paragraph (1), an eligible entity shall report data according to guidelines prescribed by the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, after consultation with relevant State, local, and Tribal public health officials, private sector developmental disability researchers, and advocates for individuals with autism spectrum disorder and other developmental disabilities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5465805-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280i/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligibility</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">To be eligible to receive an award under paragraph (1), an entity shall be a public or nonprofit private entity (including a health department of a State or a political subdivision of a State, a university, any other educational institution, an Indian Tribe, or a Tribal organization), and submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5465806-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280i/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Centers of excellence in autism spectrum disorder epidemiology</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5465807-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280i/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, award grants or cooperative agreements for the establishment or support of regional centers of excellence in autism spectrum disorder and other developmental disabilities epidemiology for the purpose of collecting and analyzing information on the number, incidence, correlates, and causes of autism spectrum disorder and other developmental disabilities for children and adults across the lifespan.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5465808-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280i/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirements</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">To be eligible to receive a grant or cooperative agreement under paragraph (1), an entity shall submit to the Secretary an application containing such agreements and information as the Secretary may require, including an agreement that the center to be established or supported under the grant or cooperative agreement shall operate in accordance with the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5465809-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280i/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The center will collect, analyze, and report autism spectrum disorder and other developmental disability data according to guidelines prescribed by the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, after consultation with State, local, and Tribal public health officials, private sector developmental disability researchers, advocates for individuals with autism spectrum disorder, and advocates for individuals with other developmental disabilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb546580a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280i/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> The center will develop or extend an area of special research expertise (including genetics, epigenetics, and epidemiological research related to environmental exposures), immunology, and other relevant research specialty areas.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb546580b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280i/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> The center will identify eligible cases and controls through its surveillance system and conduct research into factors which may cause or increase the risk of autism spectrum disorder and other developmental disabilities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb546580c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280i/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Federal response</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall coordinate the Federal response to requests for assistance from State health, mental health, and education department officials regarding potential or alleged autism spectrum disorder or developmental disability clusters.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb546580d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280i/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this part:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb546580e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280i/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Indian Tribe; Tribal organization</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The terms “Indian Tribe” and “Tribal organization” have the meanings given such terms in <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s1603">section 1603 of title 25</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb546580f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280i/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Other developmental disabilities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “other developmental disabilities” has the meaning given the term “developmental disability” in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s15002/8">section 15002(8) of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5465810-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280i/d/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> State</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Virgin Islands, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5465811-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s280i/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Sunset</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">This section shall not apply after <date date="2029-09-30">September 30, 2029</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb5465812-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title III, § 399AA, as added <ref href="/us/pl/109/416/s3/a">Pub. L. 109–416, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2006-12-19">Dec. 19, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2822">120 Stat. 2822</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/112/32/s2/1">Pub. L. 112–32, § 2(1)</ref>, <date date="2011-09-30">Sept. 30, 2011</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/125/361">125 Stat. 361</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/113/157/s3">Pub. L. 113–157, § 3</ref>, <date date="2014-08-08">Aug. 8, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1831">128 Stat. 1831</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/116/60/s3/a">Pub. L. 116–60, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2019-09-30">Sept. 30, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1111">133 Stat. 1111</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/83/dB/tII/s201/a">Pub. L. 118–83, div. B, title II, § 201(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-09-26">Sept. 26, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/1537">138 Stat. 1537</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/180/s3/a">Pub. L. 118–180, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2615">138 Stat. 2615</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb5465813-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb5465814-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb5465815-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/118/180/s3/a/1">Pub. L. 118–180, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “an Indian Tribe, or a Tribal organization” for “an Indian tribe, or a tribal organization”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/118/180/s3/a/2">Pub. L. 118–180, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, inserted “across the lifespan” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/118/180/s3/a/3">Pub. L. 118–180, § 3(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “<inline class="small-caps">Tribe; tribal</inline>” for “<inline class="small-caps">tribe; tribal</inline>” in heading of original Act which appears in heading as “Tribe; Tribal” and substituted “Tribe” for “tribe” and “Tribal” for “tribal” in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/118/180/s3/a/4">Pub. L. 118–180, § 3(a)(4)</ref>, substituted “<date date="2029-09-30">September 30, 2029</date>” for “<date date="2024-12-20">December 20, 2024</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/118/83">Pub. L. 118–83</ref> substituted “<date date="2024-12-20">December 20, 2024</date>” for “<date date="2024-09-30">September 30, 2024</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/60/s3/a/1">Pub. L. 116–60, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “adults with autism spectrum disorder” for “adults on autism spectrum disorder”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/116/60/s3/a/2">Pub. L. 116–60, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “State, local, and Tribal public health officials” for “State and local public health officials” and “and other developmental disabilities” for “or other developmental disabilities”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/116/60/s3/a/3">Pub. L. 116–60, § 3(a)(3)</ref>, substituted “a university, any other educational institution, an Indian tribe, or a tribal organization” for “a university, or any other educational institution”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/116/60/s3/a/4">Pub. L. 116–60, § 3(a)(4)</ref>, substituted “State, local, and Tribal public health officials, private sector developmental disability researchers, advocates for individuals with autism spectrum disorder, and advocates for individuals with other developmental disabilities” for “relevant State and local public health officials, private sector developmental disability researchers, and advocates for individuals with developmental disabilities”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/116/60/s3/a/5">Pub. L. 116–60, § 3(a)(5)</ref>, added par. (1) and redesignated former pars. (1) and (2) as (2) and (3), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/116/60/s3/a/6">Pub. L. 116–60, § 3(a)(6)</ref>, substituted “2024” for “2019”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2014—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/113/157/s3/1">Pub. L. 113–157, § 3(1)</ref>, inserted “for children and adults” after “reporting of State epidemiological data”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/113/157/s3/2">Pub. L. 113–157, § 3(2)</ref>, substituted “establishment or support of regional centers of excellence” for “establishment of regional centers of excellence” and inserted “for children and adults” before period at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/113/157/s3/3">Pub. L. 113–157, § 3(3)</ref>, substituted “center to be established or supported” for “center to be established” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/113/157/s3/4">Pub. L. 113–157, § 3(4)</ref>, substituted “2019” for “2014”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2011—Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/112/32">Pub. L. 112–32</ref> substituted “2014” for “2011”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb5465816-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb5465817-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Technical Assistance To Improve Access to Communication Tools</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/118/180/s4">Pub. L. 118–180, § 4</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2619">138 Stat. 2619</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/118/180/s4">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the ‘Secretary’) may, at the request of a State, Indian Tribe, Tribal organization, locality, or territory, provide training and technical assistance to such jurisdiction on the manner in which Federal funding administered by the Secretary may be used to provide individuals with autism spectrum disorder and other developmental disabilities with access to evidence-based services, tools, and technologies that support communication needs.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Annual Report</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary shall annually prepare and submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report summarizing any technical assistance provided by the Secretary in the preceding fiscal year under subsection (a) and any advancements in the development or evaluation of such evidence-based services, tools, and technologies.”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb5465818-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">National Autism Spectrum Disorder Initiative</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/113/157/s2">Pub. L. 113–157, § 2</ref>, <date date="2014-08-08">Aug. 8, 2014</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/128/1831">128 Stat. 1831</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/113/157/s2">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><content>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall designate an existing official within the Department of Health and Human Services to oversee, in consultation with the Secretaries of Defense and Education, national autism spectrum disorder research, services, and support activities.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Duties</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The official designated under subsection (a) shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> implement autism spectrum disorder activities, taking into account the strategic plan developed by the Interagency Autism Coordinating Committee under section 399CC(b) of the Public Health Service Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s280i–2/b">42 U.S.C. 280i–2(b)</ref>); and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> ensure that autism spectrum disorder activities of the Department of Health and Human Services and of other Federal departments and agencies are not unnecessarily duplicative.”</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idb5465819-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb546581a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, see note set out preceding <ref href="/us/usc/t48/s1681">section 1681 of Title 48</ref>, Territories and Insular Possessions.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
