<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb55e25a4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284"><num value="284">§ 284.</num><heading> Directors of national research institutes</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb55e25a5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb55e25a6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director of the National Cancer Institute shall be appointed by the President, and the Directors of the other national research institutes and national centers shall be appointed by the Secretary, acting through the Director of National Institutes of Health. Each Director of a national research institute or national center shall report directly to the Director of National Institutes of Health.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb55e25a7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Appointment</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb55e25a8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/a/2/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> Term</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A Director of a national research institute or national center who is appointed by the Secretary, acting through the Director of National Institutes of Health, shall be appointed for 5 years.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb55e25a9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/a/2/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Reappointment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">At the end of the term of a Director of a national research institute or national center, the Director may be reappointed in accordance with standards applicable to the relevant appointment mechanism. There shall be no limit on the number of terms that a Director may serve.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb55e25aa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/a/2/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Vacancies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">If the office of a Director of a national research institute or national center becomes vacant before the end of such Director’s term, the Director appointed to fill the vacancy shall be appointed for a 5-year term starting on the date of such appointment.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb55e25ab-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/a/2/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Current directors</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Each Director of a national research institute or national center who is serving on <date date="2016-12-13">December 13, 2016</date>, shall be deemed to be appointed for a 5-year term under this subsection beginning on such date.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb55e25ac-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/a/2/E"><num value="E" class="bold">(E)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary or the Director of National Institutes of Health to terminate the appointment of a director referred to in subparagraph (A) before the expiration of such director’s 5-year term.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb55e25ad-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/a/2/F"><num value="F" class="bold">(F)</num><heading class="bold"> Nature of appointment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Appointments and reappointments under this subsection shall be made on the basis of ability and experience as it relates to the mission of the National Institutes of Health and its components, including compliance with any legal requirement that the Secretary or Director of National Institutes of Health determines relevant.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb55e25ae-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Nonapplication of certain provision</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The restrictions contained in section 202 of the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1993 (<ref href="/us/pl/102/394">Public Law 102–394</ref>; <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s238f">42 U.S.C. 238f</ref> note) related to consultants and individual scientists appointed for limited periods of time shall not apply to Directors appointed under this subsection.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb55e25af-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Duties and authority; grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb55e25b0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In carrying out the purposes of <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s241">section 241 of this title</ref> with respect to human diseases or disorders or other aspects of human health for which the national research institutes were established, the Secretary, acting through the Director of each national research institute—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb55e25b1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> shall encourage and support research, investigations, experiments, demonstrations, and studies in the health sciences related to—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb55e25b2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the maintenance of health,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb55e25b3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> the detection, diagnosis, treatment, and prevention of human diseases and disorders,</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb55e25b4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/1/A/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> the rehabilitation of individuals with human diseases, disorders, and disabilities, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb55e25b5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/1/A/iv"><num value="iv">(iv)</num><content> the expansion of knowledge of the processes underlying human diseases, disorders, and disabilities, the processes underlying the normal and pathological functioning of the body and its organ systems, and the processes underlying the interactions between the human organism and the environment;</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb55e25b6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> may, subject to the peer review prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s289a/b">section 289a(b) of this title</ref> and any advisory council review under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s284a/a/3/A/i">section 284a(a)(3)(A)(i) of this title</ref>, conduct the research, investigations, experiments, demonstrations, and studies referred to in subparagraph (A);</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb55e25b7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> shall, as appropriate, conduct and support research that has the potential to transform the scientific field, has inherently higher risk, and that seeks to address major current challenges;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb55e25b8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> may conduct and support research training (i) for which fellowship support is not provided under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s288">section 288 of this title</ref>, and (ii) which is not residency training of physicians or other health professionals;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb55e25b9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/1/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> may develop, implement, and support demonstrations and programs for the application of the results of the activities of the institute to clinical practice and disease prevention activities;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb55e25ba-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/1/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> may develop, conduct, and support public and professional education and information programs;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb55e25bb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/1/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> may secure, develop and maintain, distribute, and support the development and maintenance of resources needed for research;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb55e25bc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/1/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> may make available the facilities of the institute to appropriate entities and individuals engaged in research activities and cooperate with and assist Federal and State agencies charged with protecting the public health;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb55e25bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/1/I"><num value="I">(I)</num><content> may accept unconditional gifts made to the institute for its activities, and, in the case of gifts of a value in excess of $50,000, establish suitable memorials to the donor;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb55e25be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/1/J"><num value="J">(J)</num><content> may secure for the institute consultation services and advice of persons from the United States or abroad;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb55e25bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/1/K"><num value="K">(K)</num><content> may use, with their consent, the services, equipment, personnel, information, and facilities of other Federal, State, or local public agencies, with or without reimbursement therefor;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb55e25c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/1/L"><num value="L">(L)</num><content> may accept voluntary and uncompensated services; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb55e25c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/1/M"><num value="M">(M)</num><content> may perform such other functions as the Secretary determines are needed to carry out effectively the purposes of the institute.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">The indemnification provisions of <ref href="/us/usc/t10/s3861">section 3861 of title 10</ref> shall apply with respect to contracts entered into under this subsection and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s282/b">section 282(b) of this title</ref>.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb55e25c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Support for an activity or program under this subsection may be provided through grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements. The Secretary, acting through the Director of each national research institute—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb55e25c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> may enter into a contract for research, training, or demonstrations only if the contract has been recommended after technical and scientific peer review required by regulations under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s289a">section 289a of this title</ref>;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb55e25c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> may make grants and cooperative agreements under paragraph (1) for research, training, or demonstrations, except that—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb55e25c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/2/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> if the direct cost of the grant or cooperative agreement to be made does not exceed $50,000, such grant or cooperative agreement may be made only if such grant or cooperative agreement has been recommended after technical and scientific peer review required by regulations under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s289a">section 289a of this title</ref>, and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb55e25c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/2/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> if the direct cost of the grant or cooperative agreement to be made exceeds $50,000, such grant or cooperative agreement may be made only if such grant or cooperative agreement has been recommended after technical and scientific peer review required by regulations under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s289a">section 289a of this title</ref> and is recommended under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s284a/a/3/A/ii">section 284a(a)(3)(A)(ii) of this title</ref> by the advisory council for the national research institute involved; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb55e25c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> shall, subject to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s300cc–40c/d/2">section 300cc–40c(d)(2) of this title</ref>, receive from the President and the Office of Management and Budget directly all funds appropriated by the Congress for obligation and expenditure by the Institute.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb55e25c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Before an award is made by a national research institute or by a national center for a grant for a research program or project (commonly referred to as an “R-series grant”), other than an award constituting a noncompetitive renewal of such a grant, or a noncompetitive administrative supplement to such a grant, the Director of such national research institute or national center shall, consistent with the peer review process—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb55e25c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> review and make the final decision with respect to making the award; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb55e25ca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> take into consideration, as appropriate—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb55e25cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> the mission of the national research institute or national center and the scientific priorities identified in the strategic plan under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s282/m">section 282(m) of this title</ref>;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb55e25cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> programs or projects funded by other agencies on similar research topics; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb55e25cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/b/3/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> advice by staff and the advisory council or board of such national research institute or national center.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb55e25ce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination with other public and private entities; cooperation with other national research institutes; appointment of additional peer review groups</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out subsection (b), each Director of a national research institute—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb55e25cf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> shall coordinate, as appropriate, the activities of the institute with similar programs of other public and private entities;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb55e25d0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> shall cooperate with the Directors of the other national research institutes in the development and support of multidisciplinary research and research that involves more than one institute;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb55e25d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> may, in consultation with the advisory council for the Institute and with the approval of the Director of NIH—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb55e25d2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> establish technical and scientific peer review groups in addition to those appointed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s282/b/16">section 282(b)(16) of this title</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb55e25d3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> appoint the members of peer review groups established under subparagraph (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb55e25d4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> may publish, or arrange for the publication of, information with respect to the purpose of the Institute without regard to <ref href="/us/usc/t44/s501">section 501 of title 44</ref>.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to the duration of a peer review group appointed under paragraph (3).</continuation>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb55e25d5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title IV, § 405, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/158/s2">Pub. L. 99–158, § 2</ref>, <date date="1985-11-20">Nov. 20, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/826">99 Stat. 826</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/607/tI/s116">Pub. L. 100–607, title I, § 116</ref>, <date date="1988-11-04">Nov. 4, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/3053">102 Stat. 3053</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tII/s2613/c">Pub. L. 100–690, title II, § 2613(c)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4239">102 Stat. 4239</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/43/tIII/s301/a/1">Pub. L. 103–43, title III, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, (b), <date date="1993-06-10">June 10, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/150">107 Stat. 150</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/482/tI/s102/f/1/B">Pub. L. 109–482, title I, § 102(f)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2007-01-15">Jan. 15, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3685">120 Stat. 3685</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/dA/tII">Pub. L. 114–255, div. A, title II</ref>, §§ 2033(a), (b), 2036(c), <date date="2016-12-13">Dec. 13, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1057">130 Stat. 1057</ref>, 1058, 1063; <ref href="/us/pl/117/81/dA/tXVII/s1702/j/1/B">Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1702(j)(1)(B)</ref>, <date date="2021-12-27">Dec. 27, 2021</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/135/2159">135 Stat. 2159</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/286/s4/a/232">Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(232)</ref>, <date date="2022-12-27">Dec. 27, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/4331">136 Stat. 4331</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb55e25d6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb55e25d7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb55e25d8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/117/286">Pub. L. 117–286</ref> substituted “Chapter 10 of title 5” for “The Federal Advisory Committee Act” in concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2021—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/81">Pub. L. 117–81</ref> substituted “section 3861” for “section 2354” in concluding provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s2033/a">Pub. L. 114–255, § 2033(a)</ref>, amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Director of the National Cancer Institute shall be appointed by the President and the Directors of the other national research institutes shall be appointed by the Secretary. Each Director of a national research institute shall report directly to the Director of NIH.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(C) to (M). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s2036/c">Pub. L. 114–255, § 2036(c)</ref>, added par. (C) and redesignated former pars. (C) to (L) as (D) to (M), respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s2033/b">Pub. L. 114–255, § 2033(b)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Subsec. (c)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/109/482">Pub. L. 109–482</ref> substituted “section 282(b)(16)” for “section 282(b)(6)”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (b)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/103/43/s301/a/1">Pub. L. 103–43, § 301(a)(1)</ref>, added subpar. (C).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/103/43/s301/b/2">Pub. L. 103–43, § 301(b)(2)</ref>, inserted concluding provisions relating to Federal Advisory Committee Act.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/103/43/s301/b/1">Pub. L. 103–43, § 301(b)(1)</ref>, amended par. (3) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (3) read as follows: “may, in consultation with the advisory council for the Institute and the approval of the Director of NIH, establish and appoint technical and scientific peer review groups in addition to those established and appointed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s282/b/6">section 282(b)(6) of this title</ref>; and”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/100/607/s116/1">Pub. L. 100–607, § 116(1)</ref>, struck out “the” after “with respect to” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/100/690">Pub. L. 100–690</ref> substituted “establish and appoint” and “established and appointed” for “establish” and “established”, respectively.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/607/s116/2/A">Pub. L. 100–607, § 116(2)(A)</ref>, amended par. (3) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (3) read as follows: “may, with the approval of the advisory council for the institute and the Director of NIH, appoint technical and scientific peer review groups in addition to those appointed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s282/b/6">section 282(b)(6) of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/100/607/s116/2/C">Pub. L. 100–607, § 116(2)(C)</ref>, added par. (4).</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb55e25d9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb55e25da-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2007 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/482">Pub. L. 109–482</ref> applicable only with respect to amounts appropriated for fiscal year 2007 or subsequent fiscal years, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/482/s109">section 109 of Pub. L. 109–482</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s281">section 281 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb55e25db-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/690">Pub. L. 100–690</ref> effective immediately after enactment of <ref href="/us/pl/100/607">Pub. L. 100–607</ref>, which was approved <date date="1988-11-04">Nov. 4, 1988</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s2600">section 2600 of Pub. L. 100–690</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s242m">section 242m of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb55e25dc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Federal Research</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/117/215/tIV/s401">Pub. L. 117–215, title IV, § 401</ref>, <date date="2022-12-02">Dec. 2, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/2265">136 Stat. 2265</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/117/215/tIV/s401">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2022-12-02">Dec. 2, 2022</date>], the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in coordination with the Director of the National Institutes of Health and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall submit to the Caucus on International Narcotics Control, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report on—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> the potential therapeutic effects of cannabidiol or marijuana on serious medical conditions, including intractable epilepsy;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><chapeau> the potential effects of marijuana, including—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> the effect of increasing delta-9-tetrahydrocannabinol levels on the human body and developing adolescent brains; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> the effect of various delta-9-tetrahydrocannabinol levels on cognitive abilities, such as those that are required to operate motor vehicles or other heavy equipment; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><chapeau> the barriers associated with researching marijuana or cannabidiol in States that have legalized the use of such substances, which shall include—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> recommendations as to how such barriers might be overcome, including whether public-private partnerships or Federal-State research partnerships may or should be implemented to provide researchers with access to additional strains of marijuana and cannabidiol; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><chapeau> recommendations as to what safeguards must be in place to verify—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="i">“(i)</num><content> the levels of tetrahydrocannabinol, cannabidiol, or other cannabinoids contained in products obtained from such States is accurate; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I24" class="indent3"><num value="ii">“(ii)</num><content> that such products do not contain harmful or toxic components.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Activities</inline>.—</heading><content>To the extent practicable, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, either directly or through awarding grants, contacts, or cooperative agreements, shall expand and coordinate the activities of the National Institutes of Health and other relevant Federal agencies to better determine the effects of cannabidiol and marijuana, as outlined in the report submitted under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a).”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">[For definitions of terms as used in <ref href="/us/pl/117/215/s401">section 401 of Pub. L. 117–215</ref>, set out above, see <ref href="/us/pl/117/215/s2/a">section 2(a) of Pub. L. 117–215</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t21/s801">section 801 of Title 21</ref>, Food and Drugs.]</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb55e25dd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Enhancing the Clinical and Translational Science Award</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/109/482/tI/s106">Pub. L. 109–482, title I, § 106</ref>, <date date="2007-01-15">Jan. 15, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3696">120 Stat. 3696</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/109/482/tI/s106">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In General</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In administering the Clinical and Translational Science Award, the Director of NIH shall establish a mechanism to preserve independent funding and infrastructure for pediatric clinical research centers by—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> allowing the appointment of a secondary principal investigator under a single Clinical and Translational Science Award, such that a pediatric principal investigator may be appointed with direct authority over a separate budget and infrastructure for pediatric clinical research; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> otherwise securing institutional independence of pediatric clinical research centers with respect to finances, infrastructure, resources, and research agenda.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Report</inline>.—</heading><content>As part of the biennial report under section 403 of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s283">42 U.S.C. 283</ref>], the Director of NIH shall provide an evaluation and comparison of outcomes and effectiveness of training programs under subsection (a).</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definition</inline>.—</heading><content>For purposes of this section, the term ‘Director of NIH’ has the meaning given such term in section 401 of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s281">42 U.S.C. 281</ref>].”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
