<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb5609655-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g"><num value="284g">§ 284g.</num><heading> Expansion, intensification, and coordination of activities of National Institutes of Health with respect to research on autism spectrum disorder</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5609656-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5609657-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Expansion of activities</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director of NIH (in this section referred to as the “Director”), in consultation with relevant Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate, shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5609658-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><chapeau> subject to the availability of appropriations, expand, intensify, and coordinate the activities of the National Institutes of Health with respect to research on autism spectrum disorder, including basic and clinical research—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb5609659-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/a/1/A/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> in fields, such as pathology, developmental neurobiology, genetics, epigenetics, pharmacology, nutrition, immunology, neuroimmunology, neurobehavioral development, endocrinology, gastroenterology, toxicology, psychiatry, psychology, developmental behavioral pediatrics, audiology, and gerontology; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb560965a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/a/1/A/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> on interventions to maximize outcomes for individuals with autism spectrum disorder; and</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb560965b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> ensure that research referred to in subparagraph (A)—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb560965c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/a/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> investigates the causes (including possible environmental causes), diagnosis or ruling out, early and ongoing detection, prevention, services and supports across the lifespan, intervention, and treatment of autism spectrum disorder and co-occurring conditions, including dissemination and implementation of clinical care, supports, interventions, and treatments;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb560965d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/a/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> examines supports for caregivers; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I14" class="indent3" id="idb560965e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/a/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> reflects the entire population of individuals with autism spectrum disorder, including those individuals with co-occurring conditions and the full range of needs for supports and services, including such supports and services to ensure the safety, and promote the well-being, of such individuals.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb560965f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Consolidation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director may consolidate program activities under this section if such consolidation would improve program efficiencies and outcomes.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5609660-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Administration of program; collaboration among agencies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director shall carry out this section acting through the Director of the National Institute of Mental Health and in collaboration with any other agencies that the Director determines appropriate.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5609661-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Centers of excellence</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5609662-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director shall under subsection (a)(1) make awards of grants and contracts to public or nonprofit private entities to pay all or part of the cost of planning, establishing, improving, and providing basic operating support for centers of excellence regarding research on autism spectrum disorder.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5609663-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Research</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each center under paragraph (1) shall conduct basic and clinical research into autism spectrum disorder. Such research should include investigations into the causes, diagnosis, early and ongoing detection, prevention, and treatment of autism spectrum disorder across the lifespan. The centers, as a group, shall conduct research in fields such as developmental neurobiology, genetics, genomics, psychopharmacology, developmental psychology, behavioral psychology, clinical psychology, and gerontology.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5609664-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Services for patients</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb5609665-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/b/3/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A center under paragraph (1) may expend amounts provided under such paragraph to carry out a program to make individuals aware of opportunities to participate as subjects in research conducted by the centers.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb5609666-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/b/3/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Referrals and costs</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">A program under subparagraph (A) may, in accordance with such criteria as the Director may establish, provide to the subjects described in such subparagraph, referrals for health and other services, and such patient care costs as are required for research.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb5609667-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/b/3/C"><num value="C" class="bold">(C)</num><heading class="bold"> Availability and access</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The extent to which a center can demonstrate availability and access to clinical services shall be considered by the Director in decisions about awarding grants to applicants which meet the scientific criteria for funding under this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb5609668-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/b/3/D"><num value="D" class="bold">(D)</num><heading class="bold"> Reducing disparities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Director may consider, as appropriate, the extent to which a center can demonstrate availability and access to clinical services for youth and adults from diverse racial, ethnic, geographic, or linguistic backgrounds in decisions about awarding grants to applicants which meet the scientific criteria for funding under this section.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5609669-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Organization of centers</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Each center under paragraph (1) shall use the facilities of a single institution, or be formed from a consortium of cooperating institutions, meeting such requirements as may be prescribed by the Director.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb560966a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/b/5"><num value="5" class="bold">(5)</num><heading class="bold"> Number of centers; duration of support</heading><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb560966b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/b/5/A"><num value="A" class="bold">(A)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">The Director shall provide for the establishment of not less than seven centers under paragraph (1).</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I18" class="indent4 firstIndent-2" id="idb560966c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/b/5/B"><num value="B" class="bold">(B)</num><heading class="bold"> Duration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2">Support for a center established under paragraph (1) may be provided under this section for a period not to exceed 5 years. Such period may be extended for one or more additional periods not exceeding 5 years if the operations of such center have been reviewed by an appropriate technical and scientific peer review group established by the Director and if such group has recommended to the Director that such period should be extended.</p>
</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb560966d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Facilitation of research</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director shall under subsection (a)(1) provide for a program under which samples of tissues and genetic materials that are of use in research on autism spectrum disorder are donated, collected, preserved, and made available for such research. The program shall be carried out in accordance with accepted scientific and medical standards for the donation, collection, and preservation of such samples.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb560966e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Public input</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb560966f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/d/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director shall under subsection (a)(1) provide for means through which the public can obtain information on the existing and planned programs and activities of the National Institutes of Health with respect to autism spectrum disorder and through which the Director can receive comments from the public regarding such programs and activities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5609670-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/d/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Guidance</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Director may provide guidance to centers under subsection (b)(1) on strategies, activities, and opportunities to promote engagement with, and solicit input from, individuals with autism spectrum disorder and their family members, guardians, advocates or authorized representatives, providers, or other appropriate individuals to inform the activities of the center. Such strategies, activities, and opportunities should consider including, as appropriate, individuals, family members, and caregivers of individuals with autism spectrum disorder who represent the entire population of individuals with autism spectrum disorder, including those individuals with co-occurring conditions and the full range of needs for supports and services, including such supports and services to ensure the safety, and promote the well-being, of such individuals, to inform the activities of the center.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5609671-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s284g/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Budget estimate</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029, the Director shall prepare and submit, directly to the President for review and transmittal to Congress, an annual budget estimate for the initiatives of the National Institutes of Health pursuant to the strategic plan developed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s280i–2/b/5">section 280i–2(b)(5) of this title</ref> and updated under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s280i–2/b/6/B">section 280i–2(b)(6)(B) of this title</ref>, after reasonable opportunity for comment (but without change) by the Secretary and the Interagency Autism Coordinating Committee established under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s280i–2">section 280i–2 of this title</ref>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb5609672-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title IV, § 409C, as added <ref href="/us/pl/106/310/dA/tI/s101">Pub. L. 106–310, div. A, title I, § 101</ref>, <date date="2000-10-17">Oct. 17, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1105">114 Stat. 1105</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/109/416">Pub. L. 109–416</ref>, §§ 2(a), 4(b), <date date="2006-12-19">Dec. 19, 2006</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/2821">120 Stat. 2821</ref>, 2830; <ref href="/us/pl/109/482/tI">Pub. L. 109–482, title I</ref>, §§ 103(b)(9), 104(b)(1)(D), <date date="2007-01-15">Jan. 15, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3687">120 Stat. 3687</ref>, 3693; <ref href="/us/pl/116/60/s2">Pub. L. 116–60, § 2</ref>, <date date="2019-09-30">Sept. 30, 2019</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/133/1110">133 Stat. 1110</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/118/180/s2">Pub. L. 118–180, § 2</ref>, <date date="2024-12-23">Dec. 23, 2024</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/138/2614">138 Stat. 2614</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb5609673-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb5609674-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb5609675-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Another section 409C of act <date date="1944-07-01">July 1, 1944</date>, was renumbered section 409G and is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s284k">section 284k of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb5609676-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2024—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/118/180/s2/a">Pub. L. 118–180, § 2(a)</ref>, made numerous amendments to text and structure of par. (1). Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Director of NIH (in this section referred to as the “Director”) shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, expand, intensify, and coordinate the activities of the National Institutes of Health with respect to research on autism spectrum disorder, including basic and clinical research in fields including pathology, developmental neurobiology, genetics, epigenetics, pharmacology, nutrition, immunology, neuroimmunology, neurobehavioral development, endocrinology, gastroenterology, toxicology, and interventions to maximize outcomes for individuals with autism spectrum disorder. Such research shall investigate the causes (including possible environmental causes), diagnosis or ruling out, early and ongoing detection, prevention, services across the lifespan, supports, intervention, and treatment of autism spectrum disorder, including dissemination and implementation of clinical care, supports, interventions, and treatments.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/118/180/s2/b/1">Pub. L. 118–180, § 2(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “in fields such as” for “including the fields of” and “behavioral psychology, clinical psychology, and gerontology” for “behavioral psychology, and clinical psychology”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/118/180/s2/b/2">Pub. L. 118–180, § 2(b)(2)</ref>, substituted “seven centers” for “five centers”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/118/180/s2/b/3">Pub. L. 118–180, § 2(b)(3)</ref>, substituted “period not to exceed” for “period of not to exceed”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/118/180/s2/c">Pub. L. 118–180, § 2(c)</ref>, amended subsec. (d) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Director shall under subsection (a)(1) provide for means through which the public can obtain information on the existing and planned programs and activities of the National Institutes of Health with respect to autism spectrum disorder and through which the Director can receive comments from the public regarding such programs and activities.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/118/180/s2/d">Pub. L. 118–180, § 2(d)</ref>, added subsec. (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2019—Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/116/60/s2/1">Pub. L. 116–60, § 2(1)</ref>, substituted “toxicology, and interventions to maximize outcomes for individuals with autism spectrum disorder” for “and toxicology” and “Such research shall investigate the causes (including possible environmental causes), diagnosis or ruling out, early and ongoing detection, prevention, services across the lifespan, supports, intervention, and treatment of autism spectrum disorder, including dissemination and implementation of clinical care, supports, interventions, and treatments.” for “Such research shall investigate the cause (including possible environmental causes), diagnosis or rule out, early detection, prevention, services, supports, intervention, and treatment of autism spectrum disorder.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/116/60/s2/2/A">Pub. L. 116–60, § 2(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “causes, diagnosis, early and ongoing detection, prevention, and treatment of autism spectrum disorder across the lifespan” for “cause, diagnosis, early detection, prevention, control, and treatment of autism spectrum disorder” and “neurobiology, genetics, genomics, psychopharmacology, developmental psychology, behavioral psychology, and clinical psychology.” for “neurobiology, genetics, and psychopharmacology.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3)(D). <ref href="/us/pl/116/60/s2/2/B">Pub. L. 116–60, § 2(2)(B)</ref>, added subpar. (D).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Subsec. (b)(4) to (6). <ref href="/us/pl/109/482/s104/b/1/D">Pub. L. 109–482, § 104(b)(1)(D)</ref>, redesignated pars. (5) and (6) as (4) and (5), respectively, and struck out heading and text of former par. (4). Text read as follows: “The Director shall, as appropriate, provide for the coordination of information among centers under paragraph (1) and ensure regular communication between such centers, and may require the periodic preparation of reports on the activities of the centers and the submission of the reports to the Director.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/109/482/s103/b/9">Pub. L. 109–482, § 103(b)(9)</ref>, which directed the striking of subsec. (e), could not be executed because of prior amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/416">Pub. L. 109–416</ref>. See 2006 Amendment note below.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2006—<ref href="/us/pl/109/416/s2/a/1">Pub. L. 109–416, § 2(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “autism spectrum disorder” for “autism” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/109/416/s2/a/3">Pub. L. 109–416, § 2(a)(3)</ref>, added pars. (1) and (2), redesignated former par. (2) as (3), and struck out heading and text of former par. (1). Text read as follows: “The Director of NIH (in this section referred to as the ‘Director’) shall expand, intensify, and coordinate the activities of the National Institutes of Health with respect to research on autism.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1), (2). <ref href="/us/pl/109/416/s2/a/2">Pub. L. 109–416, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “autism spectrum disorder” for “autism” in par. (1) and in two places in par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c), (d). <ref href="/us/pl/109/416/s2/a/2">Pub. L. 109–416, § 2(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “autism spectrum disorder” for “autism”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/109/416/s4/b">Pub. L. 109–416, § 4(b)</ref>, struck out heading and text of subsec. (e). Text read as follows: “There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section. Amounts appropriated under this subsection are in addition to any other amounts appropriated for such purpose.”</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb5609677-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb5609678-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2007 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/482">Pub. L. 109–482</ref> applicable only with respect to amounts appropriated for fiscal year 2007 or subsequent fiscal years, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/482/s109">section 109 of Pub. L. 109–482</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s281">section 281 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
