<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb56c7d1b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–2"><num value="285c–2">§ 285c–2.</num><heading> Division Directors for Diabetes, Endocrinology, and Metabolic Diseases, Digestive Diseases and Nutrition, and Kidney, Urologic, and Hematologic Diseases; functions</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb56ec70c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–2/a"><num value="a">(a)</num><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb56ec70d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–2/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> In the Institute there shall be a Division Director for Diabetes, Endocrinology, and Metabolic Diseases, a Division Director for Digestive Diseases and Nutrition, and a Division Director for Kidney, Urologic, and Hematologic Diseases. Such Division Directors, under the supervision of the Director of the Institute, shall be responsible for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56ec70e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–2/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> developing a coordinated plan (including recommendations for expenditures) for each of the national research institutes within the National Institutes of Health with respect to research and training concerning diabetes, endocrine and metabolic diseases, digestive diseases and nutrition, and kidney, urologic, and hematologic diseases;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56ec70f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–2/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> assessing the adequacy of management approaches for the activities within such institutes concerning such diseases and nutrition and developing improved approaches if needed;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56ec710-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–2/a/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> monitoring and reviewing expenditures by such institutes concerning such diseases and nutrition; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56ec711-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–2/a/1/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> identifying research opportunities concerning such diseases and nutrition and recommending ways to utilize such opportunities.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb56ec712-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–2/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Director of the Institute shall transmit to the Director of NIH the plans, recommendations, and reviews of the Division Directors under subparagraphs (A) through (D) of paragraph (1) together with such comments and recommendations as the Director of the Institute determines appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb56ec713-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–2/b"><num value="b">(b)</num><chapeau> The Director of the Institute, acting through the Division Director for Diabetes, Endocrinology, and Metabolic Diseases, the Division Director for Digestive Diseases and Nutrition, and the Division Director for Kidney, Urologic, and Hematologic Diseases, shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56ec714-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–2/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> carry out programs of support for research and training (other than training for which Ruth L. Kirschstein National Research Service Awards may be made under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s288">section 288 of this title</ref>) in the diagnosis, prevention, and treatment of diabetes mellitus and endocrine and metabolic diseases, digestive diseases and nutritional disorders, and kidney, urologic, and hematologic diseases, including support for training in medical schools, graduate clinical training, graduate training in epidemiology, epidemiology studies, clinical trials, and interdisciplinary research programs; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56ec715-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–2/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> establish programs of evaluation, planning, and dissemination of knowledge related to such research and training.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb56ec716-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title IV, § 428, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/158/s2">Pub. L. 99–158, § 2</ref>, <date date="1985-11-20">Nov. 20, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/842">99 Stat. 842</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/43/tXX/s2008/b/4">Pub. L. 103–43, title XX, § 2008(b)(4)</ref>, <date date="1993-06-10">June 10, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/211">107 Stat. 211</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/107/206/tI/s804/c">Pub. L. 107–206, title I, § 804(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-02">Aug. 2, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/874">116 Stat. 874</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb56ec717-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb56ec718-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb56ec719-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2002—Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/107/206">Pub. L. 107–206</ref> substituted “Ruth L. Kirschstein National Research Service Awards” for “National Research Service Awards”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/43">Pub. L. 103–43</ref> substituted “the” for “the the” before “Division Director for Diabetes” in introductory provisions.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
