<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb56ec743-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5"><num value="285c–5">§ 285c–5.</num><heading> Research and training centers; development or expansion</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb56ec744-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Diabetes mellitus and related endocrine and metabolic diseases</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb56ec745-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> Consistent with applicable recommendations of the National Commission on Diabetes, the Director of the Institute shall provide for the development or substantial expansion of centers for research and training in diabetes mellitus and related endocrine and metabolic diseases. Each center developed or expanded under this subsection shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56ec746-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/a/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> utilize the facilities of a single institution, or be formed from a consortium of cooperating institutions, meeting such research and training qualifications as may be prescribed by the Secretary; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56ec747-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/a/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> conduct—</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56ec748-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/a/1/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> research in the diagnosis and treatment of diabetes mellitus and related endocrine and metabolic diseases and the complications resulting from such diseases;</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56ec749-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/a/1/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> training programs for physicians and allied health personnel in current methods of diagnosis and treatment of such diseases and complications, and in research in diabetes; and</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56ec74a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/a/1/B/iii"><num value="iii">(iii)</num><content> information programs for physicians and allied health personnel who provide primary care for patients with such diseases or complications.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb56ec74b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> A center may use funds provided under paragraph (1) to provide stipends for nurses and allied health professionals enrolled in research training programs described in paragraph (1)(B)(ii).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb56ec74c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Digestive diseases and related functional, congenital, metabolic disorders, and normal development of digestive tract</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Consistent with applicable recommendations of the National Digestive Diseases Advisory Board, the Director shall provide for the development or substantial expansion of centers for research in digestive diseases and related functional, congenital, metabolic disorders, and normal development of the digestive tract. Each center developed or expanded under this subsection—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56ec74d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> shall utilize the facilities of a single institution, or be formed from a consortium of cooperating institutions, meeting such research qualifications as may be prescribed by the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56ec74e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> shall develop and conduct basic and clinical research into the cause, diagnosis, early detection, prevention, control, and treatment of digestive diseases and nutritional disorders and related functional, congenital, or metabolic complications resulting from such diseases or disorders;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56ec74f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> shall encourage research into and programs for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56ec750-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> providing information for patients with such diseases and the families of such patients, physicians and others who care for such patients, and the general public;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56ec751-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> model programs for cost effective and preventive patient care; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56ec752-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> training physicians and scientists in research on such diseases, disorders, and complications; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56ec753-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> may perform research and participate in epidemiological studies and data collection relevant to digestive diseases and disorders and disseminate such research, studies, and data to the health care profession and to the public.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb56ec754-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Kidney and urologic diseases</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director shall provide for the development or substantial expansion of centers for research in kidney and urologic diseases. Each center developed or expanded under this subsection—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56ec755-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> shall utilize the facilities of a single institution, or be formed from a consortium of cooperating institutions, meeting such research qualifications as may be prescribed by the Secretary;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56ec756-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> shall develop and conduct basic and clinical research into the cause, diagnosis, early detection, prevention, control, and treatment of kidney and urologic diseases;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56ec757-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> shall encourage research into and programs for—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56ec758-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/c/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> providing information for patients with such diseases, disorders, and complications and the families of such patients, physicians and others who care for such patients, and the general public;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56ec759-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/c/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> model programs for cost effective and preventive patient care; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb56ec75a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/c/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> training physicians and scientists in research on such diseases; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56ec75b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> may perform research and participate in epidemiological studies and data collection relevant to kidney and urologic diseases in order to disseminate such research, studies, and data to the health care profession and to the public.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb56ec75c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Nutritional disorders</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb56ec75d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Director of the Institute shall, subject to the extent of amounts made available in appropriations Acts, provide for the development or substantial expansion of centers for research and training regarding nutritional disorders, including obesity.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb56ec75e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> The Director of the Institute shall carry out paragraph (1) in collaboration with the Director of the National Cancer Institute and with the Directors of such other agencies of the National Institutes of Health as the Director of NIH determines to be appropriate.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb56ec75f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Each center developed or expanded under paragraph (1) shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56ec760-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/d/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> utilize the facilities of a single institution, or be formed from a consortium of cooperating institutions, meeting such research and training qualifications as may be prescribed by the Director;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56ec761-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/d/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> conduct basic and clinical research into the cause, diagnosis, early detection, prevention, control and treatment of nutritional disorders, including obesity and the impact of nutrition and diet on child development;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56ec762-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/d/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> conduct training programs for physicians and allied health professionals in current methods of diagnosis and treatment of such diseases and complications, and in research in such disorders; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56ec763-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/d/3/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> conduct information programs for physicians and allied health professionals who provide primary care for patients with such disorders or complications.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb56ec764-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–5/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Geographic distribution; period of support, additional periods</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Insofar as practicable, centers developed or expanded under this section should be geographically dispersed throughout the United States and in environments with proven research capabilities. Support of a center under this section may be for a period of not to exceed five years and such period may be extended by the Director of the Institute for additional periods of not more than five years each if the operations of such center have been reviewed by an appropriate technical and scientific peer review group established by the Director and if such group has recommended to the Director that such period should be extended.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb56ec765-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title IV, § 431, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/158/s2">Pub. L. 99–158, § 2</ref>, <date date="1985-11-20">Nov. 20, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/846">99 Stat. 846</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/103/43/tVI/s601/b">Pub. L. 103–43, title VI, § 601(b)</ref>, <date date="1993-06-10">June 10, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/161">107 Stat. 161</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb56ec766-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb56ec767-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb56ec768-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsecs. (d), (e). <ref href="/us/pl/103/43">Pub. L. 103–43</ref> added subsec. (d) and redesignated former subsec. (d) as (e).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
