<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb56ec769-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285c–6"><num value="285c–6">§ 285c–6.</num><heading> Advisory council subcommittees</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There are established within the advisory council for the Institute appointed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s284a">section 284a of this title</ref> a subcommittee on diabetes and endocrine and metabolic diseases, a subcommittee on digestive diseases and nutrition, and a subcommittee on kidney, urologic, and hematologic diseases. The subcommittees shall be composed of members of the advisory council who are outstanding in the diagnosis, prevention, and treatment of the diseases for which the subcommittees are established and members of the advisory council who are leaders in the fields of education and public affairs. The subcommittees are authorized to review applications made to the Director of the Institute for grants for research and training projects relating to the diagnosis, prevention, and treatment of the diseases for which the subcommittees are established and shall recommend to the advisory council those applications and contracts that the subcommittees determine will best carry out the purposes of the Institute. The subcommittees shall also review and evaluate the diabetes and endocrine and metabolic diseases, digestive diseases and nutrition, and kidney, urologic, and hematologic diseases programs of the Institute and recommend to the advisory council such changes in the administration of such programs as the subcommittees determine are necessary.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idb56ec76a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title IV, § 432, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/158/s2">Pub. L. 99–158, § 2</ref>, <date date="1985-11-20">Nov. 20, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/847">99 Stat. 847</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
