<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb56ec7a2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285d–4"><num value="285d–4">§ 285d–4.</num><heading> Interagency coordinating committees</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb56ec7a3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285d–4/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment and purpose</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56ec7a4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285d–4/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> better coordination of the research activities of all the national research institutes relating to arthritis, musculoskeletal diseases, and skin diseases, including sports-related disorders; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb56ec7a5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285d–4/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> coordinating the aspects of all Federal health programs and activities relating to arthritis, musculoskeletal diseases, and skin diseases in order to assure the adequacy and technical soundness of such programs and activities and in order to provide for the full communication and exchange of information necessary to maintain adequate coordination of such programs and activities,</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Secretary shall establish an Arthritis and Musculoskeletal Diseases Interagency Coordinating Committee and a Skin Diseases Interagency Coordinating Committee (hereafter in this section individually referred to as a “Committee”).</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb56ec7a6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285d–4/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Membership; chairman; meetings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each Committee shall be composed of the Directors of each of the national research institutes and divisions involved in research regarding the diseases with respect to which the Committee is established, the Under Secretary for Health of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Health Affairs (or the designees of such officers), and representatives of all other Federal departments and agencies (as determined by the Secretary) whose programs involve health functions or responsibilities relevant to arthritis and musculoskeletal diseases or skin diseases, as the case may be. Each Committee shall be chaired by the Director of NIH (or the designee of the Director). Each Committee shall meet at the call of the chairman, but not less often than four times a year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb56ec7a7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title IV, § 439, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/158/s2">Pub. L. 99–158, § 2</ref>, <date date="1985-11-20">Nov. 20, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/849">99 Stat. 849</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/102/405/tIII/s302/e/1">Pub. L. 102–405, title III, § 302(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-09">Oct. 9, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1985">106 Stat. 1985</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/43/tXX/s2008/b/6">Pub. L. 103–43, title XX, § 2008(b)(6)</ref>, <date date="1993-06-10">June 10, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/211">107 Stat. 211</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/105/362/tVI/s601/a/1/D">Pub. L. 105–362, title VI, § 601(a)(1)(D)</ref>, <date date="1998-11-10">Nov. 10, 1998</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/112/3285">112 Stat. 3285</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb56ec7a8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb56ec7a9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb56ec7aa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1998—Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/105/362">Pub. L. 105–362</ref> struck out subsec. (c) which read as follows: “Not later than 120 days after the end of each fiscal year, each Committee shall prepare and transmit to the Secretary, the Director of NIH, the Director of the Institute, and the advisory council for the Institute a report detailing the activities of the Committee in such fiscal year in carrying out paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) of this section.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/103/43">Pub. L. 103–43</ref> substituted “Department of Veterans Affairs” for “Veterans’ Administration”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/102/405">Pub. L. 102–405</ref> substituted “Under Secretary for Health” for “Chief Medical Director”.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
