<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb5713806-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285e"><num value="285e">§ 285e.</num><heading> Purpose of Institute</heading><content>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The general purpose of the National Institute on Aging (hereafter in this subpart referred to as the “Institute”) is the conduct and support of biomedical, social, and behavioral research, training, health information dissemination, and other programs with respect to the aging process and the diseases and other special problems and needs of the aged.</p>
</content><sourceCredit id="idb5713807-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title IV, § 443, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/158/s2">Pub. L. 99–158, § 2</ref>, <date date="1985-11-20">Nov. 20, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/854">99 Stat. 854</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb5713808-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb5713809-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb571380a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study of Malnutrition in Elderly</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/103/43/tXIX/s1902">Pub. L. 103–43, title XIX, § 1902</ref>, <date date="1993-06-10">June 10, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/201">107 Stat. 201</ref>, directed Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through National Institute on Aging, to conduct a 3-year study on health benefits and cost-effectiveness of nutrition screening and intervention activities of the elderly, and a 3-year study to determine extent of malnutrition in elderly individuals in hospitals and long-term care facilities and in elderly individuals who are living independently, provided for creation of advisory panel to oversee studies, provided for submission to Congress of reports containing findings of such studies, and provided for termination of advisory panel 3 years after <date date="1993-06-10">June 10, 1993</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb571380b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Study of Personnel for Health Needs of Elderly</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/158/s8">Section 8 of Pub. L. 99–158</ref> directed Secretary to conduct a study on the adequacy and availability of personnel to meet the current and projected health needs (including needs for home and community-based care) of elderly Americans through the year 2020, and report the results of the study, with recommendations, to Congress by <date date="1987-03-01">Mar. 1, 1987</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
