<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb57863f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285l–4"><num value="285l–4">§ 285l–4.</num><heading> Federal agency action</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb57863f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285l–4/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Identification of tests</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With respect to each Federal agency carrying out a program that requires or recommends acute or chronic toxicological testing, such agency shall, not later than 180 days after receiving an ICCVAM test recommendation, identify and forward to the ICCVAM any relevant test method specified in a regulation or industry-wide guideline which specifically, or in practice requires, recommends, or encourages the use of an animal acute or chronic toxicological test method for which the ICCVAM test recommendation may be added or substituted.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb57863f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285l–4/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Alternatives</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each Federal agency carrying out a program described in subsection (a) shall promote and encourage the development and use of alternatives to animal test methods (including batteries of tests and test screens), where appropriate, for the purpose of complying with Federal statutes, regulations, guidelines, or recommendations (in each instance, and for each chemical class) if such test methods are found to be effective for generating data, in an amount and of a scientific value that is at least equivalent to the data generated from existing tests, for hazard identification, dose-response assessment, or risk assessment purposes.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb57863f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285l–4/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Test method validation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each Federal agency carrying out a program described in subsection (a) shall ensure that any new or revised acute or chronic toxicity test method, including animal test methods and alternatives, is determined to be valid for its proposed use prior to requiring, recommending, or encouraging the application of such test method.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb57863f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285l–4/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Review</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 180 days after receipt of an ICCVAM test recommendation, a Federal agency carrying out a program described in subsection (a) shall review such recommendation and notify the ICCVAM in writing of its findings.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb57863f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285l–4/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Recommendation adoption</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Each Federal agency carrying out a program described in subsection (a), or its specific regulatory unit or units, shall adopt the ICCVAM test recommendation unless such Federal agency determines that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb57863fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285l–4/e/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the ICCVAM test recommendation is not adequate in terms of biological relevance for the regulatory goal authorized by that agency, or mandated by Congress;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb57863fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285l–4/e/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the ICCVAM test recommendation does not generate data, in an amount and of a scientific value that is at least equivalent to the data generated prior to such recommendation, for the appropriate hazard identification, dose-response assessment, or risk assessment purposes as the current test method recommended or required by that agency;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb57863fc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285l–4/e/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> the agency does not employ, recommend, or require testing for that class of chemical or for the recommended test endpoint; or</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb57863fd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285l–4/e/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> the ICCVAM test recommendation is unacceptable for satisfactorily fulfilling the test needs for that particular agency and its respective congressional mandate.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb57863fe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/106/545/s4">Pub. L. 106–545, § 4</ref>, <date date="2000-12-19">Dec. 19, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/2723">114 Stat. 2723</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb57863ff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb5786400-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb5786401-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the ICCVAM Authorization Act of 2000, and not as part of the Public Health Service Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
