<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb578644b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285m–4"><num value="285m–4">§ 285m–4.</num><heading> National Institute on Deafness and Other Communication Disorders Advisory Board</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb578644c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285m–4/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall establish in the Institute the National Deafness and Other Communication Disorders Advisory Board (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Advisory Board”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb578644d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285m–4/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Composition; qualifications; appointed and ex officio members</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Advisory Board shall be composed of eighteen appointed members and nonvoting ex officio members as follows:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb578644e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285m–4/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> The Secretary shall appoint—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb578644f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285m–4/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> twelve members from individuals who are scientists, physicians, and other health and rehabilitation professionals, who are not officers or employees of the United States, and who represent the specialties and disciplines relevant to deafness and other communication disorders, including not less than two persons with a communication disorder; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5786450-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285m–4/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> six members from the general public who are knowledgeable with respect to such disorders, including not less than one person with a communication disorder and not less than one person who is a parent of an individual with such a disorder.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">Of the appointed members, not less than five shall by virtue of training or experience be knowledgeable in diagnoses and rehabilitation of communication disorders, education of the hearing, speech, or language impaired, public health, public information, community program development, occupational hazards to communications senses, or the aging process.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5786451-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285m–4/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The following shall be ex officio members of each Advisory Board:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5786452-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285m–4/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> The Assistant Secretary for Health, the Director of NIH, the Director of the National Institute on Deafness and Other Communication Disorders, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Under Secretary for Health of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Health Affairs (or the designees of such officers).</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5786453-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285m–4/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Such other officers and employees of the United States as the Secretary determines necessary for the Advisory Board to carry out its functions.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5786454-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285m–4/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Compensation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Members of an Advisory Board who are officers or employees of the Federal Government shall serve as members of the Advisory Board without compensation in addition to that received in their regular public employment. Other members of the Board shall receive compensation at rates not to exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate in effect for grade GS–18 of the General Schedule for each day (including traveltime) they are engaged in the performance of their duties as members of the Board.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5786455-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285m–4/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Term of office; vacancies</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The term of office of an appointed member of the Advisory Board is four years, except that no term of office may extend beyond the expiration of the Advisory Board. Any member appointed to fill a vacancy for an unexpired term shall be appointed for the remainder of such term. A member may serve after the expiration of the member’s term until a successor has taken office. If a vacancy occurs in the Advisory Board, the Secretary shall make an appointment to fill the vacancy not later than 90 days from the date the vacancy occurred.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5786456-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285m–4/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Chairman</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The members of the Advisory Board shall select a chairman from among the appointed members.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5786457-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285m–4/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Personnel; executive director; professional and clerical staff members; consultants; information and administrative support services and facilities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall, after consultation with and consideration of the recommendations of the Advisory Board, provide the Advisory Board with an executive director and one other professional staff member. In addition, the Secretary shall, after consultation with and consideration of the recommendations of the Advisory Board, provide the Advisory Board with such additional professional staff members, such clerical staff members, such services of consultants, such information, and (through contracts or other arrangements) such administrative support services and facilities, as the Secretary determines are necessary for the Advisory Board to carry out its functions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5786458-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285m–4/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Meetings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Advisory Board shall meet at the call of the chairman or upon request of the Director of the Institute, but not less often than four times a year.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5786459-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285m–4/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Functions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Advisory Board shall—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb578645a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285m–4/h/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> review and evaluate the implementation of the plan prepared under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s285m–1/a">section 285m–1(a) of this title</ref> and periodically update the plan to ensure its continuing relevance;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb578645b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285m–4/h/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> for the purpose of assuring the most effective use and organization of resources respecting deafness and other communication disorders, advise and make recommendations to the Congress, the Secretary, the Director of NIH, the Director of the Institute, and the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies for the implementation and revision of such plan; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb578645c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285m–4/h/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> maintain liaison with other advisory bodies related to Federal agencies involved in the implementation of such plan and with key non-Federal entities involved in activities affecting the control of such disorders.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb578645d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285m–4/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Subcommittee activities; workshops and conferences; collection of data</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In carrying out its functions, the Advisory Board may establish subcommittees, convene workshops and conferences, and collect data. Such subcommittees may be composed of Advisory Board members and nonmember consultants with expertise in the particular area addressed by such subcommittees. The subcommittees may hold such meetings as are necessary to enable them to carry out their activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb578645e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285m–4/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Repealed. <ref href="/us/pl/109/482/tI/s104/b/1/J">Pub. L. 109–482, title I, § 104(b)(1)(J)</ref>, <date date="2007-01-15">Jan. 15, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3693">120 Stat. 3693</ref></heading><content />
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb578645f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285m–4/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Commencement of existence</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The National Deafness and Other Communication Disorders Advisory Board shall be established not later than <date date="1989-04-01">April 1, 1989</date>.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb5786460-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title IV, § 464D, as added <ref href="/us/pl/100/553/s2/4">Pub. L. 100–553, § 2(4)</ref>, <date date="1988-10-28">Oct. 28, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/2772">102 Stat. 2772</ref>, and <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tII/s2613/a/1">Pub. L. 100–690, title II, § 2613(a)(1)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4235">102 Stat. 4235</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/tII/s2613/b/2">Pub. L. 100–690, title II, § 2613(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="1988-11-18">Nov. 18, 1988</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/102/4238">102 Stat. 4238</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/101/93/s5/b">Pub. L. 101–93, § 5(b)</ref>, <date date="1989-08-16">Aug. 16, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/611">103 Stat. 611</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/405/tIII/s302/e/1">Pub. L. 102–405, title III, § 302(e)(1)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-09">Oct. 9, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1985">106 Stat. 1985</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/102/531/tIII/s312/d/8">Pub. L. 102–531, title III, § 312(d)(8)</ref>, <date date="1992-10-27">Oct. 27, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/3504">106 Stat. 3504</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/103/43/tXX/s2008/b/8">Pub. L. 103–43, title XX, § 2008(b)(8)</ref>, <date date="1993-06-10">June 10, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/211">107 Stat. 211</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/109/482/tI/s104/b/1/J">Pub. L. 109–482, title I, § 104(b)(1)(J)</ref>, <date date="2007-01-15">Jan. 15, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3693">120 Stat. 3693</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb5786461-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb5786462-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb5786463-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/100/553">Pub. L. 100–553</ref> and <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s2613/a/1">section 2613(a)(1) of Pub. L. 100–690</ref> contained identical provisions enacting this section. See 1988 Amendment note below.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb5786464-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Subsec. (j). <ref href="/us/pl/109/482">Pub. L. 109–482</ref> struck out subsec. (j) which read as follows: “The Advisory Board shall prepare an annual report for the Secretary which—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) describes the Advisory Board’s activities in the fiscal year for which the report is made;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) describes and evaluates the progress made in such fiscal year in research, treatment, education, and training with respect to the deafness and other communication disorders;</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(3) summarizes and analyzes expenditures made by the Federal Government for activities respecting such disorders in such fiscal year; and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(4) contains the Advisory Board’s recommendations (if any) for changes in the plan prepared under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s285m–1/a">section 285m–1(a) of this title</ref>.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1993—Subsec. (b)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/103/43">Pub. L. 103–43</ref> substituted “Department of Veterans Affairs” for “Veterans’ Administration”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1992—Subsec. (b)(2)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/102/531">Pub. L. 102–531</ref> substituted “Centers for Disease Control and Prevention” for “Centers for Disease Control”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/405">Pub. L. 102–405</ref> substituted “Under Secretary for Health” for “Chief Medical Director”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1989—Subsec. (k). <ref href="/us/pl/101/93">Pub. L. 101–93</ref> substituted “<date date="1989-04-01">April 1, 1989</date>” for “90 days after the date of the enactment of the National Institute on Deafness and Other Communication Disorders Act”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1988—<ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s2613/b/2">Pub. L. 100–690, § 2613(b)(2)</ref>, amended this section to read as if the amendments made by <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s2613/a/1">Pub. L. 100–690, § 2613(a)(1)</ref>, which enacted this section, had not been enacted. See Codification note above.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb5786465-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb5786466-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2007 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/482">Pub. L. 109–482</ref> applicable only with respect to amounts appropriated for fiscal year 2007 or subsequent fiscal years, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/482/s109">section 109 of Pub. L. 109–482</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s281">section 281 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb5786467-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1988 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">For effective date of amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s2613/b/2">section 2613(b)(2) of Pub. L. 100–690</ref>, see <ref href="/us/pl/100/690/s2613/b/1">section 2613(b)(1) of Pub. L. 100–690</ref>, set out as an Effect of Enactment of Similar Provisions note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s285m">section 285m of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb5786468-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Termination of Advisory Boards</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Advisory boards established after <date date="1973-01-05">Jan. 5, 1973</date>, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on the date of their establishment, unless, in the case of a board established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such board is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a board established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided by law. See sections 1001(2) and 1013 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/93/641/s6">Pub. L. 93–641, § 6</ref>, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2275">88 Stat. 2275</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s217a">section 217a of this title</ref>, provided that an advisory committee established pursuant to the Public Health Service Act shall terminate at such time as may be specifically prescribed by an Act of Congress enacted after <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb5786469-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Other Laws to GS–16, 17, or 18 Pay Rates</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">References in laws to the rates of pay for GS–16, 17, or 18, or to maximum rates of pay under the General Schedule, to be considered references to rates payable under specified sections of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, see section 529 [title I, § 101(c)(1)] of <ref href="/us/pl/101/509">Pub. L. 101–509</ref>, set out in a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s5376">section 5376 of Title 5</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
