<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb57d1f84-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r"><num value="285r">§ 285r.</num><heading> Purpose of the Institute</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb57d1f85-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The general purpose of the National Institute of Biomedical Imaging and Bioengineering (in this section referred to as the “Institute”) is the conduct and support of research, training, the dissemination of health information, and other programs with respect to biomedical imaging, biomedical engineering, and associated technologies and modalities with biomedical applications (in this section referred to as “biomedical imaging and bioengineering”).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb57d1f86-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> National Biomedical Imaging and Bioengineering Program</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb57d1f87-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The Director of the Institute, with the advice of the Institute’s advisory council, shall establish a National Biomedical Imaging and Bioengineering Program (in this section referred to as the “Program”).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb57d1f88-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Activities under the Program shall include the following with respect to biomedical imaging and bioengineering:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb57d1f89-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r/b/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> Research into the development of new techniques and devices.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb57d1f8a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r/b/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> Related research in physics, engineering, mathematics, computer science, and other disciplines.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb57d1f8b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r/b/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> Technology assessments and outcomes studies to evaluate the effectiveness of biologics, materials, processes, devices, procedures, and informatics.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb57d1f8c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r/b/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> Research in screening for diseases and disorders.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb57d1f8d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r/b/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> The advancement of existing imaging and bioengineering modalities, including imaging, biomaterials, and informatics.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb57d1f8e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r/b/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> The development of target-specific agents to enhance images and to identify and delineate disease.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb57d1f8f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r/b/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> The development of advanced engineering and imaging technologies and techniques for research from the molecular and genetic to the whole organ and body levels.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb57d1f90-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r/b/2/H"><num value="H">(H)</num><content> The development of new techniques and devices for more effective interventional procedures (such as image-guided interventions).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb57d1f91-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb57d1f92-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> With respect to the Program, the Director of the Institute shall prepare and transmit to the Secretary and the Director of NIH a plan to initiate, expand, intensify, and coordinate activities of the Institute with respect to biomedical imaging and bioengineering. The plan shall include such comments and recommendations as the Director of the Institute determines appropriate. The Director of the Institute shall periodically review and revise the plan and shall transmit any revisions of the plan to the Secretary and the Director of NIH.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb57d1f93-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><chapeau> The plan under subparagraph (A) shall include the recommendations of the Director of the Institute with respect to the following:</chapeau><clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb57d1f94-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r/b/3/B/i"><num value="i">(i)</num><content> Where appropriate, the consolidation of programs of the National Institutes of Health for the express purpose of enhancing support of activities regarding basic biomedical imaging and bioengineering research.</content>
</clause>
<clause style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb57d1f95-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r/b/3/B/ii"><num value="ii">(ii)</num><content> The coordination of the activities of the Institute with related activities of the other agencies of the National Institutes of Health and with related activities of other Federal agencies.</content>
</clause>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb57d1f96-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Membership</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The establishment under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s284a">section 284a of this title</ref> of an advisory council for the Institute is subject to the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb57d1f97-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The number of members appointed by the Secretary shall be 12.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb57d1f98-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> Of such members—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb57d1f99-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r/c/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> six members shall be scientists, engineers, physicians, and other health professionals who represent disciplines in biomedical imaging and bioengineering and who are not officers or employees of the United States; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb57d1f9a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r/c/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> six members shall be scientists, engineers, physicians, and other health professionals who represent other disciplines and are knowledgeable about the applications of biomedical imaging and bioengineering in medicine, and who are not officers or employees of the United States.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb57d1f9b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s285r/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> In addition to the ex officio members specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s284a/b/2">section 284a(b)(2) of this title</ref>, the ex officio members of the advisory council shall include the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Director of the National Science Foundation, and the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (or the designees of such officers).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb57d1f9c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title IV, § 464z, as added <ref href="/us/pl/106/580/s3/a">Pub. L. 106–580, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2000-12-29">Dec. 29, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/3089">114 Stat. 3089</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/109/482/tI/s103/b/37">Pub. L. 109–482, title I, § 103(b)(37)</ref>, <date date="2007-01-15">Jan. 15, 2007</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/120/3688">120 Stat. 3688</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb57d1f9d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb57d1f9e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb57d1f9f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2007—Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/109/482">Pub. L. 109–482</ref> struck out subsec. (d) which related to appropriations for fiscal years 2001 to 2003.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb57d1fa0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb57d1fa1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2007 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/109/482">Pub. L. 109–482</ref> applicable only with respect to amounts appropriated for fiscal year 2007 or subsequent fiscal years, see <ref href="/us/pl/109/482/s109">section 109 of Pub. L. 109–482</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s281">section 281 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDate" id="idb57d1fa2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/580/s4">Pub. L. 106–580, § 4</ref>, <date date="2000-12-29">Dec. 29, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/3092">114 Stat. 3092</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/580/s4">“This Act [enacting this subpart, amending <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s281">section 281 of this title</ref>, and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">section 201 of this title</ref>] takes effect <date date="2000-10-01">October 1, 2000</date>, or upon the date of the enactment of this Act [<date date="2000-12-29">Dec. 29, 2000</date>], whichever occurs later.”</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb57d1fa3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Findings</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/580/s2">Pub. L. 106–580, § 2</ref>, <date date="2000-12-29">Dec. 29, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/3088">114 Stat. 3088</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/580/s2">
<inline>“The Congress makes the following findings:</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> Basic research in imaging, bioengineering, computer science, informatics, and related fields is critical to improving health care but is fundamentally different from the research in molecular biology on which the current national research institutes at the National Institutes of Health (‘NIH’) are based. To ensure the development of new techniques and technologies for the 21st century, these disciplines therefore require an identity and research home at the NIH that is independent of the existing institute structure.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Advances based on medical research promise new, more effective treatments for a wide variety of diseases, but the development of new, noninvasive imaging techniques for earlier detection and diagnosis of disease is essential to take full advantage of such new treatments and to promote the general improvement of health care.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> The development of advanced genetic and molecular imaging techniques is necessary to continue the current rapid pace of discovery in molecular biology.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> Advances in telemedicine, and teleradiology in particular, are increasingly important in the delivery of high quality, reliable medical care to rural citizens and other underserved populations. To fulfill the promise of telemedicine and related technologies fully, a structure is needed at the NIH to support basic research focused on the acquisition, transmission, processing, and optimal display of images.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> A number of Federal departments and agencies support imaging and engineering research with potential medical applications, but a central coordinating body, preferably housed at the NIH, is needed to coordinate these disparate efforts and facilitate the transfer of technologies with medical applications.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> Several breakthrough imaging technologies, including magnetic resonance imaging (‘MRI’) and computed tomography (‘CT’), have been developed primarily abroad, in large part because of the absence of a home at the NIH for basic research in imaging and related fields. The establishment of a central focus for imaging and bioengineering research at the NIH would promote both scientific advance and United States economic development.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> At a time when a consensus exists to add significant resources to the NIH in coming years, it is appropriate to modernize the structure of the NIH to ensure that research dollars are expended more effectively and efficiently and that the fields of medical science that have contributed the most to the detection, diagnosis, and treatment of disease in recent years receive appropriate emphasis.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> The establishment of a National Institute of Biomedical Imaging and Bioengineering at the NIH would accelerate the development of new technologies with clinical and research applications, improve coordination and efficiency at the NIH and throughout the Federal Government, reduce duplication and waste, lay the foundation for a new medical information age, promote economic development, and provide a structure to train the young researchers who will make the pathbreaking discoveries of the next century.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb57d1fa4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Establishment of Institute and Advisory Council</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/106/580/s3/b">Pub. L. 106–580, § 3(b)</ref>–(d), <date date="2000-12-29">Dec. 29, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/3091">114 Stat. 3091</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/106/580/s3/b">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Use of Existing Resources</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In providing for the establishment of the National Institute of Biomedical Imaging and Bioengineering pursuant to the amendment made by subsection (a) [enacting this subpart], the Director of the National Institutes of Health (referred to in this subsection as ‘NIH’)—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> may transfer to the National Institute of Biomedical Imaging and Bioengineering such personnel of NIH as the Director determines to be appropriate;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> may, for quarters for such Institute, utilize such facilities of NIH as the Director determines to be appropriate; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> may obtain administrative support for the Institute from the other agencies of NIH, including the other national research institutes.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="c">“(c)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Construction of Facilities</inline>.—</heading><content>None of the provisions of this Act [enacting this subpart, amending <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s281">section 281 of this title</ref>, and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s201">section 201 of this title</ref>] or the amendments made by the Act may be construed as authorizing the construction of facilities, or the acquisition of land, for purposes of the establishment or operation of the National Institute of Biomedical Imaging and Bioengineering.</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="d">“(d)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Date Certain for Establishment of Advisory Council</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 90 days after the effective date of this Act [<date date="2000-12-29">Dec. 29, 2000</date>] under section 4 [set out above], the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall complete the establishment of an advisory council for the National Institute of Biomedical Imaging and Bioengineering in accordance with section 406 of the Public Health Service Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s284a">42 U.S.C. 284a</ref>] and in accordance with section 464z of such Act (as added by subsection (a) of this section) [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s285r">42 U.S.C. 285r</ref>].”</content>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
