<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb58d9954-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d"><num value="289d">§ 289d.</num><heading> Animals in research</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb58d9955-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Establishment of guidelines</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, acting through the Director of NIH, shall establish guidelines for the following:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb58d9956-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> The proper care of animals to be used in biomedical and behavioral research.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb58d9957-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><chapeau> The proper treatment of animals while being used in such research. Guidelines under this paragraph shall require—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb58d9958-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d/a/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the appropriate use of tranquilizers, analgesics, anesthetics, paralytics, and euthanasia for animals in such research; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb58d9959-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d/a/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> appropriate pre-surgical and post-surgical veterinary medical and nursing care for animals in such research.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I17" class="indent1 firstIndent0">Such guidelines shall not be construed to prescribe methods of research.</continuation>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb58d995a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> The organization and operation of animal care committees in accordance with subsection (b).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb58d995b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Animal care committees; establishment; membership; functions</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb58d995c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> Guidelines of the Secretary under subsection (a)(3) shall require animal care committees at each entity which conducts biomedical and behavioral research with funds provided under this chapter (including the National Institutes of Health and the national research institutes) to assure compliance with the guidelines established under subsection (a).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb58d995d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Each animal care committee shall be appointed by the chief executive officer of the entity for which the committee is established, shall be composed of not fewer than three members, and shall include at least one individual who has no association with such entity and at least one doctor of veterinary medicine.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0" id="idb58d995e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><chapeau> Each animal care committee of a research entity shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb58d995f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d/b/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> review the care and treatment of animals in all animal study areas and facilities of the research entity at least semi-annually to evaluate compliance with applicable guidelines established under subsection (a) for appropriate animal care and treatment;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb58d9960-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d/b/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> keep appropriate records of reviews conducted under subparagraph (A); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb58d9961-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d/b/3/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> for each review conducted under subparagraph (A), file with the Director of NIH at least annually (i) a certification that the review has been conducted, and (ii) reports of any violations of guidelines established under subsection (a) or assurances required under paragraph (1) which were observed in such review and which have continued after notice by the committee to the research entity involved of the violations.</content>
</subparagraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Reports filed under subparagraph (C) shall include any minority views filed by members of the committee.</continuation>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb58d9962-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Assurances required in application or contract proposal; reasons for use of animals; notice and comment requirements for promulgation of regulations</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Director of NIH shall require each applicant for a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement involving research on animals which is administered by the National Institutes of Health or any national research institute to include in its application or contract proposal, submitted after the expiration of the twelve-month period beginning on <date date="1985-11-20">November 20, 1985</date>—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb58d9963-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><chapeau> assurances satisfactory to the Director of NIH that—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb58d9964-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d/c/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the applicant meets the requirements of the guidelines established under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) and has an animal care committee which meets the requirements of subsection (b); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb58d9965-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d/c/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> scientists, animal technicians, and other personnel involved with animal care, treatment, and use by the applicant have available to them instruction or training in the humane practice of animal maintenance and experimentation, and the concept, availability, and use of research or testing methods that limit the use of animals or limit animal distress; and</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb58d9966-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a statement of the reasons for the use of animals in the research to be conducted with funds provided under such grant or contract.</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">Notwithstanding subsection (a)(2) of <ref href="/us/usc/t5/s553">section 553 of title 5</ref>, regulations under this subsection shall be promulgated in accordance with the notice and comment requirements of such section.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb58d9967-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Failure to meet guidelines; suspension or revocation of grant or contract</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">If the Director of NIH determines that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb58d9968-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d/d/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> the conditions of animal care, treatment, or use in an entity which is receiving a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement involving research on animals under this subchapter do not meet applicable guidelines established under subsection (a);</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb58d9969-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d/d/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> the entity has been notified by the Director of NIH of such determination and has been given a reasonable opportunity to take corrective action; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb58d996a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d/d/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> no action has been taken by the entity to correct such conditions;</content>
</paragraph>

<continuation style="-uslm-lc:I10" class="indent0 firstIndent0">the Director of NIH shall suspend or revoke such grant or contract under such conditions as the Director determines appropriate.</continuation>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb58d996b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s289d/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Disclosure of trade secrets or privileged or confidential information</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No guideline or regulation promulgated under subsection (a) or (c) may require a research entity to disclose publicly trade secrets or commercial or financial information which is privileged or confidential.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb58d996c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title IV, § 495, as added <ref href="/us/pl/99/158/s2">Pub. L. 99–158, § 2</ref>, <date date="1985-11-20">Nov. 20, 1985</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/99/875">99 Stat. 875</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb58d996d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb58d996e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb58d996f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prohibition on Funding of Projects Involving Use of Chimpanzees Obtained From the Wild</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/102/394/tII/s213">Pub. L. 102–394, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="1992-10-06">Oct. 6, 1992</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/106/1812">106 Stat. 1812</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/102/394/tII/s213">“No funds appropriated under this Act or subsequent Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Acts shall be used by the National Institutes of Health, or any other Federal agency, or recipient of Federal funds on any project that entails the capture or procurement of chimpanzees obtained from the wild. For purposes of this section, the term ‘recipient of Federal funds’ includes private citizens, corporations, or other research institutions located outside of the United States that are recipients of Federal funds.”</quotedContent>
</p>
<p>Similar provisions were contained in the following prior appropriation acts:</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/102/170/tII/s213">Pub. L. 102–170, title II, § 213</ref>, <date date="1991-11-26">Nov. 26, 1991</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/105/1127">105 Stat. 1127</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/517/tII/s211">Pub. L. 101–517, title II, § 211</ref>, <date date="1990-11-05">Nov. 5, 1990</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/104/2209">104 Stat. 2209</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/101/166/tII/s214">Pub. L. 101–166, title II, § 214</ref>, <date date="1989-11-21">Nov. 21, 1989</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/103/1178">103 Stat. 1178</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb58d9970-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Plan for Research Involving Animals</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/99/158/s4">Section 4 of Pub. L. 99–158</ref> directed Director of National Institutes of Health to establish, not later than <date date="1986-10-01">Oct. 1, 1986</date>, a plan for research into methods of biomedical research and experimentation which reduces the use of animals in research or which produce less pain and distress in animals to develop methods found to be valid and reliable, to train scientists in use of such methods, to disseminate information on such methods and to establish an Interagency Coordinating Committee to assist in development of the plan, prior to repeal by <ref href="/us/pl/103/43/tII/s205/b">Pub. L. 103–43, title II, § 205(b)</ref>, <date date="1993-06-10">June 10, 1993</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/107/148">107 Stat. 148</ref>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s283e">section 283e of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
