<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb59e89c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290aa–2a"><num value="290aa–2a">§ 290aa–2a.</num><heading> Report on individuals with co-occurring mental illness and substance abuse disorders</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb59e89ca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290aa–2a/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2000-10-17">October 17, 2000</date>, the Secretary shall, after consultation with organizations representing States, mental health and substance abuse treatment providers, prevention specialists, individuals receiving treatment services, and family members of such individuals, prepare and submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Commerce of the House of Representatives, a report on prevention and treatment services for individuals who have co-occurring mental illness and substance abuse disorders.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb59e89cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290aa–2a/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Report content</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The report under subsection (a) shall be based on data collected from existing Federal and State surveys regarding the treatment of co-occurring mental illness and substance abuse disorders and shall include—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb59e89cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290aa–2a/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a summary of the manner in which individuals with co-occurring disorders are receiving treatment, including the most up-to-date information available regarding the number of children and adults with co-occurring mental illness and substance abuse disorders and the manner in which funds provided under sections 300x and 300x–21 of this title are being utilized, including the number of such children and adults served with such funds;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb59e89cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290aa–2a/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> a summary of improvements necessary to ensure that individuals with co-occurring mental illness and substance abuse disorders receive the services they need;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb59e89ce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290aa–2a/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> a summary of practices for preventing substance abuse among individuals who have a mental illness and are at risk of having or acquiring a substance abuse disorder; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb59e89cf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290aa–2a/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> a summary of evidenced-based practices for treating individuals with co-occurring mental illness and substance abuse disorders and recommendations for implementing such practices.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb59e89d0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290aa–2a/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Funds for report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary may obligate funds to carry out this section with such appropriations as are available.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb59e89d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title V, § 503A, as added <ref href="/us/pl/106/310/dB/tXXXIV/s3406">Pub. L. 106–310, div. B, title XXXIV, § 3406</ref>, <date date="2000-10-17">Oct. 17, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1221">114 Stat. 1221</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb59e89d2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb59e89d3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idb59e89d4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Committee on Commerce of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives, and jurisdiction over matters relating to securities and exchanges and insurance generally transferred to Committee on Financial Services of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Seventh Congress, <date date="2001-01-03">Jan. 3, 2001</date>.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
