<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb5a5b5da-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–11"><num value="290bb–11">§ 290bb–11.</num><heading> Building capacity for family-focused residential treatment</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5a5b5db-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–11/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5a5b5dc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–11/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible entity</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “eligible entity” means a State, county, local, or tribal health or child welfare agency, a private nonprofit organization, a research organization, a treatment service provider, an institution of higher education (as defined under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">section 1001 of title 20</ref>), or another entity specified by the Secretary.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5a5b5dd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–11/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Family-focused residential treatment program</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “family-focused residential treatment program” means a trauma-informed residential program primarily for substance use disorder treatment for pregnant and postpartum women and parents and guardians that allows children to reside with such women or their parents or guardians during treatment to the extent appropriate and applicable.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5a5b5de-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–11/a/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Secretary</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5a5b5df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–11/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Support for the development of evidence-based family-focused residential treatment programs</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5a5b5e0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–11/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Authority to award grants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities for purposes of developing, enhancing, or evaluating family-focused residential treatment programs to increase the availability of such programs that meet the requirements for promising, supported, or well-supported practices specified in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s671/e/4/C">section 671(e)(4)(C) of this title</ref>) <ref class="footnoteRef" idref="fn002225">1</ref><note type="footnote" id="fn002225"><num>1</num> So in original.</note> (as added by the Family First Prevention Services Act enacted under title VII of division E of <ref href="/us/pl/115/123">Public Law 115–123</ref>).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5a5b5e1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–11/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Evaluation requirement</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall require any evaluation of a family-focused residential treatment program by an eligible entity that uses funds awarded under this section for all or part of the costs of the evaluation be designed to assist in the determination of whether the program may qualify as a promising, supported, or well-supported practice in accordance with the requirements of such section 671(e)(4)(C).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5a5b5e2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–11/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section, $20,000,000 for fiscal year 2019, which shall remain available through fiscal year 2023.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb5a5b5e3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/pl/115/271/tVIII/s8083">Pub. L. 115–271, title VIII, § 8083</ref>, <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4102">132 Stat. 4102</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb5a5b5e4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb5a5b5e5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb5a5b5e6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Family First Prevention Services Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), is title VII of <ref href="/us/pl/115/123/dE">Pub. L. 115–123, div. E</ref>, <date date="2018-02-09">Feb. 9, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/232">132 Stat. 232</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb5a5b5e7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Section was enacted as part of the Substance Use–Disorder Prevention that Promotes Opioid Recovery and Treatment for Patients and Communities Act, also known as the SUPPORT for Patients and Communities Act, and not as part of the Public Health Service Act which comprises this chapter.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb5a5b5e8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb5a5b5e9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Supporting Family-Focused Residential Treatment</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/115/271/tVIII/s8081">Pub. L. 115–271, title VIII, § 8081</ref>, <date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/132/4097">132 Stat. 4097</ref>, provided that:<quotedContent origin="/us/pl/115/271/tVIII/s8081">
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="a">“(a)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Definitions</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Family-focused residential treatment program</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘family-focused residential treatment program’ means a trauma-informed residential program primarily for substance use disorder treatment for pregnant and postpartum women and parents and guardians that allows children to reside with such women or their parents or guardians during treatment to the extent appropriate and applicable.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Medicaid program</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Medicaid program’ means the program established under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Secretary</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘Secretary’ means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Title iv–e program</inline>.—</heading><content>The term ‘title IV–E program’ means the program for foster care, prevention, and permanency established under part E of title IV of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s670">42 U.S.C. 670</ref> et seq.).</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><num value="b">“(b)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Guidance on Family-focused Residential Treatment Programs.—</inline></heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">In general</inline>.—</heading><content>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [<date date="2018-10-24">Oct. 24, 2018</date>], the Secretary, in consultation with divisions of the Department of Health and Human Services administering substance use disorder or child welfare programs, shall develop and issue guidance to States identifying opportunities to support family-focused residential treatment programs for the provision of substance use disorder treatment. Before issuing such guidance, the Secretary shall solicit input from representatives of States, health care providers with expertise in addiction medicine, obstetrics and gynecology, neonatology, child trauma, and child development, health plans, recipients of family-focused treatment services, and other relevant stakeholders.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><heading> <inline class="small-caps">Additional requirements</inline>.—</heading><chapeau>The guidance required under paragraph (1) shall include descriptions of the following:</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="A">“(A)</num><content> Existing opportunities and flexibilities under the Medicaid program, including under waivers authorized under section 1115 or 1915 of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1315">42 U.S.C. 1315</ref>, 1396n), for States to receive Federal Medicaid funding for the provision of substance use disorder treatment for pregnant and postpartum women and parents and guardians and, to the extent applicable, their children, in family-focused residential treatment programs.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="B">“(B)</num><content> How States can employ and coordinate funding provided under the Medicaid program, the title IV-E program, and other programs administered by the Secretary to support the provision of treatment and services provided by a family-focused residential treatment facility such as substance use disorder treatment and services, including medication-assisted treatment, family, group, and individual counseling, case management, parenting education and skills development, the provision, assessment, or coordination of care and services for children, including necessary assessments and appropriate interventions, non-emergency transportation for necessary care provided at or away from a program site, transitional services and supports for families leaving treatment, and other services.</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I23" class="indent2"><num value="C">“(C)</num><content> How States can employ and coordinate funding provided under the Medicaid program and the title IV–E program (including as amended by the Family First Prevention Services Act enacted under title VII of division E of <ref href="/us/pl/115/123">Public Law 115–123</ref> [<ref href="/us/stat/132/232">132 Stat. 232</ref>], and particularly with respect to the authority under subsections (a)(2)(C) and (j) of section 472 and section 474(a)(1) of the Social Security Act (<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s672">42 U.S.C. 672</ref>, 674(a)(1)) (as amended by <ref href="/us/pl/115/123/s50712">section 50712 of Public Law 115–123</ref>) to provide foster care maintenance payments for a child placed with a parent who is receiving treatment in a licensed residential family-based treatment facility for a substance use disorder) to support placing children with their parents in family-focused residential treatment programs.”</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
