<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb5af52bd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–34"><num value="290bb–34">§ 290bb–34.</num><heading> Suicide prevention technical assistance center</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af52be-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–34/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Program authorized</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af52bf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–34/a/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary, shall establish a research, training, and technical assistance resource center to provide appropriate information, training, and technical assistance to States, political subdivisions of States, federally recognized Indian Tribes, Tribal organizations, institutions of higher education, public organizations, or private nonprofit organizations regarding the prevention of suicide among all ages, particularly among groups that are at a high risk for suicide.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af52c0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–34/a/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Collaboration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In carrying out this subsection, as applicable with respect to assistance to entities serving members of the Armed Forces and veterans, the Secretary shall, as appropriate, collaborate with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af52c1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–34/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Responsibilities of the Center</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The center established under subsection (a) shall conduct activities for the purpose of—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52c2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–34/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> developing and continuing statewide or Tribal suicide early intervention and prevention strategies for all ages, particularly among groups that are at a high risk for suicide;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52c3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–34/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> ensuring the surveillance of suicide early intervention and prevention strategies for all ages, particularly among groups that are at a high risk for suicide;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52c4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–34/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> studying the costs and effectiveness of statewide and Tribal suicide early intervention and prevention strategies in order to provide information concerning relevant issues of importance to State, Tribal, and national policymakers;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52c5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–34/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> further identifying and understanding causes and associated risk factors for suicide;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52c6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–34/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> analyzing the efficacy of new and existing suicide early intervention and prevention techniques and technology;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52c7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–34/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> ensuring the surveillance of suicidal behaviors and nonfatal suicidal attempts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52c8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–34/b/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> studying the effectiveness of State-sponsored statewide and Tribal suicide early intervention and prevention strategies on the overall wellness and health promotion strategies related to suicide attempts;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52c9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–34/b/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> promoting the sharing of data regarding suicide with Federal agencies involved with suicide early intervention and prevention, and State-sponsored statewide or Tribal suicide early intervention and prevention strategies for the purpose of identifying previously unknown mental health causes and associated risk factors for suicide;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52ca-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–34/b/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> evaluating and disseminating outcomes and best practices of mental health and substance use disorder services at institutions of higher education; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52cb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–34/b/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> conducting other activities determined appropriate by the Secretary.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af52cc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–34/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of carrying out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $9,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af52cd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–34/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Annual report</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not later than 2 years after <date date="2022-12-29">December 29, 2022</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report on the activities carried out by the center established under subsection (a) during the year involved, including the potential effects of such activities, and the States, organizations, and institutions that have worked with the center.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb5af52ce-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title V, § 520C, as added <ref href="/us/pl/106/310/dB/tXXXI/s3104/b">Pub. L. 106–310, div. B, title XXXI, § 3104(b)</ref>, <date date="2000-10-17">Oct. 17, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1173">114 Stat. 1173</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/108/355/s3/a">Pub. L. 108–355, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-21">Oct. 21, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1405">118 Stat. 1405</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/dB/tVI/s6001/c/1">Pub. L. 114–255, div. B, title VI, § 6001(c)(1)</ref>, title IX, § 9008(a), <date date="2016-12-13">Dec. 13, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1203">130 Stat. 1203</ref>, 1241; <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dFF/tI/s1421">Pub. L. 117–328, div. FF, title I, § 1421</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5702">136 Stat. 5702</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb5af52cf-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb5af52d0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb5af52d1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—<ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s1421/a/2">Pub. L. 117–328, § 1421(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “Tribal” for “tribal” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s1421/b">Pub. L. 117–328, § 1421(b)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), inserted par. heading, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s1421/a/1">Pub. L. 117–328, § 1421(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Tribes” for “tribes”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s1421/c">Pub. L. 117–328, § 1421(c)</ref>, substituted “$9,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027” for “$5,988,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s1421/d">Pub. L. 117–328, § 1421(d)</ref>, substituted “Not later than 2 years after <date date="2022-12-29">December 29, 2022</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives” for “Not later than 2 years after <date date="2016-12-13">December 13, 2016</date>, the Secretary shall submit to Congress”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—<ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s9008/a/1">Pub. L. 114–255, § 9008(a)(1)</ref>, substituted “Suicide prevention technical assistance center” for “Youth interagency research, training, and technical assistance centers” in section catchline.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s9008/a/2">Pub. L. 114–255, § 9008(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “acting through the Assistant Secretary, shall establish a research, training, and technical assistance resource center to provide appropriate information, training, and technical assistance to States, political subdivisions of States, federally recognized Indian tribes, tribal organizations, institutions of higher education, public organizations, or private nonprofit organizations regarding the prevention of suicide among all ages, particularly among groups that are at a high risk for suicide.” for “acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, and in consultation with the Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention, the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance and the Director of the National Institutes of Health—</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(1) shall award grants or contracts to public or nonprofit private entities to establish not more than four research, training, and technical assistance centers to carry out the activities described in subsection (c); and</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1">“(2) shall award a competitive grant to 1 additional research, training, and technical assistance center to carry out the activities described in subsection (d).”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s6001/c/1">Pub. L. 114–255, § 6001(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use” for “Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s9008/a/5/C">Pub. L. 114–255, § 9008(a)(5)(C)</ref>, substituted “suicide” for “youth suicide” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s9008/a/5/B">Pub. L. 114–255, § 9008(a)(5)(B)</ref>, in introductory provisions, substituted “The center established under subsection (a) shall conduct activities for the purpose of” for “The additional research, training, and technical assistance center established under subsection (a)(2) shall provide appropriate information, training, and technical assistance to States, political subdivisions of a State, Federally recognized Indian tribes, tribal organizations, institutions of higher education, public organizations, or private nonprofit organizations for”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s9008/a/5/A">Pub. L. 114–255, § 9008(a)(5)(A)</ref>, substituted “Responsibilities of the Center” for “Additional center” in heading.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s9008/a/3">Pub. L. 114–255, § 9008(a)(3)</ref>, (4), redesignated subsec. (d) as (b) and struck out former subsec. (b). Text of subsec. (b) read as follows: “A public or private nonprofit entity desiring a grant or contract under subsection (a) shall prepare and submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.”</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s9008/a/5/D">Pub. L. 114–255, § 9008(a)(5)(D)</ref>, substituted “developing and continuing” for “the development or continuation of” and inserted “for all ages, particularly among groups that are at a high risk for suicide” before semicolon at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s9008/a/5/E">Pub. L. 114–255, § 9008(a)(5)(E)</ref>, inserted “for all ages, particularly among groups that are at a high risk for suicide” before semicolon at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s9008/a/5/F">Pub. L. 114–255, § 9008(a)(5)(F)</ref>, inserted “and tribal” after “statewide”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(5). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s9008/a/5/G">Pub. L. 114–255, § 9008(a)(5)(G)</ref>, inserted “and prevention” after “intervention”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(8). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s9008/a/5/H">Pub. L. 114–255, § 9008(a)(5)(H)</ref>, struck out “in youth” before semicolon at end.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s9008/a/5/I">Pub. L. 114–255, § 9008(a)(5)(I)</ref>, substituted “health and substance use disorder” for “and behavioral health”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(10). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s9008/a/5/J">Pub. L. 114–255, § 9008(a)(5)(J)</ref>, inserted “conducting” before “other”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsecs. (c) to (e). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s9008/a/6">Pub. L. 114–255, § 9008(a)(6)</ref>, added subsecs. (c) and (d) and struck out subsec. (e) which authorized appropriations for prior fiscal years.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2004—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/108/355/s3/a/1">Pub. L. 108–355, § 3(a)(1)</ref>, substituted dash for comma after “National Institutes of Health”, designated remainder of existing provisions as par. (1), substituted “; and” for period, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c). <ref href="/us/pl/108/355/s3/a/2">Pub. L. 108–355, § 3(a)(2)</ref>, substituted “(a)(1)” for “(a)” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/108/355/s3/a/5">Pub. L. 108–355, § 3(a)(5)</ref>, added subsec. (d). Former subsec. (d) redesignated (e).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/108/355/s3/a/3">Pub. L. 108–355, § 3(a)(3)</ref>, designated existing provisions as par. (1), substituted “awarding grants or contracts under subsection (a)(1)” for “carrying out this section”, and added par. (2).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/108/355/s3/a/4">Pub. L. 108–355, § 3(a)(4)</ref>, redesignated subsec. (d) as (e).</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
