<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb5af52d5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36"><num value="290bb–36">§ 290bb–36.</num><heading> Youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategies</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af52d6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, shall award grants or cooperative agreements to eligible entities to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52d7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> develop and implement State-sponsored statewide or Tribal youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategies in schools, educational institutions, juvenile justice systems, substance use disorder programs, mental health programs, foster care systems, pediatric health programs, and other child and youth support organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52d8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> support public organizations and private nonprofit organizations actively involved in State-sponsored statewide or Tribal youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategies and in the development and continuation of State-sponsored statewide youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52d9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> provide grants to institutions of higher education to coordinate the implementation of State-sponsored statewide or Tribal youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52da-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> collect and analyze data on State-sponsored statewide or Tribal youth suicide early intervention and prevention services that can be used to monitor the effectiveness of such services and for research, technical assistance, and policy development; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52db-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> assist eligible entities, through State-sponsored statewide or Tribal youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategies, in achieving targets for youth suicide reductions under title V of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s701">42 U.S.C. 701</ref> et seq.].</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af52dc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Eligible entity</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af52dd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/b/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Definition</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In this section, the term “eligible entity” means—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5af52de-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/b/1/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> a State;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5af52df-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/b/1/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> a public organization or private nonprofit organization designated by a State or Indian Tribe (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</ref>]) to develop or direct the State-sponsored statewide or Tribal youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategy; or</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5af52e0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/b/1/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> a Federally recognized Indian Tribe or Tribal organization (as defined in the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5301">25 U.S.C. 5301</ref> et seq.]) or an urban Indian organization (as defined in the Indian Health Care Improvement Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t25/s1601">25 U.S.C. 1601</ref> et seq.]) that is actively involved in the development and continuation of a Tribal youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategy.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af52e1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/b/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Limitation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall ensure that a State does not receive more than 1 grant or cooperative agreement under this section at any 1 time. For purposes of the preceding sentence, a State shall be considered to have received a grant or cooperative agreement if the eligible entity involved is the State or an entity designated by the State under paragraph (1)(B). Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to apply to entities described in paragraph (1)(C).</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af52e2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/b/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Consideration</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall take into consideration the extent of the need of the applicant, including the incidence and prevalence of suicide in the State and among the populations of focus, including rates of suicide determined by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention for the State or population of focus.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af52e3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/b/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">An entity described in paragraph (1)(A) or (1)(B) that applies for a grant or cooperative agreement under this section shall agree to consult or confer with entities described in paragraph (1)(C) and Native Hawaiian Health Care Systems, as applicable, in the applicable State with respect to the development and implementation of a statewide early intervention strategy.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af52e4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Preference</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In providing assistance under a grant or cooperative agreement under this section, an eligible entity shall give preference to public organizations, private nonprofit organizations, political subdivisions, institutions of higher education, and Tribal organizations actively involved with the State-sponsored statewide or Tribal youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategy that—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52e5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/c/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> provide early intervention and assessment services, including screening programs, to youth who are at risk for mental or emotional disorders that may lead to a suicide attempt, and that are integrated with school systems, educational institutions, juvenile justice systems, substance use disorder programs, mental health programs, foster care systems, pediatric health programs, and other child and youth support organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52e6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/c/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> demonstrate collaboration among early intervention and prevention services or certify that entities will engage in future collaboration;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52e7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/c/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> employ or include in their applications a commitment to evaluate youth suicide early intervention and prevention practices and strategies adapted to the local community;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52e8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/c/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> provide timely referrals for appropriate community-based mental health care and treatment of youth who are at risk for suicide in child-serving settings and agencies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52e9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/c/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> provide immediate support and information resources to families of youth who are at risk for suicide;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52ea-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/c/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> offer access to services and care to youth with diverse linguistic and cultural backgrounds;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52eb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/c/7"><num value="7">(7)</num><content> offer appropriate postsuicide intervention services, care, and information to families, friends, schools, educational institutions, juvenile justice systems, substance use disorder programs, mental health programs, foster care systems, pediatric health programs, and other child and youth support organizations of youth who recently completed suicide;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52ec-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/c/8"><num value="8">(8)</num><content> offer continuous and up-to-date information and awareness campaigns that target parents, family members, child care professionals, community care providers, and the general public and highlight the risk factors associated with youth suicide and the life-saving help and care available from early intervention and prevention services;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52ed-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/c/9"><num value="9">(9)</num><content> ensure that information and awareness campaigns on youth suicide risk factors, and early intervention and prevention services, use effective communication mechanisms that are targeted to and reach youth, families, schools, educational institutions, pediatric health programs, and youth organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52ee-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/c/10"><num value="10">(10)</num><content> provide a timely response system to ensure that child-serving professionals and providers are properly trained in youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategies and that child-serving professionals and providers involved in early intervention and prevention services are properly trained in effectively identifying youth who are at risk for suicide;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52ef-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/c/11"><num value="11">(11)</num><content> provide continuous training activities for child care professionals and community care providers on the latest youth suicide early intervention and prevention services practices and strategies;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52f0-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/c/12"><num value="12">(12)</num><content> conduct annual self-evaluations of outcomes and activities, including consulting with interested families and advocacy organizations;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52f1-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/c/13"><num value="13">(13)</num><content> provide services in areas or regions with rates of youth suicide that exceed the national average as determined by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52f2-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/c/14"><num value="14">(14)</num><content> obtain informed written consent from a parent or legal guardian of an at-risk child before involving the child in a youth suicide early intervention and prevention program; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5af52f3-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/c/15"><num value="15">(15)</num><content> provide to parents, legal guardians, and family members of youth, supplies to securely store means commonly used in suicide, if applicable, within the household.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af52f4-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Requirement for suicide prevention activities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Not less than 85 percent of grant funds received under this section shall be used to provide suicide prevention activities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af52f5-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Coordination and collaboration</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af52f6-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/e/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall collaborate with relevant Federal agencies and suicide working groups responsible for early intervention and prevention services relating to youth suicide.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af52f7-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/e/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Consultation</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall consult with—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5af52f8-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/e/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> State and local agencies, including agencies responsible for early intervention and prevention services under title XIX of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</ref> et seq.], the State Children’s Health Insurance Program under title XXI of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1397aa">42 U.S.C. 1397aa</ref> et seq.], and programs funded by grants under title V of the Social Security Act [<ref href="/us/usc/t42/s701">42 U.S.C. 701</ref> et seq.];</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5af52f9-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/e/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> local and national organizations that serve youth at risk for suicide and their families;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5af52fa-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/e/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> relevant national medical and other health and education specialty organizations;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5af52fb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/e/2/D"><num value="D">(D)</num><content> youth who are at risk for suicide, who have survived suicide attempts, or who are currently receiving care from early intervention services;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5af52fc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/e/2/E"><num value="E">(E)</num><content> families and friends of youth who are at risk for suicide, who have survived suicide attempts, who are currently receiving care from early intervention and prevention services, or who have completed suicide;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5af52fd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/e/2/F"><num value="F">(F)</num><content> qualified professionals who possess the specialized knowledge, skills, experience, and relevant attributes needed to serve youth at risk for suicide and their families; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5af52fe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/e/2/G"><num value="G">(G)</num><content> third-party payers, managed care organizations, and related commercial industries.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af52ff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/e/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Policy development</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5af5300-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/e/3/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> coordinate and collaborate on policy development at the Federal level with the relevant Department of Health and Human Services agencies and suicide working groups and the Department of Education, as appropriate; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5af5301-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/e/3/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> consult on policy development at the Federal level with the private sector, including consumer, medical, suicide prevention advocacy groups, and other health and education professional-based organizations, with respect to State-sponsored statewide or Tribal youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategies.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af5302-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction; religious and moral accommodation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section shall be construed to require suicide assessment, early intervention, or treatment services for youth whose parents or legal guardians object based on the parents’ or legal guardians’ religious beliefs or moral objections.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af5303-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/g"><num value="g" class="bold">(g)</num><heading class="bold"> Evaluations and report</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af5304-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/g/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Evaluations by eligible entities</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than 24 months after receiving a grant or cooperative agreement under this section, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary the results of an evaluation to be conducted by the entity concerning the effectiveness of the activities carried out under the grant or agreement.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af5305-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/g/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">Not later than <date date="2025-12-31">December 31, 2025</date>, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report concerning the results of—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5af5306-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/g/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> the evaluations conducted under paragraph (1); and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5af5307-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/g/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> an evaluation conducted by the Secretary to analyze the effectiveness and efficacy of the activities conducted with grants, collaborations, and consultations under this section.</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af5308-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/h"><num value="h" class="bold">(h)</num><heading class="bold"> Rule of construction; student medication</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36a">section 290bb–36a of this title</ref> shall be construed to allow school personnel to require that a student obtain any medication as a condition of attending school or receiving services.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af5309-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/i"><num value="i" class="bold">(i)</num><heading class="bold"> Prohibition</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Funds appropriated to carry out this section, <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–34">section 290bb–34 of this title</ref>, <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36a">section 290bb–36a of this title</ref>, or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36b">section 290bb–36b of this title</ref> shall not be used to pay for or refer for abortion.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5af530a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/j"><num value="j" class="bold">(j)</num><heading class="bold"> Parental consent</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">States and entities receiving funding under this section and <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36a">section 290bb–36a of this title</ref> shall obtain prior written, informed consent from the child’s parent or legal guardian for assessment services, school-sponsored programs, and treatment involving medication related to youth suicide conducted in elementary and secondary schools. The requirement of the preceding sentence does not apply in the following cases:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5b19bfb-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/j/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> In an emergency, where it is necessary to protect the immediate health and safety of the student or other students.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5b19bfc-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/j/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> Other instances, as defined by the State, where parental consent cannot reasonably be obtained.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5b19bfd-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/k"><num value="k" class="bold">(k)</num><heading class="bold"> Relation to education provisions</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Nothing in this section or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36a">section 290bb–36a of this title</ref> shall be construed to supersede <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1232g">section 1232g of title 20</ref>, including the requirement of prior parental consent for the disclosure of any education records. Nothing in this section or <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36a">section 290bb–36a of this title</ref> shall be construed to modify or affect parental notification requirements for programs authorized under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 [<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6301">20 U.S.C. 6301</ref> et seq.] (as amended by the No Child Left Behind Act of 2001; <ref href="/us/pl/107/110">Public Law 107–110</ref>).</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5b19bfe-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/l"><num value="l" class="bold">(l)</num><heading class="bold"> Definitions</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">In this section:</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5b19bff-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/l/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> Early intervention</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “early intervention” means a strategy or approach that is intended to prevent an outcome or to alter the course of an existing condition.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5b19c00-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/l/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Educational institution; institution of higher education; school</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term—</chapeau><subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5b19c01-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/l/2/A"><num value="A">(A)</num><content> “educational institution” means a school or institution of higher education;</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5b19c02-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/l/2/B"><num value="B">(B)</num><content> “institution of higher education” has the meaning given such term in <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s1001">section 1001 of title 20</ref>; and</content>
</subparagraph>
<subparagraph style="-uslm-lc:I13" class="indent2" id="idb5b19c03-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/l/2/C"><num value="C">(C)</num><content> “school” means an elementary school or secondary school (as such terms are defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 [<ref href="/us/usc/t20/s7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</ref>]).</content>
</subparagraph>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5b19c04-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/l/3"><num value="3" class="bold">(3)</num><heading class="bold"> Prevention</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “prevention” means a strategy or approach that reduces the likelihood or risk of onset, or delays the onset, of adverse health problems that have been known to lead to suicide.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5b19c05-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/l/4"><num value="4" class="bold">(4)</num><heading class="bold"> Youth</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The term “youth” means individuals who are up to 24 years of age.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5b19c06-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36/m"><num value="m" class="bold">(m)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of carrying out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $40,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb5b19c07-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title V, § 520E, as added <ref href="/us/pl/108/355/s3/c">Pub. L. 108–355, § 3(c)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-21">Oct. 21, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1409">118 Stat. 1409</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/tIX/s9215/kkk/3">Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9215(kkk)(3)</ref>, <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/129/2187">129 Stat. 2187</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/dB/tVI/s6001/c/1">Pub. L. 114–255, div. B, title VI, § 6001(c)(1)</ref>, title IX, § 9008(b), <date date="2016-12-13">Dec. 13, 2016</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/130/1203">130 Stat. 1203</ref>, 1242; <ref href="/us/pl/116/260/dBB/tIII/s315">Pub. L. 116–260, div. BB, title III, § 315</ref>, <date date="2020-12-27">Dec. 27, 2020</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/134/2932">134 Stat. 2932</ref>; <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/dFF/tI/s1422">Pub. L. 117–328, div. FF, title I, § 1422</ref>, <date date="2022-12-29">Dec. 29, 2022</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/136/5702">136 Stat. 5702</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb5b19c08-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb5b19c09-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb5b19c0a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Social Security Act, referred to in subsecs. (a)(5) and (e)(2)(A), is <ref href="/us/act/1935-08-14/ch531">act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/49/620">49 Stat. 620</ref>. Titles V, XIX, and XXI of the Act are classified generally to subchapters V (§ 701 et seq.), XIX (§ 1396 et seq.), and XXI (§ 1397aa et seq.), respectively, of chapter 7 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s1305">section 1305 of this title</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(1)(C), is <ref href="/us/pl/93/638">Pub. L. 93–638</ref>, <date date="1975-01-04">Jan. 4, 1975</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/88/2203">88 Stat. 2203</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 46 (§ 5301 et seq.) of Title 25, Indians. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s5301">section 5301 of Title 25</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Indian Health Care Improvement Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(1)(C), is <ref href="/us/pl/94/437">Pub. L. 94–437</ref>, <date date="1976-09-30">Sept. 30, 1976</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/90/1400">90 Stat. 1400</ref>, which is classified principally to chapter 18 (§ 1601 et seq.) of Title 25, Indians. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t25/s1601">section 1601 of Title 25</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965, referred to in subsec. (k), is <ref href="/us/pl/89/10">Pub. L. 89–10</ref>, <date date="1965-04-11">Apr. 11, 1965</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/79/27">79 Stat. 27</ref>, which is classified generally to chapter 70 (§ 6301 et seq.) of Title 20, Education. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6301">section 6301 of Title 20</ref> and Tables.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">The No Child Left Behind Act of 2001, referred to in subsec. (k), is <ref href="/us/pl/107/110">Pub. L. 107–110</ref>, <date date="2002-01-08">Jan. 8, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/115/1425">115 Stat. 1425</ref>. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 2002 Amendment note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6301">section 6301 of Title 20</ref>, Education, and Tables.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idb5b19c0b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 290bb–36, <ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373/tV/s520E">act July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title V, § 520E</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/pl/106/310/dB/tXXXI/s3111">Pub. L. 106–310, div. B, title XXXI, § 3111</ref>, <date date="2000-10-17">Oct. 17, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1186">114 Stat. 1186</ref>, and amended, which related to suicide prevention for children and adolescents, was renumbered section 520E–1 of act <date date="1944-07-01">July 1, 1944</date>, by <ref href="/us/pl/108/355/s3/b/2">Pub. L. 108–355, § 3(b)(2)</ref>, <date date="2004-10-21">Oct. 21, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1409">118 Stat. 1409</ref>, and transferred to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–36a">section 290bb–36a of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb5b19c0c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2022—<ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s1422/2">Pub. L. 117–328, § 1422(2)</ref>, substituted “Tribal” for “tribal” wherever appearing.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s1422/3">Pub. L. 117–328, § 1422(3)</ref>, inserted “pediatric health programs,” after “foster care systems,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(B). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s1422/4">Pub. L. 117–328, § 1422(4)</ref>, amended subpar. (B) generally. Prior to amendment, subpar. (B) read as follows: “a public organization or private nonprofit organization designated by a State to develop or direct the State-sponsored statewide youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategy; or”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(1)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s1422/1">Pub. L. 117–328, § 1422(1)</ref>, substituted “Tribe” for “tribe”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s1422/5/A">Pub. L. 117–328, § 1422(5)(A)</ref>, inserted “pediatric health programs,” after “foster care systems,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(7). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s1422/5/B">Pub. L. 117–328, § 1422(5)(B)</ref>, inserted “pediatric health programs,” after “foster care systems,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(9). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s1422/5/C">Pub. L. 117–328, § 1422(5)(C)</ref>, inserted “pediatric health programs,” after “educational institutions,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(15). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s1422/5/D">Pub. L. 117–328, § 1422(5)(D)</ref>–(F), added par. (15).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (d). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s1422/6">Pub. L. 117–328, § 1422(6)</ref>, substituted “suicide prevention activities” for “direct services” in heading and “suicide prevention activities” for “direct services, of which not less than 5 percent shall be used for activities authorized under subsection (a)(3)” in text.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e)(3)(A). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s1422/7">Pub. L. 117–328, § 1422(7)</ref>, inserted “and the Department of Education, as appropriate” after “agencies and suicide working groups”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s1422/8/A">Pub. L. 117–328, § 1422(8)(A)</ref>, substituted “24” for “18”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s1422/8/B">Pub. L. 117–328, § 1422(8)(B)</ref>, substituted “<date date="2025-12-31">December 31, 2025</date>” for “2 years after <date date="2016-12-13">December 13, 2016</date>”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (<i>l</i>)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s1422/9">Pub. L. 117–328, § 1422(9)</ref>, substituted “up to 24 years of age” for “between 10 and 24 years of age”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/117/328/s1422/10">Pub. L. 117–328, § 1422(10)</ref>, substituted “$40,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027” for “$30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2020—Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/116/260">Pub. L. 116–260</ref> added par. (4).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2016—Subsec. (a). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s6001/c/1">Pub. L. 114–255, § 6001(c)(1)</ref>, substituted “Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use” for “Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration” in introductory provisions.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (a)(1). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s9008/b/1">Pub. L. 114–255, § 9008(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “substance use disorder” for “substance abuse”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s9008/b/2/A">Pub. L. 114–255, § 9008(b)(2)(A)</ref>, substituted “ensure that a State does not receive more than 1 grant or cooperative agreement under this section at any 1 time” for “ensure that each State is awarded only 1 grant or cooperative agreement under this section” and “received” for “been awarded”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (b)(3). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s9008/b/2/B">Pub. L. 114–255, § 9008(b)(2)(B)</ref>, added par. (3).</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (c)(1), (7). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s9008/b/1">Pub. L. 114–255, § 9008(b)(1)</ref>, substituted “substance use disorder” for “substance abuse”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (g)(2). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s9008/b/3">Pub. L. 114–255, § 9008(b)(3)</ref>, substituted “2 years after <date date="2016-12-13">December 13, 2016</date>,” for “2 years after <date date="2004-10-21">October 21, 2004</date>,”.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (m). <ref href="/us/pl/114/255/s9008/b/4">Pub. L. 114–255, § 9008(b)(4)</ref>, added subsec. (m) and struck out former subsec. (m) which authorized appropriations for fiscal years 2005 to 2007 and provided that the Secretary should give preference to certain States if less than $3,500,000 was appropriated for any fiscal year.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">2015—Subsec. (<i>l</i>)(2)(C). <ref href="/us/pl/114/95">Pub. L. 114–95</ref> substituted “elementary school or secondary school (as such terms are defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965)” for “elementary or secondary school (as such terms are defined in section 9101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965)”.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb5b19c0d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb5b19c0e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 2015 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Amendment by <ref href="/us/pl/114/95">Pub. L. 114–95</ref> effective <date date="2015-12-10">Dec. 10, 2015</date>, except with respect to certain noncompetitive programs and competitive programs, see <ref href="/us/pl/114/95/s5">section 5 of Pub. L. 114–95</ref>, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s6301">section 6301 of Title 20</ref>, Education.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb5b19c0f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Congressional Findings</heading><p><ref href="/us/pl/108/355/s2">Pub. L. 108–355, § 2</ref>, <date date="2004-10-21">Oct. 21, 2004</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/118/1404">118 Stat. 1404</ref>, provided that: <quotedContent origin="/us/pl/108/355/s2">
<inline>“Congress makes the following findings:</inline>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="1">“(1)</num><content> More children and young adults die from suicide each year than from cancer, heart disease, AIDS, birth defects, stroke, and chronic lung disease combined.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="2">“(2)</num><content> Over 4,000 children and young adults tragically take their lives every year, making suicide the third overall cause of death between the ages of 10 and 24. According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, suicide is the third overall cause of death among college-age students.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="3">“(3)</num><content> According to the National Center for Injury Prevention and Control of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, children and young adults accounted for 15 percent of all suicides completed in 2000.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="4">“(4)</num><content> From 1952 to 1995, the rate of suicide in children and young adults tripled.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="5">“(5)</num><content> From 1980 to 1997, the rate of suicide among young adults ages 15 to 19 increased 11 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="6">“(6)</num><content> From 1980 to 1997, the rate of suicide among children ages 10 to 14 increased 109 percent.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="7">“(7)</num><content> According to the National Center of Health Statistics, suicide rates among Native Americans range from 1.5 to 3 times the national average for other groups, with young people ages 15 to 34 making up 64 percent of all suicides.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="8">“(8)</num><content> Congress has recognized that youth suicide is a public health tragedy linked to underlying mental health problems and that youth suicide early intervention and prevention activities are national priorities.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="9">“(9)</num><content> Youth suicide early intervention and prevention have been listed as urgent public health priorities by the President’s New Freedom Commission in [probably should be “on”] Mental Health (2002), the Institute of Medicine’s Reducing Suicide: A National Imperative (2002), the National Strategy for Suicide Prevention: Goals and Objectives for Action (2001), and the Surgeon General’s Call to Action To Prevent Suicide (1999).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="10">“(10)</num><content> Many States have already developed comprehensive statewide youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategies that seek to provide effective early intervention and prevention services.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="11">“(11)</num><content> In a recent report, a startling 85 percent of college counseling centers revealed an increase in the number of students they see with psychological problems. Furthermore, the American College Health Association found that 61 percent of college students reported feeling hopeless, 45 percent said they felt so depressed they could barely function, and 9 percent felt suicidal.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="12">“(12)</num><content> There is clear evidence of an increased incidence of depression among college students. According to a survey described in the Chronicle of Higher Education (<date date="2002-02-01">February 1, 2002</date>), depression among freshmen has nearly doubled (from 8.2 percent to 16.3 percent). Without treatment, researchers recently noted that ‘depressed adolescents are at risk for school failure, social isolation, promiscuity, self-medication with drugs and alcohol, and suicide—now the third leading cause of death among 10–24 year olds.’.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="13">“(13)</num><content> Researchers who conducted the study ‘Changes in Counseling Center Client Problems Across 13 Years’ (1989–2001) at Kansas State University stated that ‘students are experiencing more stress, more anxiety, more depression than they were a decade ago.’ (The Chronicle of Higher Education, <date date="2003-02-14">February 14, 2003</date>).</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="14">“(14)</num><content> According to the 2001 National Household Survey on Drug Abuse, 20 percent of full-time undergraduate college students use illicit drugs.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="15">“(15)</num><content> The 2001 National Household Survey on Drug Abuse also reported that 18.4 percent of adults aged 18 to 24 are dependent on or abusing illicit drugs or alcohol. In addition, the study found that ‘serious mental illness is highly correlated with substance dependence or abuse. Among adults with serious mental illness in 2001, 20.3 percent were dependent on or abused alcohol or illicit drugs, while the rate among adults without serious mental illness was only 6.3 percent.’.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="16">“(16)</num><content> A 2003 Gallagher’s Survey of Counseling Center Directors found that 81 percent were concerned about the increasing number of students with more serious psychological problems, 67 percent reported a need for more psychiatric services, and 63 percent reported problems with growing demand for services without an appropriate increase in resources.</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I22" class="indent1"><num value="17">“(17)</num><content> The International Association of Counseling Services accreditation standards recommend 1 counselor per 1,000 to 1,500 students. According to the 2003 Gallagher’s Survey of Counseling Center Directors, the ratio of counselors to students is as high as 1 counselor per 2,400 students at institutions of higher education with more than 15,000 students.”</content>
</paragraph>
</quotedContent>
</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
