<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb5ace11a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–25d"><num value="290bb–25d">§ 290bb–25d.</num><heading> Centers of excellence on services for individuals with fetal alcohol syndrome and alcohol-related birth defects and treatment for individuals with such conditions and their families</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5ace11b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–25d/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall make awards of grants, cooperative agreements, or contracts to public or nonprofit private entities for the purposes of establishing not more than four centers of excellence to study techniques for the prevention of fetal alcohol syndrome and alcohol-related birth defects and adaptations of innovative clinical interventions and service delivery improvements for the provision of comprehensive services to individuals with fetal alcohol syndrome or alcohol-related birth defects and their families and for providing training on such conditions.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5ace11c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–25d/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Use of funds</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">An award under subsection (a) may be used to—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5ace11d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–25d/b/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> study adaptations of innovative clinical interventions and service delivery improvements strategies for children and adults with fetal alcohol syndrome or alcohol-related birth defects and their families;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5ace11e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–25d/b/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> identify communities which have an exemplary comprehensive system of care for such individuals so that they can provide technical assistance to other communities attempting to set up such a system of care;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5ace11f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–25d/b/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> provide technical assistance to communities who do not have a comprehensive system of care for such individuals and their families;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5ace120-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–25d/b/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> train community leaders, mental health and substance abuse professionals, families, law enforcement personnel, judges, health professionals, persons working in financial assistance programs, social service personnel, child welfare professionals, and other service providers on the implications of fetal alcohol syndrome and alcohol-related birth defects, the early identification of and referral for such conditions;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5ace121-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–25d/b/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> develop innovative techniques for preventing alcohol use by women in child bearing years;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5ace122-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–25d/b/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> perform other functions, to the extent authorized by the Secretary after consideration of recommendations made by the National Task Force on Fetal Alcohol Syndrome.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5ace123-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–25d/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Report</heading><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5ace124-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–25d/c/1"><num value="1" class="bold">(1)</num><heading class="bold"> In general</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">A recipient of an award under subsection (a) shall at the end of the period of funding report to the Secretary on any innovative techniques that have been discovered for preventing alcohol use among women of child bearing years.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I79" class="indent3 firstIndent-2" id="idb5ace125-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–25d/c/2"><num value="2" class="bold">(2)</num><heading class="bold"> Dissemination of findings</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1">The Secretary shall upon receiving a report under paragraph (1) disseminate the findings to appropriate public and private entities.</p>
</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5ace126-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–25d/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Duration of awards</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">With respect to an award under subsection (a), the period during which payments under such award are made to the recipient may not exceed 5 years.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5ace127-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–25d/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Evaluation</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Secretary shall evaluate each project carried out under subsection (a) and shall disseminate the findings with respect to each such evaluation to appropriate public and private entities.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5ace128-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s290bb–25d/f"><num value="f" class="bold">(f)</num><heading class="bold"> Authorization of appropriations</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For the purpose of carrying out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for fiscal year 2001, and such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2002 and 2003.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb5ace129-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title V, § 519D, as added <ref href="/us/pl/106/310/dB/tXXXI/s3110">Pub. L. 106–310, div. B, title XXXI, § 3110</ref>, <date date="2000-10-17">Oct. 17, 2000</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/114/1185">114 Stat. 1185</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
</section>
