<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section xmlns="http://xml.house.gov/schemas/uslm/1.0" style="-uslm-lc:I80" id="idb5c9915b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s291e"><num value="291e">§ 291e.</num><heading> Projects for construction or modernization</heading><subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5c9915c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s291e/a"><num value="a" class="bold">(a)</num><heading class="bold"> Application; contents</heading><chapeau style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">For each project pursuant to a State plan approved under this part, there shall be submitted to the Surgeon General, through the State agency, an application by the State or a political subdivision thereof or by a public or other nonprofit agency. If two or more such agencies join in the project, the application may be filed by one or more of such agencies. Such application shall set forth—</chapeau><paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5c9915d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s291e/a/1"><num value="1">(1)</num><content> a description of the site for such project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5c9915e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s291e/a/2"><num value="2">(2)</num><content> plans and specifications therefor, in accordance with regulations prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s291c">section 291c of this title</ref>;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5c9915f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s291e/a/3"><num value="3">(3)</num><content> reasonable assurance that title to such site is or will be vested in one or more of the agencies filing the application or in a public or other nonprofit agency which is to operate the facility on completion of the project;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5c99160-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s291e/a/4"><num value="4">(4)</num><content> reasonable assurance that adequate financial support will be available for the completion of the project and for its maintenance and operation when completed;</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5c99161-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s291e/a/5"><num value="5">(5)</num><content> reasonable assurance that all laborers and mechanics employed by contractors or subcontractors in the performance of construction or modernization on the project will be paid wages at rates not less than those prevailing on similar work in the locality as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with sections 3141–3144, 3146, and 3147 of title 40; and the Secretary of Labor shall have with respect to the labor standards specified in this paragraph the authority and functions set forth in Reorganization Plan Numbered 14 of 1950 (15 F.R. 3176) and <ref href="/us/usc/t40/s3145">section 3145 of title 40</ref>; and</content>
</paragraph>
<paragraph style="-uslm-lc:I12" class="indent1" id="idb5c99162-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s291e/a/6"><num value="6">(6)</num><content> a certification by the State agency of the Federal share for the project.</content>
</paragraph>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5c99163-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s291e/b"><num value="b" class="bold">(b)</num><heading class="bold"> Approval by Surgeon General; requisites; additional approval by Secretary of Health and Human Services</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">The Surgeon General shall approve such application if sufficient funds to pay the Federal share of the cost of such project are available from the appropriate allotment to the State, and if the Surgeon General finds (1) that the application contains such reasonable assurance as to title, financial support, and payment of prevailing rates of wages; (2) that the plans and specifications are in accord with the regulations prescribed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s291c">section 291c of this title</ref>; (3) that the application is in conformity with the State plan approved under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s291d">section 291d of this title</ref> and contains an assurance that in the operation of the project there will be compliance with the applicable requirements of the regulations prescribed under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s291c/e">section 291c(e) of this title</ref>, and with State standards for operation and maintenance; and (4) that the application has been approved and recommended by the State agency, opportunity has been provided, prior to such approval and recommendation, for consideration of the project by the public or nonprofit private agency or organization which has developed the comprehensive regional, metropolitan area, or other local area plan or plans referred to in <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s246/b">section 246(b) of this title</ref> covering the area in which such project is to be located or, if there is no such agency or organization, by the State agency administering or supervising the administration of the State plan approved under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s246/a">section 246(a) of this title</ref>, and the application is for a project which is entitled to priority over other projects within the State in accordance with the regulations prescribed pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s291c/a">section 291c(a) of this title</ref>. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, the Surgeon General may approve such an application for a project for construction or modernization of a rehabilitation facility only if it is also approved by the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5c99164-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s291e/c"><num value="c" class="bold">(c)</num><heading class="bold"> Opportunity for hearing required prior to disapproval</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">No application shall be disapproved until the Surgeon General has afforded the State agency an opportunity for a hearing.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5c99165-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s291e/d"><num value="d" class="bold">(d)</num><heading class="bold"> Amendments subject to same approval as original applications</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Amendment of any approved application shall be subject to approval in the same manner as an original application.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<subsection style="-uslm-lc:I19" class="indent2 firstIndent-2" id="idb5c99166-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa" identifier="/us/usc/t42/s291e/e"><num value="e" class="bold">(e)</num><heading class="bold"> Outpatient facilities; requirements of applicants</heading><content><p style="-uslm-lc:I11" class="indent0">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, no application for an outpatient facility shall be approved under this section unless the applicant is (1) a State, political subdivision, or public agency, or (2) a corporation or association which owns and operates a nonprofit hospital (as defined in section 291<i>o</i> of this title) or which provides reasonable assurance that the services of a general hospital will be available to patients of such facility who are in need of hospital care.</p>
</content>
</subsection>
<sourceCredit id="idb5c99167-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">(<ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373">July 1, 1944, ch. 373</ref>, title VI, § 605, as added <ref href="/us/pl/88/443/s3/a">Pub. L. 88–443, § 3(a)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-18">Aug. 18, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/453">78 Stat. 453</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/pl/91/296/tI">Pub. L. 91–296, title I</ref>, §§ 111(a), 116(e), <date date="1970-06-30">June 30, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/340">84 Stat. 340</ref>, 342; <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/tV/s509/b">Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b)</ref>, <date date="1979-10-17">Oct. 17, 1979</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/93/695">93 Stat. 695</ref>.)</sourceCredit>
<notes type="uscNote" id="idb5c99168-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="editorialNotes" id="idb5c99169-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Editorial Notes</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I75" topic="referencesInText" id="idb5c9916a-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">References in Text</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Reorganization Plan Numbered 14 of 1950, referred to in subsec. (a)(5), is set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I76" topic="codification" id="idb5c9916b-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Codification</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">In subsec. (a) (5), “sections 3141–3144, 3146, and 3147 of title 40” substituted for “the Davis-Bacon Act, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s276a">40 U.S.C. 276a</ref>—276a–5)” and “<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s3145">section 3145 of title 40</ref>” substituted for “<ref href="/us/act/1934-06-13/s2">section 2 of the Act of June 13, 1934</ref>, as amended (<ref href="/us/usc/t40/s276c">40 U.S.C. 276c</ref>)” on authority of <ref href="/us/pl/107/217/s5/c">Pub. L. 107–217, § 5(c)</ref>, <date date="2002-08-21">Aug. 21, 2002</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/116/1303">116 Stat. 1303</ref>, the first section of which enacted Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="priorProvisions" id="idb5c9916c-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Prior Provisions</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 291e, act July 1944, ch. 373, title VI, § 622, as added <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-13/ch958/s2">Aug. 13, 1946, ch. 958, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/1041">60 Stat. 1041</ref>; amended 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 1, §§ 5, 8, eff. <date date="1953-04-11">Apr. 11, 1953</date>, 18 F.R. 2053, <ref href="/us/stat/67/631">67 Stat. 631</ref>, authorized Surgeon General to prescribe general regulations, prior to the general amendment of this subchapter by <ref href="/us/pl/88/443">Pub. L. 88–443</ref>. See <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s291c">section 291c of this title</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 291h(a), (c), <ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373/tVI/s625">act July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title VI, § 625</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/act/1946-08-13/ch958/s2">Aug. 13, 1946, ch. 958, § 2</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/60/1041">60 Stat. 1041</ref>; amended <ref href="/us/act/1949-10-25/ch722/s8">Oct. 25, 1949, ch. 722, § 8</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/63/901">63 Stat. 901</ref>, related to subject matter similar to this section, prior to the general amendment of this subchapter by <ref href="/us/pl/88/443">Pub. L. 88–443</ref>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">A prior section 291v(d), <ref href="/us/act/1944-07-01/ch373/tVI/s654">act July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title VI, § 654</ref>, as added <ref href="/us/act/1954-07-12/ch471/s3">July 12, 1954, ch. 471, § 3</ref>, <ref href="/us/stat/68/463">68 Stat. 463</ref>, related to subject matter similar to this section, prior to the general amendment of this subchapter by <ref href="/us/pl/88/443">Pub. L. 88–443</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="amendments" id="idb5c9916d-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Amendments</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">1970—Subsec. (b)(4). <ref href="/us/pl/91/296/s111/a">Pub. L. 91–296, § 111(a)</ref>, inserted provisions requiring that the appropriate area wide health planning agency be given an opportunity to consider the project for which an application is made before approval is given.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Subsec. (e). <ref href="/us/pl/91/296/s116/e">Pub. L. 91–296, § 116(e)</ref>, substituted “an outpatient facility” for “a diagnostic or treatment center” and inserted provisions extending coverage to include corporations and associations which, although not owning or operating hospitals offer services of a general hospital to patients in need of hospital care.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="statutoryNotes" id="idb5c9916e-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I78" topic="changeOfName" id="idb5c9916f-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Change of Name</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">“Secretary of Health and Human Services” substituted for “Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare” in subsec. (b) pursuant to <ref href="/us/pl/96/88/s509/b">section 509(b) of Pub. L. 96–88</ref>, which is classified to <ref href="/us/usc/t20/s3508/b">section 3508(b) of Title 20</ref>, Education.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="effectiveDateOfAmendment" id="idb5c99170-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Effective Date of 1970 Amendment</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/91/296/tI/s111/a">Pub. L. 91–296, title I, § 111(a)</ref>, <date date="1970-06-30">June 30, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/340">84 Stat. 340</ref>, provided that the amendment made by that section is effective with respect to applications approved under this subchapter after <date date="1970-06-30">June 30, 1970</date>.</p>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/91/296/tI/s116/e">Pub. L. 91–296, title I, § 116(e)</ref>, <date date="1970-06-30">June 30, 1970</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/84/342">84 Stat. 342</ref>, applicable with respect to applications approved under this subchapter after <date date="1970-06-30">June 30, 1970</date>, see <ref href="/us/pl/91/296/s116/g">section 116(g) of Pub. L. 91–296</ref>, set out as a note under section 291<i>o</i> of this title.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb5c99171-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Applications Approved Prior to <date date="1964-08-18">Aug. 18, 1964</date></heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/88/443/s3/b/1">Pub. L. 88–443, § 3(b)(1)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-18">Aug. 18, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/462">78 Stat. 462</ref>, providing that applications approved, and allotments appropriated prior to <date date="1964-08-18">Aug. 18, 1964</date>, shall be governed by this subchapter as in effect prior to such date, is set out as an Effective Date note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s291">section 291 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" topic="miscellaneous" id="idb5c99172-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered smallCaps">Funds for Modernization Projects; Conditions To Be Met Before Approval</heading><p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0"><ref href="/us/pl/88/443/s3/b/5">Pub. L. 88–443, § 3(b)(5)</ref>, <date date="1964-08-18">Aug. 18, 1964</date>, <ref href="/us/stat/78/462">78 Stat. 462</ref>, provided that no application with respect to a modernization project may be approved for purposes of receiving funds from an allotment under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s291/a/2">section 291(a)(2) of this title</ref> before <date date="1965-07-01">July 1, 1965</date>, or before a State plan has been approved, as well as certain other requirements. See Effective Date note set out under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s291">section 291 of this title</ref>.</p>
</note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I74" role="crossHeading" topic="execDoc" id="idb5c99173-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa"><heading class="centered"><b>Executive Documents</b></heading></note>
<note style="-uslm-lc:I85" topic="transferOfFunctions" id="idb5c99174-3a70-11f1-ae07-e4213316b5fa">
<heading class="centered smallCaps">Transfer of Functions</heading>
<p style="-uslm-lc:I21" class="indent0">Office of Surgeon General abolished by section 3 of Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1966, eff. <date date="1966-06-25">June 25, 1966</date>, 31 F.R. 8855, <ref href="/us/stat/80/1610">80 Stat. 1610</ref>, and functions thereof transferred to Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare by section 1 of Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1966, set out as a note under <ref href="/us/usc/t42/s202">section 202 of this title</ref>. Office of Surgeon General reestablished within the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Health, see Notice of Department of Health and Human Services, Office of the Assistant Secretary for Health, <date date="1987-03-30">Mar. 30, 1987</date>, 52 F.R. 11754.</p>
</note>
</notes>
</section>
